苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
Episode 004
Ball torn to pieces
- Wow…
- Awesome.
Such an accurate spike…
…almost like a machine.
You're right… she's amazing.
Are you the new captain,
Ayuhara Kozue-san?
Midori! Midori, is it you?
Naka? Wah!
Midori, what's the matter?
I've transferred today.
My dad's company opened a new office here in Fujimi.
- Ah. Long time no see.
- How many years has it been?
Hayakawa Midori-san and I were in the same class in the grade school.
We were in the fifth class, I think.
If I remember, she moved to her mom's place, but she returned now.
Hayakawa-san's family is in top management, so they're very rich.
Who would've think you'd enter a cool volleyball club.
I've just started, so I'm not any good yet.
But you're something else, Midori. I could see it.
Really. It's my first time seeing someone this good.
I've been playing ever since I went to Kyoto.
But this much should be easy for Ayuhara-san.
Well, I'd have to try…
There's no way you couldn't do it. After all, Kozue-san, you're the captain, right?
From now on, I'll be coming to the volleyball club, captain.
Well, let's practice. The tournament's close.
OK!
Bye.
I'll be coming to practice too from tomorrow.
I hope we get along.
Hey, captain!
The volleyball club's new captain!
Tsutomu-san!
Ayuhara-kun, did something happen? You seem down.
No, it's nothing.
Tired from the practice?
The tournament's schedule was decided.
It'd be troublesome if the new captain Ayuhara Kozue wasn't there.
You have to do your best to win the championship.
- Hey, Tsutomu-san.
- Hm? What it is?
Tsutomu-san!
Tsutomu-san!!
- It's Midori-san.
Let me introduce you.
Oh. Ayuhara-san.
What, you know yourselves already?
Yes. I entered the volleyball club today. I've already greeted captain Ayuhara-san.
That's how it was.
Tsutomu-san, you're not in the same class as Ayuhara-san, but I feel you get along.
Yeah. To tell you the truth, we're related.
My aunt, in other words my mom's younger sister, is married to Ayuhara-kun's father's younger brother.
In short, her uncle. Understand?
It's a little roundabout, but we're most definitely relatives.
Oh, that was it? Ayuhara-san, I've known Tsutomu-san ever since kindergarten.
We became good friends at elementary school.
Midori-san was my neighbor before she went to Kyoto.
Hey, Tsutomu-san. I was about to deliver a welcome gift to your family from my papa.
It's good that I met you here. Let's go together.
We'll be going then.
Bye.
Hayakawa Midori-san has transferred.
I feel that something's about to happen in the club.
I hope I am thinking too much.
Fujimi Academy
Teachers room
Thank you very much.
No, no. After having received the call from your father, I thought I should put an effort into the sport clubs as well.
Well, volleyball club comes first.
The students who were said to be poor performing are slowly improving their grades too.
I guess this is thanks to the sports, too.
Indeed. This alone is enough to consider sports important.
The school is mostly about academic achievements. But yes, putting effort into club victories should be good.
If they do win, it might increase the school's prestige.
I will do my best. We will certainly win the tournament.
There's no way we'll lose.
- Bye bye!
- See you later!
Hm? I wonder where's everyone.
Chief! I mean, captain!
What's the matter? It's practice time.
We can practice in the gym since today.
Huh? In the gym?
After our match, the teachers and everyone have finally noticed us.
They want to support sport clubs more. Especially the volleyball club!
- Really?
- Yep. They're slow if you ask me.
But in reality, Midori has asked the head teacher for a favor.
Eh? Hayakawa-san did?
- Leave them here.
- Okay.
Thank you, Hayakawa-san. It's wonderful that we can practice here.
We no longer need to worry about cold weather.
Ha- Hayakawa-san sure is powerful.
It's only natural when she's so rich. With wealth comes great power.
Right. It's good that Hayakawa-san has joined us.
Not only we're able to practice here - her spike is amazing.
Thank you, Hayakawa-san.
Hm? What for?
Ah, for being able to practice here? It's only natural.
It's all for the victory in the tournament. Now, let's practice. You better do you best too.
I heard about your reputation of the "useless group".
- Huh?
- Don't say that, it makes my ears hurt.
That's an old story. We're different now.
Exactly! We're serious now.
That's because of the volleyball, right?
Yep. Ever since we started playing-
That's not it, isn't it?
Huh? Then what is it?
If it wasn't for Ayuhara-san, you'd get expelled from the school, no?
Who said that?
That's outrageous.
It's way over the line. Who said it? I won't forgive it.
I heard that from Ayuhara-san.
- Really?
- Her?
I never said such a thing!
Ayuhara-san, it's okay to be open about this. Didn't I make myself clear about that?
But…
We truly owe Ayuhara-san…
…but expulsion?
- That's cruel.
- Yes, it's just heartless.
- Don't get ahead of yourself!
- Easy there.
Everyone, let it be. You're here now, right? If we win the tournament, let's just forget it.
Hmph! Stick it.
Hmph.
Practice time. Toss the ball.
Hayakawa-san, here I go.
Here!
That's… that's terrible.
- Ayuhara-san.
- Katsuragi-san…
I don't think you're such a person.
Ayuhara-san!
Midori was like that since elementary school.
She's wealthy, alone and selfish.
Huh…
Everyone, listen.
The Fujimi Academy hasn't won a match even once.
I want a team that is a capable of winning the upcoming tournament.
I also think that we need a resolute captain. Don't you think so too?
- Of course.
- Hayakawa-san would be good.
Yeah. After all it's thanks to her that we can practice in a gym.
If Midori was the captain, we'd get far.
What are you saying?
You have some never saying that.
Who do you think gathered us here?
Even so, Ayuhara-san did badmouth us.
Do you really think our captain would do that? That's ridiculous.
Midori, what are you scheming? Stop being so egocentric. If you only think about yourself, you'll trip soon enough.
- Hey, it's about time you said something!
- Kashiwagi-san.
It's okay already.
But she…
Hayakawa-san.
I resign my role as a captain.
Ayuhara-san…!
Ayuhara-san, don't get me wrong.
I wanted to be the captain, but didn't ask the head teacher.
I am thinking of the volleyball club.
Also it's not up to oneself to become or quit being a captain.
It's a decision of everyone.
Let's skip the practice today.
Yeah.
Get a hold of yourself. You're the only one who can be the captain.
Exactly. Our chief must be the captain.
Rather than who is or isn't the captain…
…I am afraid if Hayakawa-san will torn apart our club that we've just managed to form.
Volleyball is about team work.
Don't lose to that selfish lass.
When captain has it together, everything works out.
I won't give up my love for volleyball.
I want a strong and elegant team as much as Hayakawa-san. No, I want it even more than her.
But…
- Hold it while I pull the other side.
- Roger.
Here!
Oh Hayakawa-san, you don't need to do such things.
We'll do it for you.
Yeah, I'll do it.
It won't do. No matter how good I am, I am still a new member. It's only natural that I perform newcomers' tasks.
Hayakawa-san is so splendid.
Ayuhara-san never did such things.
That's because she's the captain. I am different.
But I'd do this even if I was the captain.
After all when one loves volleyball, they're fine doing any important task.
How nice.
She's great.
Way better than Ayuhara-san ever was.
Yeah, way better!
Ayuhara-kun.
Here you are. I came all the way from home.
Do you need anything?
I heard you resigned.
Everyone heard.
Kashiwagi-san is really worried about you.
People like Midori-san are restless since their childhoods until they're treated like a queen.
That's the truth of it.
I guess.
But why does she want to become a captain so much?
I'd be fine if I wasn't captain.
Don't talk like that. It's not like you.
I could probably talk her out of it…
…but it'd be better if you resolved it by yourself.
With the tournament around the corner, it's the most important time for your club.
What's wrong, new captain?
Get a grip!
Haven't you found your purpose in the volleyball club?
Or did you become like a balloon without air again?
Quit the volleyball!
Quit?!
Well, with the way you're now…
I still have the patience for this.
What would happen if we had a fight now?
Volleyball club will end.
I love volleyball.
That's why even if Hayakawa-san did become a captain, I'd still be okay with it.
I'm home.
Hm?
What's that? There's no stamp.
It was delivered directly.
Ayuhara-san. I want to talk with you alone.
Please meet me at 7 AM at the volleball's club room.
I wonder what Hayakawa-san is up to now?
Hayakawa-san, wait!
Why are we here so early?
I forgot to lock the door yesterday.
I realized only this morning.
It'd be bad if our equipment was stolen, and this is why I've asked you to come.
That was it. I don't think anyone would steal anything.
I think it'll be all right, but let's go and find out.
Volleyball club's room
It it's unlocked all right.
Ayuhara-san!
Ayuhara-san, you…
What are you doing here?
You come at the right moment. Look at this.
- Whoa.
- How terrible!
The net is torn too.
Who would do such a thing?
Someone who hates volleyball club.
Ayuhara-san, what is this?
This? It was lying here.
They probably used this.
- Ayuhara-san, you're pretty dreadful person.
- What are you talking about?
- Ayuhara-san, you're holding a grudge against me, is that right?
- Huh?
Hayakawa-san, are you saying it was me?
I can't think of anyone but you.
There's no way any of us could destroy important equipment.
I'm finished listening to our captain. Aren't you, everyone?
The title of captain doesn't fit Ayuhara-san.
What do you think?
I'm disappointed in you. I didn't think you're such a person.
What's so funny?
Hayakawa-san, do you want to become the captain this bad?
If that's the case, just say so openly!
Don't resort to writing roundabout letters.
What's with that look?
Are you trying to pick a fight with me?
With this, I think it's clear that you don't deserve the title of captain.
Let's go, everyone.
She's the worst.
She's finished.
I am trying to do my best for the club, but…
…what should I do from now on?
- Wow!
- Brand new!
These were all funded by Hayakawa-san's father. It sure is nice to be rich.
With these we'll be able to practice.
Oh, Ayuhara-san.
Everyone decided that I'll be our new captain.
Let's work together.
Midori, if you don't knock it off, I'm not going to tolerate it.
Hayakawa-san, don't you think that's too much?
But that's the decision of our members.
Midori…!
It's okay. It already has been decided.
Ayuhara-san, won't you be coming to practice today?
But it'd be bothersome to everyone if you don't listen to me from tomorrow on. I want to make a strong team.
Everyone is crazy.
It's okay.
Ayuhara-san, looks like you lost to Hayakawa-san.
Yeah. Defeat doesn't suit you, chief.
I'll endure it if it means improvement for the volleyball club.
- Bu…
- How far can you go by yourself?
Kouze-chan.
- Kozue-chan.
- Oh?
What is it, auntie?
Oh, did something happen?
You've returned earlier today and you seem off.
Did you feel unwell?
No, it's nothing.
That's good then. I got a call from Hayakawa-san's house today.
They want to invite you to a dinner, Kozue-chan. They'll even send a car for you.
Hayakawa-san…?
Why again?
This way please. Make yourself comfortable.
Ayuhara-san!
You too?
- Yeah.
- Yep.
My, my.
Welcome. Please sit.
I am Midori's father.
Uhm, where is Midori?
She'll be here in a second. Sit, sit.
As a matter of fact, it was me who called you here today.
I wonder why?
Midori became your captain. I hope you get along well?
- Uhm…
- Yeah.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
What I want to ask you is…
…is for you to do your best under Midori.
What do you mean?
I want to show Midori to the world by putting her in the Fujimi Academy.
I think that Midori's true power goes unnoticed.
If your volleyball club became Japan's best, Midori's fame would obviously rise too.
As a bonus, I'll buy each of you whatever you like.
I want to get along with you.
I refuse.
Volleyball isn't a place to make yourself popular.
Yeah. You're asking you to work hard so that Midori alone gets famous.
That's ridiculous.
Midori-san, I'll make myself clear.
With your way of thinking, there's no way you'll get to the top.
What are you saying.
- Let's go back.
- Excuse us.
Dad…
What did I say to offend her so much.
Damn. I have to think of something else.
She has some nerve.
What does she think volleyball is about?
Exactly.
I hoped that if I persevered, everything will work out, but…
Wait.
Wait!
I need to talk with you.
Ayuhara-san, I'm sorry. I have to apologize to you.
It was me who cut balls and the net.
I thought it'll be hard for us to get famous under Ayuhara-san.
That's why I did it. It's very embarrassing and I regret it now. I apologize.
But…
I really want to make up with you.
For the sake of our club… for teamwork.
I think the same.
Will you forgive me then?
Yes, of course.
Let's do our best on our way to the tournament.
Yeah… thank you very much.
It went well.
No matter what, I need Ayuhara Kozue-san's power for the tournament.
But when it comes to playing, I'm the best.
I'll certainly become a queen.
After Midori and Kozue called a truce, the coach Hongou…
…immediately begins a hard training.
But the peace doesn't hold long and soon enough, a problem with staff members arises.
Even so, the coach continues with his training.
Under his guidance, Kouze and Midori's true rilvarly becomes ablaze.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.