Episode 001
Fujimi Academy's new star
《Fujimi Academy》
I can't believe you can't solve such a simple problem.
You think you're such big shots for being here at Fujimi Academy.
Nakazawa-kun!
Yes.
I don't know.
I haven't even asked you a question yet.
What year are you?
Huh... we're second year students.
Second year students, hm?
And you still don't understand this problem?
I've mistaken you for juniors for a moment,
but you really are second year students.
Really strange.
Have you been listening to my class until now? Or maybe you've been sleeping all this time?
Like Ayuhara here.
《Math》
Aihara-kun. Aihara-kun!
Ayuhara-san...
What is it, Ikizaki-san?
Teacher...
Sir.
The answer is a square root of 3.
Did I get it right?
That's correct.
Yay.
She solved it in her sleep, I wonder?
She must have read the example.
She's pretty bold in front of His Majesty.
Nobody asked for your opinion.
Even though you've just transferred, I won't allow such attitude. How dare you act like this?
What did I do wrong?
If my class is so boring, go to the nurse office and sleep there.
Yes sir.
Ayuhara!
Oh?
You poor things.
Well then, I'm going to the nurse office.
She surprised me.
She has some nerve acting like this.
You want to be friends with me, and that's why you followed me here?
Mr. Wind, take them to a peaceful place.
Be safe.
Receive!
Got it.
- Shoot!
- Here goes!
What are you doing, falling like that?
Are you all right?
Here!
Get it together!
Here goes next serve.
Here!
You need to jump higher.
One more time!
- Roger.
- Let's give it our best.
All right, one more time!
Let's finish this.
Here I go.
Here!
Watch out!
Hold on.
You're Ayuhara-san?
Yes.
Captain Katsuragi-san, I presume?
You come to see us practice ever since transferring here, right?
Do you like volleyball?
Why don't you join our club?
I think I'll pass.
Why...?
You are interested, no?
Yes. But I also hate losing.
Excuse me.
Hate losing?...
Captain...
Is she making of us? Did she just call us losers?
Knock it off.
N- Nakazawa-san...
Hehehe.
Is that a compact you're holding?
Did you put a makeup?
Never mind that, come with me.
She's here.
Let's welcome our heroine.
My... why are you all here?
- We were waiting for you.
- Kozue-san.
Ayuhara-san, this way.
Make yourself comfortable. Take a sit.
Come on.
Err...
Do you need anything from me?
You did well, Ayuhara-san.
What did I do?
The way you sticked it to His Majesty was splendid.
This. Me and Debu couldn't believe our ears.
You're so brave, Ayuhara-san.
And with that, you've became the heroine of our useless students group.
Useless students?
Basically we're the kind of students who don't fit in the prestigious Fujimi Academy.
What do you say, Ayuhara-san? Wanna join us?
We want to be friends. We could achieve something together.
Right, Ike-chan?
Hey, Ike.
Eh?
Yeah. We could use your help, Ayuhara-san.
It's decided. We're friends now.
I'm flattered, but...
Hmm...
What kind of friends?
- No big deal.
- We'll only play around.
What do we exactly do?
For example...
...this.
Let's go!
Aw yeah!
Good, good.
Don't just sit there. Dance with us.
Yeah, yeah!
Just like this. Hurry up.
Dance!
Like this?
Whoa, you've got some nice moves.
Don't hang out with the others, though.
Got it?
Yeah. The rest of the class are only goodie-good students after all.
If we learned you told someone what we are doing here, we'll show you.
Yeah.
Show me, show me... show me what?
Eh?
Kakko!
What is it?
It's the vice president.
- This is bad. Party's over.
- Let's run!
Ayuhara-kun, right?
You know me?
Well, you're pretty famous.
And you are...?
I'm Ichinose.
Kashiwagi-kun was here just a moment ago, wasn't she?
Oh, is that so?
What were they doing?
You tell me.
Please don't play dumb.
I could hear the music.
And other things too...
- Are you feeling well, Ichinose-san?
- Don't be rude.
Don't hang out with these girls.
That's none of your business.
They treat me way better than you do, mister detective.
What are you saying?
You're student council vice president, right?
Let me make myself clear: I hate Fujimi Academy.
Some school I've transferred into.
Ayuhara-kun!
Same goes to Fujimi Academy. You trouble us with your behavior.
- Ken!
- How do you know Ken?
That's how it was.
Tsutomu-san is my nephew. Kozue is my niece, on my husband's side.
Understood?
- What? This means...
- We're actually related.
What a pretty shell.
You can find shells like that anywhere.
I can't hear anything...
What did you expect to hear?
The sound of Tokyo.
When I stayed at home in Tokyo, mama has taught me...
...if you put your ear near a sea shell, you can hear the sound of the sea.
Now that I'm at sea, maybe it could work the other way too, and I could hear Tokyo?
I was thinking that... but there's no way that'd work, right?
Why have you transferred in the middle of the school term?
Do I need a reason?
But...
I wonder if I can return to Tokyo some day.
Home is where you make it.
As long as you stay away from the useless bunch, you'll make many friends in no time.
Tsutomu-kun, you just don't get it, do you.
What do you mean?
Wah, so cold.
Of course it is.
But I love the waves so much.
Taking a long, long time, they eventually wear down their obstacles.
Waves are remarkable.
So wonderful.
I want to ask you something.
What is it?
Say, why are you skipping classes?
I don't really want to skip them, but... motivation just doesn't seem to come.
When I don't have a goal, I don't feel like doing anything.
A goal?
Yes. What are you studying for, Tsutomu-san?
Why did you become vice president?
Why do you seem absent-minded?
I, ehm...
Wow, Fuji looks so pretty!
It wasn't this clear for a while now. It's refreshing.
It's Ichinose-san.
How curious.
How curious...
《Teachers room》
By Meihou Academy do you mean that prestigious institute in Tokyo?
Yes. That's why I've had high expectations for having Ayuhara-san transfer here.
Bad call. She doesn't even come to class.
What do you think, professor Hongou?
Hm. Simply put, she does whatever she wants.
But I don't think we should chase every student and tell them what to do.
I see.
At any rate, I won't allow such misconduct.
This school has its rules for a reason.
See for yourself.
Wanna hang out after school? I need to ask you something.
She hangs out with the other delinquents already.
I pity them.
It's true that their grades are poor.
That's a nice way to say it.
What they need is to vent their aggression...
- ...but with our sports section being in such a sorry state...
- Professor Hongou!
The focus of our school lies in scholar achievements. Sports are marginal.
I oppose to this way of thinking.
- W-w-what?
- Let's ease up.
Regarding Ayuhara Kozue, for time being let's just observe her.
I don't know any of this. What did they say I talked with Tsutomu-kun about?
Don't play dumb.
They said you ratted us out and told him we were go-go dancing earlier.
No one but you could have told him.
We have two witnesses. Is that right?
Y-yeah!
You're being silly. Nobody had to tell him, Tsutomu-kun figured it out on his own.
Stop calling him Tsutomu "-kun".
I should have known you'd want your hands all over Ichinose-san.
Eh? Hands?
What are you saying? Me with Tsutomu-kun?
Here you go again. So cheeky.
Ayuhara-san, wanna fight?
Stop it. This isn't some yakuza movie.
Now you've said it!
Ike-chan.
Go!
Too slow, too slow!
It hurts.
- Endure it.
- Why are you butting in?
Stop right here. Ayuhara-san didn't betray you.
Sorry. We jumped to conclusions.
It's all right.
I jump to conclusions all the time too. Right, Tsutomu-san?
I'm so jealous.
Ayuhara-san and Ikinose-san being related...
Ike-chan, your hand...
Ah, this?
- Ichinose-san grasped it earlier. Now I'll treasure it forever.
- Don't be stupid.
Tsutomu-san looks like a model.
Super-handsome.
Eeh? H-how?
Putting that aside...
About your go-go dance... It seems it was discussed at today's faculty meeting.
You'll end up getting in trouble if you don't stop.
I refuse it, vice president.
Ayuhara-kun...
You and the teachers are viewing us in a bad light.
What do you mean?
They assume anyone to be a little different to be delinquent.
But...
Let's end this prejudice.
They assume everything they don't understand must be bad.
If they tried it, they might have fun.
Naka! Radio!
Ayuhara-san...
Yay!
Yahoo!
How is it, Tsutomu-san? Wanna try it?
Ayuhara-san, you're our boss... our chief!
Chief?
Would you teach me how to be like you?
Us too.
We count on you, chief.
Stop that. But yeah, I can show you something.
Everyone, let's go to the beach.
Let's go!
Ayuhara-san.
Katsuragi-san asked us to find you. We've looked everywhere.
She wants to see me?
She'd love to have you join our team.
After yesterday's practice, she's sure you got what it takes.
This is a chance. You should take it.
I'm sorry but I'd rather hang out with Kashiwagi-san than play volleyball with you.
First of all, that club is, well...
Eh?
How should I put it?
What do you mean, Ayuhara-san?
Nothing particular.
Only that I'm disappointed with your practice.
Excuse me.
Let's go to the beach.
See you around.
How rude!
There's no telling what I'll do if she joins our club.
What a joke.
She's so full of herself. What makes her so special anyway?
Don't get so angry over this.
It's true that our academy's sports section is in pieces.
Even the newspapers say we're falling down.
Kozue-san is in the eye of the cyclone. Something's about to happen.
Ayuhara-san.
Hase-san and Hara-san told me.
You insulted the volleyball club.
I don't think I've ever insulted you...
Don't lie, now!
I am not lying to anyone.
I've only spoken the truth.
How cocky!
You're full of yourself, for a transfer student.
Ayuhara-san, you seem to be confident about volleyball.
Who knows.
You're not sure?
All right. We'll test you.
Eh?
You're going to test me?
Yeah. It's going to be rough, though.
Ayuhara-san, receive the serve.
Here it goes.
Hara-san!
Here!
Continue. Don't stop serving.
You little...!
Pretty good.
All right!
That was low!
Attack!
What are you doing to our captain?
Hey!
Same goes to you.
What are you doing to Ayuhara-san?
What now? Your delinquent bunch isn't welcome here.
Now you've said it.
Am I mistaken? Aren't you the garbage of Fujimi Academy?
If you have complaints, let's hear them.
That's cruel... calling us delinquents...
We never did anything to your volleyball club.
Just ask the teachers.
Everyone calls you garbage.
- What the heck?
- Calm down, Naka. His Majesty is watching.
If you've got a problem, I'm here listening.
But we're not delinquents. We won't fight with you.
Of course.
We can always compete in sports, though.
We'll do this.
Do... what?
We, the "delinquents", the useless group...
...will challenge you to a match and show you how to win.
Don't make me laugh.
You don't even know the rules of the volleyball.
One month. One month is all I'm asking for.
With that, you'll see that I'm not all talk.
Interesting. Truly curious.
Wanna do this?
- No way we wouldn't.
- I agree.
Chief, this is impossible.
It's reckless. We don't even know the rules.
What do you plan to do, Ayuhara-san?
We can do this.
We can do this!
Let's make it official.
After taking over the group called "garbage of Fujimi Academy"...
...and challenging the volleyball club, Ayuhara Kozue...
...immediately begins a harsh training.
But she runs into trouble.
The useless group seems to be more interested in dancing than volleyball.
Soon enough two of them want to quit.
If she doesn't think of something...
...Kozue will be forced to forfeit the match.
But Kozue doesn't give up.
Please look forward to the next episode.