苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts...
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
...even though I feel sad...
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
...in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight...
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
...under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
Episode 003
New captain arrives!
What should I do? What if the radiograph shows I can't do volleyball...
Hmm...
Yes?
Uhm...
How is it, doctor?
This is a mystery. I can't believe it.
What is the matter?
Please, let me play volleyball tomorrow.
It's unbelievable, but...
But?
Looks like it healed.
Healed?
Well, then...
It's healing neatly.
I was worried at first, but looks like playing volleyball is actually good for her.
There you have it.
Auntie!
Good for you, Kozue-chan!
Doctor, in that case...
Yes, it's good. You don't have to worry about anything anymore.
So that's how it is. Thank you very much.
Ah, it's good, it's so good.
I'm so happy!
I'll be able to go with Kashiwagi-san.
I'll give my best in the tomorrow's match.
If volleyball club loses today, I'm giving you my favorite guitar.
Ok. I'll approach Ayuhara. If she loses, I'll take her to movies.
- I might be even able to kiss her.
- How filthy.
Ayuhara Kozue sure is popular.
She really is awesome.
She's got the highest scores on tests.
Moreover, she has this escapism vibe around her.
Came from the prestigious Meihou Academy.
A chief of the "useless group".
Now that she made them into "useless team", she throws a professional challenge.
Now matter how you look at her, she's so cool.
《Teachers room》
I am secretly looking forward to the today's match.
Me too, actually.
I can't help but wonder how far can those bad-performing students go.
The game is about to start. Shall we go?
You better hurry.
Hey, Ichinose. Did you come to see the game?
Yeah, I did.
- There!
- OK!
I got this!
- There!
- OK!
Here I go!
- Got it!
- Catch!
Ayuhara!
Here!
OK, got it!
Do your best!
I'm surprised to see so many people here.
I'm a little anxious. I feel like everyone looks at me.
You better not lose it!
No way we're going to lose. If we do, it'll be all over.
Are you ready?
Yes. Bring it.
Ayuhara-san, even if we didn't do this match, the result is obvious.
The match hasn't even started. But fine, talk all you can.
- Don't regret it later.
- Heh.
Referee, we're ready.
The match between the volleyball club and second year...
- Do your best!
- Break a leg!
- Go for it!
- You better not lose!
...A-Ayuhara's team, spanning 1 set, is about to start.
I request the both captains to step in.
- I won.
- Do you choose court or service?
We'll serve first.
Which side do you want?
It's all right as it is.
- Bow.
- Please take care of us.
Assume positions.
Begin the match.
You can do it.
It's coming.
Here I go!
It's here!
- Keiko-chan!
- Point!
They scored.
We got one point already!
Don't sweat it.
Don't worry. Next one is coming.
Here!
Kashiwagi!
- Don't worry.
- Next one will be better.
- I'm sorry.
- Be careful.
This is bad. Without Kashiwagi-san, we'll lose the match.
Let's score a lot.
Here you go.
Yes.
Here!
Receive the ball!
Ah...!
I'm sorry...
One more time.
Damn. I shouldn't have made it a one-set match.
It's no use noticing it now.
Looking at these novices, the match is already over.
What are you going to do, "chief" Ayuhara?
It's good, everyone.
It'll be okay. Calm down.
Captain!
Deep ball!
Receive!
Point!
I'll get it!
Watch out!
Ah... again...
Here it comes.
Go!
What's that, fail team? You came to play volleyball, no?
What the heck are you doing?
Get a hold of yourselves!
It's like adults fighting children.
I expected a bit more...
This is dangerous.
Ayuhara-kun what is it? Call for time!
Don't be so negative. Smile, smile.
It'll be over soon enough anyway.
Don't joke like that. I regret making this stupid bet.
Quit already!
It'll shake Ayuhara-san's popularity.
I'm surprised they don't give up already.
It's pointless.
At this rate, our morale is too low.
I have to think of a way to restore it.
If we lose now, we'll just drift apart.
One-two! One-two! One-two!
It hurts.
- Here. - OK.
The waves...
The waves...?
That's it!
This is how I'm going to name my strategy.
One that will make captain Katsuragi take aback.
- Time! Referee, we ask for time.
- Time!
Hurry and come close.
We've got only one minute.
What's wrong? This isn't even 10% energy you showed at practice.
Chief, this is unfamiliar.
I feel anxious in a real match.
Ch-chief...
Fighting on empty stomach is bad.
Isn't it all in your heads? We haven't even started the struggle.
Your strength is plenty enough.
What's left is the willpower.
The willpower?
I have a strategy. Come closer.
Let's do this.
This will be embarrassing.
This isn't the time to be thinking this.
- I wonder if this will be good?
- We have to try this.
We're going to join our strength.
They're pretty cheeky for calling for time...
...but what is it going to change?
- Yeah.
- All goes as planned so far.
- Let's continue as it is.
- OK.
I guess this is it for Ayuhara's team.
Looks like it.
Ayuhara-kun seems to have an idea...
Will it work out?
Looks like they gave up.
Ayuhara-kun.
Time out. Resume the match.
OK. Here we go.
One-two! One-two! One-two!
Whoa, awesome.
What are you doing! It's shameful for our club to be scared with this.
Resume the match.
Let's stop them.
Yeah!!
- Captain, go for it!
- Do your best!
Here I go!
Right side!
Second pass!
So cool!!
Let's cheer her on! Team Ayuhara!
- Look, they're cheering us on. Let's not lose our focus now.
- Yeah.
As planned, we've taken the serve from Katsuragi-san's team.
We might be able to win this.
We have to get the serve back. Don't drop it no matter what.
- Fight!
- Yeah.
She got it!
Damn.
Katsuragi-san, here comes the next one.
Captain!
Everything as planned. We need to continue this.
Here, Kashiwagi-san!
Leave it to me!
Got it!
Please make it!
Here I go.
Got it!
Useless group, you're cool!
Here!
Shoot!
Ayuhara-kun, one more push!
At last!
Don't mind!
Ayuhara-san, I focused only on attack.
I didn't consider you a formidable enemy.
We're even. Four points left.
I have to do something.
- Fight!
- Yeah!
It's shameful if our club loses to novices.
We can't be defeated.
I won't forgive any misses now.
- Understood?
- Yes.
One more push.
Let's continue at this pace.
Yeah. We have to win this match no matter what.
Time out.
Resume the match.
Don't mind, don't mind!
I'm sorry.
Don't mind, don't mind.
Out.
Here!
Captain!
Attack!
Go, go, team Katsuragi!
They seem to go at it.
It's frustrating.
Last push. Let's do our best.
Superior comeback.
Here she goes!
Attack!
Chief!
That move was foul play.
What?
You lifted the ball with an open palm.
I saw it clearly.
Yeah. I saw it too.
You're making this up.
Wh- what? Hey, referee.
What should we do?
It was holding, wasn't it?
Now that you think of it, I think I saw it too...
You're a man! Make yourself clear!
You're still novices. What do you know about volleyball?
What? Wanna piece of me?
Did I just hear the useless group threaten us?
Screw you!
Things got messy...
If they start fighting here, it'll be bad.
What do you want?
- Make up for your foul play.
- Wait. Let's leave it to the referee.
Agreed.
Make it clear.
Yeah!
Well then, I declare holding. Ball goes to team Ayuhara.
Now nobody can complain.
Let's score a point.
Resume the match.
Here!
Got it!
It's back at you!
Here!
You got this!
Damn.
I can return this.
Good going, Ayuhara-kun!
Match is over. Team Ayuhara wins 16:14.
Splendid match.
We did this.
We won.
Chief...
It's our victory.
Yes.
We won.
I'm so happy.
Me too.
Chief...
Thank you, Ayuhara-san.
I feel like this for the first time.
Good. You did well.
Awesome. I can't believe they actually won.
I'm so happy...
We must look silly now.
Everyone took it seriously.
Maybe more than me.
Ayuhara-san.
This is...?
Please hear me out.
We've completely lost.
Furthermore, you're not useless at all.
You were splendid.
We're embarrassed that we made fun of you until now.
We apologize.
My...
We've also got a favor to ask.
We want you to join the volleyball club.
What do you think?
Huh?
Why?
The volleyball club has only seniors now.
If we had second year students too, we would grow stronger.
Yeah.
Us seniors have many things around the corner, so we can't give the practice our all.
Ayuhara-san, what are we going to do?
Isn't it all right?
Let's join the volleyball club together.
This is a chance for us.
I'll do it.
Yep. Me too. I'll join too.
I'm joining too.
I'll be hungry all the time, I bet.
Nevermind being hungry.
Do you join? Do you not?
I'll join, I'll join with you.
My figure will improve for sure.
Moreover we want you, Ayuhara-san, to be our captain.
Huh?
Me, a captain?
Does anybody oppose?
Of course we agree!
It's decided then.
Ayuhara-san, since a long time, this jersey was used by the captain of the volleyball club.
Let us see you in it.
OK.
- Wonderful.
- It suits you well.
It matches you perfectly, chief.
Perfectly. What a strong posture!
Like a pro athlete.
Thank you. Let's all work together.
- New captain.
- Katsuragi-san.
The start of beautiful friendship.
I'll be graduating soon.
But until then, I'll play volleyball.
I'm glad. Please help me out in my new duties.
I'm sure we'll get along well.
You really deserve this jersey.
Katsuragi-san.
I'm so glad I'm able to play volleyball.
I also met new friends.
How wonderful.
I feel as if my heart grew a little.
The new friends... this happiness...
One-two! One-two!
I'll be the first today. We might have won yesterday but I feel as I've lost to you.
Yeah. I'm afraid I'm still physically fitter than you.
Let's run with all might.
Yeah.
- Touchdown!
- Kakko, Naka, it's too bad.
- Whoa, you're here already?
- You woke up so early?
Today is our first practice together.
- Too bad.
- I'm exhausted now.
Huh, we thought we'd be the first today.
Looks like everyone thinks the same.
Looks like you're having fun.
Ayuhara-san, there's a letter to our club.
Here.
Oh? Katsuragi-san, why do you not open it?
The club's matters are resolved by the captain.
My.
What do you think it is?
I wonder.
Listen, everyone.
It's an invitation to a second years match in Toukai.
A real game.
It's a chance for our new members to shine.
Good, now we have a goal. Let's do it.
Yeah. Let's do this.
Now then, let's begin today's practice.
Looks like everyone's into it. I'm happy.
It's thanks to you.
I only gave them a little motivation.
Let's do our best.
We won't lose this match.
It'll be my first interschool match though.
Interschool, huh. We have to do our best.
What are they doing?
Looks like they're watching someone.
Who is this person in black shirt?
Who hides behind these machine-level precise movements?
Having chosen Kozue as their captain, the volleyball club...
...sets out to work on their new goal.
But Hayakawa Midori makes her appearance.
Uneasiness settles in Kozue's heart.
Apparently perfect Hayakawa Midori gets a gym for the club...
...and quickly becomes popular.
Looks like Kozue's left behind.
Then one day, she receives a mysterious letter.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky...
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
...bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there...
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
...painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes...
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
...bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.