苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
Episode 005
Demon coach's challenge
Here!
Throw me more. Don't hold back!
All right, here goes.
Here goes another.
Next!
Roger!
I'll show who's the best in the match.
I'll become your heroine.
All right, keep throwing!
Come on!
Hayakawa-san's practicing all by herself.
What about us?
We want to practice too.
Well then, let us begin too.
Wah, I've been waiting for this!
All right, don't just stand like that. Let's start.
Yeah, let's do it.
Wait, I'm not through my own practice yet.
Eh?
Ehh?
I think you've practiced enough already.
But the match is just the day after tomorrow.
That's why no matter how good you now get, nothing's going to change.
Isn't that right?
Good timing requires all players.
Yeah.
Do you have a problem with my methods?
There's no way we do.
- Right?
- Right.
I do.
I think that no one's going to make any progress with your methods.
I am the captain here.
I've been chosen by everyone's free will.
That's why we're going to have it my way.
No offense.
Ah…
We won't win the match at this rate.
Leave it to me.
All I need you to do is to listen to me.
Aha.
So that's what this is about.
You reconciled with us only so that you could gain power.
Katsuragi-san!
Say what you want.
The game will be decided with strength after all.
Isn't that right?
Ayuhara-san.
- Well then. Keep them coming!
- OK.
Fight, fight!
Here!
Got it.
《Toukai district middle school volleyball championship》
《City Gym》
Go, Mikawa!
Go, go! Mikawa!
Noisy as expected.
It's so lively!
But our team looks weaker.
I wonder if that's because of the cheering though.
Yeah. They don't look nearly as strong as Mikawa.
What do you know.
Our Fujimi Academy has Ayuhara-san and Hayakawa-san.
Hmm. We have no chance of winning.
What did you say?
Ah, professor Hongou.
It's futile. It doesn't matter if their opponent is Mikawa or whoever. They won't win.
But…
Then what the heck did he come for?
Ayuhara-san! We count on you!
Ayuhara-san!
Give us a good serve!
OK!
Got it! Go—
Harakawa!
All right!
Hit it!
Make it through!
Don't mind, don't mind!
Let's keep at it!
Bring it!
Hayakawa-san, calm down.
I know.
Good going!
Leave it to me!
Strange. She's been always so good.
Don't mind, don't mind!
Hayakawa-san, what's your experience in actual matches?
Eh? Matches?
Today is my first match.
Eh? Th-The first?
Yeah.
Everyone was too scared to become my partner.
I understand.
After you've pulled that one man show in the gym, it didn't occur to you to ask anyone for help.
Shut it.
My volleyball won't be defeated.
No one will defeat me.
Hey, you're too easy!
Her timing is completely off.
So strange.
I feel a little off. I'll get better in a second.
Hayakawa-san!
Get it together!
Do your best!
Easy win!
Damn it.
It got completely one-sided.
Hey, won't you stay till the end?
- What for?
- The match's already decided.
See you around.
Just a little more!
Do your best!
Hey! Fight back!
Hayakawa-san.
You're responsible for this.
Thanks to you Fujimi Academy now suffers crushing defeat.
How vexing.
What a shame.
Here I go!
Ayuhara-san!
You got this!
Attack!
Saw that, Hayakawa-san?
This is a match.
This is how we fight.
But really.
After all, we only got 3 points thanks to Ayuhara-san.
Yeah.
We have been losing until now, but I thought maybe we could win this time around.
Hey. Are you saying this is my fault?
Eh?
You're trying to drive me out, no?
Am I right?
What's that? What's going on?
No… that's not true…
This is your first game. No one blames you.
Yeah.
What are you saying?
That's not the problem here.
If only…
If only you did better, we could have easily won this.
Knock it off, Hayakawa-san.
What do you think volleyball is?
It's a team sport.
Oh my, Ayuhara-san.
Are you really going to start preaching here?
It seems you don't know much about volleyball.
We're in the bus for crying out loud.
A strong volleyball team must have outstanding players.
I agree.
But outstanding means playing an important role in the crucial moments.
And that is not you.
You're only thinking of yourself.
Eh…
- Ah, they get on my nerves.
- You two, cut it out.
Look around.
We're on the bus.
Sir.
It's no good at this rate.
After I've discovered them…
I need to do something.
Hoho.
You want to be a volleyball coach?
Yes, sir.
But do you have any experience with volleyball?
No, sir.
Not even slightest.
But I have played baseball in the college.
But Ayuhara-kun…
Since a long time ago, all the good managers started as good players, and those started somewhere too.
Yeah.
So the chances that professor Hongou might become our coach are pretty big, right?
If that wasn't the case, he wouldn't be so enthusiastic.
How wonderful.
I'm sure professor Hongou will make a great coach.
In girls volleyball, I think that friendship is the most important.
But the current volleyball club is in pieces.
If I become a coach, you'll certainly get promoted, too.
Hm.
I wonder about that.
I'm sure of it.
Oh well, okay then.
If you say so, then okay.
Hongou-kun.
So you'll let me do this?
Thank you very much, sir.
But in return, please let me do it my way.
All right. With this, the remaining problem is Ayuhara. Hayakawa. Those two.
But I'll certainly reconcile them.
Ah, I'm done with the cleaning.
Ayuhara-san.
Yes?
- Have you heard about it already?
- Eh? About what?
They've decided on our coach.
It's prof. Hongou.
Reall— ah, ow.
Oh.
It's true.
He volunteered by himself.
Wah, I knew it!
We'll get better now.
Yeah.
Hayakawa-san might step off a little too.
I'm glad.
Let's go.
OK!
Let's go!
Can't wait to meet him.
Yeah.
Whoa.
They seem to be at it.
Hey, what were you doing?
S-Sir.
We've been cleaning.
Too slow!
Eh?
You get 30 minutes tops.
No exceptions.
Fufu.
That goes to you too.
Listen. Volleyball isn't kids' play.
As long as I'm your coach, I don't intend to go easy on you.
Those who have a problem with that, quit the club at once!
Fufu.
I get it, I get it.
It's the "look, I'm serious" part.
Furthermore…
I'll be deciding the captain.
Understood?
Hmph!
Until my decision, there's no captain.
Now, let's start the evaluation.
I won't lose.
I'll win without fail.
I won't…
…lose!
I'll win.
Certainly.
Ah, ow!
Who said you can rest?
Stand up!
- Stand up at once!
- Y-yes sir!
No matter what happens, I can't lose to Hayakawa-san.
I can't lose to Ayuhara-san.
No way I'm losing!
All right, here goes.
Here!
Come on, come on!
Yes sir!
Get up this instant!
This much defeats you?
Continue!
Get it together!
Sir!
Use your legs!
It hurts…
There's more!
What's wrong!
Here it goes!
What now!
What's that?
Stand up!
Here goes!
What are you doing? Come on!
What's with your posture!
Here goes!
All right.
I've got them hooked.
Pull it together!
We haven't done a single lap yet!
Hey, what are you doing!
- Yeah!
- We're going!
I won't lose.
I won't lose!
I won't lose…
Hold it!
Stop!
That was new low.
Tripping me up like that…
Huh…?
- I'm sorr—
- What are you saying? You did it on purpose.
I was just trying to outpace you.
Outpace? You deliberately tripped me up.
Knock it off!
What are you doing?
Are you fighting in the middle of the practice?
But she…!
No "but she"s!
Do you think I'll forgive fighting within the club?
As a punishment, three more laps!
Eh?
Me too?
Not only you.
All members!
- Eh?
- I'm shocked.
For those that rest along the way… take an example in me!
Come on!
This is absurd…
I won't lose…
I won't lose.
I will… win…
Hayakawa-san, let's talk later.
Fine by me.
Let's settle this.
What a terrible practice.
I'm so tired I can't do anything now.
My legs feel heavy.
- I don't even feel I have legs anymore.
- Well said.
It's going to be all the same tomorrow too, right…
Hey, troubles!
What happened?
Ayuhara-san fights Hayakawa-san!
I thought it'd happen!
Let's go see the chief at once.
Troubles!
Ah! My limbs are heavier than Godzilla!
- What are you doing, Hayakawa-san, Ayuhara-sa—
- Leave us. This is between us two.
I'm not talking about you.
Umehara-san and Yamada-san have just quit the club.
Eh? Why?
They don't want to put up with our new coach.
The others feel similar.
Hold on.
We can talk about it later.
We'd like to settle things between us first.
We don't have time for this.
What do you plan to do if everyone quits?
Hayakawa-san, if the club's gone, how can you become its heroine?
Ayuhara-san, did you forget you're responsible for the useless team?
While you're busy fighting, our club undergoes terrible things.
《Principal's room》
At any rate, I think you went overboard.
《PTA
– Parent-Teacher Association》
We received a complaint from the PTA, too.
Hmm.
I'd like to have you put your excessive energy into something more useful.
Do you really think so?
For the students, club activities are a way to learn things about life that textbooks don't offer.
Hmm.
That's naive point of view. As expected from a young teacher.
At any rate, the PTA complaint is a huge problem.
I'd like to wash my hands from this.
But you agreed for me to use my methods.
That's it.
It's those "methods" of yours.
The students are backing away, aren't they?
Am I not correct?
Please think it over, professor Hongou.
All right. Understood.
Really?
Is that so.
Good.
It's fine then.
If the students definitely oppose to my coaching, I'll step down.
Is that so.
It can't be helped.
Those that can't keep up can quit.
But professor, we've got only 8 people left.
You don't need to worry about that.
Let's go on with the practice!
- Yes sir!
Do your best!
Fool!
Ikezaki! Are you slacking again?
Sir!
Safe.
Wait!
If you can't do such a simple receiving, I'll train you myself!
We'll fix this right now!
Eh?
Here we go!
Here it goes!
Ike-chan!
Where's your motivation?
I can't hear you!
Please stop it!
Who do you think we are?
We're not your dolls, professor.
Yeah.
Yep!
All of you. Do you disagree to my coaching this much?
We do.
Me too.
Is that so.
Ikezaki-san, let's go home.
- Ok.
- Are you hurt? Hang in there.
Wait a moment.
I've got a news for you.
Actually I decided to hold a practice match tomorrow.
- Eh?
- Practice match?
I also thought to myself that if you can win that game, I can step down as your coach.
We'll surely win.
Naturally.
Yeah…
But your opponent is Matsushima Middle School.
Matsushima?
Wah…
How's that? Can you win?
If you win, good.
If you lose, you'll acknowledge the need for training.
I expect you to be stronger than now.
There's no way you'll win.
After all, your opponents are too strong.
They got to the championship semi-finals.
You're powerless.
How's that?
Do you still accept my challenge?
How will it be? You finally have a chance to get back at me.
If they win, the demon coach will step down.
The first set. Thanks to Midori's excellence, they get the first set point.
But the game soon enough turns around in Matsushima's favor.
Matsushima controls the match completely.
Meanwhile the demon coach Hongou observes Fujimi Academy team's pinch from the side.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.