苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
Episode 002
The Gamble for Tomorrow
One-two! One-two!
I can't take it anymore.
This is nothing yet.
Come on, stand up.
It hurts.
I've had enough too.
This won't get you anywhere. Come on, stand up.
Hey, how about we run somewhere else without sand?
While it'd feel easier, running on sand is the best for training your legs.
Now, one more lapse to the lighthouse.
That far…?
Get it together. Our opponents are volleyball club's regulars.
If we admit defeat here, we'll never win.
It's just as the chief says.
Let's keep at it until we pass out.
Exactly, exactly.
Well then, let's go!
Ah… wait…
Wait for me…
Here!
Let's do your best.
Here I go.
Pull yourself together.
- I'm sorry.
- Isn't this enough?
It's no good.
It's bad if you start thinking that way.
But our opponents are just a bunch of newcomers.
There's no way they could win with us.
Don't let your guard down.
We've no idea what Ayuhara-san's plans might be.
It's okay.
She might be doing her best, but…
…you can't say that about the others.
One-two! One-two!
Do your best.
Maybe I should quit.
If I keep at this, I'll pass out for real.
Again? What's with that attitude?
Come on. Last few steps.
I've had it.
Looks like volleyball is impossible for us after all.
Yeah. Our opponents are genuine volleyball club members. I'm hungry all t—
Hey, are you serious about this?
Yeah.
Yep. Go go dancing is much more fun.
Right?
Don't get so soft, you two.
Hold on, Nakazawa-san.
But those two…
It's all right. Leave it to me.
Hit me all you want.
Anyway, I quit.
Ah… wait…
Chief, what do we do?
What about you?
Even if I'm all alone, I'll still do it.
- Me too.
- Of course me too.
Thank you.
Let's continue then.
They will come to their senses soon enough.
- All right. Let's continue.
- We'll go on with just the 4 of us.
But we can't play with just 4 people.
It'll be bad if I don't get them back.
Hmm. It's still too early to give up.
I have no intention of giving up, but…
Two of them have already dropped out of training.
I don't believe in myself.
With things like this, shouldn't you suspend the match?
It's a shame, but… I guess…
If you don't, you'll be only giving the other girls false hopes, Ayuhara-kun.
Looks like my plan was absurd to begin with.
That's weak. It doesn't suit you.
But it's impossible to hold a match with just 4 people.
Do your best. One more time.
Keep at it.
I see. By the way, volleyball club's practice seems to be more intense lately.
That's because they don't want to lose to the Kashiwagi's group.
But why is Ayuhara Kozue staying with these delinquents, I wonder.
I don't get it myself.
She transferred from Meihou Academy after all.
That's right. Ultimately, the volleyball isn't her only redeeming feature.
Eh? Meihou Academy, you say?
Yeah. The one in Tokyo that only accepts the best among the best students. That Meihou Academy.
Then, their volleyball club must be famous too?
That's why she made fun of us.
We can't let our guard down.
But I can't believe it.
For her to be a Meihou's prodigy…
Even the best school has its worst students.
Just like our Fujimi Academy.
Yeah. With that in mind, perhaps Ayuhara-san got expelled.
Hey, listen, listen, listen.
Got news.
Ayuhara-san got expelled from Meihou Academy.
And now that she came to our school, she started hanging out with the delinquents.
Hey.
What did you just say?
Eh? N-Nothing.
It's not like we called you delinquents.
Never mind that.
Where did you hear that Ayuhara-san was expelled?
Err… from a member of the volleyball club.
Say what?
Hey, hey! Everyone!
What is it, Naka?
- We're gonna attack the volleyball club.
- Wait, why?
Yeah. They're telling a story that Ayuhara-san was expelled from a school in Tokyo.
They're spreading this rumor to everyone.
I can't let it slide any longer. Come with me.
Should we go too?
I'll still do it.
I won't give up till the very end.
Good.
One does what one can do.
Hey! Chief, this is bad!
Listen, Naka and the others went to attack the volleyball club. What do we do?
Eh? I'll go and see.
Why do you go around saying whatever you please?
What's wrong with calling expulsion for what it is.
Even if she was expelled, that's no reason to spread it.
It's not like we're spreading rumors on purpose. It spread naturally.
Yeah. There's nothing to be upset about.
People now understand that Ayuhara-san is a fitting boss for your group.
Those are some big words.
Today I'll fix this once and for all.
I've had enough of it.
Because you can't beat us in volleyball, you're going to resort to violence, huh?
Exactly.
Volleyball is such a boring game anyway.
I'm already out.
Oh my, is that so.
Did you really quit?
You don't care about Ayuhara-san, then?
Yeah.
We haven't decided whether to quit yet.
Oh my. Family trouble already?
Volleyball is so out of reach for you girls.
Shut it!
- What do you know!
- What are you doing?
Wait!
- Ayuhara-san.
- I heard about it from Kashiwagi-san.
But resorting to the violence is low.
It doesn't matter.
Wrong. The moment you lose your cool, you lose.
But fine, be my guest.
You'll get expelled in return.
Eh?
With that, you'll play right into volleyball club's hand.
But they're so impudent.
I understand.
But vent your feelings in the match.
Okay?
Can you understand?
It's as the chief says.
Everyone. Let's save our chief's face and withdraw for now, okay?
Okay.
All right.
Thanks.
Let's head back.
We'll surely settle this.
You better remember it.
Boo.
Booo!
Looks like I calmed them down.
As expected from Ayuhara-san.
She must regard herself as a good chief.
Huh?
Where did Ikezaki-san and Ooki-san go?
It's no good.
They allied for the quarrel, but their decision didn't change.
Is that so.
But I'm not giving up yet.
What a mess…
I'm not giving up.
I'll persist till the very end.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
Oh?
What is it?
Ah. Midterm tests results are in.
It only shows the best results though.
It doesn't concern us, does it.
Hey, listen! Big news!
Ayuhara-san has the highest score.
Huh? That's ridiculous.
Don't deceive us.
It's the truth. Come see for yourself.
Ah. She's right.
Ayuhara-san is the first.
Wow…
What sort of method did you study with?
Nothing particular.
Ayuhara-kun.
Yes?
Until now, I've been the first all the time.
Having you, a delinquent, surpass me…
I can't believe it.
Yeah.
There's no way you'd pull it off.
It's very fishy.
Fishy how?
She means you must have done something.
Like what?
Yeah. For example, you cheated.
What did you say?
Don't be rude.
Yeah. If you make such statements about our chief, we won't stand by idle.
Hey, how about you say something.
Do you have any proof that I cheated?
I have.
Eh?
Isn't it obvious?
After expulsion from the Meihou Academy, no matter how different our level is…
…there's no way you'd suddenly get the best score.
My. When did I get expelled from anywhere?
Eh?
So that's not how it was? Then, I…
Whoa, whoa. You guys.
You can't say rude things.
Professor…
Ayuhara-kun always stood at the top in the Meihou Academy.
- At the top…
- Now you see how much of an insult your claim was.
Awesome.
Too bad, Miura-san.
Ah, I'm in shock. For her to be at the top of the Meihou Academy…
I feel like we've made fools of ourselves.
All right, Now that it came to this, let's show our strength through volleyball to her.
Yeah. We mustn't lose to them.
She tricked us after all.
She's plenty dignified without being our chief.
She's totally different from us.
But life sure is strange. I didn't saw it coming at all.
What are you doing gathered like that?
Eh?
Ah, this… we're, you know…
You're acting strange.
But sure you're cruel, Ayuhara-san.
Why?
I mean you hiding your status at Meihou Academy.
Oh, it's not like I've been hiding it with malice.
It's just that if I haven't stayed silent, it'd come across as boasting.
But you're in a different world from us.
A prodigy like you has no business in hanging out with losers like us.
Are you saying this seriously?
That we can't be friends just because I happen to have good grades?
I am me. Ayuhara Kozue.
Weren't we going to take on the volleyball club together? Wasn't that so?
Hmm.
- But…
- Do you really mean it?
Yeah. If I didn't, I wouldn't be able to befriend you to begin with.
I wouldn't have the painful memories nor care about the assault either.
Ah, I'm touched.
She's truly our chief.
Then, we can hang around like we used to?
Of course.
Ikezaki-san. Ooki-san.
Why don't we make up and stay friends again?
Eh?
Us too? Wah…
How is it?
Ooki-san.
Don't you too want to beat the volleyball club?
That's why you too came during the assault, no?
Training sure is hard.
But we need to overcome its hardship.
Ikezaki-san. Ooki-san.
- Okay.
- I'll do it too.
Thank you.
Will you forgive us?
There's nothing to forgive.
We're all on the same page.
The strength lies in teamwork.
Wah. I'm happy.
We won't make fun of good students like you anymore.
Yeah. Now all that's left is to train.
Ok. Now that it's decided, let's do our best.
No quitting midway, got it?
Then, from today, it's one month of strict training.
Got it?
- Okay!
This should be good.
All that's left is to win the match.
If we win, it will give these girls the confidence they need and everything will go well.
One-two! One-two!
All right. From today we'll focus on handling the ball.
There's only one rule to winning.
It's practice. Practice. Practice!
- Got it?
- Yeah.
Okay then. Nakazawa-san, here I go.
- Okay.
- Naka, do your best!
Here!
No good.
In 6-player volleyball, if you let yourself lose the ball, it's a foul play.
Pass must be done with the fingertips.
Roger.
Then, let's do it in turns.
Okay.
Here I go.
- It hurts.
- I'm sorry.
Good.
If they stay this inspired for a month, we might make it.
This won't cut it.
All right, here goes!
Do your best!
Today we'll focus on serving and receiving.
In 6-player system, you only get one serve, so aim to hit the ball into the opponents court.
- Got it?
- Yeah.
Here!
Pull it together.
Come on, stand up.
They're really giving their best.
These girls are full of potential.
It hurts.
Ah, my finger twisted to the right.
Huh? What are you saying.
It's just a jammed finger.
It'll normal to have all 10 fingers jammed at once.
Eh? All 10?
At this rate, my beautiful fingers will get all lumpy.
This isn't the time to joke.
We've got three weeks before the match.
Those with jammed fingers, switch to jumping until healing. Got it?
Ehh?
She seems to be at it.
The others are pathetic though.
There's no way they'd win with just 1 month of training.
Ah. It's the volleyball club.
Hmph.
They came to spy on us.
Don't pay attention to them.
All right, let's begin.
- They'll be the same during the match.
- Yeah.
Hmph.
Say what you want.
Yeah. You'll pay if you underestimate us.
Shut up and practice.
They say such things because they're scared.
Okay. Begin, begin!
- Professor Hongou.
- Hm?
What do you think about those girls?
I'm probably thinking the same thing as you do.
My…
Ever since Ayuhara-kun started coaching the volleyball…
…their diligence in the classroom and their grades have improved.
Perhaps with her help, the girls will return to the right track.
Am I correct?
Exactly.
As her homeroom teacher, I'm taking my hat to Ayuhara-san.
I feel the same.
Let's stay silent for a little longer and watch over her.
Right now, she's earnestly devoted to the volleyball.
Keep at it!
Got it.
Got it!
Here!
One more time!
Do your best, do your best!
Three days left.
Now that they mastered basic techniques, the match is on.
We will win without fail.
What do you mean, Tsutomu-chan? Kozue-chan plays volleyball?
Yep.
She's taken the volleyball club on.
So that's why she's been coming late recently.
Auntie, you didn't know?
How was I supposed to?
I was sure she was studying in the library every day.
Ah– damn.
Then, please keep it a secret that I told you.
I can't do that.
Kozue-chan's body won't withstand volleyball.
Huh?
It's that bad?
Of course it is.
Otherwise, why'd she come all the way here in the middle of the school term.
But she looks so full of energy—
You can see it just by looking at her face.
You're a responsible boy. Why didn't you tell me earlier?
Err…
I'm sorry.
"Sorry" doesn't cut it.
Kozue is the one that knows her own body the best.
That's why I think it's okay.
No.
We can't let it get any worse.
Let's go to the hospital at once.
But there's only one day before the match.
If I withdrew today, what would happen to Kashiwagi-san and our group?
Group?
It can't be helped.
That match cannot be this important.
That's not true.
The tomorrow's match means very precious thing to me.
What is so precious?
That's… err…
Hey, Kozue-chan.
At any rate, we need to take care of yourself, too.
Otherwise how would we apologize to your mom and dad?
Apologize? Don't you grumble now.
- Let's hurry and go see the doctor.
- No!
Kozue!
Kozue.
Hey, Kozue-chan.
You understand, right?
For time being, at least let's take a radiograph, okay?
What should I do?
What if something shows up on the radiograph…
Kozue.
Y-Yes!
《Fuji Hospital》
The doctor is taking too long.
My heart is pumping.
Worrying now won't do any good.
We'll know the results soon.
Calm down.
What will I do, if the results turn out to be a "no"?
Everything will be over.
Kashiwagi-san's group's energy… their spirit… their hopes… our dream…
After they made me their coach and followed me this far, how will I apologize to them?
Ayuhara-san.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
How is it?
Doctor.
The doctor's gaze over radiograph is long and inscrutable.
However, the youthful devotion to the volleyball seems to have helped in curing the illness.
Finally, the day of the match. The useless group led by Kozue settles things out with the volleyball club.
The extreme training spanning one month seems to have fruited, but…
…the useless group tenses up in front of a crowd of spectators.
Unfazed, the volleyball club has no intention of going easy.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.