south wind subs
presents
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
Neverending story (Owaranai monogatari) sung by Jun Morioka
Walk towards
RYOUTE NI ATARASHII ASA
the new day
JIBUN NI KITAISHITE
with hope
ARUITE YUKOU
In my childhood days,
OSANAI HI
my little heart
CHIISANA MUNE WO
beat faster
TOKIMEKASETETA
I will
ZUTTO
watch over you always,
SOBA DE MIMAMOTTERU
like a lullaby from the earth
DAICHI NO KOMORIUTA NO YOU NI
I'm sure everyone
SORE WA KITTO
has one within them,
DARE NO NAKA NI MO ARU
a neverending story
OWARANAI MONOGATARI
I'M NOT ALONE
Hot! Hot!
John... it's time for me to leave.
Jules Verne...
I liked it too...
What?
Father, good morning.
That's bad, I'm late for work.
I'll go now, your breakfast is ready.
What about my mother?
She has been at Hamilton's
since yesterday.
Nothing happened.
Is that so?
What? Haven't been born yet?
Bye!
Oh, today I'll return late,
so take care of the house.
Your mother will be back soon.
Tell me, a boy or a girl?
Oh? What?
Mrs. Hamilton's baby!
I hope it's a boy!
If this happens, I will take him
to the hill of the Rocky Heath!
Goodbye!
Bye!
Well, I'm leaving!
Be careful!
Good morning, Sam!
Good morning, Ed!
Good morning, Kevin!
Good morning, Sam!
Good morning, I rely on you today!
Good morning!
How are you today?
This is the best way to make delicious food!
Thank you for the food!
I'm leaving!
No one is answering to me!
Be careful, John!
I'm leaving!
I remembered, before I go to school...!
John Carraclough!
Where are you going?
This is not the road to school!
I haven't said "Good morning" to my mother!
So I'm going to Mrs. Hamilton!
Bye, Grandma!
Melissa, your son came!
Wait, I can't talk to him, I'm working!
What are you saying, Mrs. Carraclough?
You mustn't make your son leave.
Oh, Doctor...
Mom!
Well, good morning!
Have you eaten your breakfast today?
Yes, my father made it for me!
Is not obstetrics difficult for you?
Your mother is skilled.
Difficulty is because of children.
The night is gone and the child is not born yet.
Hey! Well okay... wait a little, do your best!
Mrs. Carraclough! Please help me!
When the child is born, I will return home.
Bye!
Do your best!
Yeah? Ah!
Hm!
I understood!
That's great!
Hey, Brad Hamilton's baby was born recently!
She's a girl!
Congratulations, you became a father!
Congratulations!
Thank you, thank you!
Listen, Colin...
What do you think of going to the river
before we go home?
I'd like to go, but I have work in the store.
Well okay, my mom will be home
in the afternoon.
The river, you say? Do you want
to play there again until you get muddy?
Listen, you speak as usual.
No, I will not go to the river again.
What? You don't go?
Well... it doesn't matter!
Bye bye!
I'm back!
Mom, I'm here!
Mom?
Mom, haven't you come home yet?
Is she sleeping on the second floor?
Mom?
Oh, John, you are here?
Tell me, the child is born yet?
Yes, when your father told me the news,
I came right away!
The ladies who also helped have left.
Now come and see our child!
Good, but...
Tell me, where is my mother?
Well, she left with Dr. Hooper, don't worry!
And now, this way! This way, come on!
Hey, it's nice!
You see? Her eyebrows are very beautiful,
aren't they?
John...
I am grateful to your mother and father.
Thank you!
Yes...
Hello John!
Mom!
You act like a little boy!
Oh sorry, but I have to go out again.
Roger has been infected with peritonitis.
He needs a procedure, so I have
to take care of him all night.
But, Mom, you haven't slept last night!
Your mother is skilled!
But John, can you have dinner alone?
I'll be fine, of course!
Is that right? You are already a big boy!
Well, I prepared the food for you
and put it on the dish so you can eat.
Yes!
Colin!
John?
Hello Colin!
I told you before that I can't play.
I know that! Are you going
to deliver the goods? Is that it?
Yes...
It seems difficult!
Tell me, can I help you?
Huh? Oh really?
Yes, that way I can walk around
with you, Colin, all over the city!
If I let you ride this bike, I'll take this.
To move around the city...
I wonder what happens to me
if it's damaged?
I wanted to go with Colin...
I'm alone again...
I have no other choice...
Ah, it's an airplane!
Amazing, I would like
to fly with this plane!
It's landing here!
Just awesome!
Hey, stay away of this bike!
Hey don't do that! This is not mine!
Don't touch it!
This is bad...
How long will they continue to walk?
Hey! You are...
Why are you here? This is the?
Don't move! You will be crushed if you move!
Wait for me!
Hey, stay where you are!
Where did it go?
Hey, where did you go?
You, you...
Hey, come here...
Well... well, are you okay?
It hurts!
Are you okay, right?
Did you get hurt?
Don't approach the sheep again,
you will be crushed if you do!
Go home quickly, okay?
I have to deliver these immediately!
Bye!
Ah ah, I am tired...
I have to go home and have dinner alone.
What's the matter, hey? Are you still here?
Could be...
Don't you have a home to go back to?
Are you lost?
Cheer up... What should I do?
Could you be sick?
This is bad! This is bad!
Wait, I'll take you home immediately!
Colin! I finished the delivery!
Your bike is outside!
Bye!
John!
Faster! Faster! Faster!
Look, I lit the fire!
Come here and warm by the fire!
My mother often come back late,
so I know how to light it on!
What do you think? Do you feel better?
Great smell, dinner made by my mother!
You, could you be hungry?
Wait a moment!
This... this...
What? There is no milk!
Wait, I'm going to fetch milk!
Sandy!
Tell me, what color is the puppy?
Ah, I wonder...
It's covered in brown,
and also it has white.
It's this size.
So it's still a puppy!
Listen, next time I'll see the puppy!
Well, that's fine!
Do you agree?
Take care of it!
Thanks for the milk!
It's milk! It's delicious!
What is the matter? Aren't you hungry?
What is the matter?
Can't you drink milk by yourself?
Like a baby...
I'm tired, I want my father
come back quickly...
Okay here you go...
There are two men that haven't yet ascended.
I wonder what happened?
Time has already passed....
I hope there wasn't an accident.
What is that? It's still a puppy!
Yes, yes that is!
Colin!
John! Is it you, John?
Yes!
Sorry John, my father scolded me a lot...
Did you say "thank you" for delivery to John?
This is because you were busy.
Tell me, do you have a child's bottle?
Child's bottle?
- A puppy?
- Yes!
Last child's bottle was sold to Mrs. Hamilton.
Is that right?
Ah wait! I have one from my little brother!
Next time I'll see the puppy!
Yes!
Can it drink through it?
You're very hungry!
You've already finished!
What is that?
Your mood has changed completely!
You feel better, right?
I arrived late...
You do extra work, Sam Carraclough?
No, it's not that.
There were two men I didn't see,
so I rushed to look for them.
I found them relaxing inside!
Today Hamilton had a baby!
What about your child?
Poor one is still asleep alone?
No, I know, I'm going to him!
John, really...
John?
You wait until I get back?
I wonder where it came from?
I understand, you are no longer alone...
While I went to school
I left the puppy at home, though.
Because of that, it brought mess in the house.
What to do?
Next episode:
A BIG MESS AT HOME
Look forward to that!
Shounen no Oka sung by Jun Morioka
Tasogare niwa kimi to
okano ue kakenobori
Tooi sora o miteta
shounen noanogoro woo
Poketto kara ochita
CANDY to tokino suna
Otona ninarutameno
tabi wa hajimatteta
Moeagaru
yuuhi no kanata
Mada deaenai
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
Hohoen de
yakusoku shitane
Ano oka o koe
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni ikouto