OldCastle and South Wind Subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Walk towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
In my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
watch over you always,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari
a neverending story
Goodbye, Lassie
So she got here on this boat?
Yeah. I mean, the collar
I found fits her perfectly.
And she replied when I read
the name written on it.
Right, Lassie?
See?
Grandpa!
Oh, hello, John.
Do you know
the owner of this boat?
Huh?
Ah, that one.
It's been here
for two or three days.
Maybe it has no owner?
Take a good look.
The rope it was tied with
is now cut off.
The boat probably couldn't stand
its owners and escaped them.
Huh?
By escaping its owners, you mean
the rope broke and the boat
drifted here on its own?
Maybe so.
In the end, you won't know the truth
until you ask the boat itself.
I don't think the boat is gonna
tell us where it came from.
Hey, Lassie,
where did you come from?
Is it all right to move it
without anyone's permission?
It's in a good cause.
We have to find its owner.
Oh!
Wait for me.
If we learn where
the boat came from,
we may find Lassie's mom.
Right?
I see. So once you find her owner,
you'll have to give her back.
Naturally.
Naturally, huh…
Yes. If Lassie lives with her mother,
she'll be much happier.
If you say so, John.
It's an airplane!
This plane belongs to a family
we were recently delivering to.
Dad told me so.
Now that I think of it, when I met you
for the first time, there was an airplane, too.
If it wasn't for that plane,
I wouldn't meet Lassie.
This is the road to school!
It's the bridge we always cross.
Oh? John and Colin.
Where did you get this boat?
Guess what!
We're searching for Lassie's mom!
What?
Have you found
the owner of the puppy?
Not yet!
But I'm sure that
we'll find Lassie's mom!
So… John! Wait!
Hey, listen to me!
The backyards
near the town square.
Yes.
This is the first time I see them.
I saw him, I saw him!
John!
Mr. Curry!
She's so beautiful, sir!
From the river, our town
looks like another place.
Yes.
Dr. Hopper!
Hello. You're Carraclough's son, right?
That's a nice boat you have.
Thanks. But…
This reminds me…
Wait, what was it?
Ah, right! I remember seeing
that puppy on this boat a few days ago.
Dr. Hopper,
you've seen it before?
Yes. They must've floated
down here from upstream.
John.
Yeah.
Thank you very much, Doctor!
No problem, just don't tell
your mother that you saw me here.
What, you're scared?
You're such a coward.
Let's go!
We've came pretty far.
How long are we going
to oar like this?
Oh?
It's a steamer.
Lassie!
Wait for me, Lassie.
Hey!
Lassie!
This is dangerous, Lassie.
If you're not careful,
you'll get ran over.
What's this wheel doing here?
John!
Hey, John!
Here, look. Check this rope.
It's the same rope
as the one on the boat.
So, this means…
Look, they're exactly the same.
So Lassie drifted down from here?
Thank goodness, Lassie.
You're going to see your mom soon.
It went easier than I thought.
Hey, what's the racket?
You two rascals, why are you making
noise around other people's houses?
Hey! It's the boat
I lost the other day.
Y-You got it wrong, sir. It drifted
on its own and we've brought it back.
I'm telling the truth.
I'm not convinced.
Hm?
Where did you find this dog?
Uh, she…
Uhm… You see…
It's Lassie.
This means…
Sir, you know Lassie?
Of course I do.
She's my dog.
What's the matter?
Do you want me to say this again?
No, everything's fine.
I'll return her immediately.
But…
But what?
I found her about to get crushed
under a herd of sheep,
so I rescued her and
she stayed with me for a while.
Please give me a moment
to say goodbye to her.
Hmph.
Fine, do whatever.
Bring her to me
when you're finished.
Isn't it great, Lassie?
We've found your owner.
Lassie?
Your mom must be
worried about you.
Stay healthy, Lassie.
Don't forget about me, okay?
All right.
Now go to your mother.
Come on, go! Don't you want
to see your mother?
Hey!
Lassie, that's not the way!
I'm going, I'm going,
you impatient bastard.
I'm opening the valve, all right.
Whoa, kid!
It's not a place to play!
Get out of there!
It's not a playground.
I remember about you, for crying out loud!
A minute won't save you.
Hurry up, old man!
Did the pump break again or what?
Watch your mouth!
Our pump is the best around—
Damn, I have no time for this.
Hey, kid!
Come here and lend me a hand!
Listen, Lassie, let's leave this wheel
and go greet your owner.
Come on.
Good. Pull it harder, kid!
What's the matter?
You can't move it any further?
What are you doing?
First we close the gate,
then we raise the level of the water.
Then we let the boat in and close the gate
behind it, after that we let the water out.
Finally, once the water's low,
we open the gate and let the boat out.
How's it going?
Did you close it yet?
Yeah, somehow.
But why did he ask you, Colin?
I don't know, but
he sure works his men hard.
What's the matter?
Have you said your
goodbyes to the dog, kid?
Look at yourself. A bit of honest work
and you stop fooling around.
Are you okay?
Give me a few minutes.
You can't do anything.
I'm taking it now, all right.
And don't think of coming here again.
Go to your moms.
Sir, are you
the operator of this lock?
No, I'm a mailman.
Don't ask stupid questions, kid.
Do you live here alone?
Yes.
Don't you have a family
other than this puppy?
I don't. What's wrong with that?
I guess there's nothing we can do.
You get here.
If you misbehave, I'll eat you.
Come on, old man.
Open the other gate already.
I told you to wait.
I'm sure that man
loves Lassie, too.
I wouldn't be so sure.
Oh, right, I forgot
to tell him something.
John?
What is it?
You're that kid again.
What do you want this time?
Sir…
Lassie drinks milk
from a baby bottle.
However…
What of it?
I think she could be trained
to drink from a plate.
So I was thinking…
Err… Sir, what if…
Don't you have better things to do
than bothering people?
I'm not gonna spend
every day training it.
If it can't drink milk
on its own, so be it.
"So be it"? So what's going
to happen to her?
How can I know?
How can I know…
Well, the world was never easy
to live in to begin with.
John…
Hm?
Let's go back.
Listen, John, let's go back.
But that looks so interesting!
Ah, it started to move!
Now you're spying on people!?
What is your problem?
Why were you looking through my window?
But I was so surprised!
I didn't know people could have
such amazing machines in their houses.
Can I go inside
and take a look at it, sir?
Absolutely not.
That includes peeking
through my windows.
Oh?
What?
Stop fooling around.
It's not here.
I can't find one anywhere.
I won't repeat myself twice.
Get out of my house, kid.
Don't you have a doghouse, sir?
Huh?
A doghouse?
There's no such thing here.
Huh? You don't have one?
Then where do you keep it?
Why do you even care?
I don't have time to answer
your countless questions.
Now get lost.
No time?
A boat arrives every once in a while,
but other than that, what else are you doing?
Another question?
Leave me alone.
Hey, sir! Don't close the doors!
I want to ask you something else!
Give me a break.
But it's important.
John, that's enough.
Let's go back.
But it really is important.
I've had enough.
Fine, I'll answer one last question.
What is it?
Uhm, what do you have
to eat for today, sir?
What's for dinner?
Is this what you wanted to ask?
Yes.
It's canned food.
Canned food?
Yes. Canned food in the morning.
Canned food in the evening.
I don't have time to cook
so my food is just like that.
Oh, thank goodness.
It's not like it's good, you know.
There's nothing else for me to eat here.
Kid, why are you
interested in my food?
If you didn't have food to eat,
you might have to eat Lassie.
What?
You think I meant what I said to it before?
That I'm going to eat it?
Maybe you weren't serious, but…
I don't see Lassie's mom anywhere,
and I can only guess the reason.
Huh?
You don't see Lassie's mom here?
Where is Lassie's mom?
I didn't eat her, that's for sure.
Sir! Tell me where she is!
We want to find Lassie's mom and
bring them together. We came this far.
Why isn't she here?
Is she really not here?
Yes, I looked all around.
I bet he's a liar.
He's not the owner of Lassie!
I'm not a liar!
I hate lying!
It's because of that flat tire.
It's all because of it.
A flat tire? Ah, that wheel…
You know what
I'm talking about, kid?
No, but earlier when Lassie escaped me,
she immediately ran to a car wheel.
A few days ago there was
a car on this road with a flat tire.
The owner said he was from a foreign country
and was accompanied by a big Collie.
When the driver was busy replacing
the tire, this guy fled away.
He couldn't find it.
The port was far away and
he couldn't stay any longer.
So he decided to leave it alone.
He also asked me to
take care of it, if I ever find it.
See? Which is why this puppy
belongs to me now.
He left it under my care,
so I have no other choice.
Stop with that bark!
You're not taking care of her at all!
You have to promise me
that you will take good care of Lassie!
Are you stupid?
Watch where we are!
What are you doing, kid?
I thought it was not possible
for me to take care of her,
so I had decided to take her
to her real owners!
And yet…
You think if you're persistent enough,
I'll let you have it like that?
No!
No? Don't lie to me!
I'm not lying!
Let me hear it.
Admit you just want
her for yourself.
I don't!
As if I can believe that.
Think your barking
is going to help?
John, are you okay?
Well, don't come here again.
You're a liar and unable
to take care of it. Go home, kid.
I'm not going anywhere
until you promise me!
Stupid!
Oh! John!
I can't leave you now.
Here, grab onto this.
No! I won't grab it, not before you
promise me to take good care of Lassie!
This is not the time
for worthless arguments!
Promise me that
you won't bully her again!
I'm sorry I wasn't born
with a pretty attitude!
I never planned to bully it, all right!
Look, it's a ship!
Hurry up and get your butt
outta there or you'll regret it, kid!
All right, all right!
I promise you!
Lassie.
This mister lives alone,
so take care of him.
Hmph. As if it could
understand you.
Oh…
Here, it's yours.
But I brought her to you
because you are her real owner.
It's true that I made
a promise to take care of it.
But in the end,
it doesn't matter who gets to raise it.
Doing it myself would be a pain
in the butt, so I'll leave it to you.
Come visit me again some day,
the three of you.
I will offer you
some fresh seafood then.
You hear me?!
Yes! We will come, for sure!
Now, Lassie, let's go.
To our home.
Hot tea and milk are waiting
for us. Come on!
Tomorrow is my Mom's birthday.
But looks like Dad lost his salary.
He can't buy any gift for Mom.
Lassie, we're gonna
look for it with your nose!
Next episode:
"My Father's Salary".
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams