OldCastle and South Wind Subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Walk towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
In my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
watch over you always,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari
a neverending story
My Father's Salary
What is that? It started
to drink milk by itself!
You see?
Listen Lassie, you grow up quickly!
Eh…
- Ah!
- Oh!
Ah…!
Hey Lassie!
What-- what's up?
It has teeth!
Huh?
Lassie's teeth had appeared!
Small… small, but real!
Lassie!
If you upset the puppies, it wouldn't be nice!
Stop it!
What's with this face?
Lassie!
Always serious, always going out since dawn!
John…!
Come here, it's breakfast time!
That's it!
My father joins
the morning march of the workers.
I wish there were more nurses in the hospital!
It eats well, it's already bigger.
But don't eat too much, Lassie!
Leave some food for later!
Today is my father's salary day,
tomorrow is my mother's birthday!
Isn't it?
That's right, but what if there's
a surgery on my birthday?
Or perhaps there is a patient in critical
condition, and prevents me from returning.
Don't expect too much, okay?
Of course!
But I always pray that people
of Greenall Bridge to be in good health!
Hmm…
Always pray for it…
You take care of the house, when I come
back I'll go to the store to buy dinner!
Yes!
Well, it's getting closer, take your places!
And now push hard!
Push it!
You should be glad,
because today is the payday!
Did I heard well? He said: Be glad…
today… is the payday…
Everyone worked hard, didn't they?
I don't know, what about it?
All I have to do is pay monthly.
Well, it doesn't matter, it's important
not to make a mistake.
Do you think I made a mistake?
No, I don't mean that!
Don't worry!
I do my best to keep my salary.
Yes!
What is the matter?
You are not Sam!
Mr. Carraclough!
He wants only Mr. Carraclough!
Hm!
What is the matter?
Oh…
I received news from the bottom that
the water came out of the second channel.
Water?
Is it a lot?
I don't know the details…
It's better to go down and see for yourself.
There is no one at the bottom
wanting to get wet with water.
Eli!
Do you want to go down while we're busy?
No, I apologize!
No, I'll take your place.
You and your companion, be careful!
I apologize for making you wait!
What is that person's speaking about?
Carraclough is already appreciated here…
Although the office work is shared by us,
he left it to me and went away.
I'm happy! So glad! Today is our payday!
Yes…
Well let's get going!
Sandy, get up there!
Yes, I have stepped up!
Okay!
The weather is beautiful today, grandfather!
Yes, more beautiful than I expected!
The mine workers are working hard
to get their salary today.
Since today is the payday,
surely everyone will buy delicious food!
Those who don't work will not eat anything,
but those who work hard
will eat until they are full.
Hey, would you please tell me?
The village of Greenall Bridge
is straight ahead, right?
Yes that's right, are you going to trade?
How is it over there?
Are there many customers?
Not as it is usual, because people
received their salaries.
Hm, I understand… thank you!
There are certainly a large
number of customers.
When the mine's payday comes,
traders come from everywhere.
Look here Lassie! There are lots of stands here!
There are many farmers
who sell very tasty vegetables!
I wonder what kind of food my mother will cook?
I look forward for tonight, Lassie!
We have finally finished…
My energy is over…
When will you give it to me?
Wait, wait, don't rush!
I must put the president's salary
in the treasury first!
Quickly, and give me my salary immediately!
Well well…
Group II, Bio!
Bio… Bio…
There he is! 3 pounds and 10 shillings.
Group II, Hamilton!
Hamilton, Hamilton…
Well, here it is, hurry up, next!
Group II, Roger!
The amount of water is not great,
you will be fine.
Well, let's go!
Get your salary right away
and buy good food for yourself!
It's best to fix it before water increses.
Isn't it, Sam?
Yes!
What will you do? I don't think you
will enjoy your holiday, do you?
The latest thing?
No…
He said his daughter gave birth to his
granddaughter and is coming here to see her.
Heck, you are a talkative man!
It's better to come back.
Don't be silly!
Sorry, if so, I can take his place
because I'm a new worker and I want
to learn how to stop the water leakage.
But…
I will also stay with him.
Well, in fact I can only say that you saved me.
You have to finish it quickly,
Melissa and John are waiting for you!
Yes!
It looks delicious, Lassie!
Instead of watching the food,
I have to find it!
Something like that…
What's up, kid?
Are you interested in silverware?
No, no. Let's go, Lassie!
What? Sandy's brother!
Ah John, I've got it from Lake Dartford.
Eh? You got all of it from the lake?
Don't it look delicious?
Sandy's there, with my grandfather.
Yes, thank you!
What? What's your problem?
John! Lassie!
Hello!
Hello John, take this!
But…
Can't you eat a free watermelon? Eh?
Yes, thank you!
Tell me, only you and Lassie came?
Yes, my father haven't returned yet
so I went first.
Well, you know, Sandy…
What is the matter?
Today is my mother's birthday,
what kind of gift do you think she wants?
Birthday!
Present!
Hey Sandy! Listen!
In here! In here! In here!
And now, choose the one for your wife!
This will make your wife more beautiful!
This is it!
It's a good choice, as you expect!
What do you think?
So… jewelry…
…but I have no money…
There is nothing wrong with buying
the gift together with your father!
Ah, right!
We have to wait for my father, Lassie!
I'm tired, I'm tired…
Now, go to the office to get your salary.
Okay.
Eli!
He left before me.
Mr. Carraclough, salary is in the treasury…?
I have completed the delivery
of salaries to all employees.
Have you received your salary yet?
Not yet… does it take long?
Not at all! You don't have to worry!
Well, this is your salary.
It's more than usual.
Today, you've done extra work.
Thanks! Well, see you later…
Thank you so much for today!
Yes!
It's bad…
He seems to have forgotten
to put Brock's salary in the closet.
It seems that Eli is not accurate
in his calculations.
I have no salary because of that.
I can't celebrate my wife's birthday.
What to do?
We have his leg exactly like him!
I'm back!
What?
You lost it! What do you mean?
Well, that's the truth…
Lost all your salary! But what will you do
tomorrow at my mother's birthday?
No, that's why… I mean…
Where have you lost it?
Where…?
No, it's not that…
If not, then what does it mean?
Don't you know where you lost it?
Where did you go after receiving your salary?
No, that…
You don't think about my mother!
John!
We can't do anything as long as we lose it.
But…
The bathroom is hot, go immediately.
Bathroom?
You're all black!
Oh!
Why? Why are you so, Father?
All the important things are overflowing
and distracting yourself with trivial things!
John…
I will borrow this to restore it!
Lassie!
He seems serious…
He was doing everything for me.
I understand, I've done something really bad.
You lied to us when I said you lost it.
Oh?
You used this excuse to lie to us,
isn't it?
Impossible, I didn't lied.
You spent your money helping people, right?
No…
The bathroom is ready!
Okay.
Seriously, he is our son.
Do you think he will act like children?
Right.
So…
Lassie, you're a dog.
Can you pick my father's smell
and recover his money?
My father went somewhere, and lost his money.
There!
Well, well done!
No, my father's job is on the hillside!
Perhaps it's impossible for it to do so.
John Carraclough!
Sam apparently returned home
after climbing the hill.
You have to trust Lassie.
Dad was down the hill?
Thank you!
Yes…
Did my father come here
when he came back from work?
I understand, it's twice the way home
and it's hard for you to determine the route.
Hey Lassie, if you go this way…
No, I was completely satisfied.
The place is very busy, and this
is due to the delivery of salaries.
Oh, thank you very much for that!
You have increased my salary
and estimated my extra work.
You seem like Carraclough.
Working hard and treating
people well is the best.
That's what I wanted to tell you!
See you later!
Are you feeling good, dear?
Oh?
Oh…
Who was that? It seems I've seen him before.
He is a miner anyway.
Is my father having fun when he came here?
People began to dissipate again…
Does that mean that he lost the money
before coming here?
This way!
But… if the money fell here,
it will be hard to find.
Hm?
Hm!
Eh?
Why did my father come here?
Ah, keep it away, kid!
Yes! Hey, Lassie!
Stop it, Lassie!
Move the dog quickly!
This is not a game for the dog!
A while ago a man came from the minecovered in coal and touched the brooch
and wanted to sell it to him!
Sorry…
What?
How does the person covered
with coal looked like?
He is a skinny man, who seems
to have stepped out of his job recently.
He wanted to get this brooch
and said he'll pay me the next day.
He said he wanted to give
an expensive gift to a woman.
And I said to him, "Stop this, this!"
Listen to this, Lassie…
I'm no longer angry with my father.
After all, I think my father like me.
Thief!
Catch him! He just stole!
I'll be damn!
He's a thief!
Thief? Oh!
I don't have my wallet!
He's there! Catch him!
Follow him! Maybe he stole
my father's money!
Step aside!
Is this the thief?
Lassie!
This crook guy stole my wallet too!
I really apologize, Mr. Carraclough!
It's okay…
I tell to the manager
to open the closet tomorrow.
No, it's not like I'm about to die!
Well…
I'm the only óne to blame and
the victim is you, Mr. Caraclough.
I made a big mistake.
That's enough, let's talk later.
See you on Monday, good night!
As I expected, you've done a good deed!
Oh…
You're a shy man!
I'm back!
Father, just a moment… come here!
- Oh!
- Hm?
I haven't find the money, but look!
This is yours…
Dad, you wanted to give
this gift to my mother, right?
How did that happen?
Come on, Lassie!
Ah I know!
I'll be eating your birthday tomorrow!
So don't worry, good night!
Like someone else?
Is it okay not to worry about the food?
I will look forward to tomorrow!
You are right!
What a stupid village!
I was robbed, and rewarded that boy.
He have chosen that excellent brooch!
I won't go back to this village again!
Today is Saturday!
It's a holiday for everyone,
but not for me!
Now Lassie, let's go to the lake today!
I want to catch something to cook!
Next episode:
"6 Miles In Search For Food".
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams