OldCastle and South Wind Subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Walk towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
In my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
watch over you always,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari
a neverending story
6 Miles In Search For Food
Well, the weather is lovely!
With the sunshine I have
to find something to cook!
Lassie, wake up!
I have to catch something to cook
for my mother's birthday!
You are lazy!
This is our food!
This is your bag.
Can you carry it? There is
nothing wrong with that!
I look forward to the promise I made.
Goodbye….
Well, Mr. Pew's fishing tool
that I borrowed yesterday.
The lunch is ready!
Well, let's go, Lassie!
Where are you going Lassie?
The road is not in there!
But in there, through the backyard!
John Carraclough!
Good morning!
What do you do early in the morning
during your holiday?
Isn't all this a inconvenience?
There is no inconvenience!
It's my secret,
to surprise everyone with food!
Isn't that so my mother will be surprised?
The lake is very far away, and be careful
of walking under the hot sun.
Grandma Forrest thinks she knows
everything, but she is wrong!
We won't go back empty handed, Lassie!
This window is very hot…
It's nice to see the sun,
but not in the summer!
Hm?
John! Lassie!
Where are they going?
This is my first time running
so I can't bear it anymore, Lassie!
We must not tire before going to the lake!
Look here!
The corresponding contrast is red.
These hills are covered with many flowers.
People from the mine say
that behind this hill there are flowers
but there is a large rocky hill
that I haven't seen yet.
I haven't seen much of it yet
but I can see it with you, Lassie!
John…!
Good morning!
Sandy! Why did you wake up early in the morning?
That's what I wanted to ask you about!
John, I've heard from my big brother
that you're going to Lake Dartford, right?
Eh?
That's true, though…
Listen, if you want to swim,
take me with you!
Eh…?
I want to swim with Lassie!
Okay, do you agree?
What?
But you are wrong…
What is this tool?
Sandy is not patient.
Once her fault was revealed,
her face became red and she went away!
What?
Sandy is strange…
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Sandy?
What's up, Sandy?
If you want to go with me,
you can only say that!
Lassie, you go with your big sister!
John, hurry up, before we get away from you!
What?
Tell me, will Grandpa Banson
take the train for Saturday as well?
This is for transporting the coal that was
produced yesterday to another channel.
But Grandpa is always drunk.
But when he moves the coal
he feels excited and loves his work!
Hm…!
I will be waiting for him!
It's coming!
Hey hey! Stop!
Listen, Grandpa Banson!
This is dangerous! Children can't play here!
Now go back home
before my anger gets worse, okay?
Sorry…
What is the matter? I'm very busy!
Excuse this Grandpa Banson train for this.
Banson?
He stayed there to fix
a column of a broken cabin.
Eh?
Did your father say that?
Not at all…
I don't have time to be late!
- Tell me!
- Oh?
Can we go with you?
No no!
And now go away, I must leave quickly!
Grandpa Banson lets me go often!
This thing he warned me about
is very important!
I had an interview last week
and the owner told me about it.
The office owner is my father.
Don't go near!
Do you want to go home and tell him
I violated the rules?
Or something like that?
Well…
Move away!
What? Where are Lassie and Sandy?
Ah…
Since when are those two there?
Sandy!
Haven't you been so late?
What about your bike?
We'll be back soon, so it'll be fine!
Be careful not to fall, Lassie!
Lassie, get down, he will see you!
Did he heard it?
I don't know…
Somehow I want to scream loud!
I can't hear you!
And in such a place…
I shouldn't scream anymore!
If Sandy did it without being noticed,
well I will do it too!
Here it is!
This is another tunnel!
Lassie! When we get out of the tunnel
we don't have to scream!
Hey!
When I find you next time,
I will not call you two!
Damn…
So bad, my bag is on the cart!
I'm hungry…
When I woke up in the early morning,
I didn't think of having lunch outside.
What about this bag?
These swimwear are specific to the lake.
How long will you continue to walk like this?
My legs swelled!
If that happens with you,
my legs will certainly swell even more!
What do you mean?
Grandpa Banson took me often on the train.
Maybe we should go in my brother's cart…
If you want to go back,
you can go back on your own,
I'll go with Lassie.
Bridge of London collapses, collapses, collapses,
Bridge of London collapses, what a poor thing!
We have to rebuild the bridge
with iron and steel
until it becomes beautiful!
Bridge of London collapses, collapses, collapses,
Bridge of London collapses,
what a poor thing!
How long will you continue to sing this song?
I don't know…
Looks delicious.
It's just meat crumbs.
Is that right?
You seem to be in big trouble!
Yes!
If you are really hungry,
this is all I have!
It's regrettable that only these have
remained, but this is really the case.
Even though it's for my horse,
it's okay to eat it.
It's delicious and edible!
Thank you for the food!
Sandy!
You really eat it, Sandy!
I apologize for this,
but this is better than none!
It is said, "You cross the bridge
to reach the house."
Are you going to Lake Dartford to fish
and cook food for someone's birthday?
Yes…
That's what I thought!
Hey? What? What do you mean?
No, I mean food, food!
What are you talking about?
What food will you cook?
No, that's not important.
You're a shy boy!
Move! Move!
I apologize for what happened to you,
it's best to get down!
But…
Get down quickly and ask for help!
Lassie, let's go!
Sandy, go ahead of me!
What are you talking about?
Come on quickly!
Wacky, what are you saying to me?
Sandy, hurry up!
Okay…
Sandy!
John!
Don't move, if you lose balance you will fall!
Eh…
Kid, go and ask for help!
But…
The nearest house is about
one mile away, go quickly!
Don't be late, hurry up!
The nearest house is about one mile away!
Today I walked far away and I was very tired!
But time is not appropriate for that!
There is a big problem!
Auntie…?
I can't hold it no more!
Be patient!
There it is!
There is the house, hurry up!
No use, my legs can't move…
But, I have to go…
I'm crushed, I have to rest a little…
It hurts…
I have injured my knee…
I can't move…
Hey! The cart is in big trouble!
Hey!
Well, Lassie, go and get any man from there!
Come on, hurry up!
Go Lassie! I can't go with you!
Ah, my leg hurts me, as you haven't
brought any man, I will die!
Faster!
What are you doing to me, dog?
What do you say? Where did it came from?
There really is someone!
It's no use, Auntie, I don't seem
to hold it any more!
Hey Sandy!
Wait, we'll help you right away!
Finally we arrived…
Ah…
My legs swelled because I walked long distances.
When I asked for help, the vehicle was hit more.
With that we miraculously arrived…
But we have to get good food…
Ah…
Hey, you, I will help you get food!
I see! You do this for your parents!
All of them are professionals in fishing!
And now they all will help us!
Yes, you rely on us!
Happy birthday, Mom!
Congratulations!
Eh, looks delicious!
Where did you get all this?
Well, John…
Yes, this is a secret, Lassie!
Although I don't know how,
but I'm sure it was very difficult!
Just eat…
You are right…
The storm is coming.
A storm like no other.
There is strong wind and continuous rain!
But Lassie, we have to get out immediately!
To give Dr. Hopper the syringe!
Next episode:
"Running Through The Storm".
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams