RUNNING THROUGH THE STORM
Colin, faster!
Wait for me...
Do we have to climb this up?
What? You said you'll come with me, Colin!
My father told me when I was a child
to go up and look from there, but...
I can't do that...
You'll be fine!
You see? Lassie climbed easily!
Push it well, okay?
You'll be fine...
It's very high!
Well, rest a little!
We arrived!
This hill is the largest rocky hill here!
It's just awesome!
The rocks looks like a castle!
This opening is so big!
This rock looks like a king's throne!
The light is coming from the top!
This place is suitable for reading books!
Here, we can enter through here!
Eh?
You want to go further? I prefer to stay here!
Yes!
I want to climb the top of the rock!
I want to stop here!
Hey John! Are you fine?
Hey, John, answer me!
I can see the sky!
Just wait a little!
This is the top of the rock!
Colin! The sky is strange!
What happened?
There are dense clouds covering the other side!
Also...
...looks like a black line...
What?
Are you still working?
Yes.
What is that? Where did you got it from?
Is that gift we got from someone
when we married?
It's for my desk.
For your desk?
That's good, we'll take advantage
of it for the weather bulletin!
What are you talking about?
This is the most sophisticated
machine that has appeared so far.
I want to see it right away.
However, it seems that John
is still playing forth as usual.
Also there is no space on your desk!
Where can you put it?
It's weird...
What is the matter?
Nothing, it's good but...
The scale goes down.
My God, it means the storm is coming?
Oh...?
It's broken, as I expected.
There is no cloud to announce the storm...
Oh, my God, I washed the clothes!
We can't rely on it!
Hmm...
However, John...
What just happened?
I don't know.
Hey, Grandpa Banson? What is the matter?
Don't call me!
Stop grumbling and see if it will
withstand heavy winds or not!
I know that.
Hm!
It really is...
Ah, no use!
The rust gathers around the upper tars!
Look!
Are they all right?
Anyway, this tower is very old!
Maybe it will fall if a strong storm passes.
When such a thing happens,
a problem will be solved.
What will you do? Will you
tell the manager that?
No, I'll tell Sam first!
Well, that's better!
We can't rely on the manager anyway.
But...
Whatever, we had to hurry!
I must hurry, before it starts raining!
Lassie, what are you doing there
at a time like this?
Hey, come quickly!
You should beware of hypotension.
So be careful!
Welcome back, how was the weather outside?
The clouds looked like an arch,
and there were strong winds!
Father, it's very windy...
Hi John, are you playing?
Sorry, what's up?
With such faces? Have you quarreled?
We haven't quarreled. I was
only talking to your father.
I came to ask Sam for something,
is not it?
How do you connect the two ropes together?
Well about this, we can do so
as long as the wind is medium.
Let us gather the people!
Yes!
Where did my father and the other man go?
The vertical tower of the coal mine
appears to be about to fall.
Eh?
Is it so weak to fall?
Maybe the big wheel will fall
and roll toward our house!
I wonder what will happen next?
Eh...
Ah, this...
It will be fine and will not fall easily!
This is because your father and
the others will do something.
My hat... wait! Wait for me!
I don't know who to rely on in this work!
You'll be fine, Lassie!
These winds can't drop a huge tower!
It's down in the afternoon
but the sky is dark...
Where did the sun disappear?
How long will the wind last?
Sandy's house...
I wonder what Sandy is doing?
I hate thunder! Get away from me!
John! John!
John, come here for minute!
What's up, Mom?
I'm going out!
Hey? In such a storm?
I'm sorry, John!
Morton's grandfather double heart again.
Hello, Doctor!
Hello!
John, depend on you in the rest!
Hey?
Are you okay, Doctor?
Well, a little cohesion please!
Damn, the expensive medicine has broken!
They are in a difficult time! If the storm
didn't come, the bottle wouldn't be broken!
Oh...
What? It doesn't work...
The whole neighborhood is dark! I'm sure
the electricity is off on everyone!
What is the matter? Are you scared?
Wait, well, matches, matches...
What? Can't be found...
Ah, I found it!
We got the light, Lassie!
Is it the noise of the wind?
Don't you think this is it true?
What? Sandy's brother!
Well, you saved me!
We lost a sheep and went out to look
for it. The situation was difficult.
Can I rest here?
Tell me, are things bad outside?
It's not so bad.
But my grandfather said there was
a more severe storm going to Yorkshire.
Eh...?
It goes and stops...
I wonder how long the weather
will last this way?
Well, I'm going before it gets stronger!
Be careful!
The weather is even worse.
Low pressure moves towards North Yorkshire.
The intensity of the wind will increase,
so we advise citizens not to go out...
The power is out again...
What are you doing all this time?
Hm?
This is...?
Maybe it would be difficult
for my mother to return...
But Dr. Hooper may not be able
to do anything without the injection.
What to do, Lassie?
Outside is a severe storm.
It's difficult to walk under this weather.
But...
I must go to deliver the syringe!
If you don't want to go, you can stay here.
And now Lassie...
I wonder how the storm will
look like if we were abroad?
Come on, Lassie!
We must survive the great storm for Mr. Morton!
Let's go!
I know that, I have to go to that direction!
Somati! What are you doing here?
Here we are...
Here you will be fine for now.
Stay in my house until the storm is over.
Well, here we go again!
Come on, Lassie!
Damn, I mustn't go except through Mr. Morton!
Damn!
We must pass this square
but the wind is very strong!
We have to go!
Bad, it's the syringe!
Back again, we can never pass!
But we must go!
How do you feel? Are you tired?
Yeah, I do anything...
You'll be fine, you've taken
your medicine, and you ate well!
Your life is not at stake.
It hurts...
Stop it! You are too big to do that!
Ah, but I feel so much pain...
Damn...
It would be better to take some sedatives.
No other choice for us, I lost the syringe
when my bag was opened in your home.
Listen Doctor, give me
some of the painkillers...
Don't rely on medication alone!
Can't you bear that with
the power of your body?
Well now...
You are not so sick.
Nor can we get the injection
with such intense weather.
Just ignore him.
Yes.
Awesome water! I can't move my legs!
What is this...?
It's Sandy's sheep!
It can't stay there, I have to take it away!
Wait for me, I'll be there soon!
The pulse of this man's heart is weak,
he may have had a real fit.
Mrs. Carraclough!
Yes!
Take care of him!
What?
I'll go and get a new syringe.
Will you go, Doctor?
Don't do it!
I know the storm is severe.
I don't mean that!
The doctor must stay for patient treatment!
I will go!
Mrs. Carraclough!
No, I can't send you in such a storm!
Also to bear my mistake!
No, Doctor!
Go both of you!
Please hurry up!
Well, how to work?
This is true...
Sorry...
Just now, this...
Oh...!
I'm happy for you...
Ah...!
Somehow we were able to do it...
Oh really...
It's just awesome!
We didn't stayed long because of the storm...
These is our rocky castle!
The snow came.
One of my friends' shawls was stolen at school.
Everyone thought that the culprit
was Lassie who stole the shawl.
It's not you, is it, Lassie?
Next episode:
THE CAPTURE OF THE ROBBER
Be sure to watch!