OldCastle and South Wind Subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Walk towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
In my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
watch over you always,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari
a neverending story
Catch The Muffler Thief
Well, see you later!
Goodbye!
The weather is cold.
Even in such a cold morning, I have to work.
Today you have many patients with fever.
You can play with the snow,
but be careful not to get fever too!
Okay!
The handle is frozen.
I wonder if it crashes?
Well, I'm leaving!
Okay!
Even this is frozen!
How did my mother boil tea for breakfast?
That's it, I will test the boiler!
Ah hot!
Lassie, what are you looking at?
You see, this is your first winter, right?
Although you seem very big…
It's snow! The snow!
Today it's snowing, this weather is cold!
Look at this, Lassie!
The road and the roof and
everything is white, right?
As expected, from this morning
even Grandma Forrest closed the window!
From there, she still watches
outside the house as usual!
Well, Lassie…
I will leave the house under your care today.
Don't show this sad face…
I'm sure you'll be used to staying
at home until I come back, right?
When I come back we'll play together!
I will let you go in snow!
Bye!
Colin is absent because he has fever,
and Sandy can't ride the bike
because of the snow.
John Carraclough!
Stop staring outside!
Oh…
Okay!
Stop laughing!
You know that you get a penalty when
you're late without an excuse, right?
Yes. We used the sleigh for our preparation,
which took a long time to get it ready.
I understand.
Take off your coat and take your seat.
Okay!
Colin took a vacation, right?
He has fever!
Listen, my grandfather made me cookies
and I put it in my coat, outside.
Eh?
Want to try it?
Hey!
What about Lassie?
Um…
I usually leave it in the backyard to play there.
Today it is inside the house.
Have you locked the doors?
I had no choice.
If it feels bored, I hope not to cause
chaos inside the house.
Push!
I feel sick.
The weather is very cold.
However, I can't resist not the drink.
Hey, what is it, dog?
Why did you stop?
Look, this is the same as machine oil.
Without this thing, my body
will not hold up anymore.
I can't put it away.
I'm hiding here until I drink as I please!
You want to try it, right?
You will feel warm!
Eh?
Pfff!
That's why I hate dogs!
Does the smell of wine is really strong?
Maybe everyone is having fun now
and making a snowman…
Oh?
Lassie!
Lassie! Come here!
You shouldn't be in such a cold place!
I'm also on my own now.
Does everyone is having fun?
My father delivers the goods through the snow.
My mother took my little brother
and went to Dr. Hopper.
My little brother has fever.
Me too.
But when you are beside me
I feel more comfortable.
All I do is read books.
Don't look here and there!
The place is a mess and I feel embarrassed.
Come here, Lassie! It's warm!
I have no friends now.
You are the first to enter my room.
John and the others haven't come yet.
I don't know anyone other than John,
I can talk to him with all ease.
I'm very shy.
What should I do to come John and Sandy?
Oh?
Ah, that?
Do you look at the strange shape?
I made it badly.
I'm a little bad at manual work.
Our store uses these mobile machines.
I used to buy things like that.
Look!
It is small, but it moves correctly.
These is just a motor ship
on the river, but it moves fast!
I wonder why I don't?
I'm not quite sure of myself
to be a dynamic person.
I don't have any!
I have no choice but to read novels.
Anything can be done in books.
The book I'm reading now
is "The Dog of Baskerville".
And it's about a dog
turned into a big monster.
This great mystery has been
followed by a detective.
I love Sherlock Holmes because he is fast-paced!
He is amazing!
Lassie, what would you say
if you were in his place?
Are you sleeping?
Well, let's sleep together!
Ah…
It's very warm…
In any case, you don't understand
what people are saying.
Lassie, what's up?
I understand, do you want to go now?
Wait a moment!
The snowing has stopped.
It's okay to go out now.
But the weather is still cold.
Come back again, Lassie!
In fact, I don't want you to go.
Yet I will let it go on its way.
But Lassie was very warm…
This means that the war
lasted for 100 years…
Carraclough!
Oh? Yes!
Who was the ruler of England
when the war started?
He was the Black Prince…
Well done.
Which caused the suffering of the French.
Who is it, Spinner?
Spinner!
Sorry…
What did you say about Rock?
Focus on the lesson while explaining!
But…
Spinner!
What is all of this?
Horrible!
It's my coat!
Mine also!
Who did such a thing?
No, that…
The culprit is just an animal!
Is it an animal?
Calm down!
This thing is not worth any fuss!
Go back to the classroom and
prepare for the next lesson!
You too.
What's the problem if it's a bit dirty?
But in my pocket it were cookies
and it had eaten all!
Teacher, is not here!
Teacher, there is a strange dog!
It's wearing a shawl around its neck!
A dog?
Where? Where?
I really took the shawl
It's scary…
Ah…!
It barked!
- Maybe he is a predator!
- Lassie!
John Carraclough!
Is this your dog?
Yeah…
The school if for study only!
You don't have to bring a dog here!
Okay!
I will try to get it out!
Okay, me too!
Please wait!
It may bite you!
Teacher! Lassie…
It escaped!
Wait!
Well, me too!
Please stop! Boys!
All of you, wait!
Wait…!
Children, come back immediately!
Hey!
Strange, since when Lassie…?
What are you doing here?
Hurry up and stop everyone!
But, Lassie…
Aren't you its owner?
The shawl it was wearing wasn't mine.
Spinner ah, huh?
Yes.
Just before I saw the dog wearing
a green-colored shawl, but…
My shawl is brown.
Also how can Lassie wrap
the shawl around its neck?
Oh, right!
It's better to follow everyone,
because the dog is not guilty.
What do you do?
Please wait!
All of you, please wait!
Well, we have besieged it!
Lassie!
Well, now I will deal with it!
Wait, what if it's not guilty?
But this…
Wait a moment!
Lassie didn't do it!
Spinner's shawl is different from this!
What are you talking about?
There is no one else to steal the other shawl!
Also, you're trying to say that
you know who the culprit is?
I don't know who did it, but…
You see?
You are wrong!
Spinner, please explain to them!
Oh…
Hm?
Spinner is not here!
Spinner! Make an effort, faster!
What is that?
These tracks…
…go inside!
It's dangerous!
If these were made by the culprit
and it wasn't your dog
we will know the perpetrator
only if we see it!
Carraclough, step aside!
Let me look inside!
It's angry!
Look, as I expected!
Caraclough, do something!
Lassie, what's up?
Let's take a look inside.
We won't do anything bad.
Is it okay?
Carraclough, is anything in there?
Carraclough!
- Oh really?
- Where? Where?
Those two blows?
Also her puppies!
It's my shawl!
But it's okay!
That these blows should be taken.
The beatings are still so satisfying
that I stayed here.
Yes, isn't it better to leave it alone?
It's not possible!
This is the school's warehouse!
I see.
But I will leave her until
her puppies stop breastfeeding!
That's great, Lassie!
I'm sorry, John, I…
Sorry, John…
You're a clever dog, Lassie!
A beautiful shawl!
Go back after school!
So, the teacher said!
Colin!
Hey Colin!
Hey!
John!
Lassie, was the shawl warm?
This shawl is especially from Colin?
Today, there was a thief in school,
but Lassie managed to find the real culprit!
Eh…?
Is that so?
Yes, it's like a detective!
Lassie, did you remember
what I was telling you?
I see.
You remembered then…
Lassie…
Hey Colin, will you come to school tomorrow?
Yes!
I had quarreled with Sandy at school.
Lassie, you are the reason!
This is because you are
following me like a fool!
You act with dignity,
but you can't do anything without me!
Don't follow me anymore!
Next episode:
"I Don't Like Lassie".
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams