OldCastle and South Wind Subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Walk towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
In my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
watch over you always,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari
a neverending story
I Don't Like Lassie
It came, it came! My dear!
- Look!
- Oh!
Hurry up ​​and adjust the clock time!
What is happening?
It's 2:55!
Oh?
This dog is always here at the same time!
My home clock stopped working!
This is the best way to adjust the time!
Yes!
Hey, Lassie!
Are you going today too?
Is it hard work?
I understood!
You don't understand what I'm saying to you!
How come you don't know the answer?
Are you making fun of me?
No, I really don't know!
I'm tired...!
I said the answer during the explanation.
You didn't payed attention!
Don't stick out your tongue!
I finished the lesson today!
I will leave you to find the answers!
John Carraclogh!
Yes!
You, give me the answer!
Eh...
Uh...
... three hundred and forty...
... No, twenty...
Sorry, teacher!
Hm?
What is the matter?
I'm still standing, can I sit?
Eh?
What?!
Isn't it obvious that you can't?
What are you thinking about?
Oh my God, my God!
How long will we do all this?
Oh really...
Ah...
Today he was very angry...
But Sandy made him even more!
You don't had to act provocatively.
Besides the teacher's anger
increased more when she said:
"I'm still standing, can I sit?"
I wish you were as indifferent as she was.
What?
Eh...
I know I'm a totally indifferent girl!
I apologize for that!
Sandy, what happened to you today?
I envy you for your character, Sandy!
It's because of me, although I imagined
prolonging the time of your answer.
I worked hard to think about answering longer!
But this...
You mean the teacher
is very angry because of me?
You, too, John...
Just consider me a troublesome girl!
Sandy!
Hello, Lassie! Goodbye!
We were late because of Sandy's behavior!
Don't say anything like that!
You waited John for a long time, Lassie!
You are wonderful!
Come on, Lassie!
I expected. It's better to apologize, John.
I have a lot of work in the store
so I can't go with you.
Sandy is just as well at home, right?
The study is difficult.
So...
I know that.
If you apologize, but...
Today, I have to take the goods
from the store to Morton's house.
Hi Lassie!
Well, Colin left.
Lassie, I can't play with you today.
Because I don't want to.
Wel...
Ah...
However...
I didn't know that such words
would anger Sandy.
What to do?
But when Sandy comes tomorrow
she'll forget everything, right?
Hey Lassie!
John!
Lassie doesn't need food today?
Ah, right!
What is the matter? What is the matter?
You can't forget the precious Lassie's meal!
Thank you, Mr. Nelson!
You can come here for the weekend as usual!
Well, I'll tell my father that!
Yes that's fine.
Today you were a little late.
Have you been punished
because you haven't studied well?
Eh...
Lassie!
It's a really good dog!
Yes!
We have talked about it before.
We have never seen a good dog like him.
Is that right?
Every morning it follows me annoyingly...
It's as I said about it completely.
It's persistent even if the winds
of Yorkshire are very cold.
It's not like that.
Right!
It's a good dog and the best in Yorkshire!
Even if the owner leaves it,
it can live the best.
As I expected, right?
"Even if the owner leaves it,
it can live the best."
It won't be able to do it.
Hey Lassie!
You dig again!
What exactly do you do?
You can't get inside looking like this!
If you enter, the room will be stained with mud!
You are useless...
Hey, be quiet!
You do this every day!
Well, Lassie...
In fact you are annoying!
Stay calm!
He seems angry.
What happened?
Maybe he's trying to act
like a little mature person.
John! I don't know what happened,
but stop bothering Lassie!
It's not like I'm bothering it!
Lassie is the one who causes me discomfort.
Hm...?!
Is that right?
I told it to always stay at home,
but it follows me every morning to school.
Even when I go home
it's waiting in front of the gate.
Ah!
Hey!
This water is not to drink!
And now I'm going to the second floor, Lassie!
Lassie...
Don't do this...
You are no longer a puppy.
Don't sneak in here that way...
With such a face...
You don't want to be seen this way
by Mr. Nelson the butcher.
Somehow you look terrifying.
It's best to comb your hair!
Uh ah!
Uh...
You, do you have fleas?
Do you have such things for a long time?
Where did you get it from?
Don't follow me.
I said don't follow me!
I have to go to school alone!
You can go and play by yourself now!
I'm sorry, John.
Even though you have walked
all this distance for him.
However, it's inevitable
as long as he is still feverish.
Please, when Colin gets better,
let him go back to school!
Yes, thank you!
He will be fine.
- Goodbye, Uncle!
- Yes!
That is why I told you
not to follow me like a fool.
Let me walk more freely.
Bye!
Well... Go now! Go!
What?
Oh Lassie, you also came today!
I have enough food too.
You always help me, take care of the sheep.
You are good!
Besides Colin, Sandy is also absent.
This way I can't apologize to her
for what happened yesterday.
Oh! I was about to forget!
You are really useful
You learned many things
just by staying with Bingo.
Now the farm is big and it needs you,
isn't it, Bingo?
And now Lassie,
what time did you return?
Thank you.
This is for you.
Bye!
Ah... eh!
Hm!
Well, it's its share of the day.
Thank you.
But, Uncle...
Lassie doesn't persevere even
if the winds of Yorkshire are very cold!
Huh?
I was the one who took care of it
all the time and taught it!
Lassie can't do anything without me!
Is that right?
You are also a great boy.
Thank you.
I'm glad you told me that.
See you!
Have we made any mistake about them?
No, I don't know...
Don't try in your usual way!
Now let's see...
What will we play today?
I remembered, there is an abandoned mine.
Do you want to look for treasures together?
I haven't seen this abandoned mine
for a long time.
Whoa!
The interior is very dark and terrifying!
I wonder if you will follow me, Lassie?
I don't think this area is
as cowardly as you are!
Well, I'll go in!
Hey!
Lassie, I'm here!
When I was little I was playing here!
It will be difficult for Lassie!
Bad!
How can Lassie chase me this way?
Lassie!
Hey! Lassie!
Wait for me, I will ask for help now!
Ah...!
Lassie...
I think that was my fault...
I'm sorry...
Somehow I feel that this vast sky
is much farther than it is.
Ah...
Wouldn't anyone come here?
Tell me, Lassie...
Lassie, answer me!
Hey Lassie!
That's great...
I thought you were hurt or died.
I'm really sorry, Lassie...
I don't know why but...
...all people are very grateful to you...
In fact I'm very happy
but at the same time I'm not happy.
I can't do anything.
I can't understand Sandy's feelings.
Because of this I'm angry with you,
and I don't want to speak to you.
I felt nervous and threw everything on you.
You are my most important friend.
I'm sorry, Lassie...
I want to see your face again...
Lassie, I'd do anything for you!
Lassie, you...
What's up, Bingo?
What? Where are you going?
Uh?
From here?
Oh...!
What? John, are you here?
Wait, I will help you now!
What is that?
Eat...
...as an apology for that day...
Sandy, you're absent today also...
Apology? For what?
As I expected...
By the way, John,
I took a vacation because
of a pain in my stomach.
Why do you got me something to eat?
Can't you eat it?
I thought you had a fever like Colin!
No problem, I can eat it later!
John, I don't care much about
what happened yesterday.
Okay!
Lassie, do you remember this?
When we first met, there was a plane flying!
That plane returned again!
I wonder if I can fly with it?
Next episode:
"Princess Of The Sky".
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams