OldCastle and South Wind Subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Walk towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
In my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
watch over you always,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari
a neverending story
Princess From The Sky
Good evening. Oh?
Who are you?
Why are you inside Sam's house?
What are you talking about?
Sam Carraclough's
house is next door.
Oh.
Coming!
I'll be damned. Is it you, George?
I've been away for a moment
and look how much you've grown.
You were just a baby
last time we met.
Excuse me, sir, but haven't you
confused me with someone else?
Have I made a mistake again?
My name's John, not George.
Let me think. John, John…
I'm pretty sure that Sam Carraclough's
son was named George…
Oh? I guess that's me.
But I'm John.
Oh? Mr. Dohan.
It's been ages, Melissa!
Sam is upstairs.
I'll call him in a moment.
How do I put it…
Oh, what a wonderful dog!
Its hair is absolutely splendid!
What brings you here?
Well…
At this hour, on top of it.
Am I being a nuisance?
No, no.
Really? Thank goodness.
I'm glad to hear it.
Who is this guy?
I feel like I had seen
him somewhere.
What are you talking about?
He's the director of the mine.
What?
That man, such a big shot?
Yes.
Don't judge people
from the way they look.
Naturally, don't judge them
by their job titles alone either.
So the question is when?
Well…
It was all decided so quickly.
I just got a call.
They'll come by plane tomorrow
and begin the inspection at 11 o'clock.
It's very sudden.
I know, right?
Which is why I came to talk.
By plane?
An airplane.
I wonder who's arriving?
Hey, Lassie.
Speaking of airplanes…
Do you remember that one?
That's right.
When we met for the first time,
there was an airplane as well.
So awesome.
Hey, stay away from the bike!
Hey, don't do that!
It's not mine, you know!
Hey, it's a…
What is it doing here?
Whose dog is it?
Here you are.
Come on, come here…
All's good now.
Are you okay?
If it wasn't for that airplane,
we might never have met.
To think that such a small puppy
could grow into such a large
Rough Collie in just one year.
You've grown into
one big sleepyhead, though.
The sky, huh…
I wish I could fly in the sky
some day, even if just once.
Now I remembered
who was on that plane…
Who was that girl?
Hey, Lassie…
Oh, you're so boring.
Why do I have to do this?
Good grief.
I wish we had a red carpet
for these situations…
It'll be fine.
As long as we're polite
and the place is clean.
No, no, no.
I saw in the newspaper
that movie theaters do that.
They roll the carpet out
and welcome the top brass on it…
What are those notes?
Put them away!
They're so unsightly.
There's quite a commotion above.
What's going on?
One of the stakeholders is coming.
The director never shows his face
around the office nor the shaft,
and look how flustered he is today.
Why is he licking someone's shoes?
You goof. The director has his
own superiors that can fire him.
He's just like us.
You're forgetting that he
doesn't have any rights to the mine.
The owners, huh?
Whatever, just help me
push this monster!
John!
It's rare to see you here
so early on a weekend.
Huh?
Are you here to
help us with Lassie?
No, not really.
"No, not really", he says.
Lassie is a good sheepdog.
She'll help us out, right?
Lassie is Lassie.
I am me.
Don't be like that.
Here, take this.
What do you want me to do?
This little lamb always gets lost.
Can you look after it?
I'd rather look at the sky.
The sky?
Oh, Lord. Will be really fine
without any red carpets?
Let's pretend you are serious.
Where do you expect to find it?
What if you run
to the nearest store?
What? Right now?
What kind of store?
It'll be fine.
It's just an ordinary place of work.
He expects to see
no less, and no more.
Yes, yes, but still…
Ah! Sam, Sam!
Yes?
That is no good.
That is no good at all.
We can't have him
do that out in the open!
What a drag.
Bansen.
Eh?
This is my fuel.
I know you're good at your job
no matter how much you drink,
but if you don't mind, go someplace
where nobody can see you.
Pff.
– He's here already?
– Yeah.
That rich bastard.
It's here!
It's coming here.
What's that?
Who's flying it?
I don't know.
It's the same airplane.
Oh?
Isn't it going to land?
I see.
The sheep are blocking their way.
Lassie!
Hey, buddy. Move.
Ah, I understand.
Bingo!
Gather the sheep!
Move. Move!
I'm telling you to move, dammit.
– Wait!
– Get back here!
No! Go back!
Hey!
What are going to do now?
Really…
I am going to the mine, Priscilla.
Head back to the mansion before me.
Oh? Are you not going
to take me with you?
I am only going to verify whether
my employees are doing their jobs properly.
You go play with your new horse.
My grandfather is always like that,
not caring an ounce about people's feelings.
I saw you from above.
You are the one who gathered the sheep
so that we could land. Thank you.
It is time for us to leave, milady.
If it were not for this dog,
we would not be able to land.
We should thank it properly.
Does this pasture
belong to that town?
Hm? A town?
Oh, over there?
I should pay attention to my
surroundings more closely.
Are you living there?
Good dog.
It is time to go, milady.
You are right.
See you!
It's following us.
You're such a troublemaker.
In the end I didn't see
the plane landing.
Lassie?
Lassie… Is she that girl?
I see.
Last time I checked,
we weren't soldiers.
The owner is a general,
and we're his army.
Hmph!
This is too much. We pulled
everyone away from their work.
I thought cleaning the place
would be enough.
I'd never guess
he'd ask everyone to line up.
What an idiot.
How do you like it, milady?
It's nice, but a bit boring.
Oh, I was referring
to this beautiful horse.
I have groomed his coat for hours
just for you, milady.
His coat is beautiful, I admit.
But can he run?
Of course he can, yes!
If you like, he can even gallop.
All right, let me try it!
Wh-Where are you going?
To the town!
But the weather
is about to get worse!
Ah, dammit.
She seriously thinks he can gallop that far?
She doesn't know the first thing about horses.
I don't care if she
has to go back on her feet.
Hm?
Come on, it's okay, alright?
It's just for a bit.
No, it's not okay.
We are leaving immediately
once the inspection is over.
But you could take me for a quick flight
around the area while you're waiting!
No means no, lad!
What's the problem?
You old skinflint!
What did you say?
Say it again!
Let's run for it, Lassie!
Why did Heinz lie to me?
You can't run well.
It was too early for you.
But that brown dog
could run so well…
We're almost at the town.
Let's go slowly.
Oh?
The houses stay one behind another,
without any opening.
How does one
get inside the town?
All I wanted was
just one short trip.
Whatever. Let's take a nap.
Are those the houses
of the mine employees?
I wonder where is
the shepherd's house.
It's raining…
We can't go anywhere like this.
Where was it…
Oh?
That was the last one
I got from Colin.
Come here, Mr. Hedgehog.
I won't do anything bad.
It got bigger.
Are you going already?
Ah!
Your voice is so loud.
You're the girl from that plane!
Found it.
Wanna eat it?
Yes.
I'm finally back.
Group II is operating back again.
Good work.
I'm so glad that I got here
before the rain got stronger.
So much mud…
Yes, work piles up as usual.
In addition, the director
is all trembling.
He's in the next room,
looking like he's going to black out.
I'm so tired.
He urged the owner to come visit us
with his granddaughter next time.
Oh? His granddaughter?
The Radling's pride and joy,
his cute granddaughter.
I can't imagine how spoiled
that girl must be.
Do you like it?
Yes, it's very sweet.
That's great.
It's the best candy in Colin's store.
Colin's?
Yes, they have a store
near the town square.
The only place to sell candy
in this town is at his family's store.
They also have jam
and canned goods.
So it's a candy store?
Yes. But they also sell medicines,
seeds and work as a post office.
A busy place.
Yes. They also do the deliveries
and take requests.
Even today Colin couldn't play
with me because of the work.
Oh…
I feel sorry for him.
Nah.
Colin likes to work
around the store.
When there are no customers,
he just reads his favorite books.
I see. He likes reading, doesn't he?
Yes, he reads a lot.
His favorite are adventure books.
He always begins with these.
What made you laugh?
Because Colin's…
Whenever someone enters the store,
he gets freaked out and tries to hide the book.
It's just too funny to look at.
Why does he hide the books?
Colin likes the books to the point
where he reads the ones sold in the store.
So he thinks it's bad to read the goods
he sells in front of the customers.
But no one cares about it, really.
I have recently borrowed one of
those adventure books from him.
It was fun, although
some parts were difficult.
What kind of book?
"Five Weeks in a Balloon"
by Jules Verne.
When I read it, I thought, "this is it",
and I wish I could fly in the sky some day.
You came here
by an airplane, right?
Yes.
I don't have an airplane.
But I know a place where it feels
like you can almost touch the sky.
Where is it?
It's called Rocky Castle.
– Rocky Castle?
– That's right.
It's to the south of our town,
far in the moorland.
It's a large rock formation
that looks like a castle.
When you reach the top of it,
you can see the whole sky.
Damn.
When I think about it, it would be my fault
if she fell off the horse and hurt herself.
She's traveled that far?
Milady. Milady!
Oh, no, he is already here.
Please stop kidding around.
I will get punished, too.
Okay!
I'll be right back!
Hey, just a moment.
I have to go now.
Open your hand.
Come on, just do it.
Like this?
Cover it with your other hand
so that it doesn't escape.
Something's moving!
You can see it now.
It looks like a gem, doesn't it?
It really does.
It is more beautiful than any jewel.
Milady!
See you!
I am sorry, Heinz,
I gave you trouble again.
Oh, no.
Look who just got up.
She's already gone.
Oh?
I just realized
I still don't know her name…
I forgot to ask his name.
That brown dog.
It's with him?
What are you saying, milady?
We have to go back
before I get fired.
Yes. I understand.
Trouble, trouble!
Lassie, that girl's here.
She came to my house!
Oh? She's already getting along
well with Sandy and Mom.
But something's odd.
How did she know where I live?
Next episode:
"Our First Cake".
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams