THE FIRST CAKE WE MAKE
Doesn't seem to be in good health...
Miss!
Yes?
Do I equip the car?
So, do that!
- Bring lots of milk!
- Yes!
I have many questions to ask.
But how do I go to the village?
I can't count on Heinz.
It makes me go away.
Something like that...
The car may be suitable...
Oh?
Are you looking for apricot jam?
I ate it at London, at Dennis' house,
it was delicious!
Mhm...
There is apricot jam here,
but this is the only one.
Not this.
It's not this brand.
Is that right...?
If you tell me who is the manufacturer,
then I can order it.
I don't recall who the manufacturer is,
but if I look at the brand myself
I will remember it.
Is that right?
- Also...
- Hm?
If we order it from abroad,
it will take several weeks, right?
I would have liked it
if my grandfather had tried it once.
Do you want to check for in the store?
Oh really? I'll be happy!
Thank you, Leighton!
This is not something big.
I'll go off...
Is there anything else you want?
I'll go and see it.
Uh... Will you go alone?
I'm big enough enough to go alone.
I just wanted to travel in the car.
I know!
I don't have to travel on the seat!
The important thing is to go to the village!
This way I can go anywhere in the village.
Dad, it's a car!
There is a car parked in front of our store!
It's a car from the palace.
Welcome Mr. Cook!
I can guess what you need.
Today my order is different.
I want to show me all kinds
of apricot jam you have.
Huh?
Ah...?
You're Colin, aren't you?
I know you because of this book.
Uh?
Hm, this is confusing!
I have to ask Miss for its exact shape.
Will you allow me to call her?
You mean the palace?
I will turn you to them.
I depend on you.
Hm?
Not possible!
To be in such a place...
A brown dog.
It's beautiful and lively!
As I mention its name...
It was...
Lassie?
Right, right! Lassie!
Was it named Lassie then?
What is the name of the owner of that dog?
John.
I understood, I finally know his name!
Lassie and John.
Sorry, I... am going now...
So, what do you want to show me about John's house?
But I'm...
Please.
If you go on that path you
will find two straight roads.
If you go to the left road,
you'll find adjacent houses
belonging to the mine.
I know it.
Those continuous descent that resemble.
I see.
What about the house number?
Eh... house number... as I recall... is...
The houses are really similar.
Does John live here?
You don't know his name or address,
yet you go to him! So strange...
She's definitely curious.
Okay!
Who are you? And what do you
want from John? Oh?
Sorry, I did something?
Uh... No, nothing.
- This place?
- Yes.
I wonder if John is here?
John is in the backyard!
What? What a nice Miss!
Do you know her, Colin?
Uh uh... uh...
Aah... um... um...
Goodbye!
Oh? What a strange boy!
By the way, who are you?
Your friend came!
Who is it?
She's a girl!
Sandy?
It's not her.
A long hair blonde miss.
Eh?
Where is she?
I asked her to enter.
She is waiting for you on the couch
in the living room.
Could it be?
Did she really knew my house?
Hey hey hey!
This is dangerous, you will fall!
Ah!
Ay!
Ah ah ah...
Ah ah...
Look at yourself...
I told you!
Ah!
I knew it!
Wait! I'll change my clothes!
Hey John!
What's up, Lassie?
Ah...!
We met again, Lassie!
Your name is Lassie, isn't it?
I don't know how you got to know each other.
Lassie will host you until John
comes, please excuse me!
This host is my favorite!
What is that? Does that girl know me as well?
She's definitely curious!
That girl is mysterious...
Ah...
Uh...
My heart is still beating faster...
Hm...
She's not in the palace.
As I expected that girl is definitely Miss.
Oh, the kid who was in the food store!
Oh!
Have you seen a girl in blue clothes?
Eh...
She is between 11 and 12 years old.
If you know, tell me!
Where is she, kid?
Ah...
Did not this person here?
Oh! Wait!
Ah...!
I said wait!
Why did he flee?
Maybe he knows!
In there!
Wait!
Why does this uncle chase me?
I haven't done anything!
Why is this child running away from me?
Oh, at a time like this...
What to do? I can't remove it!
I'll enter, John!
No, no, don't!
You should wash it with warm water.
Look!
Oh? What is that?
Hello!
I brought eggs and cream!
Hey Lassie!
I don't seem to know you very well.
Eh?
How did you know that Miss?
What is her name?
About this... she...
Such thing doesn't matters!
Mhm...
Right! Right!
As expected from John!
John still acts like a child!
True true, when we went to the canal...
Thank you!
Hello!
I see, then she is your friend, Sandy?
She's wrong, isn't she?
We just got to know each other.
Isn't it?
Oh?
So, this is what happened!
Was it surprising?
Well...
What? He finally came out!
Hello John!
Colin told me about your home.
So then...
Sorry, that's this...
...at that time...
Mhm!
Hey Sandy!
What? Why are you here?
Bad smell! Bad smell!
You smell like paint, John!
Eh?
Is that right?
Isn't it, Lassie?
Do you want to prepare cakes
when you are on holiday?
I asked Sandy to come,
and bring eggs and cream.
Cakes?
Good idea! Because we have guests!
Wait!
It's not a good idea!
What do you mean?
It's your fault.
Right right...
John's clothes are dirty because of the paint
and they must be washed immediately.
Eh?
I'll wash it, so make the cakes, Mom!
There is nothing wrong.
It will be made by someone else.
Isn't it, Sandy?
Isn't it, Aunt?
What does that mean?
Sandy told me she would make the cake!
What about you, Priscilla? You too!
Me?
But I haven't made cakes before...
Don't worry, I'll teach you!
She does what she always wants!
What do you mean?
But you know what I mean.
You are always with your owner, right?
You are lucky!
That's it!
I'll go to wash clothes.
I will look forward to the cake you will make!
Me too?
Can't you make it while you are three?
That would be more fun!
Mhm...
Yes, I understand!
And John will light up the fireplace!
Yes!
- Priscilla, an egg!
- Yes!
Priscilla!
Oh?
Separate the glair from the yolk!
How to do it?
Look at me!
Do it like this!
Eh, just awesome!
What do I do with this?
Give it to me!
So...!
Just awesome!
- Mix water and milk!
- Yes!
Well, that is good!
Do you want to try?
Yes!
I have ignited the fireplace!
Is that right? Thank you!
Sorry, what do I do now?
No, don't move your hand like this!
Look, I'll do this again!
Yes teacher, do this for me!
Do it until it appears in the form of horns.
Horns? Like cow horns?
Look, here are the horns, Priscilla!
Really!
That girl is Priscilla.
So, we will wait until it is baked!
Yes!
I enjoyed making cakes with you!
Have you finished?
Yes!
Oh... I remembered!
What food should I feed this?
Oh... This...
Pour water and sugar on cotton.
Water and sugar?
But it is unfortunate that you put it
in such a narrow place.
Is that right?
Tell me how to put it, John.
Yes!
First to prepare arable soil...
...then it is better to plant a tree in it, then...
He stopped running away...
I can't run anymore...
Me too...
Ah...!
How does it looks?
Good appetite!
I'm back!
Oh?
Beautiful smell...
- Welcome back!
- Welcome!
Mm...
It's nice to come back and
find such a fine smell!
Here it is!
Chiffon cake!
Looks delicious!
Your mother made it?
No no!
But these two girls made it.
- Sorry for the intrusion!
Sorry, I...
Sam, to complete our conversation...
Oh?
I wonder what this smell is?
It's a cake!
I'll take one piece.
Ah!
Who is this uncle?
It's delicious!
As I expected the Duke brought
his granddaughter with him!
He will visit us again!
Oh!
I don't want it!
That place is not for the children to see!
I seem to have come out of my way.
This is because I grew unconscious.
Oh...
John...!
Colin also came!
We have a lot of guests!
Please enter!
John, I brought a strange man with me...
Hm?
Who is the stranger?
It's your fault because
you didn't listen to me!
Leighton! What are you doing here?
How do you say that?
I hope you stop kidding.
You hid in the car.
What if you were abducted
or something like that?
It will be a big problem!
I'm sorry!
That's it...
You have to go?
I'm the worst because I did what I wanted.
I have made Leighton pass a difficult time.
You're not bad... Priscilla.
Thank you.
Thanks for this!
Ah... thanks!
Lassie...
Thanks to your looks I have
identified many people.
Thank you!
Sandy, thank you for telling me
how to make cookies!
Yes!
John...
I'll take good care of that thing you gave me.
That thing?
The little jewel...
Oh...
Colin, thank you!
Yes!
- That's it.
- Yes.
Priscilla!
I apologize for what happened today.
Well, let's go from here.
Yes.
Priscilla...
Didn't eat any piece of cake...
Yes...
Wait a moment!
Where did I heard the name of Priscilla?
Priscilla... Priscilla...
Ah! Too bad!
What is the matter?
How do I explain this?
The granddaughter of the
mine owner is called Priscilla!
- Ah?
- Eh?
If that girl...
True, that uncle came from that palace!
Ah...
It's bad, I seem to have said
something very terrible...
What a job you did, John!
You just heard the talk?
I know Priscilla's house.
- You should taste a piece of this cake!
- Yes!
Priscilla will return tonight to Scotland.
Even though she has good friends...
I know!
Let's all go to the Rocky Castle!
I want you to see places
you haven't seen before!
Next episode:
PRISCILLA, LAST SELFISHNESS
Be sure to watch!