OldCastle and South Wind Subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Walk towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
In my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
watch over you always,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari
a neverending story
Priscilla, Last Selfishness
Well, I'm done!
I won't lose!
Sandy is very happy!
She is riding the bike on her own.
You both have to hurry a little!
I'll arrive to the palace before you!
Well, I understand that you
want to go there quickly!
Colin!
Do you still think about
what happened yesterday?
Yes…
It's not your fault, Colin,
because Priscilla left my house.
Yes…
No, if I wouldn't come to you quickly,
Priscilla could have the cake with you!
You had no other choice!
And also we do this now,
Priscilla can eat the cake she made herself!
Yes…
But…
Enough, no "but"!
John! Colin!
What do you do?
John, you still have the cake,
so I can't go alone!
Now let's go!
Yes!
Just a moment!
Don't move too much
so you don't spoil the cake!
Ah oh!
Ah!
Hey!
It'll be fine! It'll be fine!
Tonight?
Right!
I'm still on vacation from school!
The schedule changed.
If you say so…
Tonight at 9 o'clock, the plane
will come to pick you up.
Stay in your room now and wait.
That 's all, for now.
Grandfather!
What is the matter?
Why didn't you returned to your room?
Grandfather, you've always told me
that there are no sudden orders
for no reason, have you forgotten?
Oh…
This is true.
If you think I'm listening to you directly and
without checking the cause, you're wrong.
But I will follow your orders
when you tell me the reason.
I'm not your dog or your horse, grandfather.
You are the only one who always responds
to my orders, you are impressive!
I'm honored to impress you!
It's an honor to pay tribute
to your Guy Funeral of Mr. Denver.
I don't think there is a better way than this
to express my gratitude to him!
Priscilla!
Yes!
You are an important Duke.
You must attend the funeral.
That's why you should come back,
did you understand?
Yes!
You can return as long as you know why.
This means…
Grandfather?
What is the matter?
If you do not mind,
can I leave my room because
there is no reason to stay there?
Hm…?
Ah!
This is true.
So, during the day, I can go anywhere!
Mhm…
That's it, my grandfather!
Hm…
I always wanted to take care of you,
but I can't do that as long as
I have to go back to Scotland.
My grandfather is like my father now.
I should therefore pay tribute
to the aristocrats there.
I want to spend my childhood more.
But I still have today!
Heinz!
Do you want to get out of the palace again?
I'll go to the village.
Eh?
Don't worry!
Today I'll go walking.
I won't bother you again.
But this…
It's better not to leave.
Why?
I'm afraid you won't be able
to go to Scotland tonight.
But there is still time.
But something else might happen
like yesterday…
This way the plane will be delayed.
I won't be late, I'll come back.
Ah… oh…
Of course, I don't doubt your words, Miss!
What if… an emergency happens?
In the end I'm the one responsible.
I hope you think about those
people who can fool you.
I see!
I won't bother you anymore!
Miss!
This is much better!
Just awesome!
The door of the house is very far away!
No doubt it is here.
Because my dad comes here
to deliver the goods sometimes.
It doesn't open!
Maybe someone will come out if we shout!
Excuse me!
Is Priscilla here?
Is it anyone?
Excuse me!
What? What?
Don't make noise in front of the door!
Sorry… Hello!
We came to see Priscilla!
Hm!
It's not tactful to call the princess
of this house by her name!
You should call her Miss Priscilla!
What to do?
Should I call her Miss Priscilla?
Strange, this is really strange!
What is so funny?
Priscilla is Priscilla, isn't it?
What does this man mean?
Yes, that's right!
Pff! You are just tiring!
And now, leave!
Miss is very busy!
Wait!
We came to see Priscilla!
Miss doesn't have time
to meet people like you!
Now, go back quickly!
But we are…
We want to give this cake to Priscilla!
Hey, you can't do what you want!
Ah…!
If you stay here…
Although it's the cake that
Priscilla made by herself…
W-w-what?
As if I would believe it!
Get back quickly! Go go!
She can't meet the children of the village!
Hm! You can never…!
What is this guy talking about?
It's terrible!
Yes…
Lassie, what's up?
Ah…!
It's Priscilla!
What are you doing there?
Lassie!
All of you, have you come to me?
Priscilla!
I thought we wouldn't
be able to see you again!
You exaggerate…
What do you think?
Delicious!
That doorman whose eyes look like this!
He is the one who destroyed it!
Do you mean Heinz?
Looks like…
This is not funny!
I'll make him pay for the cake!
Pay the price?
How?
This…
Oh?
Uh?
Miss! How did that happen?
Ah…!
How did you get out?
Please wait!
Miss!
Whoa!
What did you do, Miss?
What do you want?
Did you think I was the Miss?
Huh…
I just saw just before!
John! Priscilla! Colin!
How did it go?
Everything was perfect!
He came to me and when he fell into the trap
he looked at me in the way
you didn't look at him!
His face was like this!
Even a ghost doesn't have a face like him!
I always wanted to wear such clothes!
Me too!
I also like these clothes!
Eh?
Oh really?
I love the smell of sunny straw!
Yes!
Why does everyone like the other dress?
It's a mystery.
Listen, Priscilla!
Let's plan what we'll today!
Right!
I want to see Moi!
John said there was a rock
that looked like a castle!
What?
But… Moi is too far from here.
Can't we do that today?
Not so, however…
I want to see it!
If we go now to our castle
we will reach it at sunset.
I'm concerned about the return.
Is there no shortcut?
Are you searching for a coal car track?
That bridge is there.
It's scary…
Hm…
I see…
You're a boy, aren't you?
But I will do my best.
But Priscilla can't…
Okay!
Well, let's go to Moi!
We decided!
Oh!
Priscilla, no problem to go!
The road will be fine
as long as it passed.
Eh…
Damn!
Priscilla!
Are you okay?
Yes, I am fine!
I'm fine because I'm getting used to it!
What is it, Lassie?
Ah… Colin!
Uh… uh-uh…
I can't…
Ahh…
Are you okay?
Don't look down!
Oh!
Let's go together!
First of all…
One two three!
One! Two!
Are you okay, Colin?
He's fine!
One! Two!
Look! Priscilla!
What is it? I can see it!
With the sun shining brightly!
Ah…!
This is our secret place!
We are playing here.
Catching the names near here!
From today, Priscilla will become
our friend in the Rocky Castle!
Thank you!
I'm very happy!
I understand how you feel in this place.
John and the others, you are tempted every day!
Nager?
It's not like we're building
or something like that!
You are lucky.
I can't imagine all this!
Now you can imagine everything!
Right!
Yes…
That's right, I can do that now…
That means it's your first adventure!
Tomorrow is another adventure!
Will you leave?
The sun began to fall!
Yes.
I can't go on an adventure tomorrow.
- Oh?
- Eh?
What's up, Priscilla?
I want to climb up.
Up? Do you want to climb
to the top of the rock?
Right now?
Yes.
But…
If we do that, the night will fall!
But the sun is still bright!
We can still climb to the top today!
Please John, Sandy, Colin! Lassie!
Yes.
It's not possible? I thought…
We should return before it's getting late.
Priscilla…
Could you come tomorrow…
I want to climb!
I still want climb to the top today.
Don't worry about such a ridiculous thing!
Okay!
Climb to the top as long as the sun is shining!
Here we are!
Do you usually climb through here?
I'll go first!
You follow me!
Yes!
What to do?
The sun and sweating are the best!
Uh uh… Wait!
Priscilla, do you follow me?
There is still another way!
Priscilla, grab my hand!
Do your best, a little more!
Ah…!
Whoa!
The horizon looks like a red ribbon!
I'm happy!
And finally I was able to see it
for the last time!
The last time?
Yes.
I have to go back to Scotland tonight.
You said Scotland?
Will you leave?
There is my real home.
There is no large place like this,
or flowers, or big rocks like this…
But there are many things waiting for me…
But I wanted to play together tomorrow
and go on an adventure like this…
Priscilla?
Come here again!
Yes, certainly, and with all of you!
I thought we should return to
where Sandy's bike was left.
Yes, that's right!
But they'll will punish us!
Eh…!
You too!
You don't know where your home is, and
your parents, they're worried about you!
Yes!
Troublemaker!
Oh, anyway, kids usually do things like that…
A traveling man accompanied
by a scoundrel came to our village!
This uncle is very good!
He became very famous in the village
because we liked him.
But… that night…
Next episode:
"Who Caused The Fire".
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams