Old Castle & south wind subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Keep walking towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
Back in my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
would beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
always watch over you,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari
a neverending story
Who Caused The Fire?
What's that, John?
You can do better!
Go faster!
Lassie's gonna get ahead of us!
Told you…
I'm at my limit.
Lassie's so far already…
What's up, Toots?
Oh, who do we have here?
Huh?
Lassie.
Are you the owner
of this big fellow?
I am.
Who are you, mister?
I reached an intersection
and wondered which way to go…
So much that I fell asleep.
All right, then.
Time to introduce ourselves
to our new audience.
Audience?
We're not your audience… I think?
I'm sorry to hear that.
Right, Toots?
Oh, my goodness!
Toots is so sad,
his heart is about to break!
Quick, someone come here
and ease his grief!
Awesome!
Thank you.
This guy is my partner.
Name's Toots.
And over there
is my other partner.
Her name is Beth.
Her specialty is pulling the carriage.
That leaves me. I'm Rolly.
By the way, how good
is the bakery in your town?
Bakery? I guess it's pretty good.
Are you serious?
Mr. Rice's bakery is the best.
Oh?
That's true.
He's helped by his daughter Mary,
the prettiest girl in the whole town!
All right, it's settled.
I've decided where
I'm going today.
Ain't that right, Toots?
Finally it's over.
Let's go for a drink tonight.
Oh? You're still busy with
the deliveries at this hour?
You work harder than we do.
John? Sandy?
Lassie, too?
What are they doing?
Isn't that amazing, Lassie?
Wanna try it too?
And for the next show…
We're going to have
one of you lend a hand.
Let's see…
How about that pretty lady over there?
Think you can do it?
Yes, yes.
Who else could I have in mind
when I called for a "pretty lady"?
Oops.
Here, please hold this.
Like this?
Perfect. You're skilled at this!
Go, Toots.
Ladies and gentlemen,
that was my partner, Toots,
and this cute miss.
Let's have a round of applause for them.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
I invite you to take a look at my stand.
We sell all sorts of
cooking utensils and pans.
Let's go, let's go!
Good doggie.
Thank you for your purchase.
– I'd like this one.
– Thanks.
Rolly is doing business
while traveling all around England.
I wish I could go
to many places like him.
Yeah…
Oh, I forgot, I forgot, I forgot!
I've almost forgotten
the most important thing.
Can you buy me some bread?
Sure. Lassie?
Let's go.
We're going to the bakery.
Hey, mister!
How can you leave
your stand like that?
I am so sorry, but we're
sold out of the bread for today.
– Not even one?
– Unfortunately.
We'll have a new batch
ready for tomorrow morning.
I understand…
That's a bit of a problem.
You don't have bread for tonight?
No.
It's not for us.
It's for Rolly.
Rolly?
Ah, that man
with the acrobatic puppy?
The cheers were so loud we could
hear them all the way down here.
He came to our town because I told him
that we have a great bakery.
Really?
Mary!
There's nothing to sell anymore.
Come here and help me
around the stove.
Yes, yes.
Tell me, is he going
to stay here overnight?
Mary!
Tell him to come here tomorrow morning.
We'll give him a nice fresh bread.
Okay.
I see.
That's too bad.
Soft and fresh bread is a delight
to the taste buds and the soul alike.
Besides, there's the beautiful girl
you told me about.
Very well.
I'll stay here till tomorrow.
But what are you going to do?
You have nowhere to stay.
It's likely nothing to be proud of,
but I don't have a house at all.
So, like what? You're
sleeping in the stables?
No, nothing of the sort.
I'm a vagabond.
And it's great!
I sleep under
a beautiful starry sky.
Above us is the Milky Way,
a brilliant path made of light.
And I sleep right under it.
Ain't that right, Toots?
The starry sky, huh…
They look like they're
about to fall down.
That's kind of scary.
Yeah…
You must have traveled
to many places.
You mean me?
I guess. Right, Toots?
Manchester, Glasgow, Newcastle,
and also Liverpool.
But no matter where I went,
I went to nameless towns and villages only.
I like places like these the most.
For example, even if
I sleep outdoors tonight,
I feel relieved as I'm surrounded
by houses with people.
Behind every dimly lit window
there is a happy family.
When I think of it,
I get this warm and gentle feeling,
and I feel like I'm home myself.
But Mr. Rice is very short-tempered
and always yells at everyone.
No, no.
You shouldn't say such things.
He's right.
Oh?
It's Sandy.
I see you too have a nose
for delicious things.
I'm telling you, Beth.
This tastes amazing.
Really-really?
Really-really.
But I need to say,
this is one venerable old pot.
It'll serve for many years
if it gets patched up a little.
Your mother keeps
her dishes very well, Sandy.
Huh?
But that pot is mine.
I got it from my late grandma
when I was little.
I took care of it the best I could.
So, the one who made
this delicious soup was…
Me.
I see. Forgive me my insolence.
Well, now you know.
Right, Toots?
How are things over there?
Have you seen any shooting stars?
Not really…
Ah!
There is one!
Eh? Where?
Where, where?
It's gone already.
I saw it!
I really saw it!
A shooting star… Uh…
Hmph.
Making a campfire
in a place like this?
What if it gets out of control?
For crying out loud.
All right, kids, time for you
to go to your homes.
But we're having so much fun.
Each of you has a warm house with
their mom and dad waiting for you, right?
If you play for too long in the evenings,
you'll end up homeless like me.
See you tomorrow, then.
Will you do a show
tomorrow again?
Toots says he'd like
to show you some more tricks.
– Bye!
– Good night.
Bye.
Let's go, Lassie.
Looks like that big fellow
took a liking in you, Toots.
All right.
All done, Toots.
Let's go to sleep.
Oh my God!
Fire!
Damn!
It's fire!
Everyone! It's fire!
Wake up!
Oh? What about the fire?
Oh, it's near my house!
Water… We need water! Damn!
Faster!
This looks serious.
Coming.
Sandy!
I'm here with the milk.
Good morning.
Oh? But we have
enough milk, sweetheart.
This time it's
for someone else, though.
Listen, Rolly will appreciate some milk
to go with the bread, don't you think?
Ah, right.
You want to meet Toots
as well, don't you, Lassie?
Who could it be
so early in the morning?
– Colin?
– John!
Something bad happened.
Rolly… Rolly is in trouble!
What happened?
How many times
do I need to tell you?
I put out the campfire
before I went to sleep.
So where did that fire
come from, huh?
Let's stay calm, Mr. Rice.
This man worked hard
to extinguish the fire.
Thanks to him the fire
didn't reach the houses.
So because he extinguished the fire
he himself had started, it's all good?
Besides, he came out of nowhere
supposedly to sell some pots and pans.
Don't think we will
let you off the hook like this.
Hey, hey…
What do you want to do?
Father!
Father, you always told me that...
...we should treat every customer who
comes to buy our bread well.
This man is our—
You've got to be kidding me. I make bread
for the people of our town first and foremost.
I don't sell to…
to nefarious individuals like him.
Father!
You agree with me, right?
I don't know about your bread, but
starting fire is inexcusable, accident or not.
There you have it. We need to protect
the lives of the people in our town.
We're going to have to ask you
to leave our town immediately.
Any objections?
I'm going to tell this once more.
I didn't set the fire.
Nope, there's no doubt it was you.
Listen. We're doing you a favor,
as we didn't involve the police yet.
But you must leave.
I see that much.
Looks like there's no talking to you.
See? I knew it.
I'd like you
to understand one thing.
I sell pots and kettles,
because I have to eat something, too.
But the reason I travel is because I like
to make people smile with Toots' acrobatics.
Good bye.
Rolly!
Are you leaving?
I have no other choice.
But…
No "buts".
Thank you for the soup.
It was delightful, darling.
It's fixed…
The bakery owner wants me to leave
to protect the village… Oh, the irony.
Let's meet again some day.
Rolly…
He's gone.
I don't know if it was
the lamp or something else,
but it was so close to our house
that it almost burned because of it.
Father…
A lamp?
Something else?
Hm?
What's the big idea, Colin?
Just do what I asked, John!
So I just knock on that door?
Yes.
J-John, what do we do?
What?
You need to ask?
Mr. Rice is so scary.
That's all?
Excuse me, Mr. Rice…
What? If you are here for the bread,
we are not ready yet.
Because of the fire,
the oven has cooled down by now.
It'll take some time.
Quick, he's going away.
Excuse me, Mr. Rice…
What? I'm busy.
Colin wants to ask you something.
Uh, well, it's…
Spit it out already!
You tell him, John.
You're for real?!
Yes.
Are you serious?
Both lamp and the campfire
were put out before 11 o'clock?
Yes.
What?
At any rate, we have a witness. Colin was
looking through the window and saw it clearly.
Why a child would stay up
until so late at night?
Uh…
I was trying to see the meteors…
Which is why…
What do you mean, meteors?
If you raise your voice,
you will scare the children!
Either way, Mr. Rolly
put out the lamp
and extinguished the campfire
with water from a pot.
Right?
Yes.
That means the fire must've been
caused by something else.
True.
If it was caused by
something else, that means…
Enough, just hurry up!
Can't you go any faster?
Don't distract me
while I'm driving.
But still, what should I
say to that man?
Apologize to him, naturally.
But I only thought of the safety
of the people of our town.
He ought to understand.
Don't make excuses, Father.
Just admit that we were at fault.
I had so much fun with Rolly.
Yeah.
What if we turn into a town
that nobody wants to come to?
That would be a bummer.
I wanted to talk
to Mr. Rolly a lot more.
Why the long face, Toots?
People should just laugh it off
in such an event.
Oh, but you're a dog.
What's wrong, Beth?
Why have you stopped?
Hey, hurry up, will you?
A ship is going
to come here any minute.
There he is!
It's Rolly's carriage!
Ah! But…
Rolly is going to cross the bridge!
Damn, the engine is done for.
Rolly!
Wait for us, John!
You too, Father.
Let's run with the children.
What's wrong, Beth?
I'd like to cross the bridge
and leave things behind.
I can't wait to meet
the people in the next town.
Come on, Beth!
Lassie?
What are you doing here?
Toots!
What?
Don't cross the bridge, Rolly.
My father…
My father wants you to stay, too.
Hey!
Don't go anywhere yet!
I see, so these children
have proven my innocence.
This is why the world is such an interesting
place to live in. Ain't that right, Toots?
I see, I see!
Sandy's poor cow was stolen.
We're searching for the thief.
The whole town joined the hunt.
But Sandy is acting weird.
Next episode:
"Sandy Is Stealing The Cows?"
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams