Old Castle & south wind subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Keep walking towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
Back in my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
would beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
always watch over you,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari
a neverending story
Sandy Is Stealing The Cows?
All right, Lassie.
I'm counting on you.
Oh? You're not going by yourself?
I have homework.
Geez...
I see.
You're here for the milk.
Thanks for coming,
but I'll have to disappoint you.
I'm sorry, Lassie.
I can't give you milk today.
Hm?
Oh? There's no milk.
Huh?
I thought she'd be okay going alone.
What is that?
A message?
What's it say?
That they're out of milk.
But they have that huge cow.
What a shame, the soup
won't be as tasty without it.
But there's nothing
we can do about it.
Oh? Where are you going?
To Sandy's.
I suppose the homework
will get done by itself.
Thank goodness, your cow is fine.
She is.
I was scared
she'd died or something.
No.
It's just…
You've grown up on the
milk from this very cow, you know.
But...
But?
Moo can't make milk anymore,
not a single drop.
What?
But she's feeding
her baby right there.
That's just Baby Moo trying her best
to squeeze a single drop.
I have no choice but to
feed her other cows' milk.
Even though her mother's milk
is her favorite.
We have no other choice.
You know that as well as I do,
don't you, Dad?
We've tried so many things…
It's exactly because we tried everything
we have to make a decision.
Keep your voice down, honey,
or you'll wake up the children.
Yes. There is also the matter
of what you are going to tell the children.
That cow is Sandy's favorite.
She learned how to
milk cows on Moo.
Yes. I still remember
how happy she was.
Enough with this drama!
I also worked hard for her.
No, that is…
Even children have
to grow up eventually.
Dad, have you grown
so senile it clouds your judgment?
N-No…
A cow is not a pet.
If it doesn't bring any profit,
we need to sell it.
If it doesn't give milk,
it only means extra expenses.
Yes… You're right.
I'll take it to the town
first thing in the morning.
Okay.
Can it at least wait until Sandy
goes to school? Please.
What to do? What to do?
Good morning.
Oh, good morning.
Did you hear the news?
What news?
Apparently there is
a cattle rustler in the area.
A cattle rustler?
There you have it, gentlemen.
My poor daughter loved the stolen cow so much
that she didn't want to eat at all today.
How can you be so sure
that it was a thief?
The barn door was locked from the outside
and was wide open this morning.
What are you suggesting?
That the cow magically opened the door
from the outside and escaped by itself?
No, somehow I don't think
that's what happened.
This is no laughing matter.
How can you be sure that
you're not the next target of this thief?
Let me just say, you better have a good proof
before you call someone a thief,
otherwise you'll just
make a fool of yourself.
I speak from experience.
Whoever it was,
they stole two cows from us!
We must catch them
and bring them to justice.
Or are you saying we should
let them do what they want?
Of course I'm not.
How about we do this,
if you find any evidence, let us know.
Then we'll help you out.
That's the best option.
For now it's just finger pointing.
We can't help him like that.
Damn.
Can I help you in any way, Sandy?
That looked pretty serious.
How can my Dad say that?
What?
That I was so sad
that I didn't want to eat and whatnot.
When in reality he water
trying to sell off poor Moo.
Huh? What are you talking about?
Under Henry VII's rule, trade and industry
were the backbone of England's strength.
He firmly believed that war was nothing
but an obstacle to the economic growth.
That led him to sign the Treaty of
Perpetual Peace with the Scotland…
Damn.
I don't need anybody's help!
Sandy, if there's something
we can do to help, just say so.
Yeah.
Really?
You really want to help me?
Of course.
We don't want you to be sad.
Can you keep a secret?
A secret?
Can you?
Y-Yes.
All right, I'll show you something.
Follow me.
John… Colin.
Yes?
Promise me that
you won't tell anybody.
Sandy, what's going on?
You're acting weird.
You've got to promise me, okay?
I promise.
I promise too.
Thanks. Now I can tell you
what is the big secret.
Okay?
It was a cow!
Can it… Can it be Moo?
Wait! Listen to me first.
But the thief…
The thief…
…was me all along.
What?
This is going to end very bad.
I know.
But I had no choice.
What are you going to do now?
I didn't think that far ahead.
I can't think of anything, either.
It's better to tell your father, Sandy.
We can't do that!
He said that she's useless
and that he's going to sell her.
So what if we can't come up
with any plan right now?
Let's just raise her ourselves!
Until we think of something.
What if we can't think of anything?
We will. We just will, trust me.
Sure.
Okay.
Tell them, Lassie.
The weather is so good today.
It's so nice to be off duty.
I can drink as much as I like.
– Am I doing this right?
– Yep.
Maybe she'll give milk again
if we graze her here?
It's possible, in theory…
But we tried it already
so many times.
We've just gotta try harder.
Okay.
What? You're sure it was a cow?
Yes, I also heard some people.
Alright then!
There you have it.
This is an undeniable lead.
Bansen will take us there.
Fine by me, but, you know…
This is bad.
We've got to do something.
What? Did I hear you right?
You're not sure where it was?
Oh, I was a little bit
drunk at the time…
Uh…
Why don't we figure it on our way?
Thank goodness.
Now's our only chance
to move Moo.
Let's go.
Wait a moment!
Me?
I'd like to ask you for help.
I'd like you and your dog
to go with Bansen and us.
How does that sound?
Any objections?
That's our best shot.
Let's do it.
Sandy! Wait!
If we don't hurry up,
they will get to her before us!
Hurry.
We must catch the thief
before he escapes us!
Is there really a thief?
This is getting weirder
by the minute.
Hey, all of you!
Can't you go faster?
Colin! Hurry up!
I'm sorry, Moo.
We must take you
somewhere else again.
Please, be good.
Moo…
This is the right way, right?
You're sure of it?
Yes. I think.
Lassie…
We're not going to let them
have their way, are we?
What's the matter, Moo?
She won't move…
Okay, listen close, Lassie.
We're going to lure them away.
Look!
Looks like they lost something.
Think it belongs to the thief?
No, no, that's…
That's actually mine.
I must've dropped it
here yesterday.
You lost such an important thing?
And you call yourself a drunk?
This is not the time to laugh.
Focus on the matter at hand!
Are we close?
I think so.
Now, where to…
Was it this way?
No, maybe it was that way…
Which was it…
This way!
Looks like Lassie
picked up some scent.
Right, Lassie?
Well done, John!
This way, this way!
They're going a different way!
John did something.
Now's our chance. Quick!
Please, move, Moo!
Lassie, no.
We have to lead them
as far away as possible.
Moo…
Please.
If we stay here,
my father will find us.
Don't you get it, Moo?
Don't you care what's going
to happen to you?
As expected,
she doesn't understand us at all.
That's not true!
Right, Moo?
Baby Moo…
Hey, if we go this way…
Jon! Wait a moment!
Huh?
There is no point in going further.
There is no way through.
Oh?
I don't know who the thief is,
but they couldn't move
the cows over that river.
Isn't it better to go back
to where we were before?
Yeah.
John…
Uh…
This way?
Follow me, everyone.
We can't go this way, Lassie!
And why is that?
The previous path was a dead end.
Don't go this way, Lassie…
Is this the place?
Oh? What is this place?
Amazing…
Wild grapes!
There's so much.
They'll make a splendid wine.
Leave the cow and the milk.
Look at this treasure.
Lassie.
Damn!
She's following,
she's following!
We should've done so
right from the start.
Stop it, Moo!
We have to hurry up.
Ah!
Oh?
Moo!
Sir, wait!
Wait!
Do you even understand
what you have done?
I just wanted…
I just wanted to save Moo.
I don't want you to sell her!
Sandy.
Do you think that I'm selling her
because I want to?
Moo helped our farm a great deal.
It's difficult for me to let go of her.
Please understand.
I don't want to!
If you don't want to sell her,
just don't do it!
I…
I hate you!
Sandy…
Sir, is there any way
for us to save Moo?
You think you're saving her?
What about you, kids?
You want the baby to die?
It is better to sell her
for Baby Moo's sake, too.
When she's near her mother, she does not
want to drink milk from other cows at all.
But is there nothing we can do?
That's just a lot.
That's just too much.
Hey, Lassie.
Same as usual.
The milk doesn't come out at all.
I see.
You're worried
about her too, aren't you?
Let's not stand around
here crying like this.
Sandy?
Sandy.
Lassie?
Hey!
You won't believe it!
It's Moo! She gave milk!
What's this?
Why's everyone in such a rush?
I don't believe it.
You did it!
I was looking everywhere
for these flowers.
When Sandy's father was born, we made her
eat them until her condition improved, too.
Is that a medicinal plant?
You could say that.
Moo…
You knew that?
Are you happy, Sandy?
Listen, Dad!
Next time she doesn't give milk,
just leave it to me, okay?
I will.
Father…
I'm sorry.
Dad saved a huge man
who was on the verge of death.
He is a hard worker and
is welcomed by everyone.
But when the police came to our town,
he's started to act strange.
What? He's a bank robber?
Next episode:
"Follow The Suspicious Man".
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams