John, I count on you for the rest!
Yes, I accompanied you to safety!
HURRY! SAVE DR. HOOPER
Yes!
Good morning, John!
Ah! Have you finished?
Good morning, Lassie!
Come on!
Show her!
Well!
Before everything,
I will give it to the aunt because
she taught me how to make it!
Nothing to me?
John's share is here, no need to worry!
Where's the aunt?
She went to work already!
Eh?
Don't worry!
We'll ask Lassie to deliver it!
I rely on you, Lassie!
Sandy, we'll be late!
Wait! Wait! Wait!
I apologize for making you wait!
Doctor, don't do it!
Be patient!
What is the matter?
I told you!
I have dealt with your wound now.
It would be bad if I didn't treat it.
If you don't come, your bones may break!
Eh... Please stop it!
Take care of yourself!
The next patient!
Doctor, my daughter is in bad shape today!
Doctor, please save her!
xxx
Calm down, what happened?
Her temperature suddenly rose!
Doctor!
Put her here!
Doctor, what's up?
It's not bad.
But it hurts a lot!
Because parents are upset
when the child is sick!
Give her good food, and
let her sleep comfortably.
But...
I think your baby feels cold because
she's covered with many blankets, right?
Yes.
I understand this feeling.
You have to let her play a lot.
Is that just it?
It's important to monitor
the temperature of young children.
Well...
Because of what happened
to her she feels cold.
Yes!
Be careful!
Doctor, I still don't want her to move much!
Foolish!
What's in your mind?
You have to leave this child free!
Hm!
This dog steals my popularity.
- That's it, Doctor!
- Yes!
What is the matter? What is the matter?
Damn...
Is my face so scary?
I love kids, but...
I can't face children!
Doctor, there are still others!
Well well!
Take care of yourself!
What do you think that
you accompany me today?
Don't worry!
She only watches you.
So don't run away, sir!
What do you think?
Is it delicious?
Yes.
I wonder if the aunt can taste it?
Don't worry, Lassie will give it to her!
I don't mean that, but I mean
if it's delicious or not!
Tasty! Tasty!
Yes, no doubt about it!
Yes!
It's delicious!
Did you teach her?
That girl is very skilled.
I think Sandy has a good sense of taste!
Hm!
And what about your son John, he has what?
Eh?
You mean John?
I don't know.
It's still unclear.
But he is the owner of Lassie even grown up, right?
He only runs and plays with it!
But definitely....
Although he is very angry with it,
he still takes good care of it!
By the way, Doctor, why don't you
go somewhere today?
Hm?
You have treated many patients today.
Isn't that so?
This is true.
Well, that may be true.
I'll go for some time.
As I have always told you, when anything
happens I can hear the siren of the mine.
If something happens, send me a signal.
What is it today?
You usually say, "I decided to go today,
I've been patient enough"!
Why didn't you say that as usual?
If the patient is late, I will have
to work until evening.
You also need to pick up your energy again!
Well, he began to cast some good words!
Well...
Will you go too?
Hm?
What is the matter?
It's true that I asked you to help me, but
I didn't mean to join me at the fishing too!
Well it does not matter!
What do you think?
I'm the only one who knows about this spot!
Lassie!
What do you think of
the village of Greenor Bridge?
I love this village.
I traveled in many cities and villages
but this is a good village.
Security, peace...
Also all villagers work hard.
Do you think these words come out
of an old man only?
Don't be silly!
My clinic is a medical clinic.
Big things are not strange to me.
So I have to keep some strength.
Do you understand?
No, it's not true!
I have to prepare for those big things!
I feel like an old man walking around here and
there without paying attention to anything!
Nurse Carraclough works alone.
If something serious happens there,
it will be a big problem!
If you think about it, I can't sleep at night.
I didn't even take a nap.
No, that's not true.
Although I love my work...
Hm?
What's up, Lassie?
Oh!
I've got it!
Well well!
Got it!
Ah!
What do you think, Lassie?
Isn't it good?
I did it badly...
But Lassie, did you enjoy the day?
Right! Right!
Hm? What is the matter?
My foot is under the rock...
I appreciate your concern,
but this is impossible for you.
Well, I'll relax.
Lassie?
What happened to it?
The most recent thing it did?
Maybe it is taking a nap at home today!
It's you, Lassie?
What is the matter?
I see that you are in good health, Lassie.
What are you doing, Lassie?
Hm?
Lassie?
Lassie!
Where did it go?
With Sandy's sheep!
But they're at the farm.
They didn't came on the pasture today.
Hm...
Could it still be with my mom?
Eh?
It's gone for a long time!
Didn't it came to pick you up?
But it didn't!
Where did it go?
Hello Smarty!
Smarty, did you see Lassie today?
Lassie!
W-what's up, Lassie?
Just a moment, what are you doing? Wait!
What's up with you?
Today you didn't came to school!
Where have you been?
Where were you playing?
Lassie? What is the matter?
Ah wait!
Wait, Lassie!
Ah! Hey!
Ah...!
Doctor Hooper!
Oh...
John!
Doctor!
Doctor Hooper!
I wasn't attentive.
That's why I fell and the rocks fell
on my feet, and I can't move.
No use, it doesn't move!
Lassie!
Bring anyone...!
I know!
Lassie, I count on you in this!
Get anyone!
The first person you meet, brought it here!
Did you understand?
The first person you meet!
Doctor, are you okay?
Lassie will attend someone immediately!
I'm sorry, John...
Oh?
It's Lassie!
What is the matter? Hm?
Well okay, why did you come today?
Oh?
My God, what happened?
What's up, Lassie?
It's a handkerchief.
It's John's handkerchief!
SOS! It's bad!
Oh?
What is the matter?
John wrote this, he's near the bridge!
Don't you know where he is?
Does anyone know you?
xxx
- Oh?
Lassie, are you still looking?
How long will we stay like this?
Oh!
I'm sorry, John!
I've brought you in a difficult situation!
Doctor! Are you okay?
Yes!
But if Lassie woudn't have told
about my problem...
No one wouldn't have found me!
I would have to wait until someone passed by.
Oh...!
Thinking about being more patient...!
I look like a great man!
Hm?
John, have you heard that voice just now?
Ah...!
Lassie!
What's up, Lassie?
Is it here?
Oh, he's there!
John! Dr. Hooper!
Doctor, the help came!
Lassie called my father here!
Y-yes...
Wait, John!
I'm coming to help you now!
I will certainly help you!
Lassie!
You've done your best, John!
Are you okay?
Stop it, Lassie, this tickles!
Lassie, stop it!
John...
Are you okay?
xxx
Thank you!
Well, take care of yourself!
Doctor, the patients for today have finished!
I have survived by your favor!
Thank you again!
I'm still a doctor. I'm still slow to think.
Your presence was very helpful.
I'm glad it ended with this simple wound!
But when you are in trouble you
need a real friend to support you!
Lassie, you are a true friend!
Lassie!
Next time I'll bring you a big fish!
Doctor!
Before that, you have to take care
of your wound until it heals!
I know that.
You see? Lassie too says so!
The teacher Curry and Miss Mary,
the bakery owner, will marry!
But on the wedding day,
Miss Mary doesn't want to go to church!
What happened?
Next episode:
THE MARRIAGE OF TEACHER CURRY
Be sure to watch!