OldCastle and South Wind Subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Walk towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
In my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
watch over you always,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari_
a neverending story
Ladies and gentlemen!
Welcome to Benjamin Circus!
This is the first time that
many tricks we'll be played here!
A Big Problem! The Elephant
Escaped From The Circus
Please enjoy with us!
Oh…!
And now, gentlemen,
We have reached to our most important treasure!
It is a well-trained animal and it's
the most important star of our circus!
And now I present:
The elephant Rosalind!
Just awesome! It's a real elephant!
It's huge…!
Oh…
Please relax!
Rosalind will surprise you when it
listens to everything I say to it!
Now let's start!
This rare elephant will move
the ball with its feet!
What are you doing? Move quickly!
And now, gentlemen, the elephant
will move the ball with its feet!
I'm sorry!
But this is just a greeting.
To describe the second event!
Well done!
Just awesome! Just awesome! Just awesome!
Have you enjoyed, John?
It was very fun!
Is that right? I'm glad to hear that!
Lassie…
The circus was very fun!
Unfortunately we didn't get a ticket for you!
The best of the acrobat games
is the elephant show!
But…
He had to frighten it with the whip.
Hm…!
That's true, maybe it didn't listen
to him because of what he did.
You are right.
Rosalind!
What's with your behaviour today?
You have caused me embarrassment!
How long will these acts continue?
You are bad!
Bad!
You are useless!
You have to save your style in acrobatics!
- He is still angry.
- Yes.
You huge nasty one!
Excuse me, Captain…
Uh? What is the matter?
I have to feed Rosalind.
Feed it?
You don't have to!
If it doesn't do acrobatics,
there is no food for it!
Today it will remain hungry!
If you want to eat, don't miss it again,
understand? Huh!
We can't do anything as long as long
he's angry. It's just an animal.
Rosalind… What a poor man…
Oh… What's up, Lassie?
Oh!
It's still six o'clock.
Today is also a holiday from school…
Hey Lassie!
Where are you going with these?
Wonderful weather!
It's good to walk early in the forest!
You brought me here to see this behind?
What is behind it?
A-ah…
Lassie!
Inside there is an elephant!
Ah!
It's not possible!
It seems surprised!
Oh?
I understood, you brought this apple for it…
Lassie…
This elephant ate the apple that I gave to it!
Good!
Now, you want to eat these?
I wonder if Rosalind has learned a lesson?
Oh!
You can't… Rosalind!
This is bad!
Look! Come out!
Come on, there's no need to fear!
Come here!
You have beautiful eyes…!
Whoa! Great!
You have a great appetite!
But although the size of the elephant
is huge, it's full of scratches.
Ah! Sorry!
Have you suffered?
Okay!
Wait here!
I will bring first aid kit
from home to treat you!
I will also bring you more apples!
Come on, Lassie!
You have to wait a little!
I didn't see him!
Today I woke up late and
I didn't see anything.
Is that right? Thanks!
Let's go!
Who are they?
They are the people who were in the circus!
It's Mr. Pierrot, whom we saw yesterday.
Eh?
- No one saw it.
- Yes.
We also asked them.
We had to pay more attention to the elephant.
When he failed to hit it with a whip
and prevent him from eating.
It's a miracle he didn't lose his senses.
At night I heard the sad voice of Rosalind…
I couldn't forget its voice.
This is so terrible…
Hm? What is that?
The latest thing?
Dial the police number!
It's a bad thing, it's an elephant!
It walks around!
An elephant?
An elephant…
Who has a long nose?
Hey!
Rosalind!
Hey…!
Rosalind?
Where did you go?
Hey!
Lassie, did you smell Rosalind?
I see!
Maybe he caught up with us.
Now come on!
Hey Rosalind!
Let's go back to the circus!
If you don't listen to me…!
Oh!
The police car…
What happens?
Could it be that elephant?
We heard that this elephant was walking out!
P-please wait!
To bring such weapons…
It's not dangerous.
It's the precious treasure of our circus!
If you kill it, we will lose our lives!
If so, take it quickly from here!
If the elephant hails and hits people,
we will get rid of it immediately!
Ah, I know that!
Well, I will do everything!
You heard, Rosalind?
Listen to my orders only!
Listen to my promises directly!
Otherwise…
Oh?
Move!
Ah-ah…!
Oh!
- xxx
- Wait!
Wait a moment!
It will listen to me now!
Listen to me immediately, you bad!
There is no point in doing such acts…
Oh! xxx
What are you doing, Rosalind?
Oh?
What is this dog?
You hear? They'll shot him at once!
Stop!
Rosalind!
Don't do such a thing…
You know me!
Kid, this is dangerous!
Don't shoot!
Rosalind is really good!
Run away, John! This is dangerous!
Get back, you'll be hurt!
It's not harmful!
But it doesn't listen to my orders!
Rosalind…
Look at me, Rosalind!
I promised that I bring you apples!
Here!
Ah…
Ah!
John!
Oh…
Oh…!
It have eaten!
Rosalind?
This work again!
It's wrong, this…
Can be done by…
What about this barrel?
Yes!
Rosalind!
Rosalind, use this!
I see!
Rosalind, wants to show us
an offer as an apology?
John!
Well done!
You have prepared him to his senses!
Excuse me, boy…
I have a request.
To teach me how you managed
to bring Rosalind back to normal?
I won't do it!
Why?
Because Rosalind is afraid of the whip, uncle.
Still not afraid of whip.
You have to listen to others.
You don't understand the animal's mood, so
understand this before returning to the circus.
So Rosalind will escape again!
Isn't it, Lassie?
This boy speaks to me insolently!
Captain, stop that!
His saying is absolutely true!
We also believe that what
you did to Rosalind is terrible.
Rosalind is very poor!
Captain, if you don't think
of fixing the deal with Rosalind,
it won't go back to the circus again!
Us too…
Okay, here you go!
Give it to Rosalind!
Boy, Rosalind is fine now.
We will take good care of it!
Yes!
All of you, have you enjoyed with us?
And now, Benjamin Circus is back again!
We will show you this time
a new and unique show!
This circus treasure…
The elephant Rosalind! Queen Sera!
In return I managed
to get a special ticket.
That's great!
That day we went on
a trip outside the village.
We all boarded a ship to see the sea!
And on that ship,
a girl has become our friend.
She owned a treasure map.
Next episode:
"Colin's Love And The Treasure".
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams