Old Castle & south wind subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Keep walking towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
Back in my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
would beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
always watch over you,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari
a neverending story
Colin's First Love And The Treasure
I'm leaving!
Be careful.
Lassie?
Thank you, Lassie.
You thought I forgot
my school bag, didn't you?
The thing is, I don't need it today.
Today we're going for a trip
outside the town.
Look, this is my lunch.
So today you don't have to
walk me to school.
You want to tag along?
Is everyone ready?
Yes!
Listen, Lassie.
Wait for my sign.
What are you gonna do?
Hey, John.
Lassie's seeing you off
today as well, I see.
Yes. That's right!
You can enter, one by one.
Yes!
Being a wife is not so easy, huh?
You just married him, and he's already
taking you on his school trips.
To be honest, I like it a lot.
Everyone is on the cart, right?
All right.
Hm?
We're leaving, children!
Make sure not to fall out
from the cart.
Okay!
– We're all set, let's go.
– Gotcha.
Come on, Lassie. Hop on!
Here, here!
Is something the matter?
Nothing at all!
Children, after we get off the cart,
we are going to board this ship.
I'll go talk to the guide.
I have the tickets.
Okay.
You can step off now.
Right.
Thank you, mister.
See you when we get back.
Sure… Be careful…
Lassie, no!
Oh?
We managed to get her
on board, but what next?
I wonder if there's anywhere
we could hide her.
John, it's Mr. Curry.
Oh?
Colin, take care of Lassie.
Sir!
What's the matter,
John Carraclough?
Well… Uh…
I have a question!
Huh?
Where to hide Lassie?
Definitely not this way.
Lassie!
Thank you, doggie!
Thank goodness.
Ah, you're…
My hat!
Geez, that was my favorite hat.
I'm very sorry.
There's no recovering it now.
I'll forgive you.
Right. I have to hide Lassie.
– Hide?
– Yes.
I know a good place.
Huh?
I see. If you're going to the Skull Peninsula,
we're headed in the same direction.
The same direction?
Yes. But there I'll going to board another
big ship, bound all the way for Australia.
My father went before me
and now he is waiting for me.
You're a foreigner…
I'd like to travel abroad some day.
So what's your name?
Lassie.
You silly.
I'm asking about your name.
Colin.
I'm Chris.
Nice to meet you, Colin.
Nice to meet you, Chris.
Nice to meet you, Lassie.
What was that
piece of paper before?
It seemed really important.
It's a treasure map.
A treasure map?
Once I get to the Skull Peninsula,
I'm going to look for a treasure.
Can I go with you?
Huh?
It's to make up
for the hat that you lost.
Do you want to join us, Lassie?
Colin Jones?
Colin Jones is missing.
Did anyone see him?
Shall I look for him
on the ship once more?
This is bad.
He can't simply leave the boat.
Right. He can't leave Lassie alone.
What if he fell into the sea?!
Colin! La—
You wouldn't have brought
Lassie here, would you?
Ah… Of course not…
Sir, I have a question!
Save it for later.
I'm sorry I'm late, sir.
Colin, how will you
explain this dog?
What's wrong with Sebastian?
Sebastian?
Is that this dog's name?
Yes.
Say hello to them, Sebastian.
What about you?
I'm Chris.
We met on the ship.
Fair enough.
Now that we're all gathered,
we'll have a lunch in the lighthouse.
We're leaving.
Yes sir!
What's going on, Colin?
Hello, John.
Hello, Sandy.
I'm Chris.
Nice to meet you.
I heard about you from Colin.
It was a pretty good plan,
don't you think?
Yeah…
Hello, Chris.
We thought Lassie would stay
with her until we had free time.
Okay.
That's quite smart.
I'll wait for you near the peninsula.
Okay.
Take care of Lassie.
Let's go, Sebastian.
Oh, just a sec.
Here.
It's Lassie's lunch.
Got it.
See you at the peninsula.
– See you, Chris!
– Something doesn't sit right.
It must be her!
Hey! Lassie!
Even if I suddenly shout her name,
it didn't turn back. Must be some other dog.
It's so nice to listen
to the sea, Robert.
I wanna go with you!
Me too.
A treasure hunt…
So exciting!
It's on that island?
It's not an island
if we can get there on foot.
All right!
We'll look for treasure
during our free time!
Yeah!
Colin?
Children!
In the afternoon,
you can go down to the beach.
But make sure
not to go too far away.
In particular, any trips
to that island are strictly forbidden.
Do you understand?
Yes sir!
He says we can't go to the island.
I wonder why?
– Did we make you wait?
– No.
– Here, I'm returning Lassie.
– Thanks.
John, I'm going
with Chris, after all.
But the teacher said…
Colin, I don't want to force you.
I can go by myself.
No. It's okay.
I really want to go.
Aha.
So that's what it's about.
I'll go with you.
You're staying, John.
What? Why?
Just don't.
Take your time, Colin.
Take my time…
If possible, I'd like
to take Lassie with us…
Sure.
What the heck?
I'm sorry, John.
Let's go, Chris.
Sorry for borrowing Lassie again.
Lassie!
Look how happy Lassie was,
going with them.
So, why did I have to stay?
John, sometimes
you are so dense.
Dense?
Look…
What?!
He's fallen in love?!
Our Colin?
There you have it.
What kind of treasure is it?
Don't tell me it's a chest
buried by pirates long ago.
Nope. It's something
much more ordinary.
It's worthless to most people.
But to me it's
an invaluable treasure.
I see.
There's no way it could've been
a pirates' treasure.
Are you disappointed?
Not at all!
I'm not helping you
because of the treasure.
Let's go!
Wait, Chris!
Must be nice,
looking for treasures.
But who would suspect…
Does Colin really love Chris?
She looked much older.
What are you doing?
No daydreaming!
You dingbat.
What?
You never heard that in love,
age doesn't matter?
I didn't it.
I'm such a dingbat, after all.
Revenge!
Geez, now you've done it!
We climbed a lot.
Chris, are you sure
this is the right way?
Yes. If we walk this way,
we'll reach the summit soon.
We're going all the way
to the summit?
How are you holding up?
Are you tired?
I'm fine!
For now.
It's pushing pretty hard.
John Carraclough!
John Carraclough.
I have a question for you!
Y… Yes?
What's this?
There was a landslide.
Oh, no…
We've come such a long way,
all for nothing?
Look at Lassie.
We can climb here.
See? We can reach
the summit this way, too.
But we can't climb like Lassie.
Don't worry.
I'll make holes with this.
Okay.
It'll take a bit of time,
so you can relax in the meantime.
Okay.
Now climb up, Chris!
Okay!
Don't look down.
Yes, exactly.
You can rest your feet.
We have already reached the peak.
Yes.
And now…
Let me take a look at the map.
Sure.
Here.
A compass!
Now that's what I call
a treasure hunt.
But I don't think the map
will be all that helpful, to be honest.
No, quite the opposite.
Over there is the lighthouse.
So the treasure
is to the northwest from here.
Let's look around.
Awesome!
What's up, Lassie?
The path is gone!
The tide came in and the path
got completely flooded.
Hey!
Somebody help us!
The path got flooded!
There's no way they could hear us.
Now isn't the best time
to look for treasures.
We have to think
about the way back.
Colin, can you swim?
I can't.
Me neither.
Sooner or later,
John and Sandy will help us.
I hope it's sooner, otherwise
I won't make it to my ship.
It's possible I won't be able
to return home either.
Anyway, I'll better get down, and…
I don't mind not going to Australia.
Chris?
The treasure is
a memory of my mom.
A memory?
My mom died last month.
Dad, rather than living in a house
full of memories of my mom,
chose to start a new life
in a foreign country.
But personally I'd rather stay here.
I didn't tell it to my dad, though.
I see.
So before leaving England, I decided
to look for something my mom left behind.
When I was little, mom and dad
came here with me to play treasure hunt.
It was so much fun.
We drew this map together with Mom
and I've been holding onto it till today.
Now Mom's no longer around.
In the end, I could never find it.
Let's find it now, Chris.
Huh?
This is such an important thing,
that you cannot let go of it.
But we have to think
about how to get back.
I will find a solution.
So let's go, Chris.
Okay.
North-west. North-west!
Is this the way, Chris?
Yeah, no mistake about it!
Over there!
It was buried under that tree!
Are you sure?
It's just like I remembered it.
– We've found it!
– Yes.
I remember Mom planting it.
Look how big it has grown!
Let's dig.
Okay.
Ah… It's so beautiful.
I collected them
together with Mom.
There's something written there.
You're right.
"My Dear Chris.
I can imagine a tenderhearted girl
now reading this."
Mom…
I have to go to Australia.
I shouldn't worry Dad.
Yeah.
Let's go back.
With this, I won't drown.
I'll swim and I'll call for help.
I'll be right back.
I'll go with you!
It will sink if we go together.
We don't have the time
to make another one.
But…
I'll be fine.
Leave this to me.
Colin!
Do your best, Colin!
Faster… Faster!
Lassie!
If I don't hurry, Chris' ship
will depart without her!
Lassie?
Stop it, Colin Jones!
Go back to the ground at once!
Turn! Turn around!
I'll go help you in a moment!
We're saved.
Don't swim any further!
We'll get to you!
The ship bound for Australia
is about to leave.
Don't be late!
I'm coming!
There's not much time.
Say goodbye to her now.
Yes.
Chris, uh…
You're okay, right?
With going to Australia and all.
Yes. Colin, thanks to you,
I recovered my precious keepsake.
Thank you, Colin.
Thank you, Lassie.
Goodbye, John and Sandy.
Goodbye, Chris.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Colin.
Chris! Chris!
Colin! I will never forget
what happened today!
Me neither! Me neither!
I will never forget!
Goodbye! Goodbye, Chris!
Goodbye… Chris.
And away she goes.
So, did you find the treasure?
What was it?
I'm sorry, John.
I can't tell you.
It's our little secret.
Colin…
Right, Lassie?
Children, get ready to go!
Pff, how boring.
We have to go back.
The cart is already waiting for us.
What?!
An influenza epidemic
has spread in the village.
Even my father got sick
and stayed at home.
Every day, Mom looks more tired.
I hope she'll be okay…
Next episode:
"It's Serious! My Mother Collapsed".
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams