Old Castle & south wind subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Keep walking towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
Back in my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
would beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
always watch over you,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari
a neverending story
Ah, thank goodness.
It's Serious! My Mother Has Collapsed
Your fever's finally gone down.
Now I can go to work, right?
Absolutely not.
But I'm worried about
what's going on with the mine.
No means no.
This time it's serious.
It's very important for you to rest.
The boys will survive
without you for one day.
You're right.
But just for today.
Lassie.
Watch over Sam and make sure
he doesn't try anything funny.
Yes, yes, I'm not going
anywhere, Lassie.
I'm fine, Lassie.
I just feel a little bit dizzy.
What's going on, Mom?
It's nothing, it's nothing.
Mom, you look so pale.
You came home so late last night.
Hm?
You're worrying me.
Thank you.
I'm just a bit tired, that's all.
There's lots of patients.
I have to stay strong!
I really am fine.
You don't have to worry.
Better take care of your dad.
Be careful.
Sure.
Melissa?
I hate to ask, but could you drop by
later to check on my family?
They're still feverish?
Yeah.
All right.
Good morning.
How is your wife?
She's fine, thanks to you.
You're going to work already?
I'll be fine.
Be careful.
Oh, dear.
I could get used to this.
You finished?
Yes. Thanks for the meal.
As I'm looking out the window,
it looks like a lot of people are still sick.
Say, John.
Mom was tense, wasn't she?
Yeah.
But she still headed out.
If she was too busy to get home by now,
it means she had to skip the lunch.
Yes. It's an epidemic, after all.
But it's bad for her
if she doesn't eat anything.
Yeah.
All right!
I'll fix her something
and bring it to her.
Good. And I'm mostly fine,
so you don't have to look after me.
All right, in that case…
Let's go, Lassie!
It's all right, Lassie.
I'll be resting here.
With all my might.
On such occasions,
it is my turn to help Mom.
Good morning!
Mom?
That's weird.
It should be crowded,
but there's nobody.
Where is everyone?
That's the list of patients…
That must be it.
She's still doing house calls.
Good morning!
Mom!
Mom, we…
Oh, wait a moment.
Bring this upstairs.
It doesn't hurt, does it?
I'm not a child.
In that case get better already.
I'm sorry for calling you
to visit us again.
It's okay.
Just get better soon.
Time to go to the next house.
When is it going to end?
The pulse… 84.
Good. We just need
to take that fever down.
Don't worry and stay relaxed.
I'll try.
– Here.
– Thank you.
That's the least
I can do for you, ma'am.
On the other hand,
Mom and Doctor…
Mom!
What is it?
I almost forgot.
We brought your lunch.
Well, we'll be back here
at five o'clock.
I'll have to prepare
the next batch of the medicine.
Sounds exhausting.
All residents
of that house are sick?
How is it?
Well, it's a little high.
What about Jake?
Your son has recovered
the quickest, as a matter of fact.
So basically you're
the only one left.
Yes.
But we're running out of medicine
faster than I had anticipated.
Yesterday…
Yesterday I ordered
more ingredients.
I hope they'll arrive soon.
We won't contain this epidemic
unless we place orders every day.
Maybe the package will arrive
by tomorrow afternoon.
As soon as it arrives,
I'll go fetch it and…
Mrs. Carraclough!
Hey, she fell!
Mom…
Mom! Mom!
Mom.
John?
Doctor.
I'm sorry.
No, I'm the one
who should apologize.
I made you work so hard
that this happened.
No. I'll go back immediately.
Mom!
I'm fine, John.
I'm just a little tired.
The patients are waiting for.
Mom, your temperature
is too high.
Your son is right.
Hold out your arm.
I'll give you a shot.
That won't do, Doctor.
This medicine is…
What are you talking about?
This injection is for everyone
who has a fever.
But we don't have enough
for tomorrow morning.
We've got it covered.
I asked Mr. Rice to go ahead
and pick it up by truck.
So you can give me
the injection after he's back.
Mom!
At any rate,
I absolutely do not want it.
The other patients
need it more than I do.
Mrs. Carraclough.
Your stubbornness has become
a legend of this town.
But you need to realize…
Hey!
Sam, you're there, aren't you?
Let's just go in.
Good.
We heard that Melissa fainted
and we're here to visit her.
Sure.
I made a soup for you.
I hope you like it and get better quick.
Melissa, everyone in the town
is worried about you.
We all owe you so much.
Exactly.
Excuse me.
Melissa.
Y… Yes?
It's only natural
they worry about you.
Remember, dear,
you're the only nurse in this town.
If something were
to happen to you…
Grandma, you make us look bad.
We truly appreciate her
for all that she's done for us.
Mrs. Carraclough.
You know that
Grandma Forrest is right.
You'll help more people if you
take that injection and get better quick.
– Doctor…
– Exactly!
And while you're resting,
I'll help Dr. Hopper, so don't worry.
Hoho?
John.
Lassie, you too?
I don't know
what kind of injection it is,
but if it makes you get well,
there's no point in hesitating.
Yes.
I understand.
Mom, it's incredible how many
lives depend on you.
Yes. Well said, John.
Well…
I'm leaving your wife
in your hands, Sam.
Sure.
Dr. Hopper!
Hm?
Doctor, about the thing
I said before…
Hm?
Let me help you.
Help me how?
It will be hard for you
to work all alone, right?
I'm not as good as my Mom, of course,
but maybe I could help you, a little?
Look, Lassie wants to help, too.
Hmm.
Even if you say so…
I also want to help the patients,
who are so important to my Mom.
Very well.
I'm counting on you, John, Lassie.
Okay!
The lungs are okay.
John, spatula.
Spatula… here.
Thanks.
Say "ah".
Ahh…
– Laryngoscope.
– Right away.
Here. It's this, right?
Yes.
Lugol's iodine.
Sure. Uh… this, right?
You've got the tool names,
more or less. Who's next?
No. 21, Mrs. Harrison.
All right.
Thank you.
Don't mention it.
I hope you get well soon.
We still have a lot to do.
Good grief.
No matter how much I make,
there's nowhere near enough.
I'll go ahead and deliver these!
All right. Thank you.
I will check the inventory
in the meantime.
Okay!
Nonetheless, the most important
antipyretic is out of stock.
Not to mention that if somebody
got a high fever now, we'd be doomed.
I hope Rice returns quickly
with more ingredients.
Damn!
I went so early to avoid the traffic,
and I got stuck anyway.
This is why I hate cities,
for crying out loud.
It's Dr. Hopper's medicine.
Thank you.
All right, that's the last house.
Mr. Gabel?
Mr. Gabel!
Be quiet, will ya?
Just step inside already!
Are you gonna get in or not?!
Uh… I brought your medicine.
A kid? What happened to Melissa?
Mom got very sick,
that's why I came instead.
Hand it to me.
It's different from
the usual rheumatic medicine.
It's a medicine for a cold.
Please take it after a meal.
Hmph.
I'm leaving, sir.
Wait up!
Do you need anything… sir?
You told me to take it after a meal,
but as you can see, I can't move from bed.
So…
Are you asking me
to make food for you?
Precisely.
Or maybe it's okay if I don't take it?
This is hopeless.
I've got to start by washing all of this.
Not a single clean pot.
Stop that yammering.
Melissa did everything
without all that grumbling.
Mom did?
All right!
Did really Mom go that far?
Here you go.
I'll be on my way now.
Wait.
Like this?
Yeah.
My back aches all over,
all day long.
You're quite good at this.
I am?
Maybe you could come
more often.
Dr. Hopper?
He looked like he was in a rush.
What? What's the matter?
Mr. Gabel, I have to go now.
I have to help Dr. Hopper.
Wait a moment!
I'm sorry, but I really have to go!
No, no!
Open that cabinet,
you'll find a bottle on the shelf.
It's a special treat.
Take it with you.
I'd like to give it to Melissa.
Melissa always looked after me
without so much as a single complaint.
Thank you, Mr. Gabel.
I will come visit you again.
Dr. Hopper!
Oh, it's you, John.
Jake's temperature has risen.
You mean that boy?
We weren't careful
and it worsened.
Miss…
Is Jake going to be fine?
No worries.
There's no evidence of pneumonia.
As long as we get
his fever down, he'll be fine.
I'm so glad.
I'll take care of him now.
Miss, you have to rest.
But…
I'll look after Jake.
Miss, you just rest and take it easy.
Yes, but…
Miss, you getting better soon
is in Jake's best interest.
Isn't that right, Doctor?
Absolutely.
Go back to bed.
Tomorrow morning, when you recover,
you can hug Jake as much as you want.
Let me see.
How is his temperature?
Hmm.
If it stayed at this level,
it would be all good.
It's still rising?
Yes.
Well, as long as we have the medicine,
there's no need to worry.
We'll put cold water compresses on
his forehead and wait for Rice to return.
Damn!
You useless piece of junk.
I've had enough of you.
The medicine hasn't arrived yet.
Dr. Hopper!
Hm?
I went to the clinic and found
a note saying you'd be here.
What's the matter?
My mother's fever has risen again!
I hoped you could take a look.
As you see, I have to go
to Olsen's house.
Sorry, but I'm going to have you
look after Jake for a bit.
If his temperature suddenly rises,
let me know immediately.
Sure.
Ah, also don't forget
to change the towel.
Yes, Doctor.
Well, then.
All right.
Let's do our best
for the patient's sake, Lassie.
I am thirsty.
You want something to drink?
Will water do?
Yes.
Just a moment.
Go back to sleep now.
I will turn off the light
so that it's easier for you.
Good.
He's sound asleep.
I keep changing it,
but it gets hot so fast.
Oh, no. It's time
to take his temperature.
Thank you for
waking me up, Lassie.
Is it that late already?
Shoot…
I dozed off again.
Damn! Jake!
What to do?
His temperature has risen!
Wait, where did
this blanket come from?
Oh, you're awake, John.
Mom, how are you feeling?
Pretty good, thanks to you.
But Jake's—
Oh, right!
Calm down, John.
We need to cool him down.
I wish we had some ice…
Ice?
You need ice, right?
Lassie, we've got to find ice!
But where do we get it from?
Excuse me!
Mr. Nelson!
What do you possibly want
so late in the night?
Please give me some ice
from your refrigerator!
It's for Parkinsons' child, Jake!
Jake has a terrible fever!
What?! I'm coming down!
That's enough, John.
He's got better.
I'll sleep for a bit.
We'll shift in an hour.
It would be terrible if you fainted again
before Mr. Rice got here.
Yes, Dad.
Hm?
What's going on, Lassie?
Lassie?
Lassie!
Oh?
What's with her?
She wants me to follow her?
Lassie?
Sorry I'm late.
Dr. Hopper.
Hey, Doctor!
What are you doing here?
I brought you the medicine!
Lassie brought Mr. Rice here.
Mom! The medicine!
The medicine arrived!
Thank you so much.
Thank goodness, Jake,
you're all fine now.
Yep! Mom, too. I'm happy!
You've done well, John.
No, it wasn't even a fraction
of what you do every day.
Not even a fraction.
I am so proud of you, Mom.
Grandma Forrest's son returned
to the town after 20 years.
But she doesn't
recognize him as her son.
Soon, we all learned
that she has a grandchild!
Next episode:
"I Want To See My Grandmother".
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams