OldCastle and South Wind Subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Walk towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
In my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
watch over you always,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari
a neverending story
Will the bus return here after two hours?
The time has passed!
If you walk in this way you
will find a village nearby.
I know that.
I know that very well!
Hm?
I think I missed you very much...
Here is my hometown...
I Want To See My Grandmother
Stop making this funny sound!
What do you want?
But I apologize for leaving
and forgetting our past days!
Oh!
Leave immediately!
I don't want to see your face!
Excuse me!
Grandma Forrest!
What's the matter, Jon Carraclough?
Have you been throughout the day
when the teacher Curry?
Y-yes...
It's your fault because you read
the book until late at night!
That is why you overslept!
Grandma Forrest knows everything.
She looks from that window all the time so
she knows all the news of the village!
John, you're late!
Sorry! Sorry!
I just saw something very strange!
Eh?
Very strange?
Yes.
Grandma Forest act like I have
never seen her before!
She seemed to be arguing with someone.
She argued?
You mean Grandma Forrest?
She poured water on him
from the second floor...
It was a warm welcome!
Well, it's inevitable.
Because you left the village 20 years ago.
It's your fault because you
never communicated with her.
Yes, thank you for this.
Okay.
Twenty years...
For me it was short...
In the meantime, I never thought of returning.
Yes.
In any case, I can't forgive such a thing.
Are you going back already?
I have to go back for work.
Over time she will actually listen to me.
Until my mother forgives me
I will go to rest in the monastery!
See you!
Okay!
"Mom"?
Uncle!
I saw this guy in front of
Grandma Forest's house, though...
Yes!
He's Grandma Forest's son.
- Eh?
Grandma Forrest?
Her son?
Yes.
But Grandma Forest said:
"I don't want to see your face!"
Albert left the house after
arguing with his parents.
That's why he left this village
He argued with them?
He doesn't seem to work today either.
I wonder why Grandma Forest doesn't let him in?
Even though he is her son.
Right!
Something might have happened!
The son of Mrs. Forest left
before your father came to this village so
we can't anticipate the circumstances.
But whatever the circumstances,
he still wants to see Grandma!
Hm?
Why?
Well, isn't it?
Isn't this what a family does?
Yes, that's right!
John, it certainly does, but there are
many circumstances in this world.
But, is definitely a parent
I would like to see!
Dad, isn't that true?
Oh...
Hm...!
This is true...
Oh my God, my God!
Oh... Where are you going on your holiday?
Hm?
I'll have a short talk with Mrs. Forrest.
What do you mean by living together?
So cruel!
Mrs. Forrest, just a moment!
What? Sam Carraclough?
You came for me?
Don't say that!
Weren't you watching the latest thing?
Can I come in for a moment?
What is this...?
So you can open the door.
Enter quickly and close the door
so no stranger enters here!
Regardless of that...
Isn't that strange man your son?
My son, you said?
Yes!
Sam Carraclough!
I don't have any son!
My only family is my late husband George!
No, I mean...
Hm!
I told you that I don't have any sons!
No way, Mrs. Forrest!
F-father?
John!
Dr. Hopper, call him quickly!
Y--yes!
Well... It has little blood pressure only!
It's best to be not very active.
I'm back!
How are you?
Ah...
Will my grandmother come to our house?
Oh?
No... it seems she doesn't want to forgive me.
She was very stubborn.
Is that so?
In this picture looks like a very nice grandma.
So, I will leave your present here!
John Carraclough!
There's no need to treat me as a patient!
Aren't you late for the kite?
Oh?
Do I have to do it, grandmother?
Are you still standing here?
And now, go!
Yes, see you!
Won't you go with him, Lassie?
I always look at this part of the city.
Look!
Duhan is here much as it is now.
He thinks something good has happened to him!
This is Sam Carraclough's house.
I still remember the first day
we met in this village.
He was still young and went to school.
And the day when John got you,
you were a puppy, Lassie!
Hm?
And this?
This is an old picture of our family.
This is me!
That's my late husband George,
and this kid...
It was a beautiful day...
I wonder how things
got even bigger until they became like this?
In the end he left the house
and lived freely elsewhere.
George was working hard
to make money for my son Albert.
But that boy stole the golden piece!
Hm!
Then I didn't know how he lives
and where he was.
Even when his father died, he never came!
And when he understood his sin
he came after he left this village
to ask me to live with him!
Don't be silly!
You bastard!
Whoa!
It flew!
You are late, Lassie!
Have you been to Grandma Forest all the time?
And Grandma Forrest's son?
Eh? Lassie, did you know
that about grandmother?
What's up, Lassie?
Ah, someone is sitting there!
I wonder who is it?
Sorry...
Hm?
What is the matter?
Are you hurt?
Hurt? You are wrong!
I just lost something very precious!
Very precious?
Yes, it's a necklace I got from my father!
A necklace?
It's very precious for my father!
Ah, there it is!
I'm happy, thank you!
Tell me, we have met you
but we haven't asked who you are!
Yes, me?
I'm Roy George Forest!
Forrest?
Oh, could he be...
Grandma Forrest's grandson?
Hm?
Do you know my grandmother?
We really know her...
Yes...
We know her, yet we didn't know
anything about grandmother's grandson!
I didn't know, it was a novelty.
Hm...
That's true!
I also didn't know
about having a grandmother...
Eh?
Hm...
If you don't know anything
about your grandmother
it means that you are
very terrible and stubborn...
Ouch!
Stop it! This is rude!
Ah... right... sorry!
That's okay!
My father is the one who
oppressed my grandmother.
That's why I wanted to see my grandmother,
but that's impossible.
I have an old picture of my grandmother!
She looks very nice and she smiles!
- Eh?
I looked at the picture a lot.
That's why I wanted to see my grandmother.
Also...
Also?
I haven't told my father and mother
about coming here...
...alone!
So let's go, quickly!
I'll tell you about your grandmother's place!
Yes!
Mom!
- Oh!
My son and his mother want to see you!
He's your grandson, Mom!
Mom, you want to see him, don't you?
My grandson?
My only family is my late husband George!
I don't have any children!
I don't have any child, I mean
I don't have any grandson!
How should I meet strangers?
But Mom...
Leave!
If you don't leave, I will pour water on you!
Oh...
Grandmother... don't want to see me...
It's not true!
That's right!
Yes!
She wants to see you, Roy.
But she's a little stubborn.
I think she doesn't want to say
that she really wants to see you.
Yes...
Can't we do anything?
Hm...
Listen John...
Yes...
This is true...
I can't believe my mother is so stubborn!
What? Do you want to cry?
No way!
Since I left this village
I went to many places and
started building my own life.
In the end I stayed in a house of my own.
And so I can welcome her!
That's what I was thinking about.
It took me 20 years to think about it.
She's 20 years older!
Ah-ah...
I can't give up easily.
You can't do that easily after
you decided to leave the village!
Damn!
I don't know if I inherited this
from my mother or not.
My grandson?
Hm!
Hm?
What brings you to my home, John Carraclough?
E-e-eh...
I brought some cookies with me,
I want to have tea with you, Grandma!
I wonder what wind carry you?
Well okay, come in!
Today I haven't come alone,
is it okay if my cousin comes with me?
Ah!
This face...
Albert! It's not possible...
Now, are you ready?
I don't want to meet her as her grandson.
If I tell her that I'm her grandson,
she'll throw me out.
I'm sure you'll be fine!
Well, is it okay to have tea here sometimes?
Hm!
My grandmother...
Your cousin, John Carraclough?
The person that's with you doesn't seem to be.
Really?
Today he came to visit me in my house!
Hm!
I didn't know that you have a cousin!
Really? But it's true!
John...!
John!
Aren't you here? You're away?
They're calling you, John Carraclough!
Now answer them immediately!
Yes, I'll go at them for a moment!
Roy, pour tea for grandmother!
Oh... oh!
Wait a moment!
I can't, Sandy calls me!
See you!
You can go with him quickly!
No, I will give you tea.
Here.
Why do you stand like this?
If you want to drink tea,
you should bring a chair and sit on it!
Ah... okay!
What's your name?
My name is Roy.
Roy...
Hm! Your parents souldn't
give you that funny name.
Does this...
Does this village produce coal?
Yes.
My grandfather was a worker in the mine.
Oh...?
Is that right?
My husband too.
He was working in that mine.
What a coincidence!
A man was proud of him.
And...
And... what happened?
Oh...
I also think that your father
is proud of your hard work
because he was a mine worker, right?
Yes.
Oh, I was wrong?
That's unfortunate!
Sorry...
Uh?
Before my birth my father became a sailor.
That's why he visited many countries.
He was always yearning
for such a life of freedom.
I am shocked by his situation.
Huh?
I don't want to hear from you.
She's not looking here, it's time!
I can't hear anything!
They don't seem to speak at all!
Hm...
Listen, Colin...
Yes, I see!
Now, isn't the time to go,
John's cousin?
Yes.
That's it, goodbye!
Ah! Don't do such a thing!
Lassie, let him go!
Ah?
T-t-this is...
Give it to me, Lassie!
T-this is...
I got it from my father.
Really...
This golden piece dates back
to the fifteenth century!
Could this be...
This is the gold piece that George took!
How could a child like you have it?
I didn't know anything about it!
This is because my father
didn't tell me any word!
However, regardless of the extent of poverty,
it can't be replaced by money
because it was as precious as he said!
Eh!
Is that right?
When my father became a sailor,
he was afflicted with serious illness and yet
he worked hard to earn money for us!
...But
But he never thought
of replacing this gold with money,
but rather did his best!
Is that right?
So he didn't sold it!
That is why he worked hard
not to forget those days!
Roy!
Huh?
Don't stay there and come here!
Because of my age I can't hear you.
Come closer and talk to me!
I...
I'm very happy because I came to this village!
My father didn't work in the mine,
and became a sailor,
yet I am still proud of him!
The ship he was working in was operated by coal!
The furnace of the ship was reddening, and it
was the coal that led him to the seven seas!
Charcoal xxx my father!
I'm glad I came here!
And found my grandfather here...
Grandmother...
I know that!
Roy, you are... my grandson...
Grandmother!
Are you here, John Carraclough?
- Show yourself immediately!
- Eh!
You knew that!
Continue from Albert!
But my father returned to the bus!
But he is still in Jones' shop!
He won't go today as long as he thinks about it!
He thinks about what he will do all day long.
No, you're wrong!
Grandmother, I hid him from you!
Mr. Albert is here!
He's been here a while
and he' s listening to you!
Ah!
Hm!
That's why you tried to dismiss
my theory, John Carraclough!
Mom!
I will live in this village and
I won't leave again!
So...
I won't go anywhere...
Welcome back, Albert!
Mom!
Oh!
Yeah, Albert!
Well, I'll take the picture now!
Coal ran out of the mine suddenly!
The mine will be closed!
This is what my father did without sleep!
I...
Next episode:
"John's Decision! Protect The Mine".
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams