Old Castle & south wind subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Keep walking towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
Back in my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
would beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
always watch over you,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari
a neverending story
You don't want to close the Wellington
Coal Mine and stop the work!
Yes!
In this way I have to pay the mine workers
the usual salaries!
Of course you have to take responsibility!
You have to give me your most precious thing!
You have to give me Lassie for that!
As I said exactly. And when the coal comes out,
I will give you Lassie back!
But, if not…Lassie will be mine!
Yes!
Do you trust your father so much?
But…
I'm sure the coal will come out!
Then I will regain Lassie!
Lassie!
Do Your Best, John!
Protect Lassie
Good morning, Mom…
Ah, good morning John! I already ate!
Father haven't returned since yesterday?
I'm sorry.
I've returned after you fall asleep last night!
But John grew up a lot!
You still have Lassie!
Always…!
Mom!
I have to go to work now!
I'll leave the rest to you!
Lassie…
I can't do anything.
But I…I can't stay alone anymore!
I know!
After school I'll go to the mine, won't I?
Who were you talking to exactly?
I'll do anything!
It's bad!
As I expected here!
Oh? Bad, how long is it now?
It's the tenth!
As long as the tenth indicates
that I have grown a lot.
Go home and sleep, you didn't left last night!
No, I'm sorry.
There are a lot of things I have to do here.
That's enough, Sam, I've received
another report from the Duke!
What is it?
He said he would postpone
the closure of the mine!
You can now continue
to investigate this matter!
O-oh?
The owner will pay for these things!
He will also pay salaries to all, as usual!
But the talk that I had with him…
What is it, Sam? Shouldn't you rejoice now?
I'm sure the pressure is not on you!
Oh…
However, what makes the wind
suddenly change its way?
Don't bother about it now!
Thank you!
Please wait a little here.
Okay!
Ah, be silent!
How long will you keep barking like this?
Lassie?
Why is it in there?
You should be ashamed of what you did!
What are you talking about?
It's Lassie!
You talked to my son
to take the dog that he cared so much for!
This is a very cowardly act!
Sam, calm down! Sam…
That boy is very conscious,
and doesn't do such foolish things!
Also John, as a man, made a promise to me!
What do you mean, as a man?
He's only 11 years old!
So what?
Can't you trust your son's word?
Or don't you trust yourself?
What do you mean by that?
John trusts you so much.
He still thinks that coal will come out
exactly as you told him!
Your son has agreed, because
he trusts you, Mr. Carraclough.
Did you understand the calculation?
2 multiply by 4 equals 8!
4 multiply by 5 equals 20,
and 4 multiply by 1 equals 4.
xxx
Ah… Strange…
Today is John acting strange…
John…
This is all we studied for today!
John Carraclough!
Yes!
Today you should listen like the other
children and gather information!
Y-y-yes… i-i-information?
Oh…!
Carraclough!
Throughout the day you thought to other things!
I-I'm sorry…
In this case, you'll see!
Lassie will laugh at you when it salutes you!
Lassie came here?
Lassie!
John!
Lassie…
You…
Why did you come back, Lassie?
Later on we'll talk with the Duke.
Ah, you are here as I expected!
You have been well trained how
to escape quickly, it's so stunning!
Lassie escaped from the palace?
Tell me straight!
Didn't it learn to escape from the beginning?
No way!
You sold the dog at a high price even though you
know it won't stay with anyone else, isn't it?
What a smart plan!
You know me, I'm Heinz, you can't fool me!
It's wrong! I'm not like that!
Don't you want to go now?
Wait a moment!
Lassie… I'm sorry!
But I must keep my promise to the Duke!
I will definitely be able to recover you!
Hm!
And now, come!
John!
What happened to Lassie?
Hm!
Nothing at all!It will come back quick!
I just agreed with Priscilla's grandfather!
You agree with him…
Yes!
Priscilla loves dogs a lot!
But is it okay to let Lassie go alone?
It will be fine, it will be back soon!
Where are you going?
To the mine!
I will help my father!
But the mine is closed now…
It's moving!
I will help you, Dad.
I must do everything I can!
Excuse me, manager…
John?
Ah…! Kids can't enter here!
I want to help you bring out coal!
What did you say?
Oh! No, get back quickly!
- Manager!
- Eh?
Please let him come here!
I'll talk to him!
Thank you!
Father, I…
Can you help me here?
Dad, I want to do anything!
Father?
We must drill deeper.
Now I collect samples for each of these rocks.
It's hard to dig throuh this soil, though.
There is one thing you can do!
Use this to collect rock samples.
Father!
Let us do our best to extract coal!John!
Yes!
This is for Lassie too.
Father, that is…
Ian!
Yes!
I will!
Mr. Carraclough, is it reasonable
to let your son do that?
No, but this time I have to let him do it!
You will become a pig if you fall!
Whoa!
What is that?
My house is full of strange men!
John!
Lassie…
Haven't come yet…
John…
You can't!
If you run away I will shoot you!
I'm the one who did it!
So you can't make any hole!
Be careful, it's hot!
Please!
I feel a bit strange about this thing.
I think the Duke has something in his mind.He decided to return to
Scotland all of a sudden!
Hm?
If that's so, Lassie…
Could also Lassie…
Don't be silly!
You have to drill without thinking
about other things!
We have to prove to the Duke what we can do!
Probably…
If coal doesn't come out I won't
be able to buy food for him!
I mean, your wife is pregnant, eh?
So… If coal doesn't come out, it will die!
I can't even buy milk!
This is the father's responsibility!
- Do your best!
- Yes!
Yeah.
My responsability…
John!
Will you go to the mine today?
I'm sorry!
I haven't played with you lately.
But…
John, will Lassie go to Scotland?
Eh?
My father heard this from some people!
Today they will send it with the plane!
They told us there was no need
to send food to the dog tomorrow.
I'm sure that Lassie…
Tell me, can't we get
Lassie back before it leaves?
Now we can't!
John!
What does that mean?
We can get Lassie back when coal comes out!
Sorry, I have to go!
There's a lot I have to do!
John!
I see.
We will send these samples
to the laboratory for analysis!
Yes!
We need to know how many layers are displayed!
This place is called Old Coal Life.Although it is a very old layer.
However, when we know
the default age of the layers,
we could find coal more easily!
Yes!
Somehow you are better than me in this area!
No…
I will send it by mail!
Yes, I count on you!
John the selfish!
You'll travel two days by train,
it was comfortable in Yorkshire, right?
Oh, Heinz!
It's been a long time!
Have you brought with you a new animal?
Yes!
I brought it from the remote Yorkshire!
My grandfather ​​really likes dogs.
Is it a good type?
Ah, you can see that very soon, Miss!
Lassie!
This is the boy called John.
He is a good boy!
He decided to take responsibility
and give me Lassie without crying.
Priscilla…
I strongly acknowledge the will of that boy,
but if the coal doesn't come down,
Lassie will be mine!
It will be yours?
Priscilla!
I think I'll be back if I can!
But don't you think it's rude
to reunite John and Lassie
I think I'll be back if I can!
But don't you think it's rude
to reunite John and Lassiesuddenly after we agreed?
John!
Mail!
Dad said I should bring it off!
Please read it quickly!
Don't you rush so!
How were the results of the analyzes?
What is the matter?
We have not succeeded!
Eh?
Oh?
Coal is not under that layer.
There is a possibility that the result is zero.
It is rare that the result is zero!
I don't believe!
If…- Can't be that…
- John!
John.
Lassie…
Won't it be back yet?
John, be quiet!
I can't be quiet!
John, please wait!
Not only John…
We're all shocked…
Manager!
Lassie…
John?
John!
Colin and Sandy told me I'd find you here.
They were sure you are here.
This is your special place!
John, and Colin, and Sandy!
Miss Priscilla…
And also Lassie… father…
Ah!
I understood, also Lassie…!
Now… let's go!
Outside, others are waiting for you.
Waiting for me?
John!
Sandy…  Colin!
John the fool!
You don't have to think about it yourself!
Now let's go home!
Mother is also waiting for us, John.
Yes!
Why is Lassie inside on such iron sheets?
No, in fact we put these so it won't escape!
Escape?
Ah… Yes-yes!This is the best way I did
after it escaped from the Yorkshire
mansion several times!
No, of course it've been trained on this!
He got a lot of money after selling it to someone
else, and he knew he would run away again!
That's why I thought of this!
John couldn't think of something like that!
If Lassie is still waiting for John's return,
it can't remain silent!
It don't want to be patient!I can't bear it!
John… even John wants to see
Lassie without a doubt!
My grandfather doesn't understand anything!
Miss, what are you doing?
Lassie!
Do you want to go to John's place?You can go!
I can't believe!
Don't open it!
Don't open the door!
No, but open it!
What does that mean?
Let it go to John!
From faraway Scotland,
Lasie travels back to my home.
And without food…Lassie chasing unruly dogs.
This time it faces the gun!
Next episode:
"Unknown Places! Search For Lassie".
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams