Old Castle & south wind subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Keep walking towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
Back in my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
would beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
always watch over you,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari
a neverending story
Grandfather doesn't
understand anything!
Miss, what are you doing?
Lassie!
You want to go to John's place, right?
Here, you're free!
Don't open the gate!
No! Open it now!
What was that?!
Go, Lassie! To John's place!
Unknown Places!
Search For Lassie
Do you understand
what you have done?
Yes. Of course I do.
My entire family is made of fools. I was hoping
that at least you would have some brains.
Let us assume that this dog really knows
where Greenall Bridge is and is headed there.
We are in Scotland now.
It is four hundred miles away.
This is ridiculous.
I was finally able to acquire a decent dog,
and you sentenced it to death.
Acquire? That's just awful.
You can't be sure if John
fails to fulfill his promise,
and you're already thinking
that Lassie is all yours.
You told me that
you had a manly agreement.
Did you ever stop to think what would
happen if they did find new deposits?
You're absolutely right.
So why did John and Lassie
had to put up with it?
They didn't really want to be separated.
In the end, all you wanted
was to own Lassie.
Priscilla…
The road ahead of Lassie
will be steep and dangerous.
Not all people she's going to meet
are going to be like you,
willing to understand and love her.
You better pray
for Lassie's good luck.
Look at that, Willy!
A pretty nice dog.
It's a Rough Collie.
What do you think it's doing here?
Uh? What do you mean?
Good boy.
Wait there, yes, just like this.
It's fine. It's fine.
Good. Don't run anywhere.
No need to fear us.
Just stay still.
Very well. Good doggie.
You ready?
– Willie!
– Yeah.
Damn! Wait!
It must be a runaway
from the Duke's house!
Damn it!
Where is it hiding?
We'll get a good bonus
if we catch that dog.
Hell, I'm sure it's hiding
here somewhere.
Ah! There it is!
No, not with the stones!
If we hurt it, it'll be worthless!
But we can't catch it like this.
Lemme think.
What? A message? For me?
Who is it from?
Guess who.
Stop teasing and just tell me.
Here.
Priscilla Radling?
Ah, it's from Scotland!
It's from Priscilla!
Did she write about Lassie?
Lassie…
She escaped from
their manor in Scotland.
Huh?
When she fled the manor,
she ran straight south.
There are people who saw
Lassie heading south.
To the south…
That doesn't mean anything yet.
No, if she goes south,
she'll reach Yorkshire, Mom!
Lassie wants to return home!
Just a moment, John…
All right! I have to go!
Just a moment, John!
We must find coal,
one way or another.
I will do everything so that Lassie doesn't
have to go anywhere when she returns.
John…
How's it going, master?
The famous Loch Ness Monster
will simply not come out.
A monster would be really good.
That's just another bleak landscape.
A bit boring, no?
Not really.
I found something
interesting today.
You mean the dog over there?
It's been sitting there forever,
staring beyond horizon.
Perhaps there's something precious
to that dog on the other side of the lake.
You're quite
a romantic, aren't you?
What is it doing?
Looks to me like
it wants to cross the lake?
What?
What a dog!
What's there on the other side
that it went across the lake?
I don't know.
All I know it must be something
very dear to it.
Indeed.
So I went and said,
"here, you can have one".
I had to be specific, otherwise
Jimmy would eat the whole thing.
You're too funny, Annie.
I bet in the end
Jimmy ate everything.
Yeah, he did.
Here.
It's okay, you can have it.
They're just leftovers, anyway.
Here. Have a bite.
What a good-mannered guy.
It's okay.
John, I have published
an ad in the newspaper.
Anyone who sees a beautiful brown
Collie dog may contact me for a reward.
Oh?
Yes. So it matched the description
published in the newspaper?
Where is it now?
Yes.
I noticed that Lassie
was heading straight south.
To be specific, she was
heading straight towards London.
John.
Lassie continues
heading to your town.
The picture I sent is from Loch Ness in Scotland.
She was standing in that exact spot.
Lassie…
No! It'll bite us!
Got ya!
Caught you, you dirty dog!
Damn that mutt,
not knowing when to give in.
Stop struggling!
What's with it?
It calmed down all of the sudden.
Well, let's get it in the car.
Oh? There it is!
Unbelievable.
It fled into the court!
The defendant
can call his first witness.
Oh, my. Is that your witness?
I terribly apologize.
We'll catch it in a moment.
Good heavens! What a dog!
Dad, quick! It's here!
Damn, it's here
to attack the sheep again?
Look, there's another one!
– Did I hit it?
– Not sure.
Maybe it was
just your imagination.
It's not like that.
I'm certain I heard some noise
coming from right there.
It sounded like a hurt animal.
Well, if you say so.
Oh, that's awful.
What did you find?
Come and see.
It's a big dog.
Who did this to you?
You poor thing…
This wound was
inflicted with a gun.
Who would shoot at
such a miserable dog?
Maybe it was Tommy.
He came to repair the radio last week.
I heard that they had a problem with a dog
that assaulted their flock.
So this dog was
attacking their sheep?
No, that's not right, Dan.
This dog cannot attack sheep.
Is it your woman's intuition again?
Sometimes things are
different than it seems.
I know you agree with me,
otherwise you wouldn't let it in.
Hmm, maybe you're right.
John!
Are you still sleeping?
The breakfast is ready!
Okay, I'm coming!
Lassie was way ahead of you.
She wants to play already.
What?
Maybe she's full of energy now,
but she's always sleeping.
How are you feeling now?
I brought you some warm milk.
Here, have a sip.
You feed her our milk?
No wonder the bottles are all empty.
You can have a breakfast
without milk from time to time.
Good grief.
What Englishman
drinks tea without milk?
Looks like I'm
the only one complaining.
Oh, you can stand now.
It's been four days
since we found you.
Darling, close the door.
Purcell will come out.
Purcell, I know you can walk again.
But you need to be patient.
Come to think of it…
Ever since Danny went to war,
there's been only the two of us
living in this house.
Darling, you treat Purcell
like she was human.
You're the one to talk.
She'll be fine.
With her, we'll never have to worry that she'll
go to Belgium for war and never come back.
You're right.
This picture was taken
a week ago in a court.
After that there weren't
any sightings of her.
But I'm sure she's in good health
and continues her journey.
Lassie…
Where are you?
Purcell?
Don't open the door, Dan!
Purcell. You can't go out yet.
Your wound hasn't healed yet.
Purcell…
Please, don't make us sad.
We'd be very sad if you got sick.
Just a little longer, okay?
I'm coming in.
Okay, darling. It's fine now.
Today as well?
Yes, she does that
at three o'clock, every day.
Specifically at three o'clock…
What could she want?
I still look out the window.
Listen, John.
Lassie will come home in no time, then she'll
be sitting right there, at 3 o'clock sharp.
Yeah.
And that, as they say, is that.
Right, Purcell?
It was a funny story, wasn't it?
Purcell… you poor thing.
Today's oatmeal
is a little hardened.
Dan.
Hm? What's the matter?
I have a feeling that
she might not be happy here.
Your woman's intuition again?
It's not just a hunch.
I'm fairly certain
you've noticed it too.
You're worrying too much.
Even if her eyes are a bit teary,
it's just that something got in them.
Frankly she reminds me
of the times when Danny was born.
I feel the same.
But why don't you let her
go out for a walk?
When Danny was little, you loved
walking with him in the forest so much.
But Purcell has hurt her leg—
You know very well that
her injury has become much better.
Aren't you just afraid that once you let
her out, she won't be coming back?
She seems to be traveling
to a certain place.
Our house is just a stop
to rest for a moment.
She is clever and grateful, so she
won't go anywhere until we let her.
We may be hurting her
without knowing.
But it will be okay.
We have lived
a long and fruitful life.
Yes.
It's okay to go back to living
with just the two of us.
Even before Purcell came,
you and I were always happy.
Yes. You're absolutely right.
Come here, Purcell.
No… You have
a different name, don't you?
If you have to go,
now's the time, girl.
Be careful.
It's okay. You can go.
Be happy, wherever you go.
Yes. That is very important.
We made the right decision, right?
Yes. We did.
We found in the mine
something that gave us hope.
But we still don't know
Lassie's whereabouts.
Good luck, Lassie.
We will definitely get you back!
Next episode:
"Welcome Back, Lassie".
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams