Old Castle & south wind subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Keep walking towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
Back in my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
would beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
always watch over you,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari
a neverending story
Lassie!
Don't go this way!
Crossing this river
is too dangerous!
Lassie!
A dream?
Right.
It was just a bad dream.
Welcome Back, Lassie
John.
There were no reports
of Lassie sightings today either.
She was last seen in
West Darlington, three days ago.
But I strongly believe that Lassie is safe
and will arrive to your town soon.
Don't worry, Priscilla.
Lassie is healthy
and she's on her way home.
I've been thinking about Lassie
all night long again.
Even the results… from the laboratory…
said our chances aren't zero.
Yeah!
We can do it.
We'll find that coal, Dad!
When I see these two working,
their enthusiasm kinda rubs off on me.
Yeah.
Alright! We won't lose to them!
Yeah!
Ah? Sandy…
How are you feeling?
I'm just hopeless…
What are you talking about?
Here, a gift for you.
Thank you.
Why am I always like this?
Getting sick and all
when it matters the most.
I'm ashamed of myself.
I can't help John at all.
I know how it's like.
I feel the same, to be honest.
All I can do is make tea
for the miners when they're on a break.
Yeah.
John is working so hard,
he's like an adult man…
Ah!
But Sandy, your sweets are very delicious.
I'm sure everyone is happy to have them.
Thank you.
John…
He must be dying
to go looking for Lassie,
and yet he's holding back
to do his best helping at the mine.
I'm sure he won't ever
let her go again once she returns.
I've always liked how Lassie and John
were running around everywhere.
That sight always cheered me up
somehow, and I wanted to join them.
I wish we could do something.
But what can we do?
All right, everyone!
Time for your tea!
Oh? What did you bring today?
Something to give you
energy, a meat pie!
I started to look forward
to this moment every day!
All right, take a break!
How is it?
Yes, it was delicious. Thanks!
What? You already ate?
John?
Yes?
I can't help much here,
but I do what I can.
"Can't help much"?
You're doing everything you can.
What is that?
A week?
Yes.
This is all I could get from him.
Wellington Coal Mine has reached its limit.
The Duke said he won't be pumping
any more money into the mine.
We did what we could,
and still haven't found the coal.
Maybe it really is time to give up?
But a week? That's ridiculous.
Sam.
We have to inform
everyone about this.
We should give them as much time
as possible to let them make arrangements.
I haven't told John
about any of this yet.
Do you want me to tell him?
I'm not sure if I can do it, though.
No, I'm going to do it.
I think he'll understand.
John has grown up a lot lately.
I hope you're right.
What's the matter
with the manager?
I heard he wants to tell us something
important. Doesn't happen very often.
Finally, the end of the road, huh?
Hey, he's here.
Everyone, I'd like you to listen.
The manager has
something to tell you.
See? Strange, right? That rock.
I extracted it from the wall.
Sandy!
This is… I think that's…
Can you bring me that book?
The one with the yellow cover.
Huh?
Clean this place up
sometimes, will you?
This one?
No, the other one…
The third from the top.
Yes, this one! That's it!
What's this about?
There!
There it is. An ammonite.
What?
This is huge!
What do you mean?
This is huge, Sandy!
What's the matter?
Sir, just tell us what's going on.
We're ready for everything
you're going to say.
Sir, should I speak
with them instead?
Sorry.
The words just aren't coming out.
Listen up.
Well…
Err…
How to put it…
What I wanted to say is…
You probably already know
what I'm about to say.
Sir!
Sir, you need to hear this!
It's serious!
What's going on?
Why were you running?
Well, it's because…
What did you say?
What's that?
See? It's a critter from the same
geological age as the coal in the mine.
It's called an ammonite.
Which means…
What does it mean?
The coal we mined came from
fossilized trees that had grown long ago.
This clam comes from the—
It's not a clam!
Ammonites look a bit like clams,
but they're entirely different organisms.
In any case, this creature lived
in a time very close to the time
when the tree
that made the coal grew.
So it's possible we'll find
more coal in the vicinity?
Yes. It's possible.
All right! This is our mine.
No matter what anybody tells us,
we've gotta dig! Dig as far as we can!
Yeah!
Ah, Colin!
Hey, John… Come on.
Thank you, Colin.
I did nothing.
It was Sandy who discovered it.
But I thought
it was just a dumb rock.
Be proud of yourself!
Hey! We found something more!
Is it coal?
No, it's another fossil.
It's a fossil, but…
What could it be?
It looks huge.
What are your thoughts,
Professor?
It is a great pleasure for the scientific world
to have a complete skeleton of Eryops,
which is considered one of
the most important ancient relics.
We heard that the mine
is closing today.
In my previous geological survey
I had established
the possibility to find more coal
to be extremely slim.
I concluded at the time that
a shutdown would be the best option,
but I would like to report to Duke Radling
that it is no longer the case.
That is all. Excuse me.
Thank you so much.
No. You should thank the children.
That's right.
Oh? Where's John, by the way?
He's at the bottom of the shaft
with Mr. Beal and everyone.
He's done more than enough.
He wants to continue
until the very end.
John.
Hm?
You can stop.
I'll handle the rest.
Okay, but…
John! Get over here now!
What is it, Mr. Beal?
What's up?
We've finally done it, John.
We did it!
We finally did it!
We found more coal!
Yeah!
Well done, John.
This means Lassie can
come back to me, right?
John?
Now that we've done it,
I feel sort of sleepy…
I'm glad I trusted you, Dad.
I'm just… so very…
Sleepy.
Lassie…
John.
He can finally relax a bit.
We should let him sleep.
Do we know anything
about Lassie's whereabouts?
We've received a message from Priscilla,
but there was no news of her.
Figures.
Lassie…
Wait, Lassie!
Lassie.
From now on,
we can always stay together.
No… That's not right.
Lassie hasn't come
back home yet.
I wonder where is she?
What kind of places
is she traveling to now?
Lassie!
Where did you go, Lassie?
Where are you now?
When will I see you?
Lassie!
Lassie…
I'm so sorry I made you
go through all of this.
John?
Priscilla?
Did you sleep well?
They flew here
all the way from Scotland.
They flew?
How long was I sleeping?
Two days straight.
What?
Was I really sleeping all that time?
John.
Congratulations.
I'll be frank with you.
When I made that deal with you, I never
imagined you'd actually find a new deposit.
You have done an outstanding job.
I am truly impressed by your victory
and bow my head to you.
However…
I apologize.
I promised you that
I would give Lassie back.
But I am unable
to keep that promise.
As you already know, Lassie has—
Right! Lassie!
I have to go greet her!
Lassie is still walking
towards our town.
Ah…
I'm gonna change. Please get out.
– John!
– What's gotten into you, John?
Listen close, John.
If Lassie returns, it will be
nothing short of a miracle.
Grandfather!
It had to be said. I am sorry, but I am not
a man who beats around the bush.
You're wrong.
Lassie is on her way.
That's… uh…
I saw her! I saw her coming here.
You saw her?
But… Where are you going?
Isn't it obvious?
To the north side.
When Lassie left Scotland,
she headed straight toward this town!
Hey, John.
Oh? Where are you going?
To see Lassie!
What?
I'm going to greet Lassie.
She's gonna arrive here soon!
Huh?
North side. North side.
North side!
This is the right direction.
If I go down this path,
I'll meet Lassie!
Lassie…
Lassie!
No, Lassie! Wait!
Lassie.
This way! John went this way.
Are you okay, Lassie?
We're almost home. Can you walk?
Hey!
John!
Lassie!
Lassie…
Lassie.
Welcome back, Lassie!
The Wellington Coal Mine
is back in business!
Ah! Look over there!
John! Lassie!
Dad! Mom!
Look, everyone's here
for you, Lassie!
Hey!
Lassie came back to the town
after a long, long way.
Her adventure was taken up by the press
and she became popular throughout the UK.
Duke Radling decided
to throw a big party for us, but…
The last episode:
"Run Towards Your Dreams".
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams