RUNNING TOWARDS THE DREAM
Father! Mom!
- Come on!
- Yes!
- Ah!
- Oh!
Lassie!
Ah...!
Lassie...
Lassie was walking for a long time...
It's normal to fall after
walking all this distance!
It lost all its energy after it returned to us!
Mom, do you think Lassie...?
It will be fine.
Although it came from Scotland up to here!
It has no strength.
It has to recover slowly.
Lassie...
Lassie did all this for us...
Yes.
Grandfather...
In any case, we'll take
Lassie to John's house!
Yes!
Oh?
Ian!
Can you carry Lassie home, Ian?
And now, here is your home!
Lassie, sleep peacefully...
I won't send you anywhere!
For this you shall rest assured!
It's asleep!
Yes.
After it sleeps well, it will reactivate!
And so, we have to go back!
It returned after walking 600 miles!
It's an unreasonable distance for it!
That dog...
It returned and it completely
destroyed his hair and body!
Grandfather!
Grandfaher, are you still thinking
about taking Lassie?
No!
I mean that the dog's hair
was affected by rain and mud.
I was trying to say it is a great dog!
Yes!
- We go too!
- Take care of it!
Yes!
Thank you!
It sleeps deeply.
That's great, John!
Yes.
His body is tired so it
may not walk for a while.
You should take good care of it.
Yes!
xxx
John, breakfast is ready!
I change my clothes now!
It is still sleeping on the kitchen floor!
Good morning!
Have you slept well, Lassie?
Come on!
Lassie, it's breakfast!
Its body is too tired,
so it can't eat by himself!
I'll feed you, Lassie!
Lassie...
Lassie!
Hey!
He will be fine.
It slept again!
It feels comfortable when it is on your feet.
Hello!
How is Lassie?
Yes...
It woke up, but it was hard for it!
It should get well slowly.
But his ear was completely destroyed!
You've got a travel badge!
Hm, but this is very good!
In this way the rich man Rudling will not
put eyes on him, and he will keep them shut!
Yes!
I don't care about the shape at all!
What is important is to be with me!
Well, do your best!
Try a little more, Lassie!
Ah...
Lassie... you're gonna be fine!
Soon you can travel anywhere you want!
Bye! Good night!
Yes! Good night!
Hm?
Lassie!
You walk!
I see!
It started eating as usual!
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty the Duke of Rudling!
Hm?
Aren't you Majesty Duke Rudling?
Your Majesty, you seem to have revived the mine
as a miracle, and was about to close!
Unfortunately...
...this was not my achievement!
Oh?
If so...?
Who was it?
It's because of a boy and his dog!
No, it's not.
That dog is a Collie.
Hm...
It seems to have happened very well!
What about that?
Can't you tell me?
No. Are you a journalist?
Yeah, I'm from the London Journal...
If it is possible to tell us about
the cause of this miracle
until we publish his command in this world!
Hm!
No, it should not.
It deserves praise from all people directly.
I believe that the music
you play draws a xxx
up to the fullest of the sky
like the winds of the wind.
So put your hand on your chest and be brave!
Ah, my heart, I'm happy to be lonely!
This is all for this lesson!
It's important not to forget your homework!
Oh...
Ah!
Eh?
Ah...
Lassie!
Ah!
You have walked all this distance
and you aren't tired to meet me, Lassie!
Lassie!
Oh?
Oh, sorry! Sorry!
I understand!
It comes to you in the after noon
every day at the three o'clock!
John Carraclough!
That's right, what's up?
No, I just heard about Lassie's story
from the Duke of Rudling.
It's so great!
- xxx
- You, can you look here?
Ah...
You have to smile again!
What's going on?
It's great, isn't it?
It will be a very wonderful story!
"The boy who reopened the mine!"
And the miracle dog who
traveled a long journey!
This is why we have to publish
this story in our newspaper!
I asked the Duke!
No, I can't believe it...
Well done, can I talk to you a bit more?
What do we do, Lassie?
John!
What is it, Dad?
Have you seen the newspaper?
After work I bought it from
the Jones' store but...
I wonder where I put it?
Seriously, my father is weak...
Hm?
Is it in this place?
Yes!
You lose the things you always love!
Hm?
What's up, John?
Ah...
Father, in this newspaper...
I am there!
Eh?
Look!
John and Lassie!
The dog Lassie ​​walked 600 miles to John,
after a long reunion.
Eh?
Lassie...
You have become well known in England!
Oh?
Ah...?
Oh!
Is this from everyone to Lassie?
Yes.
After the British newspaper article,
Lassie became very impressive!
I first receive
mail of this size at once...
I'm back!
- Eh?
- I?
Dad, you came back early today!
Oh...
Ah, I'm tired...
No, I ran away.
Did you run away?
Yes.
I don't want another article to be written.
There are many journalists from
multiple companies coming to the mine.
You say Lassie?
I think the future of this dog is
different from the rest of the dogs!
Oh! Besides, didn't it do something similar?
As I recall...
When Dr. Hooper fell in the abyss,
it told us to save him!
Ah, tell us more about that!
Hey Bill!
Don't evade work!
I know that, boss...
Are you the manager?
- Uh...
- We want to talk to you for a moment!
Ah... Damn...
Even in your clinic?
And even in the mine?
Yes...
I couldn't do anything to the patients.
I was caught on.
Dr. Hooper told me not to intrude
"Don't enter the clinic"!
Ah...
But what about John?
Ah!
He has gone with Priscilla and others to play!
And also Lassie!
Aha...
You see, John? It has become
a modern newspaper!
You've become famous, John!
I'm not, Lassie is!
But when we get to this area,
no one will reach us!
Yes!
Ah!
- Ah!
- Rock Castle!
As long as Lassie is in good health,
then we can go up together!
Yes!
Hey, have you come here?
Mr. McNeill...!
Why are you here?
What? Actually I'm a journalist,
so finding this place is simple for me
In fact, I want to invite you,
John with Lassie to a party!
Eh?
- A party?
I understand!
This is your and your friends
secret rock castle!
Can you climb to the top?
Well, can you see that?
I'll take your picture.
No, it doesn't matter!
I'm busy now!
Is that right? What is that?
It's people's messages to Lassie
after they read the newspaper.
Instead of Lassie, I will read it!
Oh?
- Who who?
- Don't do it!
Isn't it audacious to read
the messages of others?
Y-yes! I apologise!
He is not our companion as well?
How long will he stay in such a place?
Hm...
- Ah!
- What is the matter?
T-t-this message!
Ah...! Wait a moment, Lassie!
I see!
You feel nostalgic, don't you?
What do you mean?
It''s a message from someone
who met Lassie on its journey!
- Eh?
To my dear Purcell
No, actually your name is Lassie, isn't it?
Dan went out to the village to sell the eggs.
He brought with him that newspaper.
As I expected, you returned after a long wait.
You also had a precious family!
We haven't mistaken to send you to them.
When you returned you were finally happy.
I am also very happy for you!
Greetings to your precious family!
It's a wonderful message!
Yes!
It's a nice message!
Lassie, you met many people on your trip!
One day I want to thank them with you!
How was it?
Isn't it happy that I wrote
about Lassie in the newspaper?
Eh... Approximately...
If only the concert is held!
These... on what occasion?
Duke Rudling said
he would organize a concert marking
the miraculous journey of Lassie,
and it would be praised there!
Of course the villagers will be invited!
Grandfather?
Also... can you call
the old couple at the party?
What's your reply?
Of course you can attend the concert together!
Ah, as or the concert,
please keep it secret from
the rest of the journalists!
Our library will work on exclusive coverage!
In the end we couldn't climb the peak...
Although Priscilla had trouble coming here...
Ah! The preparation of the day
was strictly confidential!
This is thanks to John and Lassie!
No doubt about it!
Is everything ready, McNeil?
Yes, of course!
John and the miners are all here!
I'm sure the equipment
will appeal to you!
Well now I'll look at the equipment!
I'm the one who made the journalists do
all the hype!
Because of that I thought of myself only,
and put John and Lassie under
the pressure of many people!
How do I make him trust him?
Hey hey you have to come!
How long will you work on our star for today?
This child is not nice at all!
Should I wear these?
You, don't move!
What are you talking about?
Duke Rudling has invited many
people with high positions!
You will become an apprentice
if you appear on your nature, right?
Does my usual look really pathetic?
I didn't mean that!
You have a motive so strong that
the mine is not closed because of you!
No adult can do what you do!
The Duke of Rudling admire you so much!
That is why we want to
show you in the finest form.
You have to think that this
will  make your future better!
Did you understand?
You will be treated in this
ceremony as an adult!
This clothes will not make you
jump and play in the fields!
So I rely on you!
It will change your mindset when
it takes you a beautiful picture!
Bye...!
Oh! Sir McNeill!
Hm?
Do you still want something else?
Excuse me, will Grandpa Dan
and Grandma and Dili really come?
Of course!
Today's concert will highlight the elderly
couple who helped to reunite Lassie!
Well, they seem to be a little late! See you!
Ah wait!
Hm?
Sorry... What about Lassie?
Rest assured,
it will not go anywhere!
It is decorated in the next room!
Decorated?
You mean Lassie?
The next is to brush off your hair!
Eh...!
Everything is going well!
Well, just wait!
These devices will add an amazing effect!
We have to pay attention to the guests now!
Yes!
Our sales this time will be better
because our material is full of tears!
Yes!
Oh, I'm glad to meet you!
I thought it was a good idea!
Here is the Duke!
All seem to have high positions!
Everyone came because of what they
read about Lassie in the newspaper!
Everyone is excited about John's future!
Hm...
Well you can wait here!
It took a long time because of your ear!
Isn't it nice?
They seem to have started!
When your turn comes I will tell you,
wait here!
What is this face?
Ah, I don't like this shape!
We...
They exaggerated our form, don't you think so?
In some way, I feel that it is completely wrong.
I'm the only one who found coal,
and Lassie faced death on its way?
Yes, that is true!
And now...
The story of Lassie's long journey
was full of misfortunes and fatigue!
The basis of it was his separation from John
but John...
For Greenor Bridge he swore that coal
would come out with all the power he had!
He said: Lassie! Sorry I can't come
back to you, with tears in his eyes!
I'll take full responsibility!
John was very sure he would
extract coal for the village!
It was here that Lassie decided
to return to whatever the way!
Now let me introduce to you,
Miracle dog Lassie, and its owner John!
Eh?
Oh?
What is happening?
They have not yet appeared.
What happened to John?
Actually this message...
Damn, they run away!
Duke of Rudling,
I'm still unable to enter the world of adults.
I still want to run with Lassie
and the others in the fields!
That's it!
I apologize to everyone, despite the fact
that they have struggled to come here,
John Carraclough...
I'm Remy!
I sing!
No, I'm not alone!
Because I have a lot of nice friends!
But, where is my mother?
Mom!
"HOMELESS GIRL REMY"
Please look forward!