FOLLOW THE SUSPICIOUS MAN
Hm?
Hey... just a moment!
Ah! Oh...!
How is he doing?
He is fine.
After he eats enough food
he will get better soon.
I don't know his identity, but I apologize
because I looked at his luggage.
Do you know where he came from?
No...
It's huge...!
One, two...
Oh...!
Ah...!
Whoa!
Oh...!
He waked up! Mom!
I see...!
You're looking for work.
You travel a lot, but as long
as you're physically fit
you can do a lot of work,
don't you?
This is very bad...
Hm?
What's wrong?
Sometimes I feel bad.
Is that so?
And now well...
Tell me, what will he do now?
He will stay in our house for
a while until he gets better.
Then where will he go?
After that, that's right!
He will find a place to stay if he works here.
What? You don't have to be so depressed!
My colleagues at work are good people!
Don't worry, Ian!
Ian?
Ian Cooper!
This is his name!
Is that it?
You chose the man you
found falling in your way?
In the future, we will rely on this work!
Doesn't he look great in his work?
We can't say it's just great.
Even if the four vehicles are empty,
they are still made of iron!
Oh really!
He has an amazing power!
His arms look like they were made of iron!
Hey, Ian!
If you have finished pushing the carts,
bring the shovels here!
Shovels?
Look, it's in that box near the warehouse!
I brought the shovels.
Oh!
You also brought the box?
Yes.
I was very surprised!
No one can carry all the shovels
inside the box, right?
But, he carried the box with all
the shovels! What a rare person!
Is it really amazing?
Yes!
Hm... um?
That man is much bigger than you!
It's up to this size!
We are detectives.
Ian Cooper...
Mr. Carraclough seems
to have brought a good person.
Even though we hear some
strange words about him.
If we rely on him,
our work will be much easier!
That man was seen
by an employee at the mining office
last week as he was on his way...
It seems to be him.
Seemingly?
I feel it's definitely him!
When we find a phone we will
contact the head office immediately!
Yes!
Hey! Uncle!
Hm?
Is this car you, Uncle?
Yes.
There is nothing inside, really nothing.
Uncle, are you a merchant?
Merchant?
What? Am I wrong?
There are none other than the wandering
hyenas who come to this village in this way.
I asked if you were among them!
- We...
- Walter!
Oh?
There is no time to talk with children!
I apologize very much!
A detective?
He's a policeman!
Something might have happened.
News this evening:
Last Thursday, a criminal has robbed
London Bank and it's still at large.
The scope has been expanded
in England to look for
to solve this serious issue...
- "That's it!"
- Says about a bank.
Well yes... Is that all?
Yes. Thanks, this will help us!
Detective!
That man that we talked about
before was here at the time.
That's what I thought!
I have worked at the police headquarters for 15
years, it's impossible for me to make a mistake!
I felt where he was now...
Why not take an insight into it?
The police of England
must arrest the bank robber!
Yes!
Bank robber?
The bank robber is in this village?
What is wrong with you?
Hm?
What is the matter?
Nothing!
Ah!
It's the right building!
Thanks!
Why are they heading towards the mine?
Wait, Lassie! Don't do it!
Hm?
Is it here?
Therefore, the store owner said completely.
But there is no light!
Is he outside?
Just watch!
Okay!
What? It's the warehouse!
What do they want from such a place?
Light was turned on!
I knew it!
Learn wisdom from me before uttering any word!
Yes!
Oh my God, my God, almost extinguished!
You have got a suitable place.
How do you like it?
Is it okay to live here?
I apologize because I have no other room,
you can use it as you like!
Yes.
As for the food order,
you can go to Richard's shop,
which I told you about,
and I can bring it to you if you tell me.
Yes.
If the purposes are insufficient
or difficult, feel free to tell me!
You can rely on me!
Yes.
He looks like the real criminal!
Hm!
See you again tomorrow!
I can't make mistakes!
He's the real criminal! No doubt about it!
Oh ah!
Ah...
Father!
Yes?
About the Ian's command...
Yes!
He's so good at the work in the mine!
Yes...
What is the truth about him?
What's up, John?
Your face seems strange!
Is there something that worries you?
This...
You too heard the rumors?
In fact I think all this is nonsense.
Of course I too heard those rumors about Ian.
But when I heard that
I thought it was important
to take more care of him.
Yes.
That's a bit strange...
but that guy is really good!
When I met Ian,
I thought that that person was terrifying.
You heard bad words about him, didn't you?
People become more terrified
when they talk bad of the others,
so they seem to have a lot of enemies.
It's painful to misunderstand him.
Isn't that true?
Maybe the police officers misunderstood
him because they didn't know him well!
But if he was the bank, he really would...
I don't know!
Certainly the police will find the truth!
That's why I will not interfere!
But...
What if Ian is really a criminal...
My father will be sad...
He hasn't moved yet...
That's what I thought!
He thinks this place is his best hiding place.
In such a simple place,
no evidence will be left behind!
What would you do if you don't
find any evidence against him?
I will depend on you!
Oh?
Tomorrow I will leave it to you.
Oh!
What about you, detective?
Hm!
Well, just watch me!
I will set a trap in this city for that man!
Good morning, Sam!
Good Morning, Ed!
Good morning, Kevin!
Ah! Good morning, Ian!
He's a really big man!
Ian Cooper.
Did he do something bad?
No, just that London police are looking for
someone who looks like him!
Can he be a bank robber as the rumors say?
Oh!
It seems that this man
has found a good job here.
Yes.
Whoever goes, he will never
be released from prison!
Prison?
No, I didn't mean anything!
Sorry!
Is there a mine?
Does your husband work in the mine too?
Yes!
I worry about him!
John!
John! John!
Eh... eh?
We've agreed to pick up
some berries today, right?
Uh-uh...
Sorry.
I'm a bit busy!
Uh?
John left...
Hm...
Where are you going?
Oh?
Where he goes?
Lassie...
Oh!
He disappeared...
What? It's you, Lassie?
Hey, where is he going?
Oh!
Ian?
Ah! A knife?
Ah-ah ah!
Did the police come to your house as well?
Yes!
This is what they told to my family!
Did he really participate in the bank robbery?
Maybe we'll be deceived by
the bank robbery, I'm worried!
Hey!
Oh!
He has a criminal record!
Oh?
He had to bring that man here!
You may be right!
He is a criminal.
What does Mr. Carraclough think?
Hey!
Is there a problem with my father?
No, nothing at all!
Welcome back, John!
What is the matter?
Dad, I want to talk to you a bit!
About Ian...
Ian has come here.
I invited him to dinner because
he worked hard today!
It is very delicious!
Of course, because it's taboo!
Ian, do you want another bowl?
Yes!
What's up, John?
You are quiet.
Yes.
Yes!
Hello, is that you?
Mr. Carraclough!
What is the matter?
Sir Carraclough, when I left,
something bad happened!
The manager has lost his golden watch!
Mr. Carraclough, that man you brought
is the real thief!
That man?
It's Ian!
We have been deceived!
You, what are you doing here?
Ian is here.
Eh?
Anyway, get out of here.
What did Ian do?
Did you hear that from the police?
Grandma Forrest heard about
of the strange rumor they had published.
They are here now.
You!
Oh?
Why do you accuse Ian of criminality?
Do you have any evidence?
That's right, leave the rest to us!
We can have you arrested.
Why did you accused Ian being
a criminal by spreading rumors?
What would you do if he is innocent?
I won't stop from discovering the truth!
But stop spreading doubts
among the villagers!
That's it!
Hm!
You can come back now!
- Father!
- Yes.
I have seen him...
Ian had a knife.
I know, it was part of the luggage.
Eh?
John, you also have a knife, right?
And I'm the one who gave it to you.
Yes.
That's right!
Those people have just
listened to our conversation.
Yes, but...
Quick, after them!
Yes yes!
It will be good to be the thief.
I'll catch him...!
I'm going!
Listen, Lassie!
I don't know the truth yet.
I have to trust Ian!
This is because he works hard with my father!
What's up, Lassie?
I'll be late for school!
Lassie, wait!
Please enter!
Why the police come early in the morning?
Hasn't your boss come yet?
Not yet.
Can we wait here for him to come?
Please enter.
You can wait in the manager's office, there.
Eh...
By the way, what questions should we ask him?
Hm!
You are the detective!
This is bad!
To do something like that!
Just close your mouth!
Perhaps the man in the next room notices us!
Hey Lassie!
Oh...
Maybe this is it!
What do you mean?
I was right!
It's not good to forget such
an important thing here,
what a terrible man!
I'll tell them we have found the watch.
No, don't tell to the people!
Oh?
However I will inevitably catch him!
It's bad!
Ian has been arrested!
Ian was arrested for stealing the golden
watch as the interrogator accused him!
That guy is not bad!
Lassie, I'm sure there is something!
Next episode:
DETECTING THE INNOCENCE OF IAN
Be sure to watch!