GOODBYE LASSIE
Was its owner using this boat?
That's because I found its leash in this boat.
When I read the name written on it,
it replied immediately.
Isn't it, Lassie?
You see?
Grandpa!
Oh, is it you, John?
Don't you know who owns that boat?
Huh?
Ah, that one...
That was here just a few days ago.
Maybe it has no owner.
I knew when I looked at it.
The boat's rope was cut off, indicating
that the owner was running away.
Eh?
Perhaps not to run away,
I think the rope it teared by itself.
Maybe so.
In fact I don't know
the answer to your question.
Where did this boat come from?
I wish I could find the answer!
Tell me, where did you came from?
Is it wise to move it?
But we must find the owner!
Oh!
Me too!
Because, if we know where it came from
we may find the mother of Lassie.
Isn't it?
I understand, if you find the owner
you will give it back.
We have no other choice!
We have no other choice...
True, if Lassie lives with its mother,
it will live happily ever after.
Maybe you are right.
It's an airplane!
The delivery goods that were
in my house are on the plane now.
My father is a contractor.
I remembered, I met you for the first time
when I saw the plane flying.
If the plane wasn't there,
I would't meet Lassie.
This is the school road!
That bridge we always see!
What?! John and Colin!
Where did you get this boat?
Isn't it great?
We are going to Lassie's mother!
Eh?
Have you found the owner of the puppy?
Not yet!
But I'm sure we'll find Lassie's mother!
Wait for me! I'll go with you!
Wait! Listen to me!
There is the backyard of the houses!
Yes!
First time I see it!
I saw him, I saw him!
John!
Mr. Curry!
She's so beautiful, teacher!
The village looks quite different by the river.
Yes!
Dr. Hooper!
Hello, you're Carraclough's son, isn't it?
That's a good boat!
Yes, but...
This remainds me... what was it?
I remembered, I saw a puppy on board
of this boat two or three days ago.
Dr. Hooper, have you seen it before?
Yes, it came on this river.
John!
Yes!
Doctor, thank you very much!
Hey, it's important not to tell
your mother that you saw me here!
What is it? You are a coward!
Let's go!
We crossed a long distance...
How long we'll continue this way?
Oh...
It's a steamer!
Lassie!
Wait for me!
Hey!
Lassie!
This is dangerous, Lassie!
If you cross this road, you will be crushed!
What is it with this wheel?
John!
Hey John!
Look here! This rope!
It's the same rope as on the boat,
it's cut in the same shape!
Well that means...?
Look, the two ropes are exactly the samel!
So Lassie was coming from here?
We are going to find your mother soon!
We finally found her!
Hey, it's so annoying, so annoying!
You two! Children, you are making
noise around other people's houses!
Hey! It's my boat that I lost!
Eh... eh?
Well, we came to look for
the owner of this boat!
It's the truth!
Whatever...
Hm?
What's with this puppy?
Sorry for this... sorry...
Isn't that Lassie?
Eh?
This means...
Uncle, do you know anything about Lassie?
Of course I know, because it's mine!
What is the matter?
Do you want to say this again?
No, I understand, I will return it immediately!
But...
What is the matter?
It stayed with me for a while
after it almost crumbled
under the feet of the sheep.
So please let me say goodbye.
Hm!
I will give it some time.
When you finish it, bring it to me!
This is great, Lassie, we've found your owner!
Lassie...
Give your mother a lot of love.
Take care of yourself, Lassie.
I won't forget you!
Come on, now go to your mother!
Hey go! Don't you want to meet your mother?
Hey!
Lassie, not that way!
I understand, you bastard!
I will do it immediately!
Oh, the child!
Don't play here, move right away!
This is not a place to play!
I understand, I'll do it right away!
The water level must rise quickly!
Shut up, our steam pump is not...
Damn, I have no time for this!
Hey kid!
Come here and help me!
Listen Lassie, this is just a wheel,
so you have to go to your owner!
Look!
So pull more and work hard, kid!
What is the matter? Can't you move it?
What do you do?
Close the gate to raise the water level!
This side must be closed
when this ship comes...
We must send the high water
to the opposite side!
What is the matter? Have you closed it?
It's closed.
But, why do you do that, Colin?
I did this because the uncle
asked me to do so, to use my force.
What is the matter?
Kid, have you called this puppy?
And as it looks, they can leave now!
Are you okay?
I still want to rest more...
Pff...
You can't do anything!
Are you satisfied with this now?
And don't you think of coming here again,
go away!
Uncle, will you use it for guarding?
Don't ask about things that don't concern you!
Do you live here alone?
Yes.
Don't you have a family other than this puppy?
What's wrong with that?
If there is no other choice for us...
Well get here immediately!
If you'll do bad things, I'll eat you!
You must open the rest of the gates quickly!
Wait!
I'm sure that man knows
how to behave with the poor Lassie.
I hope so, but...
I found it, I should tell him so!
John?
What is it? You are the child
who came earlier!
What do you want?
Sorry...
Lassie drinks milk from a child's bottle.
So...
So what?
But you try to train it to eat from the dish.
So... sorry...
You, uncle, will you...
How long will you keep bothering me?
I have no time to train it!
If it doesn't drink milk
by its own, is it over!
Is it over? What do you mean?
I don't know, how will I know?
What should I do?
Well, this world is not that easy!
John...
Hm?
Come on, let 's go back...
Eh...?
Listen, John, let's go back...
But that sounds fun!
Ah, it worked!
Don't look at my house!
What is it, why do you look
at other people's houses?
But I was surprised!
That an amazing machine like this
could be found in someone's house!
Would you let me look at it a bit?
I will not!
I told you not to look!
What?
What is the matter?
Don't do that!
It's not here!
Not here too!
You have to leave immediately, kid!
Sorry, is there a house for the dog?
Huh?
A dog house? There is no such thing!
Hey? No house for the dog?
Where did it go?
What do you want from me?
I don't have time for your likes!
Get away from me!
I said no!
What would you do if a ship
passed by and didn't notice?
Another question? Stop that!
Hey, listen to me, uncle!
I want to ask you something else!
Stop it!
It's important!
John, enough, let 's go back!
But... it's really important!
I will answer only one question!
What is it?
Excuse me, what do you have
to eat for today, uncle?
How are you?
Is this what you wanted to ask?
Yes!
It's canned food!
Canned food?
Yes, today canned food
and every day canned food!
I don't have time to cook
so my food is just like that!
Hey, this is great...
It's not like it's good, there's no food to eat.
Kid, why are you interested by my food?
If you don't have food to eat,
you may have to eat Lassie!
What?
If you think I'll really eat the puppy?
I can't eat it!
Maybe this is the truth but...
But I don't see Lassie's mother here.
Eh?
You don't see Lassie's mother here?
Where is Lassie's mother?
I didn't eat it, because I don't do that!
Uncle! I don't see it! Tell me!
I want to find Lassie's mother
and bring it here!
Why isn't it here?
The puppy's mother is really not here?
Yes, I looked around the place thoroughly.
He's a liar! He's not the owner of Lassie!
I'm not a liar!
I hate lying!
It's because of that driver!
The driver...
Driver! Yes, that wheel...
Do you know that, kid?
No, but it was strange of Lassie
to smell that wheel...
A few days ago there was
a car on this road with a flat tire.
He is said he was coming from a foreign
country and was accompanied by a Collie dog.
When the driver fix his car,
this puppy fled away.
He couldn't find it.
The port was far away and
he couldn't stay any longer
so he decided to leave it alone.
He also asked me to take care of it.
You understand, this puppy belongs to me now.
He left it under my care,
so I have no other choice.
Stop with that bark!
You can't take care of it at all!
You have to promise me
that you will take good care of it!
Stupid, in such a place...
What are you doing, kid?
I thought it would grow better with you,
but if I left Lassie with you, it would die!
For sure...
I mean you wanted to take care of it
instead of someone like me?
No!
No? Don't lie!
I'm not a liar!
And now stay there!
You want to take care of it
until it grows up?
I won't!
You are a honest kid!
He made me go and come with no reason...
John, are you okay?
Well, don't come here again!
I want to take care of the puppy!
Go, liar!
I can't do that before you promise me!
Fool!
Oh! John!
I can't leave you now, grab it!
No, I won't do that before you promise me
to take good care of Lassie!
This time is not appropriate for that!
I won't bother you again if you promise me!
Insubordination will only make matters worse!
Don't try to contradict me anymore!
Look, it's a ship!
If you continue your stubbornness,
you will regret it!
I understand, I promise you!
Lassie!
This uncle lives alone, so stay with him!
Hm!
As if it would understand!
Oh...
It's yours!
But I brought it to you
because you are its owner!
It's true that I have made you a promise...
But if you are so proud of it
then you can take care of it.
It's annoying, it likes you
so I'll leave it to you!
Come to the hut again, all three of you!
You will taste some sea-food!
Be sure to come!
Yes, we'll certainly come!
Now Lassie, let's go home!
You'll be getting hot milk, come on!
Tomorrow is my mother's birthday.
But my father lost his salary.
He can't bring any gift.
Lassie, you'll find it with your smell!
Next episode:
MY FATHER'S SALARY
Be sure to watch!