SANDY STEALS COWS?
Like this you won't depend on me!
What? Didn't you go?
I have homeworks!
My God! My God!
I see.
You want milk.
I apologize for walking all this distance, but...
You know, Lassie...
I can't give you milk today.
Hm?
Look!
There's no milk!
Eh?
I thought it would be okay
when I relied on Lassie...
Hm?
What is that?
A message?
What?
The milk has been ended.
But that huge cow...
The milk placed in the soup would taste better.
We have no other choice.
What? Where are you going?
To Sandy's house!
Hm?
What will he do with his homework?
That's great!
The cow is fine!
Yes!
I thought she was dead!
No.
But...
It can give milk when it eats well!
But?
Mm, no longer give any drop of milk.
Eh?
Don't it give milk when it eats well?
This...
A veal tries to suck without caring!
It can't drink other than its milk.
Mother's milk is its favorite!
We have no other choice.
Ah...
Dad, aren't you thinking the same thing?
It's better to be more kind...
There's nothing we can do!
You have to reach any convincing result!
Dear, if you shout aloud
our children will wake up!
Ah... children are children...
That cow is Sandy's favorite.
She also learned how to milk cow's milk.
Ah...
Sandy is very happy with her.
It's enough! Stop this talk!
I also worked hard for her!
No, that...
So you have to find some way!
Dad, are you weak in front of these things?
It's not like that.
The cow is not like pets!
If it does not help, we won't need it!
If we don't get milk,
we will not benefit from it!
Eh...
So...
I'll take it to the village.
Okay.
It's better to do that when Sandy
goes to school... okay?
What to do? What to do? What to do?
Oh?
Good morning!
Yes, good morning.
But, is that the truth?
Uh?
I heard of the presence of a thief.
What, a thief?
That's it.
xxx
The cow of my kind daughter has been stolen!
I don't forgive the cause of this concern!
How can you be sure there was a thief?
There was a lock on the outside!
What do you think of opening it?
Or do you think the cow
opened the lock and ran away?
No, I can't even imagine it.
Don't laugh!
Next time I will find a cow thief no matter
if I search inside your home!
But if there is no thief you will put
yourself in an awkward position.
This happened to me earlier.
He stole from us two cows!
We must arrest him and punish him!
Is it good to let this bad person go free?
It's not easy for me.
Well you found it! You found
any evidence and told me!
I won't cooperate with you!
Well, his saying is true.
He doesn't have any evidence.
We can't help him like that!
Damn!
Sandy, that's a problem, isn't it?
I'm worried.
This is better for my father.
Eh?
I'm worried about what he's thinking!
What a subject he wants to sell my father.
Eh?
What does that mean?
- Oh...
Eh...
Henry VII, took the subject of religiosity
in the country more seriously.
So he firmly believed that the war would work.
Henry VII entered northern
and southern Scotland...
Damn...!
Ah...!
I don't care if no one cooperates with me!
Sandy!
If you want any help from us, let us know!
Right!
Oh really?
Do you really want to help me?
Yes!
The weather is very cold.
Maybe I can't help you very much.
Don't you want to tell you a secret?
A secret?
What did you say?
Yes.
Well I'll tell you.
It's a very important secret!
Eh?
Oh!
John! Colin!
Um?
Don't tell anyone.
Sandy, what's up?
You are not Sandy we know!
Die if you tell! Okay?
I-I swear!
Yes.
Me too.
Oh...
Now I'll tell you about
my most important secret!
Yes.
Oh?
Oh!
It's the voice of the cow!
Could it be that cow?
Wait! Listen to me first!
But the thief...
Uh...
The thief...
It's me.
Eh?
You also expected this will end very bad.
Yes.
But I had no choice.
What are you going to do from now on?
I never thought of that.
I also can't think of anything.
It's better to tell your father, Sandy.
I won't do it!
My father can never help
so he didn't find any reason to feed it!
We can't do anything without
finding a suitable idea!
Let's think about it ourselves!
So we find a good idea!
What if we find no good idea?
We will find a good idea!
We will definitely find a good idea!
Yes.
Isn't it, Lassie?
The weather is good!
It's okay to stay out!
I have to be a little happier!
Eh...
Is that so?
Oh...
Will the milk come out if we pull it like this?
Yes, it must happen but...
We have done this several times.
Let's do our best!
Yes!
Oh...
What is it?
Hear its voice?
Yeah, there are some people with it!
Okay!
That's it!
This is the biggest proof
of the thief's existence!
Banson will take us there!
But that's just...
This is bad!
Let's do something!
What? What does that mean?
Aren't you sure?
Oh, I was drunk a bit at that time...
Uh...
It might be something else!
That's great!
This is our chance to take the cow away!
Yes!
Wait a moment!
Me?
There is work to be done!
- Eh!
- Oh!
I want you to go with Banson and all of us!
Eh! Oh...
Is there any objection?
No other choice!
Let's do it!
Sandy, wait!
If we don't hurry up,
people will arrive before us!
Let's hurry up!
We must catch the thief before he escapes us!
Is the thief really there?
For some reason the situation has reversed...
Hey, all of you hasten more!
Colin! Faster!
Moo, I'm sorry!
I must take you somewhere else!
And now hurry up!
Moo!
Is this the right way? Haven't you mistaken?
Yeah, maybe...
Lassie...
It's not good to stay here, is it?
What's the matter, Moo?
She won't move...!
Well, listen, Lassie.
Let's do it in the right place.
Look!
There's something here which seems lost!
Is it with?
No, no...
This is mine.
Yesterday I dropped it here.
How does a drunk like you forget
the most important thing he has?
This is not the time to laugh!
Everyone shouldn't take eyes off him!
Is it near?
I think so.
From that way? Or where?
No, but from there...?
But there...
In here!
It seems that Lassie has found something!
Isn't it, Lassie?
Ah...!
Well done, John!
In here! In here!
Everyone goes in a different way!
John did it!
This is our chance, quick!
Let's go from here, Moo!
Don't do that, Lassie!
We have to drag them to another road!
Moo!
Please!
If we stay here, my father will find us!
Moo, do you understand that?
What will happen to you?
As I expected, she can't
understand our feelings.
Is not so, is that right, Moo?
Moo's baby...
Hey, if we go this way...
- Eh?
- John, wait a moment!
Eh?
There is no way out in this direction!
Eh...
Don't know if the thief
went this way on a wire.
But the cow and its baby
can't cross this river.
Isn't it better to go back
to the previous place?
Uh?
John...
Eh...
Oh!
In here!
All of you follow me!
Don't go back to this way, Lassie!
What is the matter?
That road was blocked!
Lassie, don't go this way...
In here?
Oh? What is that? This place?
Amazing...!
Mountain grapes!
This is the best mountain grapes
we can make wine from!
Abandon the cows and milk, look at this!
Lassie!
Damn!
Follow us, follow us!
It was better to do this from the start!
Stop it, Moo!
We have to hurry up!
Ah!
Oh!
Moo!
Uncle, wait!
Wait!
Ah ah...!
Ah!
Do you understand what you've done wrong?
Moo... Moo... I wanted to save them...
I don't want you to sell it!
Sandy!
Do you think I would prefer to sell it?
Because of your help for Moo
I faced more difficulty!
You have to understand that!
I don't understand!
If you don't want to sell it, don't do it!
Father...
I hate you!
Sandy!
Uncle, can't you help Moo in any way?
You say I help her? If I could,
I have done that before!
You too! You did reckless things!
Moo's baby is about to die.
If left next to Moo,
it can never drink cow's milk.
But, maybe there is some way...
Well that's a lot... too much...
Hello, Lassie!
Has not changed yet...
Her milk has not yet come out.
I see.
You are also worried about it.
Well, you can't stay that way.
Sandy...
Lassie?
- Oh?
- Um?
Oh?
Hey!
No way!
Moo! The milk came out!
What is the matter? Why did everyone rush so?
I don't believe that!
Oh?!
You did it!
I was looking hard for these flowers!
When Sandy's father was born
we made her eat them until
her condition improved one day.
Is this a popular remedy?
Right!
Moo...
You, you know that?
Isn't it wonderful, Sandy?
No, Dad!
I can't do anything except milking!
You leave this job to me!
Silly...
Father...
I'm sorry...
My father saved a very huge man on his way.
That huge guy was working hard.
But the police came to the area strangely.
There is a thief who stole from the bank.
Next episode:
FOLLOW THE SUSPICIOUS MAN
Be sure to watch!