JOHN'S DECISION! PROTECT THE MINE
Oh, Lassie, you look busy!
Here it is, it has come!
Today it was exactly on time!
Lassie, it came, it came!
How can it know exactly when John come out?
What's up, Spinner?
Uh!
Everyone has already gone!
What's wrong?
Uh...
I will leave this school soon...
Maybe we should part.
- Eh?
What is the matter?
Your father who worked in the mine
decided to resign?
Yes.
He'll stop working at the Wellington Coal Mine.
He said he was looking for work elsewhere.
But why?
My father works harder in this business
than any other work
and this work is very good.
Hm... maybe that...
Lassie!
John is lucky!
Lassie goes with him wherever he goes!
Dad, are you there?
Where is it?
There must be another possibility!
Father!
Uh?
Ah, it's you John?
I'm is a bit busy today!
You promised to go tomorrow
for fishing because it is vacation!
- Fishing?
- Yes!
Haven't you prepared the tools? Should I do it?
Huh! That's bad!
I promised you for tomorrow already!
Are you busy?
No, I just had this pile of books
so I decided to read them!
Ah, I'm sorry, John!
I forgot that!
It's okay, but...
I've heard that the Wellington Coal Mine
is in trouble, is that right?
Oh...
What are you saying, John?
It's nothing like that!
Oh really?
Hm? Yes!
Where did you hear this talk?
From Spinner.
Spiner's father is looking for another job.
He will soon resign.
Is that right?
He is looking for another job...
Father!
Yes!
Coal output may have been
fewer recently but...
What is it? I'm sure that the next
outputs will be better!
Oh really?
- Certainly?
- Yes!
This is what the manager
and all the miners say!
We will succeed without a doubt!
I'm sure there's plenty of coal waiting for us!
I see!
That's why you read these books!
Do your best, Dad!
Yes!
We can go fishing when you
get out a lot of charcoal again!
Oh?
Yes!
- Good night!
Mom's in a night shift, let's go Lassie!
Mr. Carraclough!
Please open the door!
I have something to tell you!
We seem to be going to stop working next week.
I wonder what will happen to us
when we resume work?
Everyone is worried!
We must be patient.
Can we get the salary?
I'm doing everything I can,
so I'll talk to the president about it.
Will the coal... come out again?
Of course it will come out!
I'm sure about that!
Suppose it didn't come out?
Ah...
Let it be!
Mr. Carraclough told us it would come out!
I trust what Mr. Carraclough says!
Probably...
But my household savings are now over!
Next week we will not be able to eat...
We can believe in the work we do together!
I also expected to be just soil!
Sir, what to do?
Hm?
Sir, what's your opinion?
Of course, I can't just judge this!
I can't, but...
Huh?
Coal didn't come out! And you can't!
What to do?
This analysis is not very accurate.
Do you ask me to give you urgent
results and perhaps make a mistake?
Is that right?
So, isn't there some other way?
I can't say anything now!
I hope you dig for a longer time!
If we don't check the condition of the layer,
we will not come to a conclusion!
Thanks for your hard work!
Nothing!
Yes...
They must conclude quickly
so we won't do anything!
Yes.
Coal is supposed to exist...
This layer!
This indicates that the range
is becoming relatively narrow.
My God! My God!
But I think the coal layer is not over yet,
so we have to think of something else!
I worked in the coal mine for almost 40 years.
The results were very similar.
But this time different, the coal
didn't come out suddenly!
It's a big problem!
However, each coal layer exits
the other coal 5 yards away.
I also have the same experience.
As old people say, it's very good!
Yes!
I want to be optimistic
but this is unfortunate.
Even if it is 5 yards away, but in fact the
distance has swelled to 20 yards, right?
I think previous experiences won't work here!
There is a possibility that coal will come out
when we dig larger than the usual layers.
You, do you consider yourself a geologist?
Is it me or you?
No, I mean...
Bad! Bad! Bad!
Look here, we can rely on Mr.
At least he should be able to come here,
even though he is a university lecturer.
Yes...
Hm?
Stop, stop here quickly!
Oh!
Wait Lassie! Hey!
Oh?
This car?
Lassie!
Hm? Is it your dog?
Eh? Yes!
What is your name?
John Carraclough!
So John...
The dog looks very good!
Eh?
Thank you so much!
But... you really like it?
Ah! I like dogs very much!
Even his hair type is very good!
I brush it daily!
I see!
I apologize for interrupting you!
No problem!
I hope to see you next time!
Okay!
Actually, I like to praise you... Lassie.
I understand.
I knew what actually happened.
Hello!
Is Colin here?
He's on the second floor.
Thank you!
Although my house doesn't need
anything like that, though...
What about coal? There's no way to get it out?
I don't know!
I don't really know that!
Sorry...
Did I got any message?
No, not yet.
I see.
Have you found another job?
No.
I also expected no benefit.
It's the third time.
Don't lose hope!
I'm sure you will find
a good job in the future!
Yes...
Good morning!
What's up, everyone?
Spinner seems to have already moved!
Eh?
But he doesn't know yet when that will be!
He said that his father
suddenly found a new job.
I don't believe!
So I didn't say goodbye to him...
Everybody...
We couldn't say "farewell" to him...
John!
John and Lassie!
You won't move to another place when
your father changes his work, does you?
Is not clear?
What strange words do you say, Colin?
I can't believe it...
Hm...
- Hm?
Close?
Is this the result of the
realization of that world?
I told you that the owner is the one
who published this report.
How can a report be published because
of such a simple investigation?
We could have reached another conclusion!
You understand what I really say?
I don't have the authority to do anything.
Please understand, Sam.
I can't understand anything!
Hey Sam! Where are you going?
To the owner!
It's bad!
No way!
This is unacceptable!
But Duke...
If you look at this article, you may find the
possibilities of returning a coal mine to Wellington!
Do you think the life is simple?
Do you believe the reports of the experts
or the words of the responsible director?
Uh...
Oh...
I apologize, but I'm very busy!
But...
Do you know the number of mine workers
who despaired of coal mining?
Do you want to work quickly without interest?
They don't even know if they
can get the money or not.
Or you want to reduce the salaries of miners?
What about that? Don't you think
that it's a good idea?
By the way, is not your son's name John?
Yes...
Isn't your son's dog named Lassie?
It's a very good dog!
Yes...
I also love dogs!
Many of my folks love kennel!
What do you think?
Of course when the mine closes you
will need money for your home.
Lassie...
Can't you give it to me?
What do you think? Don't you want
to make a bargain with me?
I apologize for that, but I can't!
Why?
Lassie is the friend of my son!
Excuse me!
That is strange!
If he gave it to me, it would be
the best dog in this country!
So, will you give up?
I can't give up.
But the Duke also said in his place.
Dear, wouldn't you be able to extract coal
if you investigated more precisely?
Yes...
But...
When you came to this village you
worked at the Wellington Coal Mine
for 15 years and faced many problems.
You did your best to solve such things!
You were always getting ready for things
like that, wasn't you, Sam Carraclough?
But everyone was doing their best!
For this you work harder!
You have to work hard with everyone to finish!
Yes!
This is true!
I will check the data again!
Yes.
This is what you want!
Ah, it's you John!
- It's my father's lunch!
- Okay!
Sam is in the mine now!
In the mine? My father?
Thank you. I will keep his food in his office!
Well, he is doing his best!
Yes!
My father works in the depths
of the earth to achieve his goal.
The size is 16 and 25 inches.
The number 17!
Between them one point?
This is 8.5 inches!
8.5 inches.
Sam, don't lose to those scientists!
As expected from the hard worker,
your influence will not affect you, right?
John!
He have finally slept!
Yes!
Ah, thank you, Lassie!
How it was?
As I expected, he can't trust my studies.
- Hm...
- Uh...
Listen Lassie!
When I see my father doing this,
I wonder what outcome
he has achieved in his work?
I'm sure...
Oh?
I'm sorry!
I feel like I'm running away from you!
What are you talking about?
You have decided to make your family happy!
Take care of yourself! Okay?
Do your best, Hamilton, in your new city!
That's it, everyone!
Do your best!
Bye!
- Take care of yourself!
- Live well!
xxx
Lassie! Lassie!
Father!
I wonder who will leave next time?
Although we worked for a long
time in the mine together!
He had to listen to Sam's words!
The Duke of Rudling is the grandfather of Priscilla
He is the man who praised you, remember him?
I'm sure he'll understand if he looks at you!
I see!
You came to show me Lassie?
Good! Good!
I hate how many times
I said it's still a good dog!
- That's wrong!
- Hm?
I understood, I knew you
would say something else.
Well...
Can you listen to my father again?
Did your father ask you to come today?
My father?
No, you're wrong!
My father didn't tell me that!
When I look at my father,
I can't remain silent!
So...
Please!
Listen to what my father has to say!
No!
Why?
Listen to me, John!
I don't want to get in too much trouble!
All I have to do is shut down the mine!
It is impossible to rely
on the results of unreliable investigations!
This is how you handle things!
Do you have anything else?
Do you think I'm wrong?
I'm glad you're a smart boy
who understands the situation!
But I still want you to reconsider that!
No!
Oh?
It's not possible!
But you will not know
that coal will come out or not
before you try again!
I don't have money to build
a big palace like you, Duke!
I don't own a car!
But even though all this is destined for me,
I will do anything to keep
the Wellington Coal Mine!
You say you can take responsibility?
Eh?
Responsability?
Do you know that I'm talking about
a serious and important subject
that concerns the fate of many people?
I know perfectly well.
That is why all your words
are met with responsibility!
This palace, the monastery,
all the buildings, companies
and everyone are concerned
about this important talk!
I'm responsible for all this!
But I don't know if coal will come out!
It's not like gambling or something like that!
It's not easy to deal
with such important things!
But...
But you have to try sometimes!
Oh?
So, what's your precious thing?
This...
For example the precious thing
you undoubtedly have is Lassie!
If you have to give it up, will you agree?
Lassie...
You can't, right?
That's it!
But...
Coal... as my father said...
Coal...
Certainly...
Definitely will come out!
You must keep your word
as you promised me!
Lassie, of course!
Until then...
Until then you will return to me!
I will be patient until the time comes!
Dad, he'll definitely
get out the coal, won't he?
I must do anything!
I will help everyone with anything!
Otherwise...
They will move Lassie to Scotland!
Next episode:
DO YOUR BEST, JOHN, AND PROTECT LASSIE!
Be sure to watch!