THE MARRIAGE OF TEACHER CURRY
He's coming!
Congratulations, teacher!
Oh?
Tomorrow is the day of your wedding,
I hope you don't get upset, teacher!
I wish you a happy life!
- Oh...!
The blackboard is for study only!
Don't spoil it with anything else!
What have you done?
Let's get started!
Let's start the lesson immediately!
When you see the sun at
the beginning of the summer,
the sky looks beautiful and very warm.
The wind comes in the fifth month,
and then the buds are fertilized
and so it is every summer...
Lassie... Well, that 's enough!
We'll gave her this bouqet!
The bride will be very happy!
I wish I could see teacher Curry
with a happy face!
Anyway, we'll celebrate it soon!
This is the teacher's face!
It wouldn't be bad that
teacher Curry suddenly smiles!
That's what I think too!
She'll be happy for this!
Thank you!
I want it delivered to Miss Mary directly!
I also want to congratulate her!
Ah, right now she went out with Curry!
Went for a consultation about the new home!
Well, I can give it to her myself!
No, no!
We will take it to the residence
of the teacher Curry!
Then we'll give it to Miss Mary!
What makes you laugh?
Eh?
But we are going to Mr. Curry and Miss Mary!
I know!
The teacher will be there!
I wonder how his face looks when
he talks to her on their own?
Oh?
Let's go!
We will go to the church!
Right.
Is that all?
What?
Hm?
What is the matter?
Have you forgotten anything else important?
Something else important?
Yes, something else is very important!
Well...
The wedding settings are ready.
Honeymoon equipment is arranged.
I don't mean this.
You didn't mean that...
That's right!
I forgot one thing!
Have you noticed that?
It's the wedding ring!
Hm...
So I won't forget it...
I have to keep it in my wedding
coat pocket for tomorrow!
Everything is complete now!
Oh really? Oh really?
Huh?
Isn't there something else you have forgotten?
Another thing...
It's the most important!
You haven't yet done it.
Huh?
I can't marry you!
Eh?
The situation seems strange...
What absurdity are you talking about?
It's not ridiculous!
If you don't have any idea...
Well, that's it.
There will be no wedding, be prepared.
You seem to be nervous
just before the wedding!
Come home and sleep well!
Now, I will take you!
I will be fine!
I can go back alone!
See you!
Well, be careful!
I'm serious.
Well okay, I understand!
We'll talk about this thing
again after the wedding!
Miss Mary!
Hm?
It's you!
Oh!
It smells beautiful!
Thank you!
- Listen, Miss Mary...
- Hm?
There won't be a wedding tomorrow.
Is it a lie?
I don't know...
Maybe it was a lie.
But... why?
What happened?
Could be...
Could it be that you
don't like Curry teacher?
I love him...
This is the problem.
Teacher Curry is already poor.
It's true that he is shy and very nervous.
I don't think he's a nice person at all!
John, don't say this to Miss Mary!
But...
John, it is true that he is shy.
But in the end he is a straight
person and always smiling!
He is also a very honest person with himself.
After reading his favorite poem
I can see his beautiful smile.
But why?
Really, why?
Sorry!
I can't say this thing to you.
Listen, Miss Mary!
You don't abstain, you can talk to us.
Yes.
What happened?
I am also good at listening to others.
Well...
In fact...
Father, listen!
Hm?
Sorry...
What is the matter?
What is it?
Sorry Dad...
Do you like mother?
Oh...?
Why do you suddenly ask?
What did you answer?
Of course, I love your mother!
You too.
Can you tell this to my mother directly?
Of course!
W-why did you suddenly ask?
Don't matter.
Hey John!
It's a secret!
Oh...
Dear, it's a beautiful morning!
Wake up and get ready!
Oh...
What is the matter?
It's the wedding!
Uh...
It's Curry's wedding today.
It's the best time for a wedding.
Oh...
John!
John, wake up!
What? Where did he go?
Also Lassie?
Mary...
What? Robert!
Oh...!
As expected from you, you came early!
Yeah...
What about Mary?
Isn't she in the waiting room?
Haven't you seen her yet?
Eh...
No, not yet.
Before the wedding,
it's not good to see her before she dresses!
Of course, I don't believe in superstitions!
But it wasn't in the waiting room!
She may still be asleep!
She's fine, I'm sure she's still in her room!
Yes!
See you later!
She hasn't come yet...
Oh...
I wonder what should I write?
To Robert!
To Robert...
Then...
It's 10 o'clock!
30 minutes left til the wedding!
Yes.
Somehow I feel that you helped me a lot!
xxx
Congratulations, teacher Curry!
Thank you so much!
I'm jealous of you!
No way...
Mary is late...
Mary? Hasn't she come yet?
No.
Strange!
She should be wearing her dress now...
Oh...?
Sorry, excuse me for a moment!
Where's Mary?
Mary?
Mary has long gone before me.
What is the matter?
It's...
Congratulations!
Thanks!
Why didn't Mary come?
She wanted to hear my answer!
What happened with Mary?
Yes.
I can't marry you!
I'm serious.
What happened?
Yes.
Congratulations, I'm happy for you!
How is the father feeling now?
Come come!
Huh...
Hm?
You're John Carraclough's dog, right?
You can't enter the church.
Hm?
Just a moment, give me this!
To Robert Curry
Could this be...
Oh?
Mary!
It's a message from Mary!
What is it?
Well good!
Open the envelope quickly
and read the message!
What are you going to do?
Robert!
Oh! Father! Mother!
You finally came!
Ah...!
The message is more important...!
It's my child's wedding!
Even from the other side
of the earth you can fly.
Where is your nice fiancée?
I want to see it quickly!
That's what I mean...
No, she went to bring something
she had just forgotten!
Is it a wedding dress?
So it should take longer.
This is a calamity!
Read it quickly!
I apologize for the late submission of myself...
I'm Mary's father!
Well...
Right, the message!
Congratulations, teacher!
Congratulations!
Ah... Thank you so much!
Where is your bride?
Is it okay to meet her?
Now... she went to bring something
she has forgotten...
Read the message!
What shall we do?
The priest will come soon.
What to do, Dad?
I'm not your father yet!
I apologise!
Heck, if I knew that, I wouldn't have
thought of being a husband to her!
This... I can't believe it!
Congratulations, Mr Rice! Teacher Curry!
No way!
He seems to have completely
forgotten the message!
The guests must've arrived by now...
I''m sure that teacher Curry
will come, and he is scared!
Would you do this good work?
Never doubt about it!
Will marriage be so good?
This is true.
You don't have to say that.
What happened with Mary?
Why didn't she come?
Yesterday we had no problem!
Mary...
Where are you now?
Oh...
What are you doing?
Oh?
I know, the letter!
Well done! Read it quickly!
I will wait for you in the place
of our first memories.
Mary...
Oh...
Mary!
We go also!
Yes!
Mary! Mary! Mary!
Ah! Ouch!
Mary...!
Mary!
Yes, teacher!
To the memory of xxx to your face!
But...
Not this way!
School is not on this side!
Teacher Curry went on the wrong path!
Don't go that way!
Mary!
Miss Mary wrote the place
where their memories!
I thought he would know
that right away, but...
He never knew!
Curly teacher is running fast...
Lassie, I have to hurry!
I don't have time to play with you...!
Ah...!
Hey!
This thing is a precious marriage ring!
Hey wait!
Well done, Lassie!
Please wait!
Why did she come to such a place?
Lassie, stop!
Mary...
I understand!
I have something else I forgot to say to you!
Oh really?
Yeah, it's about wallpaper!
As I said, I also like the green color!
Wallpaper?
Oh...
Am I wrong?
So what about?
I will always make sure not to bother you!
Not to bother me?
I will fix the flaws all my life!
I'll sort my clothes well!
I will be sure to brush
my teeth after eating meals!
I'll be very careful not to eat messy!
Also clean the place after cutting my nails...
He act like children!
So Mary...
Don't be angry with me and marry me!
Wait a moment!
Eh...?
I'm not angry on these things!
So, what is it?
In this place we had the first
conversation between us, right?
When I came to deliver the school trip bread...
This is true!
As long as you said this is true...
Have you remembered the memories
that we have come to here?
No, actually I went to Berry Forest near by.
After that, Lassie took my box...
Yes, the box!
Hey, give me the box, Lassie!
Robert...
Sorry...
Have you forgotten the most important
thing you should say?
I-it's true...
I thought that you would talk about the same
subject that took place yesterday.
Not just yesterday!
I wonder how many times have
I tried to ask you about it?
Is that right...
The thing I forgot, that I forgot...
Well...
Why do you want to marry me?
Of course you are nice and good at cooking!
You are also interested in books
and also the wallpaper's color...
I didn't want to say this to me!
Well...
I mean...
Marriage between men and women means...
In other words, the beginning
of the establishment of the family!
Other than that...
Tell me again...
Why do you want to marry me?
Oh!
This...
Yes...
This is because you are a professional player!
Your white fingers are clicking on the piano,
and then the melody comes out beautifully!
And then my ears...
It's a sign of the size of our relationship!
There is a word I wanted to hear from you!
I don't care!
But there is what I want of your heart
before it comes out of your mouth!
I want you to tell me with all your energy!
I love you.
What have you just said?
I love you!
I can't hear you!
I love you, Mary!
That's why I want to marry you!
Finally you managed to tell me.
You never told me that.
I don't believe it!
Oh...
So it seems...
This is true.
Yes, Lassie!
Enough now!
Lassie...
Come!
Come with me!
Yes.
I love you, Robert!
I accept your marriage!
Oh!
Congratulations, teacher!
Eh?
Congratulations, I wish you a happy life!
Congratulations!
Eh?
You, what?
Eh!
Uh!
A-ah!
Sir, don't neglect your clothes!
Make sure you brush your teeth well!
We didn't notice these things to you!
Yes! Yes!
Oh, dear ones!
Mary, throw the bouquet!
Over here! Over here!
Who picks up the bouquet
will be the next bride!
Okay!
Lassie!
There is a circus in the village!
They have a huge elephant.
It is very afraid of the whip.
And...
Next episode:
A BIG PROBLEM! THE ELEPHANT
ESCAPED FROM THE CIRCUS
Be sure to watch!