WHO CAUSED THE FIRE?
What's up, John?
Try harder!
Can't you be faster than Lassie?
Hey!
No way!
Ah... ah...
- Ah...!
Lassie went too far...
What's up, Duocho?
Oh?
Is it our guest while I sleep?
I...
Lassie!
Is this the big dog yours?
That's true, though.
What about you Uncle?
The road was divided into four
directions, and while I was thinking
I was sleepy and I fall asleep.
Oh?
And now...
We have guests!
Guests?
We are not guests!
That's too bad.
Isn't it, Duocho?
Very bad!
Doucho is very sad,
his chest is almost bursting with pain!
So one of you will come and ease his grief!
Oh...!
Just awesome!
Thanks!
This is my partner!
This is my partner.
His name is Pace! His specialty
is moving the vehicle.
I'm Rory!
By the way, do you know
a delicious bakery in the village?
Bakery? Maybe that is...
I know, Uncle Rice's bakery is the best!
Oh?
That's true!
He's helped by his daughter, Mary!
It's the best in the whole village!
Well I've decided!
I have a place to go today!
Isn't it, Duocho?
We have finally finished!
Well, let's go for a walk
and have a drink together!
Oh? Do you still deliver goods at this time?
You work harder than we do!
Eh?
John! Sandy!
And Lassie? What are they doing?
Lassie, isn't it amazing?
Can you do the same?
And now, next...
We need some help!
Let's see...
Okay!
This gentle miss, what do you think?
Yeah! Yeah!
Would your husband be reluctant to look at you?
I'm rude!
Stay there and hold this!
So?
This is the best place!
Come on, Doucho!
Ladies and gentlemen, this is
the great partner of the spotlight!
And this gentle miss,
I hope you applaud them!
And now, folks,
you have the honor to see some of my work!
We have utensils and all kinds of pans!
Let's go! Let's go!
Good! Good!
You're welcome, thank you for your purchase!
I want this one.
Rory is doing business and
is traveling around England!
Me too I wish I would go to many places!
Yes!
My God! My God! My God!
I would forget something important!
Please buy me bread to eat at dinner!
Okay! Lassie!
Let's go! To the bakery!
You are! You are!
How can you leave your job like that?
I'm sorry!
Today there is no bread because all were sold!
- Not even one?
- No!
I'll bake a new batch tomorrow morning...
I understood, there is none.
Don't you have bread for tonight?
No.
It's not for me, it is for Rory!
Rory?
Yes, that man who has a dog
which does amazing movements?
His voice is so loud that
I can hear him from here.
He came to this village because I told
him that we have a delicious bakery.
Is that right?
Mary!
We don't have anything to sell!
Let him go!
Yes, yes!
But will that man stay here tonight?
Mary!
Tomorrow morning I'll give you fresh bread!
Yes!
I see.
That's too bad.
Fresh bread makes the hearts of people happy.
Next to that beautiful girl!
Well, I will work tomorrow!
But what will you do?
You have no house here!
Nothing like that, I don't have
a house at all!
So, will you sleep in the stable?
No no, but I'm a vagabond!
Displacement is wonderful!
Under the stars of the sky that seem to fall!
Towards that sky to the large galaxies!
I sleep under it!
Isn't it, Duocho?
Sky and stars...
Look like they really fall down!
Somehow this is scary...
Yes...
Have you traveled in many places?
Me?
Just, almost.
Manchester, Glasgow, Newcastle,
and also Liverpool.
Eh...?
I only went to the simple villages.
My father was like me.
I was used to staying out at night
and homeless,
but there are many people who are bored
to stay between the walls of the house.
Yet within this dimly lit window is a family.
Thinking about it, this is warm and gentle.
It seems that staying in a home
is a lot more better than this.
But Uncle Rice is always angry
and screaming loudly!
It's no good!
You should not say that!
Right!
Look!
It's Sandy!
Can't you smell the delicious things?
Pace, it's delicious! It's the truth!
Oh really? Oh really?
Oh really! Really really!
But there is a problem with
the handle of this pot.
It can be used again after
it has been well repaired.
It seems that Sandy's mother is interested
in keeping the dishes well!
Eh?
This pot is mine.
I got it from my deceased grandmother
when I was a little girl.
That's why I cared about it well!
Is it you who made this tasty soup...
I did it!
Is that right? I apologize for my insolence!
Finally I knew! Isn't it, Duocho?
What now are natural people?
Haven't you seen a falling star
or something like that?
Yes...
Oh!
It's a falling star!
Eh? Where? Where? Where?
Just gone...
I saw it too!
I really saw it! That is the devil... I am...
Hm!
They made a fire in such a place!
What if a fire starts because of that? Damn!
Now, kids, have to go back!
Eh...?
Although we enjoy being with you...
Don't you have mothers and
a warm home waiting for you?
Children have specific times
and can't go out at night.
You are not like me, homeless!
See you tomorrow!
Did you have amazing
things for tomorrow?
Doucho wants to make this happen
with greater success!
- Bye!
- Good night!
Bye!
Lassie, let's go!
That boy owns a huge dog,
beautiful shape, Doucho.
It was good!
I have finished, Doucho.
Should I sleep now?
That's bad!
Fire!
Damn!
It's a fire!
Hey! It's a fire!
Wake up!
Oh? A fire started?
It's near my house!
Oh!
Water! Water! Curse it!
Give it to me!
It's bad!
Yes!
Sandy!
I came to deliver the milk!
Hello, good morning!
What? Have you brought milk?
Unfortunately,
it's not from my house!
Listen, Mr. Rory needs milk with
the bread at breakfast, right?
Ah, that 's right!
Lassie, do you want to meet Dousho as well?
Who came this early morning?
- Colin?
- Uh...!
John! Something bad happened!
Rory! Rory has troubles!
- Eh?
- What happened?
- Oh?
How many times should I tell you that?
I certainly turned off the fire before I slept!
So how it burned, huh?
Well, Mr Rice...
This man worked hard to extinguish the fire.
What is important is that the fire
didn't reached the nearby houses.
What will you do if we can't control the fire?
I also asked for help without any charge!
Don't think you will leave safely
after you have caused the fire!
What will you do?
Father!
Dad, you always do this!
You are very interested in your customers
to buy bread from our home!
This guy is...
Don't joke with me!
I bake bread for the villagers only!
I don't sell to men of this kind!
Father!
Isn't it?
I don't know anything about bread,
but it was hard to extinguish the fire!
This means
I must preserve my life and
the life of the people of my village.
It is better to leave our village immediately!
Do you have an objection?
I'll tell you again.
I didn't set fire!
No, no doubt it's you!
I understand.  I don't like
to say this again though.
Scum...
I know that, you don't have to tell me that.
You see? Definitely the reason!
I want to say only one thing.
I sell bowls and dishes.
I travel to make people smile through
the acrobatic games that Doucho loves.
Bye!
Rory!
Are you leaving?
I have no other chioce.
But...
Don't say "but" again!
Thank you for the food!
The food was delicious, miss!
It's fixed!
Well, the store owner wants me
to leave, so the village be protected.
We'll meet again!
Rory... left...
I don't know if the lamp
or wood caused th fire.
It was close to my house and
it almost burned because of it.
Father!
A lamp?
Or wood?
Uh?
Hey Colin!
To the worst, John!
Should I hit the door only?
John, what to do?
What?
You say what?  But Mr. Rice is scary
Mr Rice, I'm sorry...
What? I must bake the bread late today
with the oven already cooled!
I'll go to bake again!
Quick! He's gone!
Sorry, Mr Rice!
What? I'm busy!
Not me, but Colin...
Excuse me... this, sorry...
So I said, what?
John, tell him...
Eh...?
Eh?
Is this the truth?
Yes!
What do you say?
The lamp and firewood were
extinguished at 11 o'clock!
Yes...
Eh...?
This means that Colin woke up
and looked at the window.
How come a child stays up until late at night?
Uh...
I was trying to see the meteors...
That's why...
Falling stars, you say?
If you talk loudly you will scare the children!
Uh...
Anyway, Mr. Rory turned off the lamp.
And extinguished the fire with water.
Isn't it?
Yes.
This means that wasn't the cause of the fire.
Hmm...
If the cause of the fire is different
from that, then...
Enough, just hurry up!
Can't you go faster?
I'm deaf, you're distracted in driving!
But...
What do I say to that man?
You must apologize to him!
I thought about the safety of the village.
If I say so...
No matter what you say,
it's your fault anyway!
I was very impressed by Rory's presence.
Yes.
I hope he stays in our village
and doesn't go anywhere else.
That's too bad.
I want to talk more with Mr. Rory.
Don't make this sad face, Duocho!
There are times when people should laugh at it!
Hey, aren't you a dog?
What's up, Pace? Why have you stopped?
Hey, get out of the way quickly!
The ship will come soon!
Here it is! It's Rory!
Oh! But...
Rory will cross the bridge!
Damn, the engine hangs now...
Rory!
Wait, John!
You too, Dad! Run after the children!
Hey Pace!
I want to cross this bridge.
In the next village
we will see beautiful things.
Hey come on, Pace!
Lassie?
What are you doing here?
Oh Doucho!
What?
Rory, don't cross this bridge!
My father, it's my father's fault!
Hey!
Don't go on that road!
I see.
This is because of these kids.
This means we will do
fun things there, right?
Yeah! Yeah!
Sandy's poor cow was stolen.
We must find the perpetrator,
so everyone decided to look for him.
Sandy behaves strangely!
Next episode:
SANDY STEALS COWS?
Be sure to watch!