The manager has lost his golden watch!
That man you brought is the real thief!
That man?
It's Ian! The thief!
No, don't tell to the people!
However I will inevitably catch him!
DETECTING THE INNOCENCE OF IAN!
Ian is amazing!
It seems so.
To the degree the birds come
and they are reassuring to Ian.
On his shoulders and on his head...
- Eh...?!
How many birds?
How many birds...?
In any case it were many!
That's why we ask about the number of birds?
Maybe six... maybe not, five!
What? This number is not great!
Well, maybe it is.
But this is not what I meant!
I mean the birds are flying around
Ian and it is reassuring!
It's like...
I know!
I know! The trees!
At that time Ian seemed as big as trees!
But is not that man a thief?
I heard from my father that
he had stolen from the bank!
Oh...
This time he stole a golden watch.
My father and mother told me...
...he's very dangerous and
I shouldn't approach him!
Scotland Yard came here too to catch him!
B-but...
When I met Ian, I felt that
that person was terrifying.
It's painful to misunderstand him!
He can't be!
I don't think Ian is a bad person!
I also don't think he is a bad person!
Sandy!
As John said,
birds and animals can tell!
It knows who is a good person,
and who is a bad person!
Can't be fooled by only the forms of people!
Animals can't be fooled at all!
- Oh...?
Are you telling the truth?
It's the truth!
Every serious thing is always true!
But...
Birds don't understand anything.
Isn't it?
That's true!
Yes...
It doesn't seem that Ian is a bad man!
People can't be judged by their appearances!
Listen, Ian!
Ian, you're not a bank robber, right?
I trust you.
But...
If you remain silent, Ian,
the others won't understand you!
If they were wrong, you said to them,
"You are wrong"!
If you explained them directly, Ian,
I'm sure everyone will understand that!
Yes.
But I'm working now.
Ian...
Why don't you explain it to others?
Wait wait!
Has a big problem?
Good morning.
Ah, good morning!
Breakfast will be ready soon!
Sorry but... Can you deliver lunch to your
father in the mine on your way to school?
Yes.
It's okay, but why two?
One for your father.
And the other for Ian.
Uh! Ian?
But why Ian doesn't explain it to others?
John.
John, do you think Ian will relax
when he tells to the others?
It's true that he doesn't speak
much with others.
But if he doesn't speak,
he won't be believed by the others.
Listen, John...
Yes?
Your father told me.
Ian continued to work hard and didn't left,
in spite of the rumors spread about him.
That's why he's not worried about that.
Ah...
I think so too.
Yes.
That's right, this is what you
think isn't your memory?
I understood, Mom!
I rely on you, John!
Yes!
Good morning!
Hello, good morning, John! Be careful!
Hello, what's up?
Yes.
Your meal!
Ah, thank you!
Oh?
And the other... is it for Ian?
Yes!
Mother made it for him!
I see.
Father!
Hm?
Make everyone understand Ian!
Oh?
Do your best, Dad! See you!
Oh!
Ian!
Ian, are you here?
You went to the forest again?
Ah...
Whoa...
Whoa!
I see!
The knife is for making these!
Oh?
It's not Ian...
Lassie!
Who was that person a little while ago?
A button...
Well, put it here!
I apologize...
...to leave you in a place like this!
It's nothing...
We can process the things you want slowly.
These must be designed...
Oh...
This is...
Ian!
Ian Cooper!
28 years old, from Yorkshire!
Right now, we'll search your room!
The gold watch of the manager
Duhan of Wellington Mine was stolen!
Oh?
Whose is this clock?
No...
Are you?
No, you're wrong!
So who?
I don't know.
I found it here.
You found it here?
In this man's room...?
Maybe the clock is stolen!
But that is Ian...
Walter... continue from manager Duhan!
We will investigate this guide!
Yes!
The next king was James I.
James was the father of Mary Stuart.
When Queen Elizabeth died,
there was no successor then.
According to the descendants of the
King of England, the King of Stewart...
Oh, this is! This is!
Look!
It has my initials here!
It's a souvenir from my grandfather, who died.
It's very precious to me!
Thank you for your cooperation, Manager!
Who did that?
What are you talking about?
Yesterday evening you got
some very aggressive advice
from Mr. Carraclough, didn't you?
You seem to have found the directory instead.
You did a good job!
We will take the rest of the
purposes here to investigate!
We may find another evidence against him.
For example, he participated
in the bank robbery!
Walter, take it with you!
Hey stop it! Stay away!
Stop it!
Stop it, Lassie!
It's a dangerous dog.
It's wise to let such a dog free?
Lassie!
What is the matter?
It wasn't like that before!
Lassie!
One of you... one of you bring a strand!
What? Lassie's not here...
Hasn't Lassie come yet?
It's not its habit not to come with John.
I wonder if something happened?
I don't know...
He always asked me in my house!
What do they talk about?
If it's true...
I don't think so!
Dad, the latest thing?
No, that...
The police arrested Ian.
- Eh?
Well, go!
Get in the car!
Why?
Is not clear? You are detained!
When we get to the main office
you can recognize.
Not just the watch, but your other actions!
Why was the watch inside my room?
Hm!
This is what you stole!
Ian!
You seem to know the truth, Mr. Carraclough!
This means...
Ian!
Oh!
Don't approach this dangerous man, boy!
Maybe you do something bad!
I'm not a criminal.
Ian!
You seem to have become close
to a great liar, Mr. Carraclough.
I understand your feelings!
See you!
And now go in! Go in immediately!
Dad, do something!
I found the clock in Ian's room.
I remembered, when Ian was outside his room...!
Eh...
I found this button in his room
when someone entered it!
Hm?
Bring him in quickly!
Yes!
Don't try to resist!
John, have you entered his room
without his permission?
Sorry, Dad...
I know it's wrong but...
But the most important thing
is what happened next!
What are you doing? Do it immediately!
John, you mean that this button belongs
to the person who entered the room?
Yes! Probably!
John, give me the button
to let Lassie to smell it!
Yes!
What is the matter?
Haven't you moved yet?
A-ha!
Lassie, look now for the button holder!
Please wait until we check more Ian's arrest!
- The arrest for the golden watch!
- Let's go!
But...
Don't worry about it, just go!
Hey, wait!
Lassie!
Wonderful, this is good!
The police of England will close
the search file for the offender
because the real criminal is in our hands!
We did something great!
Yes.
That dog...
Let him go down!
Okay, but...
Lassie!
Oh, that's bad!
It's the same coat!
Look, it's the same button!
Yes!
What are you doing with my luggage?
Leave her alone!
I'm sure you did something!
No...
You try to harass me again?
If you use force, you will be transferred
to the public administration
to receive your punishment, Mr. Carraclough!
I'm sure you don't want to wear
the aggressor's clothes in front of your son.
I don't want that, of course!
Hmm...
To what purpose?
At that time... The person who entered
Ian's room is you, you hysterical, right?
Mr. Dohan's golden watch has been
placed by you in Ian's room!
Hm?
And what else?
I was under the bed!
Oh...
Have you seen my face?
I didn't see you, though...!
No! No!
Mr. Carraclough!
How did you teach your son?
Who does accuse others
of criminality without evidence,
is you, Mr. Carraclough! Isn't it?
Oh?
But...
Oh, I mean, this issue is different?
There is even an evidence!
It's the same button that was in Ian's room!
Hm!
It may have fallen from me
when I investigated him earlier.
This means that you have no evidence!
Ian is the golden clock thief!
Detective!
Stop it!
It's enough!
I also thought it wasn't right
that we should seize him like this!
Walter, what are you saying?
Ian is doomed to steal the bank originally!
Even if it is a criminal case,
Ian hasn't committed any crime!
Eh? Is this the truth?
I also thought he was the real thief!
What?
Also that bank robbery
is suspected of being done by a gang!
Silent, Walter!
No, I won't shut up!
Ian didn't steal the golden watch!
- Eh...?
- Oh?
I found the clock in the office drawer
of manager Duhan!
You infiltrated into Ian's room
and putting it there!
Uh uh...
I understood, if that's what happened.
Yes.
Hm... hm!
Come on, Walter!
Oh...
Go back to the head office!
Yes!
Ian Cooper!
I still think you were at the bank!
I won't give up!
Get the cuffs off of him!
Yes!
I apologise.
Yes.
What are you doing, Walter?
Go back in the car!
Don't make me lose my temper
more, you villain!
Okay! I'm coming!
Lassie, well done!
Thanks to you!
The band of the bank robbers was caught!
That's great!
This story explains!
This is the story of Ian's innocence.
Eh?
No, but this is bad!
Because of me, Ian was
accused without being guilty!
Is not it better to keep him doing his work?
For this...
I have told you from the start
that Ian can't be the bank robber!
I trusted him!
You really are a good man!
Wait, I want to see him too!
Whoa...
When Dr. Hooper went to catch
fish, he was seriously injured!
I tried to save him, but I couldn't!
Lassie, you are the only one
who can tell to the villagers!
Next episode:
HURRY! SAVE DR. HOOPER
Be sure to watch!