PRINCESS OF THE SKY
Yes, what is it?
Who are you?
Why are you inside Sam's house?
What are you talking about?
Sam Carraclough is next door!
Oh!
Yes!
Hello, aren't you George?
You have grown a lot since
the last time I met you!
You were a very young child!
Sorry, didn't you enter in a wrong home?
I made a mistake again ...?
I'm not George, but John...
Let me remember. John, John...
As I recall that the son of Sam
Carraclough was named George!
That's definitely me...
...but I'm John.
What? Mr. Dohan!
Oh...!
Hello Melissa!
He's on the top floor,
I'll take you to him immediately!
Yes...
Eh...
This is a wonderful dog,
it's one of the best species!
What is the matter?
Eh...
Go all this distance to see me...
This... Are you tired?
No no!
Ah, is that true? That's great!
Who's that person?
I feel like I saw him somewhere...
What are you talking about?
This is your father's boss.
Eh?
Is that what a man like him looks like?
Right.
Don't judge people only by their looks.
Of course, even if you look at them from near,
you won't be able to judge directly.
What about time?
This...
In a way, the decision suddenly came to me.
I received a call earlier!
Will come from the sky tomorrow
at 11 o'clock, until the coal is achieved!
I don't think the time is right.
You see?
That's why I came to talk to you.
From the sky?
Ah...
It's an airplane!
I wonder who it is?
Listen, Lassie...
I'm talking about the plane...
You remember that plane?
That's right!
The first meeting between us
was because of that plane.
Ah...!
It's amazing!
Oh!
Hey, get away!
Don't approach of it!
This bike is not mine!
Oh! You are...
What do you do in a place like this?
Where is your house?
Eh!
Ah...!
Here you are!
Come on here!
Ah...
Well okay, are you okay?
Uh! Ah!
Aye!
At that time, if that plane had not been there,
we would not have met!
You grow a little,
within one year you became very big!
I wish you a quiet sleep!
The sky!
It would be great if I could fly in the sky!
I...
I remembered, in that plane...
Who is that girl?
Tell me, Lassie!
Well, you're so boring...
Why should I do this...?
Would we really need a red carpet?
It will be good!
We will not be rude as long
as we clean it well.
No no no!
It's not like a newspaper seller
or anything like that!
When the owner sees all this...
Hey these notes!
These! Put it away!
It's not good to stay here!
Something strange happened!
What is it?
There is a man from the management coming.
That's why the manager hasn't
come out of the office yet.
What is special about that man
from the management?
The money the manager gets from him.
It's the same with us.
He is the owner of this entire mine!
The owner?
No matter, get to work immediately!
John!
It's rare to see you here early on a weekend!
Eh?
Do you like it, Lassie?
Not for that, though...
He said, "Not for that"!
But, Lassie came to help us
graze the sheep, right?
Lassie is Lassie, and I am me!
Don't say that! Take it!
What should I do?
You have to sponsor it at least!
Sorry, but what are you looking at?
I just wanted to see the sky.
The sky?
I love the red carpet, but will it be good?
Isn't it better not to open the room?
But what if you ran all your pace to buy one?
Eh? Right now?
Where do I get it?
It will be good!
It's important to work faithfully in this place.
That's what he should see.
No no, however...
Eh?
Oh?
Eh! Sam! Sam!
What is the matter?
That person! That...
I don't want him here!
Oh my God, this is exhausting...
Banson!
Uh?
This is my fuel.
I know you're good at your job no matter
how wine you drink, however...
If you don't mind, it's better
not to drink in a place like this.
Pff!
He's already arrived.
He seems very high.
It arrived!
It's coming here!
What is that? Who is flying it?
I don't know about that.
It's the same plane!
But...
Won't it land?
I see!
The sheep are blocking their way!
Lassie!
Hey, get away from here!
Uh I understood!
Bingo!
Gather the sheep!
Get away from here!
- Wait!
- Wait, wait!
Don't go that way!
Hey!
Ah!
What do you do in a place like this?
Oh...!
Priscilla, I have work to do!
Take me to the palace!
Won't you take me with you?
The staff don't work well,
so I'll just check it out myself!
You just have to stay in your place!
My grandfather always talks
like that when I go with him.
I saw you from above.
You gathered the sheep so we can land, right?
Thank you!
Miss, we have to leave now!
But we couldn't land without it!
I should thank to it!
Does this pasture belong to this village?
The village?
Huh, that place!
Maybe I should look at
the surrounding areas closely!
Is your home there?
You are good!
Now, isn't the time to leave?
This is true.
See you!
Follow me! Follow me!
You never help!
I didn't see the plane landing!
Lassie!
Lassie, is that girl?
I see...
We are not soldiers.
We must show loyalty to the original owner.
Hm!
This is too much, to stop working for it.
I thought cleaning alone was enough, but...
Upon arrival, we were assembled
in an organized manner.
Pff! They are just idiots!
Is not it wonderful, Miss?
That's true, but it's a bit boring.
No, I brought you the most beautiful horse.
I have prepared for you this horse
who has very beautiful hair!
In fact its hair is really beautiful but...
Can it run?
Of course! Yeah!
It could do it easily!
What if I try it!
Where are you going?
To the village houses!
But the weather is totally cloudy!
Damn!
The horse can run a little, but not that hard!
I don't know what will happen
to me if something happens!
Hm?
Tell me, is it okay with just a few?
No no!
When I finish I will leave immediately!
But no problem if you take me on a quick tour!
I said no... I mean it!
That's okay, you scoundrel!
What did you say?
Say it again!
Let 's run away, Lassie!
His name is Heinz, right? Why did he lie to me?
You can't run well!
However we are still abroad.
That brown dog was working hard.
We can go to that village slowly.
Look!
These houses are connected altogether.
I wonder what is inside this village?
Ah...
All I wanted was to allow me only a short trip...
Well don't matter, I'll have a nap.
This is the mine building?
I wonder where the sheep house is?
It's raining.
Yet I'm still lucky because of this.
Where is it?
Oh...!
I got it from Colin and was the last one.
Come here, hedgehog!
I won't bother you!
Don't be scared!
Are you going?
Oh!
Eh?
Ah...!
Your voice is too loud...
You who were on that plane!
I found it!
Do you want to eat it?
Yes!
Wet! Moistened!
For the second time we can
continue to work at last!
Thanks for your hard work!
But I'm glad I got here
before the rain got stronger!
Much mud...
The manager appeared to
have been hit hard in the head.
He went to the next room to crawl.
Eh...
I'm tired...
This man will make things harder when
he brings his granddaughter with him.
Oh?
His granddaughter?
This Duke is very proud of his granddaughter.
I wonder how his granddaughter looks like?
Is it delicious?
Yes. It is.
That's great!
It's the best dessert in Colin's shop!
Colin?
You were wandering around the village,
didn't you? That store...
The only place to sell this dessert
in the village is Colin's shop.
This is not jam or canned food.
Is it a candy store?
Sell medicines, seeds and also
works as a post-office.
Many things, right?
It works to deliver or receive requests.
Even today Colin can't play with me
because of the work.
Oh...
Poor little one...
No!
Colin does not hate this work!
If there are no customers,
he just reads his favorite books.
I understand, he likes reading, doesn't he?
He read many books.
His favorite books are adventure-type,
which he begins with.
What made you laugh?
This is because Colin...
When someone enters he is very surprised
and hides the book immediately!
This is what makes me laugh!
Why is he hiding it?
Colin reads books sold in the store.
So he thinks it's bad to read
in front of customers.
But no one cares about it!
I have read some of
the adventure books from Colin.
It's fun, though
I can't read that easily.
What is that book?
"Five Weeks in a Balloon".
When I read it,
I felt lucky because I could fly in the sky.
Have you come by plane?
Yes.
I don't have a plane.
I hope to fly high in the sky!
To where?
To the Rocky Castle!
Rocky Castle?
Right!
It's in the south of the village!
It's after the flower field.
It's a large rocky hill
that looks like a castle!
When we reach the top
we can see the sky more broadly!
Damn!
If I thought about it, it would be
my responsibility if she
fell off the horse and hurt!
She's in this place!
Miss! Miss!
Too bad, he's already arrived!
Uh?
I hope you stop joking,
you will be punished!
Hey!
I'm coming now!
Hey wait!
I have to go now.
Open your hands!
Um?
Nothing wrong, faster!
So?
Don't pretend to run away from you,
and lock it with your other hand!
It moves a lot!
You can see it now!
It looks like a gem, doesn't it?
Oh really!
It is more beautiful than a jewel!
Miss!
See you!
Sorry, Heinz! I made you
go through a difficult time!
Ah, no!
You woke up late.
She already gone.
But...
I remembered, I didn't askd her name...
Oh... I forgot to ask him his name.
That brown dog...
Perhaps that boy is a king.
What are you saying?
We have to go back
before we're punished!
Yes, I understood.
No good! No good!
Lassie, that girl has come
to my home!
What? What does Sandy plans with my mom?
But this is strange!
How did you know my house?
Next episode:
THE FIRST CAKE WE MAKE
Be sure to watch!