Ah, that's great!
IT IS SERIOUS! MY MOTHER FELL
It's just fever!
So I can go to work!
No! No!
But I'm worried about the workflow.
It's very important to relax
until you get better from fever.
Yes...
You can miss another day, right?
I see.
If it's only for today...
Lassie!
Watch Sam well and don't let him get up!
Yes, yes, I understood, Lassie!
Ah, I'm fine, Lassie...
Just feel a little bit dizzy.
What's up, Mom?
Ah, nothing, nothing!
Mom, you look tired!
You also came back late last night.
Hm?
All these days...
Thank you!
I'm just a bit tired!
But, I'm fine!
I have lots of patients!
I need strength!
I'm really fine, don't worry!
Please take care of your father!
Be careful!
Yes!
Melissa?
I apologize but can you come later
to check on my family?
Hasn't his temperature dropped yet?
No!
Ah, I see!
Oh, good morning!
How is your wife?
Thank you for your concern!
Ah, are you still going to work?
I'm fine.
Be careful!
My God, my God, it's rare
to be treated so harshly!
Oh!
Did you finish eating?
Thank you for the food!
Many people have had cough...
John... listen to me.
Eh?
Your mother is busy these days, right?
Yes...
She's works too much...
At these times you will be busy eating lunch.
Yes, fever is rampant anyway...
But it's bad for her not to eat lunch.
Yes...
I know!
I'll bring the lunch to my mother!
Ah, I feel fine now!
Well, if that's it...
Let's go, Lassie!
I'm fine, Lassie!
I will rest in peace!
And now go!
Yes, this time I can help my mom!
Hello!
Mom?
Eh?
It's strange...
It was very busy, but the place is empty.
Where are you?
List of patients!
I see!
No more patient visits yet!
Hello!
Sorry!
- Oh!
- Mom!
Mother, we...
I count on you to bring it
to the last floor!
And now won't hurt...
I'm not a child!
But you should be cured of fever immediately!
I'm sorry!
Still, I want you to visit us again!
It's okay.
- You'll get better quickly!
- Yes!
Now, let's get to the next house!
Busy! Busy!
The pulse...
Well, that way the heat will be gone!
Don't worry, rest only!
Yes...
- Here!
- Thank you!
No, that's at least I can do!
But... my mom and the doctor...
Mom!
What is it?
You forgot to take your lunch with you!
Oh!
Well, we'll be back here at five o'clock!
I must prepare medicines to
send them to patients in need!
This is tiring!
All the people of this house are sick!
Sorry, how is it?
Ah!
Yeah, it's a little high.
What about Jake?
The father who was in this
house treated him first!
So you'll get better quickly!
Yes...
But we don't have enough fever medicines.
Yesterday...
Yesterday I ordered other medicines.
Maybe it won't arrive quickly.
As recently as his students didn't get up!
Maybe it will arrive tomorrow afternoon.
From here...
I will go and bring it back...
Oh!
Mrs. Carraclough!
Hey, she fell!
Mom!
Mom! Mom!
John...
Doctor!
I'm sorry!
No, I'm the one who should apologize!
I made you work so hard that it happened.
No, I will wake up immediately!
Mom!
I'm fine, John!
I'm just a little tired.
Patients are waiting for me now.
Mom, your temperature is too high!
That's right!
This is a medicine for fever!
Doctor!
This medicine is...
What are you saying?
It's normal for patients with fever
to receive injection!
But the drugs will be delayed
until tomorrow afternoon.
Not until after the dawn of tomorrow!
Mr. Rice went to pick it up by truck.
You can inject this medicine
after the medication arrives.
Mom!
In any case, I never want to!
The other patients need me!
Mrs. Carraclough!
Your stubbornness won't be
as effective today as yesterday.
But...
Oh?
Hey!
Sam, are you here?
- Go to the front!
- Yes!
We've heard that Mrs. Melissa
has fallen unconscious.
Oh... Ah...
Please enter!
I made soup for you,
so eat it and get better quick!
Melissa, everyone knows
you're concerned about them.
So everyone in the village appreciates it!
Yeah! Yeah!
Excuse me!
Melissa!
Y--yes?
Everyone is in trouble now!
In the village there is one nurse,
she worked hard until she fell!
Grandma, don't say that,
you better appreciate her feelings!
Mrs. Carraclough!
Aren't the words of Grandma Forrest true?
It's better for you to get an injection to get
better, it's the desire of the people as well!
- Doctor!
- That's right!
While you are at home, Mom,
I will help Dr. Hooper!
Oh!
John...
Lassie too...
I don't know what the syringe is,
but you have to get better soon,
there's no one in your place!
Mhm!
I understand...
My mother worked hard for everyone...
Yes! That's right, John!
Well...
I'll leave your wife to you, Sam!
Y-yes!
Doctor Hooper!
Hm?
Doctor, I mentioned earlier!
I want to help you!
Help me?
It's hard for you, doctor,
to work alone, right?
I'm not as good as my mother,
but can't I help you with a little?
Look, even Lassie!
Hm...
Even if you say so...
My mother was taking care of the patients too.
And I...
Okay!
I count on you, John! Lassie!
Yes!
Well, the lungs are okay!
John, the tongue inhibitor!
Tongue inhibitor... yes!
Hm!
Say "a"!
- Laryngoscopy!
- Yes!
Yes, is that the binoculars?
Hm!
Okay!
Yes! This is...
You've got the tool names, haven't you?
Who is next?
No 21, Mrs. Harrison!
Okay!
Thank you!
Yeah!
Please get better quickly!
We still have a lot!
Oh my God, my God!
The number of medicines is many
and can't be counted!
Now I will deliver the next medicine!
Yes, I count on you!
I will check the inventory now.
Okay!
Even if his temperature is low, he is
still a person to be warned.
The man with fever never changes!
Rice went to get the medicines,
I hope he will return quickly!
Damn!
I have to go back to the village quickly!
That way I will never move!
That's why I hate the city!
It's Dr. Hooper's medicine!
Ah...!
Good, there's only one house left!
Mr. Gabel!
Mr. Gabel?
Shut up!
Open the door and come in!
I can't let you in!
Sorry...
I brought your medicine!
A child? What happened to Melissa?
My mother is very sick,
that's why I came instead.
I'm here!
It's different from the usual
rheumatoid medication.
It's a fever medicine!
Please eat your full food!
Hm!
Well, I'm leaving now!
Wait!
What is it?
Even food can't be eaten, as you see.
I can't move from bed.
Then...
You ask me to make food for you?
That's true!
I can't take this medicine.
Oh...
Whoa!
It's not possible!
I have to start by washing dishes!
I don't have any pot to use!
Do you have any complaint?
Melissa always does that!
Mom?
Okay!
Mom, do this too...
I have finished!
Well, I'm going now!
Wait!
So?
I hope you always come.
You do this well.
Is that right?
I will ask you to do so from now on.
Uh!
Dr. Hooper!
He's walking fast!
What? What is the matter?
Mr. Gabel, I have to go now!
I think Dr. Hooper has many patients!
Wait a moment!
I'm sorry, but I really have to go!
xxx!
If you open the cabinet
you will find a bottle shelf.
It's the special strawberry drink.
It have been very helpful to me.
That's why I should give Melissa this drink.
Melissa always looked after me
without grumbling.
Thank you, Mr. Gabel!
I... I will come again!
Doctor Hooper!
Oh, John!
Jake's temperature has risen.
Ah, this boy?
It was worse because we weren't careful.
Aunt...
Is Jake okay?
What? He don't have pneumonia.
If it doesn't get to the point he will be fine.
Well... I will take care of him now!
Aunt, you have to rest!
But...
I will take care of Jake.
Aunt, you have to recover your health quickly!
But this...
When you get well, Auntie,
you can take care of Jake!
Isn't it, Doctor?
Right!
Now go back to your bed.
Tomorrow morning when you recover
you can hug Jake as much as you want.
Yes...
How is it?
How is his temperature?
Hm...
The temperature is high.
Still high?
Yes.
Well, it's just a fever,
so there's no need to worry.
His temperature can decrease
if we observe it well.
We must wait for Rice to return.
Damn!
It broke at such a time...
I have a lot of work!
The medicine hasn't arrived yet.
Doctor Hooper!
Hm?
I went to the clinic and found the paper
where you wrote that you are here!
What is the matter?
My mother's fever has increased again!
Please take a look at her!
That's all. I have to go to Olsen's house.
I apologize but please take good care of Jake.
If his temperature suddenly rises,
tell me immediately!
Yes!
Ah, also don't forget to dry the towel again!
- Yes, Doctor!
- Bye!
Good...
Let's do our best... Lassie!
I am thirsty...
Do you feel thirsty?
Do you want water?
Yes.
Wait!
Oh!
Well, sleep now.
I will turn off the light now
so don't be surprised!
Yes.
He sleeps deeply.
Ah...!
Even if I kept changing, it was still hot!
Ah...
It's time to measure his temperature!
Thank you, Lassie, for waking me up...
Has time passed already?
I can't...
It has grown again...
It's bad! Jake!
What to do? His temperature has risen!
What? What's with this blanket?
What? Did you wake up, John?
Mom, is that okay?
Thank you for your hard work!
By the way, Jake...
Oh, that's right!
Calm down, John!
He needs cooling!
I wish we had snow.
Eh?
Snow?
Would you be okay with the snow?
Lassie, we must find snow quickly!
But where do we get it from?
Excuse me, Mr. Nelson!
W-what do you want at a time like this?
If there is snow in your refrigerator,
give it to me please!
In the Parkinson house, it's Jake!
Jake has a high temperature!
What? This is a big problem!
That's enough, John.
Now he calmed down.
If I sleep a little...
After an hour we'll exchange places.
So Mr. Rice is back.
It will be a problem if the fever returns.
Okay! Okay!
Hm?
What's up, Lassie?
Lassie?
Lassie!
Oh?
What is wrong with you?
What? Do you want me to follow you?
Lassie?
Sorry sorry, I'm late!
Doctor Hooper!
Ah...!
Hey Doctor!
Why are you here?
I brought medicines!
Lassie is the one who brought Mr. Rice here!
Mom! The medicine! The medicine arrived!
Thanks for your hard work!
That's great, Jake, you've already recovered!
So, even you, Mom, I'm happy!
You worked hard, John!
No, but you, Mom, you always
work hard and always...
Always do your best!
I am proud because you are my mother!
Grandmother Forrest's son returned
to the village 20 years later.
But the grandmother didn't reply
and didn't received her son.
At that time, her grandson also appeared.
Next episode:
I WANT TO SEE MY GRANDMOTHER
Be sure to watch!