GREAT MESS AT HOME
How did I...?
I did it?
How did I get to bed?
It seems like something happened yesterday.
Ah, right! That puppy!
Good morning!
Good morning, John!
You woke up early.
Yes, you too, Father!
Ah, this is not a breast!
Wait a moment, I will bring milk immediately!
Hey!
Do you want to eat soup?
Huh?
No, Dad!
He has to drink milk while
he is still breastfeeding.
Is... that right...?
You look like a puppy's mother.
- Tell me, do you see Chibi as a "baby"?
- Huh?
What do you mean?
Its name!
Wouldn't it be bad, right?
Huh...
It's not good?
Well...
It's a male and a Collie...
This name won't fit too good.
When he grows up
it's difficult to call him Chibi.
Okay, I will go!
John?
Yeah?
About this puppy...
Tell your mother about him!
Yes!
See you!
Also don't occupy only with this puppy!
Don't forget to look after yourself!
This soup is salty!
It seems Dad have put in a lot of salt...
Well, if I put a lot of sugar in it...!
Yes!
Tasty!
This is good!
There it is! I was wearing it when I was three!
This is your home.
Stay here today!
Don't worry, when I get back
from school I'll build you a real house!
There, I have to go!
Wait here quietly!
I'm leaving!
Today when I said "I'm leaving,"
someone answered me!
Good morning!
Good morning, John!
I remembered, yesterday, Colin...
John!
What? Sandy?
This is not the school way!
I wanted to walk instead of riding a bike!
Tell me, did the puppy eat the milk?
Oh... yes!
John...!
Did the puppy eat milk?
What, Colin too?
Sure!
I got a child's bottle from Colin!
Yeah?
He drank a lot, Colin!
Oh really?
This is fantastic, that he drank!
Yes.
Listen...
You promised me,
that I could see the puppy.
Yes, that's right.
Today, after school.
But it is a puppy now,
when grown, it will eat a whole dish.
Is that right?
What do you call that little fool?
That puppy?
What? Little fool?
Yes, this is because the dog
looks like its owner!
Only a fool would like a fool like it?
What!? Do you think I am one? Stop it!
Besides, I'm not its owner.
I'm just someone who
protects it because it is lost.
I'm tired, I didn't rest well in two full days.
Hello, Melissa!
I have appeared
in front of you inappropriately!
What are you talking about?
You seem to continue yawning
after the baby is already born.
If you fell tired, all the villagers
of Greenor Bridge would face a big problem.
Right, I must not burden myself.
I don't know where Dr. Hooper went.
As expected of the great doctor,
did he sleep after work?
Sure.
When he wakes up from sleep
he will go fishing as usual.
Eh?
He is a healthy old man!
So, I will also go to my bed!
Okay.
- Bye!
Well, I shouldn't worry about other tasks.
I can clean and cook later.
Ah, I'm tired...
I don't want to move anymore.
I wonder if I'll stay that way until evening?
What is that?
From there?
What is this?
5, 4, 3,
2, 1.
- Goodbye!
- I'll go first!
Wait for me!
Only a few remained.
Well, you're clean now!
What is that? It has completely
ruined the bedding.
I'm back!
Sandy! Colin!
Wait a moment!
John!
It's bad, my mom was working
till late at night and is back now!
Oh hey! Hey hey puppy!
Oh, don't get near it!
John!
Hello, Mom!
What? He is acting politely now!
You should warm it up
as long as it is a puppy.
I have to wash now.
The laundry?
Hey? Is this what it did?
I will do it!
No, that's fine, you have to warm
this little one near the fireplace.
Hey, it'll get cold!
If you do this, Mom, I'll do the wash!
Come on, you look like
you're gonna fall asleep!
But what about your guests?
Huh!
Sorry!
You seem to have heard everything.
We both must go home.
Yeah...
I'm really sorry...!
I want to see the puppy.
Don't complain!
The time was not right!
Very warm...
Quickly dry...
I think Jeffoni has reached its limits.
Thank you!
Well, I have something to say to you.
John...
What will you do with this puppy?
You said, what do I do?
He's a naughty puppy.
I must find its real owner!
But if you don't find it?
Can you take care of it?
Your mother may be a nurse...
Taking care of living creatures
is very hard work.
This is not easy.
Today is not a big thing.
When you were a little boy, it was
very difficult to take care of you.
Of course you don't remember that...
But I had a great difficulty when you
had fever, when you were a little boy.
Have you thought about what will happen to it?
John?
I don't know about this.
Anyway I have to find its owner immediately.
So, then, do what you want.
Perhaps its owner is worried about it.
And perhaps its mother
wants to see it again.
That is why I must find its owner.
Isn't it, Mom?
Tears...
Ah, hot...!
Now what does my mother usually put?
Ah, I remembered!
Salvia and parsley... And what else?
It will improve the taste if you put it...
And now, everything is ready!
When you wake up after fatigue
you will be surprised!
Hey, where did you go?
Grandma Forrest!
Have you seen a puppy here?
This size...
Have you searched your home well?
I searched but I didn't find it!
I look from here all the time.
Are you sure you searched well?
Ah I remembered, thank you!
The backyard! Maybe it went outside!
No wonder I didn't find it...
As my mother said, caring
for living creatures is very hard.
Bingo...!
Bingo!
Where did you go?
Hey Bingo, show yourself!
Sandy, what's up?
John, do you know our Bingo?
It's a sheep dog.
Haven't you seen it?
Yes...
...all the sheep have returned though...
You haven't even see the puppy?
Eh?
Ah, here, here!
Is was here all the time.
John, is this your puppy?
Oh?
My God, my God, looks like a baby bed!
It can't move one foot because of it.
Because of a small foolish puppy!
Huh!
I understood... you...
You... missed your mother.
Eh?
But Bingo is just an old dog.
It's true, this is still a puppy.
I will definitely find your mother!
Is this where I first met you?
Is there no evidence here?
Who's boat is this?
Has a dog? Are you?
There is something written here.
La... ssie...
Lassie?
Is this your name? Lassie?
I understand, if it is you.
This is the name your owner has given you.
But if we would travel on this boat...
Where this river would lead us?
After I found Lassie's leash,
I persuaded Colin to cross the river.
Then we arrived at a country house.
I wonder if the owner lives there...
Next episode:
GOODBYE LASSIE
Be sure to watch!