My grandfather doesn't understand anything!
Oh! Miss, what are you doing?
Lassie!
Do you want to go to John's place?
You can go!
Eh-ah-ah-ah!
Don't open the door!
No, but open it!
Ah...!
What does that mean?
Let it go to John!
UNKNOWN PLACES. SEARCH FOR LASSIE
Do you understand what you have done?
Yes... of course!
Huh!
This will discredit our family!
You only have to recognize what you have done!
Even if that dog knows the location
of the village of Greenor Bridge...
But now it's in Scotland,
which is 400 miles away!
This is ridiculous!
You've just left the dog mess around!
Mess around? What a terrible analogy!
No matter if this is the promise
that John made to you,
you should've thought about Lassie!
Even if that is promise that men do.
Didn't you thought about what would happen
if the coal didn't come out again?
As you said, exactly.
So what will you do for John and Lassie?
I don't want to be separated because of us!
Grandfather, in the end
you wanted to own Lassie!
Priscilla...
Lassie may face many people
who want to own it too.
I understand very well how
your heart feels about that dog.
But we can't guarantee that some
honorable people will pick it up.
Well well... It's better to hope
that Lassie will have good luck!
- Look, Willy!
- Huh?
Eh, it looks like a good dog!
This is a wonderful dog!
I wonder why it hangs around
in a place like this?
Uh?
What do you mean?
Aren't you well?
It would be great to stay with us!
Come on... just come...
Don't run!
There is no need to fear and stay still
Well, you're good!
Now are you ready?
- Willie!
- Yes!
Ah...!
Wait
He must be a runaway from the Duke's house!
Where is it hiding?
If we catch that dog we'll get a great bonus!
Damn, he must be hiding here!
Ah! It's there!
Uh!
Ay! Don't throw the stone!
We don't want to wound it!
But we won't catch it!
Eh?
Hm!
Eh? A message? For me?
From who?
Guess who?
Stop joking and tell me!
Here.
Priscilla Rodoring?
Ah, from Scotland! It's from Priscilla!
What about Lassie?
Lassie...
It fled from their palace in Scotland.
Eh?
It left the palace...
He went directly south...
Someone saw Lassie walking south!
To the South...
It says the South!
If it will go south, it will
reach Yorkshire, Mom!
Lassie returns home!
Just a moment, John!
Okay I'll go!
We must find coal in any way!
Lassie goes home, so I won't
let it go anywhere else!
I'll do my best!
John...
What do you do, teacher?
Well...
I'm only a fan of Loch Ness!
I wish the monster would appear again!
This place is suitable
for drawing pictures...
Well...
It's a bit interesting...!
This...
Don't you see it there?
Still looking at the lake.
Eh...
That dog looks so precious.
It seems to want to go to
the far side of the lake.
You are like the poets!
Oh?
What is it doing?
Maybe it wants to cross the lake!
Eh?
Somehow the dog did it...!
I wonder why it went across this lake?
I don't know...
I'm sure there's something precious about it.
Yes...
Me too...
Even if I were alone I could do it!
Then Jimmy ate everything!
So funny!
Did Jimmy eat at last?
This is true!
Take it!
You don't have to hesitate...
You have to eat and you'll be comfortable!
And now take it all!
It's stubborn.
It's okay.
John, I have published
this ad in the newspaper.
Anyone who sees this beautiful Collie dog ​
may contact me for a reward.
Oh?
Yes, is it similar to what was
published in the newspaper?
Where is it now?
Yes!
I noticed that Lassie was
heading south directly.
No, it is heading straight to London.
John...
Lassie... continues to travel to your city.
The picture I sent...
It's from Loch Ness in Scotland,
it was standing in that exact spot!
Lassie...
No, let's get away from this dog!
Ya-ah!
xxx
I found you, you dirty dog!
It may be harmful!
Hey, come on!
What it did this suddenly?
He suddenly became calm.
Well, get it in the car quickly!
Oh! It's there!
Whoa!
What is that?
He fled into the court!
Now go to the defendant!
Whoa!
What is that? It come here to watch?
Oh!
I apologize, I'll catch it now!
Oh! Oh!
Oh!
Oh...!
Damn, what a dog!
Father, in there!
Damn, the sheep will be attacked again!
There's another one!
- Are you sure?
- I don't know...
It may be your imagination!
It's not like that!
I heard a voice behind the house!
Something seems to be suffering terribly...
I didn't hear any sound!
Oh! What is this thing?
What is the matter?
Come and see! It's a big dog!
Who did all this?
Poor thing...
Hm... This wound is made by gun.
Shot this dog with a gun?
Last week I got Tommy's mail
from the neighboring town.
In that place the sheep were attacked.
I heard from the owners of the barn
complaining about it.
If this dog attacked the sheep...
Hm...
It's not so, Dan.
This dog can't attack the sheep!
Is this how you feel again?
Sometimes you make a mistake!
But you also agree with me!
Didn't we move to this house because of that?
Hm? Well maybe...
John!
Haven't you wake up yet?
Breakfast is ready!
Okay, I'm coming!
Lassie came from upstairs
to the kitchen ahead of you!
What?
Say something like that...
Lassie is lazy...
How are you now?
I brought you warm milk!
Do you feed it with milk?
There is nothing wrong with
breakfast sometimes with milk!
My God! My God!
It is rare for an English man
to drink tea instead of milk!
I think I'm the only one complaining here!
Oh...!
You can stand now!
Four days have already passed!
Dear, close the door immediately!
Purcell will come out!
Oh!
Purcell!
You are barely able to walk!
You still have more time!
However...
Danny went to war.
When we left, no one else stayed at home.
You are also satisfied with Purcell's presence.
Eh?
I suddenly became like you!
He will be fine!
Purcell went far beyond the war.
This is impossible to return again.
Hm... This is true!
This picture was taken a week ago in court.
After that, I don't know where Lassie is.
But I'm sure it is in good health!
It will continue his journey
until it reaches you!
Lassie...
Where did you go?
Purcell!
Don't open the door, Dan!
Hm? Oh?
Purcell, you can't go out now.
Your wound has not healed yet.
Purcell...
Don't make us sad for you.
If you have more health,
you will be very sad.
Isn't it?
Shall I enter please?
My dear, it's okay now!
Today too?
Yes, he always does that at three o'clock.
Hm...
What is he aiming for at three o'clock?
Somehow we don't see it anymore, do we?
Listen John!
It will certainly come soon!
Lassie will definitely sit
next time there, right?
Yes.
That's it!
Purcell? Isn't it right?
Purcell... you...
I have a feeling that oatmeal
this morning is a bit different.
Dan!
Hm? What is the matter?
It may not be happy here.
Hm?
Did you notice only at this time?
It's not like I didn't notice!
I knew that.
You care about it a lot!
Even if Purcell's eyes are nice,
but his eyes are still very sad!
It was like Danny's return when he was young.
Maybe you're right.
Why don't we let Purcell go?
When Danny was little,
he loved walking in the forest.
But Purcell has hurt his leg not long ago!
You know very well that
its injury has become much better!
When it comes out of here
it won't come back again.
Do you think the same?
It seems to be traveling to a certain place.
This house is just a passing place.
Perhaps we can do it with our hands gently.
He didn't go anywhere.
We may hurt it more without knowing.
But it will be okay, right?
We also lived a long life.
Yes.
It might come back to us, wouldn't it?
Before Purcell came
I will continue to live happily with you.
Yes!
No doubt about it!
Come, Purcell!
No, you really have a name, don't you?
Now go where you want!
Be careful!
No, just go!
Also be happy!
This is true, this is the most important thing!
It's happy now, isn't it?
That 's true!
It was back in the mine after
we discovered something!
But I don't know yet where Lassie is.
Do your best, Lassie!
I will definitely find you!
Next episode:
WELCOME BACK, LASSIE
Be sure to watch!