COLIN'S LOVE AND THE TREASURE
I'm leaving!
Be careful!
Lassie!
Thank you, Lassie!
You thought I forgot my bag and I was on
my way to school, so you brought it to me!
But I don't need a bag!
Today we will go for a stroll outside the city!
Look, this is for lunch!
So I don't want you to go to school today.
Do you want to go too?
Everyone is ready?
Yes!
You understand, Lassie?
You have to wait until we move.
What will you do?
Hello John!
Will Lassie be released today?
Yes that's right!
Because they went to the cart regularly!
- Yes!
You seem to have difficulty in your youth.
The teacher ended up going in a school trip.
But I am very excited!
Everything is okay.
Hm?
Everyone, we will move now!
Take care not to fall from the cart!
- Yes!
- Now, please!
Come on! Come! Come!
In here! In here!
What is it?
Nothing at all!
All of you, get off of the cart
and then board on the ship!
I go first to the reception!
We'll go get the tickets!
Okay!
Come on! Move! Move!
Y-yes!
Uncle, thank you!
We depend on you to return!
Yes, be careful!
No, Lassie!
Eh?
- Oh!
- Uh!
We are on board now, but what next?
Where can I hide Lassie?
John, it's the teacher Curry!
Uh?
Colin, I rely on you to take care of Lassie!
Teacher!
What's the matter, John Carraclough?
Sorry, this...
I have a question!
Uh?
I must hide Lassie...
Oh?!
This is bad...
Uh!
Ah...!
Ah!
Lassie!
Thank you, dog!
That's great!
Hey!  You are...
Eh?
Ah!
My hat!
Damn, it was my hat that I loved!
Sorry...
We can't recover it anyway!
I will forgive you!
Right, I have to hide Lassie!
- Hide?
- Yes!
I know a good place!
Eh?
I see!
I'm also going to the same place, Skull Island.
T-t-the same place?
But when we return I'll go to a different
ship, which is bound for Australia.
My father went before me
and now he is waiting for me.
You are a foreigner...
I wanted to see one of you already...
Tell me, what is the name?
It's Lassie.
Wrong, I mean your name!
Uh...
Uh... eh...
Co-Colin...
I'm Chris!
Nice to meet you, Colin!
Nice to meet you, Chris!
Nice to meet you, Lassie!
- Uh... uh...
- Hm?
A-a little while ago... What was that paper?
It seemed important.
That's it!
A treasure map!
A treasure map?
When I get to Skull Island
I'll look for a treasure!
C-can I help you?
Y-you can consider that instead
of the hat you lost!
Lassie, do you want to go with us?
Colin Jones?
Does anyone know where Colin Jones is?
Maybe we should search the ship again!
It's bad!
He can't get out just like that!
This is because he's alone with with Lassie!
Oh!
Could it have fallen into the sea?
Oh...!
Colin! Las--
You brought Lassie with you?
No, I mean...
Teacher, I have a question!
I will answer later!
Teacher, I apologize for the delay!
Colin, what about the dog?
What do you want from Sebastian?
Sebastian?
Is this dog's name?
Yes!
Say "Hello", Sebastian!
Hmm...
What about you?
I'm Chris!
We have become friends on the ship.
Well, okay.
Now get ready, we will eat
our lunch in the lighthouse!
Now, let's move!
- Yes!
What does that mean, Colin?
Hello John! Sandy!
- Hm?
I'm Chris, nice to meet you!
Colin told me about you.
It was a good plan, right?
Ah...
Hello, Chris!
When we have a vacuum, you need
to take care of the Lassie thing.
Yes!
That would be a good idea!
I will wait for you in that place!
Yes!
I rely on you to take care of Lassie!
Let's go, Sebastian!
Ah, a moment!
This...
It's Lassie's lunch.
I understand, see you!
We'll meet later!
- Farewell, Chris!
- No... But...
As I thougt!
Hey Lassie!
- Oh!
When it heard its name it didn't turn back.
Maybe it's really another dog!
- Ah...
It's nice to listen to the sea, Robert!
I want to go too!
Me too!
Treasure hunt... This is very exciting!
Is it on that island?
It's an island but we can walk on it.
Okay!
In leisure time to look for treasure!
Hooray!
Hm?
Colin?
Everyone!
You can go down to the white sandy beach
in the afternoon when it's warm!
Don't go far away!
Also don't go on that island!
You understand?
- Yes!
We can't go to the island...
I wonder why?
Hm...
Were you waiting?
Yes!
- And this will restore Lassie to you!
- Yes!
John!
I have to go with Chris.
Eh...
But the teacher said...
Colin, I don't want to force you.
I can go by myself!
No, it's okay!
I want to go...
A-ha!
Is that so, Colin?
I will go too!
You can't!
Ah, why?
It's okay!
Colin, you can go on your own!
E-eh...
Alone...
Sorry, I wanted to take Lassie with us but...
It's okay!
W-what is the matter?
Sorry, John.
Come on, Chris!
I'll borrow Lassie again.
Lassie!
Ah...
Lassie follows them too...
Listen, why can't I go?
John, it's too boring!
Boring?
I mean...
Eh...?
Love her?
What does Colin mean?
That's true!
Eh...?
Listen, how does the treasure look?
Could you have seen two hackers before?
Wrong!
It's a little trifle!
In the eyes of people is worthless!
But for me it's my precious treasure!
Right...
It isn't a pirate treasure.
What do I have?
Oh!
Not so, but I knew nothing
about the treasure at all.
- Huh?
- Oh?
Let's go!
Wait! Chris!
I want to look for treasure...
But Colin...
Do you really love Chris?
I think he doesn't care about that.
Oh!
What are you doing?
I was just xxx!
John the insensitive!
What?
Do you know anything about the age of love?
Damn, I'm not insensitive...
- Oh!
- Ah!
Just for you!
Boy!
We have climbed a lot!
Chris, is this really the way?
Yes, if we walk this way we will
reach the top of the island!
Ah...
Up to the peak...
Are you fine? You're tired?
I-I'm fine!
That's it...
Oh?
It's pushing hard...
John Carraclough!
I have a question for you!
Y-yes...
- Uh...
This...?
It's a landslide...
I don't believe it!
Although we have had all
the trouble to get here...!
Oh!
Lassie does it perfectly!
Let's go through there!
Look, Lassie walks the natural way!
But we can't climb like Lassie!
Don't worry!
I'll make holes for climbing, with this.
Ah? Yes!
I'll start digging!
So stay away and wait!
Yes!
Now climb up, Chris!
Don't look down!
Yes, you can fix your feet this way!
Come on!
We have already reached the peak!
Yes!
And now...
Listen, show me the map!
Yes!
A compass!
It looks like a real treasure!
But it doesn't help as long
as we don't have a map!
Not like that!
Thay way is the lighthouse.
So I think the treasure is to the northwest.
Eh...?
What do you see to see there?
Ah...!
Just awesome!
What's up, Lassie?
- Hm?
- Ah...!
The road has disappeared!
The sea was sunk by the tidal wave...
Hey...!
Someone help us!
The road has disappeared!
They can't hear us!
This is not the time to search for treasure...
We have to think about the way back.
Colin, can you swim?
I can't swim...
Me neither...
In the meantime, John and
Sandy will notice that!
If they don't notice quickly, the ship
bound for Australia will be departed.
Me too, maybe I can't...
Anyway, let's go!
I don't mind not going to Australia...
Chris...
The treasure was a memory of my mother.
A memory?
My mother died last month.
Ah!
My father remembered when
they lived in the same house.
He therefore decided to live
in a foreign country to build a new life.
I really want to live here!
But I can't say that to my father...
I see...
So before leaving England
I decided to look for my mother's memory.
When I was small, my father, my mother
and me came here to play a treasure game.
It was fun...
The map is from my mom
that's why I care about it a lot.
After all this...
I haven't found it...
Let's go and find it... Chris!
Eh?
You can't leave without your precious treasure!
But we have to think about the return!
I-I'll find a solution!
So let 's go, Chris!
Yes!
North West! North West!
Chris, is it that way?
Yeah, no mistake on that!
Ah!
It's there!
It was buried under that tree!
You're not wrong?
When I was little I was here!
- We've found it!
- Yes!
Ah!
My mother planted the seed,
it has already grown!
And now let's dig!
Yes!
- Ah...!
Ah! Beautiful!
My mother wanted to see
him with someone else.
It seems to have something written!
Oh really!
Dear Chris,
When you read this you should
be grown up and be a good girl.
Mom!
I have to go to Australia!
If my father doesn't see me,
I'll be in trouble!
Yes...
Let's go back...
Even if it slips from me, I won't sink.
I will swim and call for help.
At this time, just wait.
I'll go with you!
It's not good to go both of us!
So we won't be able to help each other.
But...
I'll be fine, leave the rest to me!
Colin...!
Do your best, Colin!
Faster! Faster!
Lassie!
If delayed, the ship bound
for Australia will be departed!
Lassie!
Stop it, Colin Jones!
Go back to the ground quickly!
Turn! Turn around!
We will help you now!
Ah...
We survived...
xxx
The ship bound for Australia
will leave immediately!
Don't be late!
Yes!
She seems to have no time.
You have to say farewell now.
Yes...
Chris, I'm sorry.
Are you okay?
You go to Australia...
Thanks to you, Colin, I found
the most precious thing!
Thank you, Colin!
Ah!
- Ah...!
Thank you, Lassie!
Goodbye, John! Sandy!
Goodbye, Chris!
Goodbye!
Goodbye... Colin!
Chris! Chris!
Colin, I'll never forget
what happened this day!
Me too! Me too!
I'll never forget!
Goodbye! Goodbye, Chris!
Goodbye... Chris...
Chris has already left.
Listen, did you find the treasure?
What was it?
I'm sorry, John...
It's a secret!
It's only for two people!
Colin...
Isn't it, Lassie?
And now everyone, get ready to go!
Woe to you!
We have to go back because
it's waiting for us now!
Has the influenza epidemic
spread in the village?
Even my father got sick and stayed at home!
And daily visit,
are very tiring for my mother!
Is she okay?
Next episode:
IT IS SERIOUS! MY MOTHER FELL
Be sure to watch!