Lassie!
Don't go this way!
Crossing such river is dangerous to you!
Lassie!
Uh! Ah!
It's a dream!
Right.
It's just a dream.
WELCOME BACK, LASSIE
John,
There is no news of Lassie for today.
Its last appearance was
three days ago of West Darlington.
But I'm sure Lasie has traveled safely and
it will arrive soon, that's what I think!
Don't worry, Priscilla!
Lassie is in good health and is
on its way to... my house.
I thought of Lassie until the morning came...
It is the result of the geological survey.
If the result is zero,
I can't assume that!
Yes!
Let's do our best and find coal, Dad!
When I see these two working, I feel
that the coal will definitely come out!
Yes!
Well, we too will not lose
to the current manager!
Yeah!
Ah Sandy!
How is your health?
Hm...
There is no escape from that as you see...
What are you saying?
This is your gift!
Oh?
Thank you...
I... why I'm always so?
And to get sick at such an important time?
I feel embarrassed by myself.
I can't help John at all.
Maybe so!
So the same with me!
All I can do is make tea at their own leisure!
Yes...
John is doing hard work like a man.
Ah...!
But when everyone treats the candy they offer
them will increase their strength as I think!
Thank you!
John...
Actually wants to find Lassie but he can't!
That's why he desperately tries
to find coal with others.
When Lassie returns,
they will always live together.
Hm...
I hope Lassie returns while he is in this area.
When I see it in good health,
I expect to stay next to it.
Hm...
I wish I could do even a little!
Ah...
You can't...
And now everyone!
Time for tea!
Oh? What is our food today?
The meat pie is full of energy!
Every day I look forward to this moment!
Well, take a break!
What do you think?
Yes! Thank you for the food!
W-what, did you eat already?
John!
Yes?
I don't help much!
Don't help too much?
You do everything you can!
Hm?
What is that?
Ah, one week only?
Yes.
It is time to hold your breath!
Wellington Coal Mine has reached its limit.
The bank is no longer able
to pay costs without interest!
Now we can't extract coal.
Maybe we should give up.
But, just a week!
Sam...
I have to tell everyone the truth!
We need to think about
the future of our new life!
We should talk to John.
Do you have the power to tell him directly?
I'm not sure I can say it...
No, I'm going to do it.
I think you understand that too...
John has recently become more mature.
I wish that he was...
What is the matter with the manager?
He seems to be talking
about something different.
I hope to not say to stop it.
Hey he's coming!
Oh...
Listen everyone!
The manager has something to tell you!
You see?
Is it a unique stone?
I have extracted it from the wall!
Sandy!
This! Probably...
Just a moment, bring that book to me!
- The yellow one!
- Eh?
Oh...
Wait for me to sort them out first!
This one?
No... that one! The third one!
Right! That one!
Ah!
Hm...!
What is there?
There it is!
There it is! Ammonite!
Eh?
Aah!
This is serious!
What is the matter?
That's serious, Sandy!
Hm...
What is the matter?
Manager, tell us quickly!
We are also about to lose our temper!
Manager, should I say that instead of you?
I'm sorry.
I can't say it!
Everyone...
No...
I mean...
Somewhat...
No, I mean...
We have to let you all know...
Sir!
Hey sir! It's serious!
Serious thing!
Hm?
What is the matter? Why you were running?
In fact...
What are you saying?
This...
Oh...!
There it is! It's a carbon
element of antiquity!
It is an Ammonite...
This means...
What does it mean?
Coal is a tree grown in the
earth since ancient times!
But this oyster...
This is not an object!
Ah... sir, it is a bit different...
Oh?
In any case, we have to determine
the age of this object and it will
certainly determine the age of the tree
that has grown since ancient times
and is the main source of coal.
The object indicates
the presence of coal as well...!
Yeah, and charcoal too!
Well, we have to dig more!
We don't know what is coming
out to us, but let's dig, let's dig!
Yeah!
Ah, Colin!
Hey, John!
Thank you, Colin!
No way...
Sandy is the one who
picked it up from the mine.
I thought it was a plain stone.
Be proud of yourself!
Hey! Something else appeared!
Is it coal?
No, but it stirred up!
Traces, but...
What do you think?
It looks huge!
Professor, how was it?
It's good to find the entire body of Ariophus,
which is considered one of
the most important ancient relics!
I heard that the mine will close today!
After that I can say that coal can go out
according to previous geological studies,
but still little possibility.
And order to close the mine,
it's completely wrong.
So I have to tell the Duke
to abandon his decision.
That's all, sorry I'm going!
Thank you so much!
No.
You thank the children!
Yes!
What? What about John?
He's in the place I found the oyster,
and digs with Mr. Pia and the others!
I'ts enough...
He wants to continue until the end!
John!
Hm?
You have to stop!
Leave the rest to your father!
Yes, but...
John, come here a little bit!
What's up, Mr. Pia?
What happened?
We have finally done it, John!
We did it!
We finally did it!
Coal has come out!
Yeah!
Well done, John!
With this thing Lassie
can come back to me, right?
John...
After feeling comfortable I feel sleepy...
I'm glad I trusted you, Dad...
I... somehow...
Sleepy...
Lassie...
Oh!
John...
He felt relieved after he was nervous!
So let him sleep.
What about Lassie?
I have received a message from
Priscilla but there is no news of it.
I see.
Lassie...
Wait, Lassie!
So we can always stay together!
Together...
Lassie is no longer on my side!
I wonder if it is still walking?
But, where does it walk in this world?
Lassie...!
Where did you go, Lassie?
Oh! Where are you now?
Where do you walk now?
Lassie!
Lassie... I'm sorry...
I've made you tire a lot!
John?
Oh?
Priscilla?
Did you sleep well?
They came from Scotland by plane.
By plane!
Did I sleep?
For two days!
Eh?
Have I really slept all this time?
John!
Congratulations!
Because of your faith,
you brought the coal out again,
though I didn't believe it!
Yes...
You've done a really good job!
Your heart has won over me!
However...
I apologise...
I promised you that I would give Lassie back.
But I couldn't keep it!
You are the only one who
can take care of Lassie!
Right, Lassie!
I have to find Lassie!
Lassie is still walking towards our village!
Ah!
Get out! My clothes!
- John!
- You'll change your clothes, John?
Listen, John
If Lassie returns,
it will be like a miracle!
Grandfather!
No!
I apologize but I don't know what to say!
No, Lassie is still walking to here!
No...
I saw that!
That Lassie is coming here!
You have seen?
But, where are you going?
Isn't it clear?
To the north side!
When Lassie left Scotland
it walked straight toward this village!
Hey John!
Where are you going?
Lassie!
Eh?
Lassie is on its way back here!
It will arrive here soon!
Oh?
To north, to north!
To north!
This is the right direction!
If I turn here I will meet Lassie!
Huh!
Lassie!
Ah!
No way, Lassie!
Lassie!
Ah!
Lassie...
This way! John turned this way!
Ah!
Oh!
Are you okay, Lassie?
Can you walk to get home?
Hey!
John
Lassie!
- Lassie...
- Welcome back, Lassie!
The Wellington Coal Mine is back in business!
Yes!
Ah!
Look there!
John! Lassie!
Father! Mom!
Look, everyone came for you, Lassie!
Hey!
After a long journey,
Lassie returned to our village!
After that it became famous in the newspapers!
That's why Duke Rudering decided
to organize a big party for it!
The last episode:
RUNNING TOWARDS THE DREAM
Be sure to watch!