Old Castle & south wind subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Keep walking towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
Back in my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
would beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
always watch over you,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari
a neverending story
Mr. Curry's Wedding Day
He's here!
Congratulations!
Congratulations, sir!
We're looking forward to
your wedding ceremony tomorrow, sir.
We wish you happiness!
The blackboard is
for teaching purposes.
It's not to be doodled on.
What were you thinking?
Get out your notebooks.
Class is starting.
"You remind me
of the early summer days,
but you are even more
beautiful and delicate.
The wind of May
gently takes flower seeds.
Only in the summer…"
Good. That should be enough.
We can now make a bouquet.
The bride will be happy.
It wouldn't kill Mr. Curry to show
some enthusiasm, too.
We even prepared a party
in the classroom for him.
Well, that's just how he is.
Imagine him all smiley.
Honestly, that would creep me out.
You have a point.
Mary will be overjoyed.
Thank you.
I'd like to deliver it to Mary personally,
and congratulate her while I'm at it.
She's at Robert's place right now.
They're talking about
moving in, I believe.
So, want me to keep it
until she's back?
No, it's fine.
We'll just go to them now
and give it to Ms. Marry ourselves.
What's there
to laugh about, John?
Just think about it. We're going to see
Mr. Curry and Ms. Mary together.
I got it! We'll get to see how he's like
when he's with his fiancée!
Oh…
Let's go!
We'll be standing at the altar
at this time tomorrow.
Yes.
Is that all?
What do you mean?
Hm?
Is something on your mind?
Haven't you forgotten
about something important?
Something important?
Yes, something
very, very important.
Let's see…
The preparations
for the wedding are finished.
We're all packed
for the honeymoon as well.
That's not what I meant.
That's not what you meant…
I know! I did forget
about one thing, indeed.
Did you just realize it?
It's the rings!
I wanted to put them in the suit
I'm going to wear tomorrow
so that I would not
forget them by accident.
We are buttoned up.
Are you absolutely sure?
Huh?
Isn't there something else
you forgot about?
Such as?
It is the most important thing.
You haven't done it yet.
Huh?
I can't marry you like this.
What?
Things are taking a strange turn.
Stop this tomfoolery.
It's no tomfoolery.
If you don't have any idea
what I'm talking about…
Yes. I have no choice.
I will not go with you to the altar.
Mark my words.
You're just nervous
before the ceremony.
Let's get you home.
You should take rest.
I'll walk with you.
I'll be fine by myself.
See you.
Oh… Be careful on your way.
I am very serious.
Yes, yes, I understand.
Let's talk about it
after the wedding.
Ms. Mary?
Hm?
It's you, children.
It smells so nice.
Thank you.
– Ms. Mary…
– Yes?
We overheard that you might
cancel the wedding tomorrow.
Were you serious?
Who knows.
I think I was.
But why?
Did something happen?
Could it be…
Could it be that you don't like
Mr. Curry anymore?
I love him.
That is the problem here.
I feel bad for Mr. Curry.
While I agree that
he's a very strict person
and it's not very fun
to be around him—
John, don't say this to Ms. Mary.
But…
John, while it is true
that he is a strict person,
but he is the most upstanding
and honest person I know.
Besides, even he
is not always serious.
When he's reading his favorite poems,
he has the sweetest smile in the world.
Then why?
Yeah. Why?
I'm sorry, children.
This is not something
I want to talk about to anyone.
Come on, Ms. Mary.
If you want, we can give you some advice.
Yeah. What happened?
I may be bad at talking,
but I'm good at listening to people.
All right.
You see…
Say, Dad…
Hm?
Listen…
What's up?
You can ask me anything.
Dad.
Do you love Mom?
Where did this come from?
Just answer.
Of course I love your mother.
And I love you too.
Are you able to tell her
that directly?
Of course I am.
What's gotten into you?
Never mind.
John, talk to me.
It's a secret.
Look, darling.
It's such a beautiful morning!
Wake up and get ready.
Get ready for what?
The wedding ceremony.
Oh, today is Robert's wedding.
It's a perfect day for a wedding.
John!
John, wake up!
Oh? Where did he go?
Lassie, too?
Mary…
Oh? It's you, Robert.
An early bird, as expected.
Thanks…
Where's Mary?
Isn't she in the waiting room?
You haven't seen her today yet?
No, not yet.
It's bad luck for the bride and the groom
to see each other before the wedding.
Naturally, I don't believe
in such superstitions.
But she's not in the waiting room.
Maybe she's still asleep?
It's fine. There's plenty of time
till the ceremony starts.
You're right.
See you later.
So she hasn't come yet…
What am I supposed to write here?
"Dear Robert".
"Dear Robert"…
Then…
It's almost ten o'clock.
We have only half an hour
before the ceremony.
Yes…
I feel much better
after talking to you.
Who do we have here!
Congratulations, Mr. Curry.
Thank you very much.
I'm so jealous, you bad boy.
I'm not a bad boy.
Mary is sure taking her time…
Mary? She's not here yet?
No.
That's strange.
She should be dressing right now.
I'm sorry.
Excuse me for a moment.
Do you know where Mary is?
Mary?
Mary left the house
long before me.
What's going on?
Well…
Congratulations.
Thanks.
Why Mary is not here yet?
That is something
I would like to know myself.
Anything happened
between you guys?
I can't marry you like this.
I am very serious.
Did something happen?
Not really.
Congratulations, congratulations!
I'm so happy for you.
How is the bride's father
feeling right now?
Come with me, come!
You're the Carracloughs' dog, right?
You can't enter the church.
Hm?
What's that? Show me.
"To Robert Curry"…
I recognize this handwriting…
Mary!
It's a letter from Mary!
What did she write?
Good, he's got it.
Quick, open the envelope
and read what's inside.
What's going on?
Robert!
Oh, Mother, Father!
You made it, after all!
Never mind them,
just read the letter…
Our child is getting married.
Even if we were on the other side of Earth,
there is no way we could miss that.
Where did you hide
your cute fiancée?
I'd love to finally meet her.
Well, about that…
She forgot something
and she went to get it real quick.
While wearing a wedding dress?
Yes, which is why
it's taking so long.
This isn't good.
Just read it already.
I apologize for the late introduction.
I am Mary's father.
I see.
Right, the letter!
Congratulations, Mr. Teacher.
Congratulations.
Ah, thank you so much!
Where is your bride?
Is it okay for us to see her?
She… went to get something
she had forgotten…
Is he going to read it or not?
What are you going to do?
The priest will be here soon.
What do you suggest, Dad?
I'm not your dad yet!
I'm sorry!
If I knew this would happen, I'd seriously
reconsider letting my daughter marry you.
Now is not the time for this.
Congratulations,
Mr. Rice, Mr. Curry.
Nope. He completely
forgot about the letter.
All the guests
must've arrived by now.
I'm sure the teacher
is drenching in sweat.
Was it the right thing to do?
You can't back out now.
Or are you telling me
it's okay to marry him as is?
You're right.
It's not, really.
What on earth is Mary doing?
Why didn't she come?
It's not like we had a bad fight
or anything yesterday.
Mary…
Where are you now?
What are you doing?
Right, the letter!
Good! Now read it.
"I'll be waiting for you
in our special spot."
Mary…
Mary!
Let's go with him!
Yeah!
Mary! Mary! Mary!
Ah, ouch!
Mary!
Good, good!
Right to your special spot.
Oh?
That's not the way.
School is in the other direction.
Mr. Curry got the wrong place…
Don't go that way!
I thought that he'd know in a flash
the place Ms. Mary meant…
But he doesn't have
the slightest idea!
Since when was Mr. Curry
such a fast runner?
I'm in a hurry, Lassie!
I don't have time
to play with you—
Hey!
That's the wedding rings you took!
You crazy dog!
Well done, Lassie.
Wait!
What are we doing in this place?
Lassie! Cut it out, will you…
Mary.
I finally know.
The thing I was supposed
to say to you.
Really?
Yes. It's about the wallpaper.
It can be green like you wanted.
I don't mind it!
Wallpaper?…
Oh?
That wasn't it?
Then how's this?
You're always looking after me.
Looking after you?
I will fix all the flaws in myself.
I'll sort all my clothes.
I will make sure to brush
my teeth after every meal.
I will be careful not to
make a mess when eating.
I will keep my nails short…
He's like a kid…
So, please, Mary. Don't be angry
with me anymore and marry me!
Wait a moment.
Eh?
I'm not angry over
such trivial things.
So what is it?
This is the place where we talked
for the first time. Remember?
I came to deliver bread
for the picnic you had here at school.
So that was it…
"So that was it"?
Aren't you here because I told you
to come to our special spot?
No, actually, at first I thought
you meant the Berry Forest.
But Lassie took the rings
and I chased her down here.
Right, the rings.
Give them back, Lassie!
Robert…
I'm sorry.
Remember how I told you that you forgot
to say the most important thing to me?
Yes, I do.
You said the same thing yesterday.
Not just yesterday.
Do you realize how many times
I had asked you about it?
No… I don't think I do.
The thing I forgot.
The thing I forgot…
How about this.
Why do you want to marry me?
Well, it's because you're beautiful
and good at cooking.
You are interested in books,
and have good sense of wallpapers—
These aren't the words
I want to hear! Not at all!
Uh…
So, maybe…
Marriage between a man
and a woman is…
Well, it signifies
establishment of a family…
Which means…
Let me ask you again.
Why do you want to marry me?
That's because…
Yes?
This is because you're
like a world class pianist!
When your white fingers play on the piano that
is my heart, a beautiful melody comes out!
When I hear it, everything—
That's a line from some book!
I want to hear you say it
in your own words!
I don't care about some quotes!
I just want you to tell me in your own way
what are your feelings for me.
I'm in love with you.
What have you just said?
I can't hear you!
I'm in love with you, Mary!
That's why I want to marry you!
You said it, at long last.
You never told me this before,
not even once.
I didn't?!
Uh…
So that's what it was about.
Yes.
It's okay, Lassie.
You can give it back.
Lassie…
So…
You also…
Yes.
I'm in love with you, Robert.
I will marry you.
Congratulations, sir!
Congratulations!
I wish you a happy life!
Where did you come from, children?
Remember to fold
your clothes well, sir.
Make sure you brush
your teeth well!
To think it's you
who's looking after us.
Yeah!
Oh, children…
Throw the bouquet, Mary!
Over here, over here!
Whoever picks up the bouquet
will be the next bride!
All right!
Lassie…
A circus comes to our town.
And they have a huge elephant!
But it's treated badly
and seems very scared.
And then…
Next episode: "A Big Problem!
The Elephant Escaped From The Circus".
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams