Old Castle & south wind subs present
WORLD MASTERPIECE THEATER
FAMOUS DOG LASSIE
"Neverending Story" sung by Jun Morioka
ryoute ni atarashii asa
Keep walking towards
jibun ni kitaishite
the new day
aruite yukou
with hope
osanai hi
Back in my childhood days,
chiisana mune wo
my little heart
tokimekaseteta
would beat faster
zutto
I will
soba de mimamotteru
always watch over you,
daichi no komoriuta no you ni
like a lullaby from the earth
sore wa kitto
I'm sure everyone
dare no naka ni mo aru
has one within them,
owaranai monogatari
a neverending story
The bus back goes
in 2 hours, right?
Yes. It will be the last,
so make sure not to miss it.
To reach the town,
go straight down the road…
Yes, I know.
I know that very well.
I never thought
I'd miss this place so much.
My hometown.
I Want To See
My Grandmother
Don't be a clown.
What do you want after all these years?
I'm saying, I apologize.
Let's forget the past and live together.
Get lost.
I don't want to see your face!
Uh, Grandma Forrest?
What is it, John Carraclough?
Mr. Curry kept you
after school today again?
Yes.
It's because you've been
reading books all night long.
It's no wonder you
overslept and were late.
Grandma Forrest sees everything.
Looking down from that window she knows
everything that happens around the town.
You're late, John!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I saw something
very strange just now.
Huh?
Very strange?
Yeah.
I never saw Grandma Forrest
act like this before.
She was very angry with someone.
Angry?
Our Grandma Forrest?
Yeah.
She poured water on him
from the second floor.
I must say, it was
a remarkable welcome.
It was to be expected.
You ran away from home
twenty years ago.
You didn't try to contact her, not even once.
You can only blame yourself.
Thank you for the towel.
Sure.
Twenty years.
For me, it flew by
in a blink of an eye.
It never occurred to me that Pops
could have died in the meantime.
I see.
I do not think a good-for-nothing son
like myself can be easily forgiven.
Are you going back already?
Yes. I absolutely have
to go back to work.
I plan to visit her frequently,
for as long as time allows.
I will stay patient and hope
that she will forgive me, eventually.
See you.
Take care.
Son?
Sir…
Who is that man? I saw him
in front of Grandma Forrest's house.
Well…
He is Ms. Forrest's son.
Grandma Forrest's?
Her son?
Yes.
But Grandma Forrest said
she didn't want to see his face.
Albert left this town after having
a huge fight with his parents.
A huge fight?
Rejected again.
Why doesn't
Grandma Forrest let him in?
He's her son, after all.
I don't know either.
Something happened
between those two a long time ago.
I don't really know
what it was about, though.
Her son left town
before our family settled here.
No matter what happened, I'm sure
that deep down she wants to meet him.
Hm?
Why?
Am I right?
Isn't that what family is all about?
Yes. Very true.
John, you are right, of course.
But you don't know their circumstances.
If I was a parent, I'd want
to see my children, no matter what!
Same goes for you, right, Dad?
Yes.
You're right.
My goodness.
Oh, where are you headed
on your day off?
I'm going to talk for a bit
with Mrs. Forrest.
What does he mean,
"live together"?
That shameless scamp.
Mrs. Forrest.
Do you have a moment?
Who do we have here?
Sam Carraclough.
When did you get here?
Oh, please, ma'am.
How could a hawk like you
miss anything that happens outside?
Can I come in for a bit?
What's this?
It's for you to open the door.
A strange man is bothering me lately,
so I began to lock the door.
Why would you go that far?
Isn't that strange man
actually your son?
My son, you said?
Yes.
Sam Carraclough!
Yes?
I don't have a son!
My only family is
my late husband George!
What? I mean…
Hmph.
I'm telling you.
I don't have any children—
Good Lord!
Mrs. Forrest!
D… Dad?
John, call Dr. Hopper.
Quickly!
Sure!
It was just a mild hypertension.
At your age, you should
be careful not to get too upset.
I'm back.
How did it go?
Eh.
Will Grandma come soon?
Oh? No, she still holds
a grudge against me.
I can't do much about it.
She's stubborn like a mule.
Is she?
When I look at this picture,
she looks like a very nice grandma.
I made you dinner.
I'll leave it here.
John Carraclough.
There is no need to treat me
like I was a patient in a hospital.
Aren't you going to be late
for kite flying?
Oh?
Did I tell you about it?
My eyes are sharp as ever.
I see everything.
You can go now.
Okay. See you!
Aren't you going with him, Lassie?
I've been watching over this town
for quite a long time.
Look.
Dohan is passing by, isn't he?
He's worrying over something again.
Completely unduly, I bet.
You were raised
in Sam Carraclough's house.
I still remember the first day
we met in this town.
He was still wet behind ears
and went to school.
The day John took you in
seems like yesterday to me, Lassie.
Hm?
This?
It's an old picture of my family.
This is me.
That's my late husband George.
And this pumpkin here…
He was such a nice kid back then.
At some point, he went down the wrong path.
Where did I make a mistake?
He wrote a note that he wanted to seek
freedom in a foreign country and left us.
George worked like crazy to
make money for our son's future.
He used some of it to buy an ancient gold piece,
and looked forward to passing it down.
But that boy stole the gold piece!
Hmph.
I didn't know what he was doing
and where he lived.
He never came back,
even when his father died.
And now he has the nerve to come
and ask me to live with him in some city.
Who does he think he is?
That ungrateful scoundrel.
Whoa!
It's flying!
You're late, Lassie.
Were you at Grandma Forrest's
all that time?
At Grandma Forrest's?
Huh? Lassie, did you
become friends with her?
What's up, Lassie?
Ah, look!
Someone is down there.
What are they doing?
Excuse us…
Is everything okay?
Are you feeling well?
Am I feeling…?
You got it wrong.
I lost something precious around here,
and I'm looking for it now.
Something precious?
It's a necklace I got from my Dad.
A necklace?
It was very precious to my Dad.
Ah! There it is!
I'm so happy. Thank you.
By the way, I don't think
I've seen you around here.
Oh, right.
I'm Roy George Forrest.
Forrest?
Oh, could you be…
Grandma Forrest's grandson?
Hm?
Do you know my grandma?
Well, duh! Everyone knows her.
Yeah. But come to think of it,
she knows everything about us,
whereas we don't actually know
the first thing about her.
Yeah…
You're right.
I also don't know her,
even though she's my grandma.
Huh?
If you don't know anything
about your grandma,
she has the opinion of being
very harsh and stubborn—
Ouch!
Knock it off.
You're being rude.
Ah, right. I'm sorry.
It's okay! My Dad said Grandma
was harsh and stubborn as well.
That's why even if when I asked to take me
to her place with him, he wouldn't let me.
We have an old picture
of Grandma at home.
She looks very kind
and has a nice smile.
Every time I look at that photo,
I wish I could meet Grandma in person.
That's why…
That's why?
That's why I finally came here
without telling my parents.
All by myself.
Let's go see her.
I'll guide you to her place.
Okay.
Mother!
My wife and my son
want to see you!
It's your grandson, Mother.
You want to see him, don't you?
My grandson, you say?
My only family
is my late husband George.
I don't have any children.
If I have no children, it means
I have no grandchildren either.
Why would I want
to meet some strangers?
But, Mother!
Go away.
If you don't,
I will pour more water on you.
Grandma doesn't want to see me.
That's not true.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Of course she wants to meet you.
She's just unable to say it out loud,
because she doesn't want to give in.
Mhm.
Is there anything we could do?
Hmm.
Any ideas, John?
Hmm. Let me think.
I can't believe she's this stubborn.
What is it?
Do you give up already?
Of course not.
Since I left this town, I went to many places
and finally managed to build a successful life.
I found a place for myself
and settled down.
I recently realized that
the only missing piece is my mother.
It took me only
twenty years to realize that.
Twenty years!
I… I see.
That's why I'm not going
to give up so easily.
That's the spirit. You just have to be
even more stubborn than her.
Amen to that.
Maybe I take after my Mother?
A grandson?
Hmph.
Hm?
What brings you to my home,
John Carraclough?
I brought some cookies with me.
I thought maybe we could have tea, ma'am.
I smell something fishy.
Whatever. Come in.
My cousin came by today.
Is it okay if he tags along?
That child…
Albert? No. It's not possible.
Are you ready?
Remember, I'm not here
as her grandson.
If she finds out, she'll drive us out.
Everything will be fine.
It's nice to drink tea together
from time to time, don't you think?
Grandma…
I believe you said he was your cousin,
John Carraclough.
But I can't say
he looks anything like you.
Really? Well, he just happened
to come to my house today.
Hmph.
I didn't know you had a cousin.
Really? But there he is.
John!
John?
Are you there?
If you're not, tell us!
They're calling you,
John Carraclough.
Go on and answer them.
Okay. I'll leave you for a moment.
Roy, pour some tea for Grandma.
Oh… Sure.
Hey, wait!
I can't. Sandy's calling me.
See you!
You'd better go with him.
No. I'll prepare the tea.
Here.
Why are you standing like a pole?
We're having tea,
so bring a chair and take a seat.
Ah… Sure!
What's your name?
My name is Roy.
Roy.
Hmph. That's one funny name
your parents gave you.
This town…
This town produces coal, right?
Yes.
My Grandpa was a worker
in a coal mine, too.
Oh?
I see.
My husband was one, too.
He was working in a mine as well.
What a coincidence.
He was a very proud man.
But…
But? What happened?
So your father inherited
your grandfather's ambition
and became
a great miner as well, no?
Not really.
Oh, I was wrong? That's too bad.
Ma'am…
Hm?
Before I was born,
my Dad was a sailor.
He visited many, many countries.
He always yearned
for that kind of life.
To your detriment.
Hm?
I do not want to talk
about this anymore.
She's not looking.
Now's the time!
I can't hear anything.
They're not talking at all, or what?
Listen, Colin…
Okay. Gotcha.
Isn't it time for you to go,
John's cousin?
It is.
Good bye, ma'am.
Bye.
Oh, no! Don't do this, I have to go!
Lassie, let the boy go.
T-This is…
Show it to me, Lassie!
This is…
I got it from my Dad.
It's a real… It's a gold piece that
dates back to the fifteenth century!
Could this be…
Do you know how many of George's
salaries went into this thing?!
What kind of a parent would
let a child like you have it?
I don't know anything about it!
Dad never told me
anything about it.
He just told me that no matter how poor I get,
I can never sell it for money.
I see.
When my Dad was a sailor,
he was afflicted with bad illnesses,
he was fired many times and suffered a lot.
But…
But no matter how difficult it got, he just grasped
that coin tightly and told himself to do his best.
Is that right?
So he never sold it.
I will never forget what he said to me
and will always strive to do my best with this.
Roy.
Huh?
Don't just stand there.
Come closer.
I'm a bit old and
I can't hear you well.
Come closer and talk to me.
I…
I'm so happy
that I came to this town.
My Dad didn't work in the mine
and became a sailor instead,
yet I'm still very proud of him.
That huge ship he worked on
was powered by coal!
It was coal that let the ship's furnace
heat and lead it to the seven seas!
And it was my grandfather
who mined that coal!
I'm so glad that I came here.
And that I found Grandma
in this town…
Grandma?
I knew that!
Roy. That you…
are my grandson.
Grandma!
I know you're there,
John Carraclough.
Show yourself.
She does know everything.
Call Albert for me.
But Dad went to
the bus stop already.
He's still at Jones' store.
He wanted to be particularly
persistent today and didn't go home yet.
I always knew what he was up to,
ever since he was a little boy.
Not this time, Grandma.
This time you missed.
Mr. Albert is already here.
He's been here for a while
and heard everything.
At last, for once you managed
to outwit me, John Carraclough.
Mother.
I won't tell you to leave this town
and come live with me anymore.
So, please…
I'm not going anywhere.
Welcome home, Albert.
Mother!
Congratulations, Albert.
Here it goes. Say cheese!
The mine has run out of coal!
If we don't do something,
it will get shut down.
Dad goes without sleep, trying
to figure out the cause and a solution.
I want to help him.
Next episode:
"John's Decision! Protect The Mine".
Be sure to watch!
"The Boy's Hill" sung by Jun Morioka
tasogare ni wa kimi to
The clock strikes twelve,
oka no ue kakenobori
and I run with you up the hill
tooi sora o miteta
We can see the distant skies
shounen no anogoro woo
I still remember that time, woo
poketto kara ochita
Falling out of the pocket,
candy to toki no suna
a candy and the sands of time
otona ni naru tame no
The journey has begun
tabi wa hajimatteta
to become an adult
moeagaru
The hot burning
yuuhi no kanata
setting sun
mada deaenai
is still high in the sky
hito ya machi ga kitto matteru
People and towns are waiting
hohoen de
You promised
yakusoku shita ne
with a big smile
ano oka wo koe
after we crossed that hill
itsuka yume wo sagashi ni yukou to
that someday we'll fulfill our dreams