These kids are Riders.
Despite the horrors of the Black Blight…
…they faced it bravely.
What has saved the world
was the strength of their kinship.
By bringing the light back, they made the world safe again.
However!
Avinia has been taken away by mysterious riders who claim to be Ebon Riders.
Who are the Ebon Riders that kidnapped Avinia…?
Monster Hunter Stories: Ride On
Bokura kyou mo ikiteiru
We are still living today
Bokura kyou mo waratteru
We are still laughing today
Sore dake de mou nanimo iranai
We don't need anything more
Ima sugu ni RIDE ON
Just RIDE ON
Bokura sugu ni motomeru
We're quick to want
Yokubarina ikimono sa
This feeling is only natural
Nanimo motazuni umaretekita no ni
We're born without anything after all
Shiawase wa
Happiness is
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakatte kureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
To lose sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Onaji sora no shita onaji sora wo miagenagara
We're under the same sky, we look at the same stars
Utsukushii iro no kizuna kazoeteiyou
Let's keep this beautifully colored bond
Shiawase wa itsumo
Happiness is forever
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakattekureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
Of losing sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Episode 49
Invasion of Ebon Riders
Who do you think these Ebon Riders are?
They call themselves Riders.
But are they really?
Yeah…
And why did they kidnap Avinia?
Seems like they're interested in her Kinship Stone. But why?
I'm sure they have a reason.
Yeah.
Still, we have to save her somehow.
Avinia is the one who went with you
to the Tower of Illusion, huh?
Hey, what kind of Rider was it that took her?
Could give us some more details?
This portrait gives no clues at all.
Hmm.
He was wearing this scary full body armor-nyaa.
So you couldn't see their face at all?
Nyaa-ope.
The world was just saved from the Black Blight.
And now we have to deal with this right after…
What is your opinion on this, Chief Omna?
Hmm.
If I recall correctly, Avinia was the only one
who survived back then, right?
Yep.
That might be related to the current events.
Huh?
I don't know the details, but…
I heard that in Avinia's village there was a
family that possessed special Rider powers.
A family with special powers?
Precisely.
Perhaps the Riders who took Avinia knew about that family?
Probably.
I don't know anything for sure, however.
Whether they knew or not, I won't forgive them!
Yeah.
Those Ebon Riders…
…they might be seeking a new kind of power.
Thinking back…
…I really wanted to be strong, too.
We have to save Avinia.
You got that right.
Chief. We're free to go to save her, right?
Hmm.
I understand the feeling of wanting to help your friend very well.
But we must act carefully here.
That's right, Lute. Even if you go help,
you need to be careful.
I know. I won't do anything stupid.
Don't worry, Lute has Navirou, the best navigator in the world!
Everything will be A-okay!
Just who are these Ebon Riders?
Why do you want Kinship Stones so much?
I know the answer to your question.
But I have no intention of sharing it with you.
There's no need for you to know it.
Master Anvis.
Can I put this thing in the lower zone?
She'll be a good girl now.
I bet she will.
If she doesn't want to get eaten by Wrath, that is.
I'm hungry!
Chief Omna, what's our next move?
Hmm.
To tell you the truth, I don't want anyone
to take any unnecessary risks.
However, trying to stop Lute is a risk in itself…
Can't argue with you there.
It can't be helped.
Dan, can you take Genie and the others with you?
And if they complain about it, do your best to persuade them.
Yes, sir!
Of course.
Chief, I have a favor to ask.
What is it, Nariki?
Please let me go, too.
I know I just became a Rider,
but I want to be of use to everyone.
But you're still an apprentice.
I won't be a burden. I'll do my best.
So please…!
I see trying to stop you is dangerous as well…
You resemble Lute in many ways.
Then…!?
However, Nariki.
Protecting the village is an important task for a Rider.
You will remain here, protecting the
village while your seniors are away.
This is your duty now.
Do you understand?
Yes, sir.
I will protect the village.
What do you think, Gale?
Think about what, Shadow?
About bringing that little girl in here, of course.
What's the purpose of it?
We've been stealing Kinship Stones up till now…
but we've never caught a Rider.
So what?
Master Anvis must have plans for her.
But this girl has an impressive Kinship Stone.
This girl must have other Rider friends, I doubt they'll stay silent for long.
Friends? What friends?
Wasn't her whole village annihilated?
She's all alone.
I wasn't talking about her village.
There are other Riders in this world.
The ones who stopped the Black Blight, for example.
I see.
The group from Hakum, huh?
Well, I will crush and eat anybody
who stands in my way.
Those Riders already know that we're searching for Kinship Stones.
This will be interesting.
It'll be satisfying, seeing those incompetent Riders tremble in fear of us.
Mad, if you let your guard down
with me, you'll regret it.
It will be interesting, though.
I will take you on any time.
My goal is to capture the Kinship Stone of the Rider who flies a Rathalos.
You're referring to Lute?
I'm interested in his Kinship Stone myself.
Are you going to approach him, Gale?
Because I won't let you.
Well, look at that. Shadow is interested as well.
Wait, wait. I want it too.
His Kinship Stone is mine!
Oh really?
Fools.
All Kinship Stones belong to Master Anvis.
We're only here to fulfill our duty.
I need that Kinship Stone.
The one that belongs to the Rider flying a Rathalos.
Go, Gale.
Hell yeah!
Roger that, Master Anvis.
Sorry, Mad and Wrath.
Shadow.
Tsk! Why you?
I don't like this.
Very well. Let's see what you've got.
All right, Nariki!
Try to "Ride On".
Yes, sir!
You can do it, Nariki.
You're the village protector.
Ride On!
Velocidrome!
All right!
Nice!
I did it.
I did it!
Hey, Nariki!
Don't just aimlessly run around!
You must bond with it first!
Okay!
I get it!
Yahoo!
Onwards, onwards!
Good luck, Nariki.
Make sure you take this seriously.
He's been always like this.
Well, it's the birth of a new Rider.
It is.
And I have to work hard too.
Oh? By the way…
Why are there Riders that steal Kinship Stones?
What's their goal in doing that?
I wanted to investigate it as a squad member.
Oh?
I am planning to consult Captain Simone about it as well.
Lilia is growing too.
I heard what you said.
Captain Simone!
Mr. Reverto too.
Deb…!
…li.
It's Debli! Why do you always mess it up?
Lilia.
I heard that you want to study the Ebon Riders.
Of course you have our permission.
Thank you so much.
Hey, don't ignore me!
We were on our way back to Gildegaran.
But we overheard a rumor about mysterious Riders…
…so we hurried here.
I heard that Avinia was captured.
Is it true?
Unfortunately…
…I think it's true.
Damn.
Who would do such thing?
They're obviously hunting for the
Kinship Stones all over the place.
I see.
I'm worried.
About that girl, as well as everyone's' Kinship Stones.
Investigate all that you can here, Lilia.
Not just for the squad, but also for your friends.
We can't just leave things as they are.
Yes ma'am.
We will gather all the information we can as well.
My information network is pretty cool too.
Thank you very much.
Captain Simone, Mr. Reverto…
Hey, hey, don't just skip over me!
Thank you, Deb…
Hey, it's…!
…li.
You're doing this on purpose, aren't you?
Is Avinia the girl who survived back then?
She is.
I heard that her village holds a lot of secrets.
I'd better investigate things as well.
I agree.
I'm counting on you.
Please be patient a little longer.
We'll be saved for sure.
Hey there!
It's meal time.
It'd be a waste if you threw this food away.
Thank you very much.
Hey, little girl.
I'll say this perfectly clear.
Right now, you're powerless.
You can't do anything by yourself.
Naturally, you don't have the key, or the power to break the chains.
Do not forget that.
Well, it'd be a different story if you had Wrath's appetite.
What do you hope to gain from all of this?
A Kinship Stone, of course.
And from the world's best Rider, too.
Huh?
Ride On!
Rathalos!
Nya-ow!
Lute will take Navirou.
We'll get to see just how useful he really is as a Navigator.
That said, we'll also be lending a hand.
To the other Riders, that is.
You look rather weak.
I may be right now, but I'm aiming to become the world's best Rider.
Seems impossible if you ask me.
But, you know what?
I'll become your Navigator.
One condition, though! You have to call me "senpai".
'Aight, senpai.
Please take care of me.
You're funny, y'know!
Get off my back.
Cheval.
My coolness should go well with your coolness.
Why don't we join our forces?
Sure.
We'll be a good team.
Floof wants to pair with Mille-Mille.
Mille-Mille?
Then you'll be Floof-Floof.
Hehe.
Hyoro.
We're both reserved, so I
think we'd work well together.
I think so, too.
Looks like everyone got their Navigator, Navirou.
Well, it still doesn't change the fact that Navirou is the best Navigator around.
I will go with you, Lilia.
I want to research them as well.
The Ebon Riders.
Really? That's great! I'm sure we'll be a good team.
I can be useful too, y'know.
I can fish out information from here and there as well.
Fake intel could also be useful.
Right?
…fake intel?
Of course it's not fake!
I'm just joking.
I expect a lot of you, Deb…
Alright!
Well then, let's go!
– …li.
– Debli is one word!
Chief.
I'm leaving the village to you.
We'll be back as soon as possible.
Very well.
And Nariki will be staying with us.
Exactly.
Everything will be fine.
Then, we leave things to you, Mr. Gamigami.
Don't worry about us.
What is the goal of Ebon Riders and who are they?
I want you to research
both of these things in great detail.
However, do not forget to be extremely careful.
– Yes sir.
Um, I don't see Lute anywhere.
Lute said he wanted to see the village one more time.
Oh?
He must be having second thoughts.
After all, you guys just got back.
And now you're going away again.
I'll be lonely.
We'll be back soon, Loloa.
Don't cry.
We'll always be connected by our kinship.
You're right!
Our hearts will always be connected!
Yep.
Alright.
We're pretty far back in Hakum's woods.
Yep.
The Black Blight is gone.
And now we can go save Avinia without worrying too much.
Yeah.
But I still wonder who they are?
Those Ebon Riders.
Hm. It's a mystery.
Hey!
Rathalos Rider.
Huh?
You've got a sharp look.
As to be expected from someone who stopped the Black Blight.
But I can't bring myself to like you.
Huh? What's with you?
Wait… is that a Rathalos?
It's huge.
I've never seen a Rathalos like that.
Surprised? Gale's Rathalos is a rare species.
Rare species?
I'm Gale.
I'm Nuts.
And this is my little friend, Dusk.
Charmed to meet you, Lute.
How do you know me?
Get ready, Lute.
Look at the way he's hiding his face. He's a suspicious person, for sure!
Wait a second, don't tell me you're…
A-An Ebon Rider?
Is it true?
Who knows?
What do you think?
Don't give me that look.
We're both riding a
Rathalos, so let's be friends.
Yeah, friends, the very best of friends!
I heard you've captured Avinia!
Give her back!
Uh-oh.
You caught me, I won't object to that.
Then give her back.
Before that…
Let's do it, Lute.
Huh?
Do what?
Ain't it obvious?
Let's have a battle.
Eh?
I won't fight another Rider.
I just want you to return Avinia.
Is that so?
But we have to fight.
Eh?
Why?
What are you…?
It's right on your hand.
I want your Kinship Stone.
But you probably won't hand it over if I just ask you.
So there you have it.
Lute.
I think we should get back to the village.
We won't let you.
Exactly.
Alright, here I go!
Sync Ride!
What do we do, Lute?
Ride On!
Rathalos!
Wah.
Whew? Lute! Behind us!
He's fast!
What speed!
Ratha, go up!
Hold it right there!
Are you trying to run away?
That's not going to work!
What a bunch of…
Never mind, Navirou's going to help.
Lilia gave us lots of stuff just in case we ran into trouble.
Uhm… Not that, not this either…
What's this… Ah! Got it!
Hey, Mr. The-world's-best-rider!
Your Kinship Stone is ours.
It's nothing personal.
Lute here!
What's with this guy? He's crazy strong!
If I'm going to beat him I
need… Rite of Channeling?
I don't understand it yet, but I'd better hurry up!
Next time: "A Strong and Dangerous Man
Shrouded in Mystery". Ride On!