They're called Riders.
They are those who bond with monsters.
Sky-High Extreme!
As expected from Navirou's disciple!
That disciple of yours is pretty awesome!
You got that right!
It's alive!
No way.
You're the Black Dread?
We'll take him on!
The power of kinship can't be stopped by the Black Blight.
That's why we…
…won't lose to you!
Lute and his friends defeated the Black Blight and restored peace to the world.
But now a mysterious group has abducted Avinia.
And a new Rider appears before worried Lute to challenge him.
He calls himself Gale, an Ebon Rider.
Riding an unknown species of Rathalos…
…Gale demonstrates his overwhelming power, but…
…that's not all.
The Ebon Rider's Monstie hides another secret.
Monster Hunter Stories: Ride On
Bokura kyou mo ikiteiru
We are still living today
Bokura kyou mo waratteru
We are still laughing today
Sore dake de mou nanimo iranai
We don't need anything more
Ima sugu ni RIDE ON
Just RIDE ON
Bokura sugu ni motomeru
We're quick to want
Yokubarina ikimono sa
This feeling is only natural
Nanimo motazuni umaretekita no ni
We're born without anything after all
Shiawase wa
Happiness is
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakatte kureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
To lose sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Onaji sora no shita onaji sora wo miagenagara
We're under the same sky, we look at the same stars
Utsukushii iro no kizuna kazoeteiyou
Let's keep this beautifully colored bond
Shiawase wa itsumo
Happiness is forever
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakattekureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
Of losing sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Episode 50
"A Strong and Dangerous
Man Shrouded in Mystery"
Now that you have an idea of how powerful we are.
You'd better get serious this time.
Where's Avinia?
That's none of your business.
I came here for your Kinship Stone.
But why do you want it?
Cut the small talk!
Ratha!
Pretty good.
Ratha, are you okay?
Riders shouldn't be fighting each other!
What?
We're fighting… that?
Let me say it again.
Get serious.
No, I won't fight a Rider.
There's no point.
I see.
"There's no point", you say?
Well, that's your opinion…
…but not ours!
As expected from master Gale.
You're not like the others!
If we're going to fight, I will be the winner.
Whew.
What's with that Rathalos?
Not only he can breathe fire, he's equally strong at deflecting it.
Equally strong?
Equally?
What's with you?
You're creeping me out.
You're a disgrace to Felynes.
I mean, sure, Ratha is an ordinary species, and your Rathalos is special.
And you may be stronger, but nothing can beat Lute and Ratha's kinship.
Master Gale, he has no clue.
You can't blame him.
Why don't we teach him the hard way?
Dusk, let's use Thunder Strike.
What's with that glow?
He just said Thunder Strike.
"Thunder Strike" can be used only by Stygian Zinogres.
How can a Rathalos use it?
It's because we've awakened its sleeping kinship gene.
A kinship gene?
What's that?
You don't know anything, do you?
Not even about the Rite of Channeling?
So what if I don't know!
Just tell us already!
If you awaken the kinship genes, you can increase Monstie's abilities.
Hey, Rider. Try dodging this Dragon Breath!
Dragon Breath?
A Rathalos can't use such thing.
Oh, really…?
Lute!
I-I can't move!
Ratha! Take him to safety!
Escaping, huh?
Master Gale!
Hang in there, Lute!
Hey!
Looks like we caught up!
Donuts?
Not that.
Found it!
Where are you?
There! There! Take this!
Dusk, go up!
Tsk.
Where are Lute and Navirou?
We have to get going soon.
Navirou can't be helped.
Trouble!
Hey!
Oh?
What was that?
Emergency! It's an emergency!
Lute!
The Ebon Riders are here!
Then he told Lute to give up his Kinship Stone and challenged him to a battle…
…and his Monstie could use all of these weird attacks…
…and then they were babbling about some genes and ceremonies!
You mean the Rite of Channeling?
What's that?
We have no time for explanation.
You need to locate the Channeler, Lute.
Take Cheval with you.
The Channeler?
It's a Wyverian living in the Darj Snowfields.
Isn't that where Riddlemaster lived?
I guess he knew more than riddles.
Those Riders are collecting Kinship Stones and used the Rite of Channeling.
You should depart as soon as possible.
Master Gale.
Master Gale!
Where are you?
Quit your yelling!
Hop in!
Yes sir!
Understand?
Meet with the Channeler and listen to everything he says.
Leave the village to us.
We'll keep watching over it without sleeping-nyaa.
No matter what happens, we'll be here.
Focus on collecting the knowledge you need.
Good luck, Lute.
House-sitting is pretty boring, but we'll do our best!
Well then, let's go.
Ride On!
Qurupeco!
Monoblos!
Ride On!
Gravios!
Aptonoth!
Ride On!
Rathian!
I will accompany you, Cheval!
All right, let's depart!
Lute?
If we're going to save Avinia, we'll have to fight those Ebon Riders.
But their Rathalos was so strange.
Yep.
He used Thunder Strike like a Zinogre…
…and fire Dragon Breath like a Deviljho!
Even though it was still a Rathalos.
And what's up with this Rite of Channeling?
Is that supposed to change Ratha?
For now, we can't know for sure.
But whatever it is, it won't change our kinship.
Dan.
We're pretty small in numbers.
Why don't we all go?
Yeah! Let's all kick their butts!
But we're not used to fighting other Riders.
It's different from fighting a monster.
It is.
He pulled out his sword and slashed Ratha while I was still riding.
He went that far?
This is bad.
And it wasn't just him.
He had a companion like Floof.
It's just as Chief Omna says.
We need to hurry and meet the Channeler.
Master Gale! Look there!
We found them.
What is it, Aptonoth?
Dan.
Somebody's gaining on us.
They must be…
Yep, that's an Ebon Rider, for sure!
Ride On!
Rathalos!
Nya-ow!
He must have followed us.
Everyone should go ahead.
I'll stop him here.
Nole!
Even if he rides a Rathalos, I can delay him with this flash ball!
And just who are you?
I'm a Rider from Hakum. I won't let you pass.
Won't let me pass, huh…?
Isn't your Monstie an Aptonoth?
What of it?
An Aptonoth? An Aptonoth against…
…against my Dusk?
Are you for real?
It's hilarious, Master Gale.
What's wrong with my Aptonoth?
It probably won't be worth much, but…
…hand over your Kinship Stone.
If you don't make a fuss about it, I won't hurt you.
Don't underestimate me!
Let's go, Aptonoth!
You're the one who's underestimating.
How's that?
Huh?
Why didn't that flash ball work?
You're clueless, aren't you?
What was that?
It must've been that Monstie's Dragon Breath!
Nole!
Stone!
Go without me!
Dan, I'll go as well.
What do we do, Dan?
We hurry up.
No matter what, we need to get you to the Channeler!
That's our mission!
Master Gale! Two people that aren't Lute are coming!
Ha! How persistent!
Is he the one?
Hand over your Kinship Stones.
If you do as I say, I won't hurt you.
That's some pretty big talk.
There's two of us, you know!
We'll attack you from both flanks.
They really don't know a thing about fighting.
Honestly…
Let's crush them.
Dragon Breath.
After we pass through this cave, we arrive at the Darj Snowfields.
We can lose him here.
Oh no!
He's caught up onto us!
Hurry up and get in the cave!
But what about you?
Leave it to me!
Just hurry up and go!
But…!
Let's go, Lute.
Yeah, we need to meet with the Channeler.
Don't worry! Navirou will guide you through the cave!
All right then, Dan, we'll see you later.
Be careful!
Just leave it to me.
Ride On.
Qurupeco!
Ah, it's dark!
I can't navigate like this.
Leave it to me here.
Kira-kira-nyaa!
Good work, Fifi.
Let's go.
It's not Navirou's fault this place is too dark to see!
Great, here comes another weakling Rider.
It's only small fish.
What did you do to my friends?
They're off licking their wounds somewhere.
You can avoid their fate by giving us your Kinship Stone.
Don't screw with me.
Isn't that a Qurupeco?
Think you can stop us with that?
Don't make fun of my Qurupeco.
Qurupeco… Qurupeco…
Qurupeco is…!
How's that?
Didn't think a Qurupeco could do something like this, did you?
Wah, it just multiplied.
It still doesn't change anything, though.
Attack!
Master Gale!
He…!
What?
You're not getting in here.
What was that?
Dan must be fighting him now.
Let's hurry up.
How about that?
You won't be able to follow them now.
You little…
Now you've done it!
And there's more where that came from!
In top form!
How long is this cave anyway?
We just keep on walking and walking. It never ends…
Yeah, but the Darj Snowfields will be waiting for us at the end.
Jeez, you sure gave me a hard time.
Looks like we can't go this way.
What should we do, Master Gale?
Further tracking is impossible.
We'll return to the Black Castle.
Okay.
Dan's group has returned!
Lute said that special Rathalos was tough, but I didn't think it would be that tough.
And that's not all.
It also has the power of other monsters.
That's how it went.
That is the power of the Rite of Channeling.
It lets a monster use the abilities of other monsters.
Can it really do such thing?
Chief Omna. We were robbed of our Kinship Stones.
Why are you going that far?
Whew.
Now I can't Ride On.
In bad form.
Now we're the only ones in the village that can Ride On.
This is definitely serious.
Yeah, so we'd better do our best.
Our best-nyaa.
Hyoro, Mille.
Will me and my Velocidrome be of any use?
I don't think so.
Mille! You don't have to be so harsh.
It's better to be honest in this case.
If those Riders show up, we have to know our chance of winning.
I'll still do my best!
When it comes to that, just leave things to me.
Master Anvis.
These are all the Kinship Stones we managed to get.
Here they are, sir.
The Riders they belonged to weren't that big a deal, though.
We didn't manage to snag Lute's Kinship Stone this time around.
But we won't fail next time.
Master Gale, where do you think this Lute guy went?
You seem to be behaving.
Nuts, make a good meal for this good little girl.
Roger.
A good meal for a good little girl.
Oh, it's an exit!
Finally, the Darj Snowfields!
Hurrah! We're here!
Ah… cold.
What did you expect snow fields will be like?
Aren't you cold?
Not really.
What about you, Fifi?
Hmph!
I'll be fine with this.
I'm so jealous.
Wait, I'll create us a hot mist in a second.
You should feel a little warmer with this.
N-Nope, it's still cold.
Well, we're here. But where's the Riddlemaster's cottage?
Navirou thinks it's this way.
Alright, then this way?
Nya-ow!
Hey! Don't leave Navirou behind!
Nariki here!
I haven't really proven myself as a Rider yet, but my motivation can't be beat!
Eh? Who's this weird guy!?
Next time, "The Biggest Narcissist Ever!? Mad Appears!" Ride On!