These kids are called Riders.
And they form kinship with monsters.
Avinia is still being held hostage by mysterious Ebon Riders.
So, after losing to Gale, Lute and Cheval head off to learn about the Rite of Channeling.
They meet with the Riddlemaster.
While Lute is gone, one of the Ebon Riders
called Mad attacks the village.
Although Mille and Hyoro put up a fight, they're quickly defeated.
However, Nariki's quick wits managed to drive Mad off.
In order to learn the Channeling, Lute and Cheval…
…are taught by Dede Geezer about kinship genes and receive a Channeling Gem.
Navirou isn't as lucky, he learns
the Congalala's power to freely control farts.
And now, Lute is off to learn how to enter Monstie's kinship genes into his Channeling Gem.
Monster Hunter Stories: Ride On
Bokura kyou mo ikiteiru
We are still living today
Bokura kyou mo waratteru
We are still laughing today
Sore dake de mou nanimo iranai
We don't need anything more
Ima sugu ni RIDE ON
Just RIDE ON
Bokura sugu ni motomeru
We're quick to want
Yokubarina ikimono sa
This feeling is only natural
Nanimo motazuni umaretekita no ni
We're born without anything after all
Shiawase wa
Happiness is
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakatte kureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
To lose sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Onaji sora no shita onaji sora wo miagenagara
We're under the same sky, we look at the same stars
Utsukushii iro no kizuna kazoeteiyou
Let's keep this beautifully colored bond
Shiawase wa itsumo
Happiness is forever
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakattekureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
Of losing sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Episode 52
"The Forest Ninja, Shadow Arrives!"
Take care, Lute.
Yeah! I will return right away.
I leave saving Avinia to you.
Don't worry about me, just study all you need, Lute.
I'll look for Avinia.
I'll head to Gildegaran and try to research the Ebon Riders.
Leave it to us.
There's nothing to worry about with us on the case.
See you.
A kinship once bound…
…can never be broken.
Going out, Shadow?
I don't like boredom.
Where are you going?
Where I go…
…is my business, isn't it?
Of course it is.
Where you hunt for Kinship Stones
is no concern of mine.
I don't like it.
Let's go, Storm!
Ah, Sand Barioth.
The fact that we can see Sand Barioth means we're quite far to the South.
Did you know that Sand Barioth is part of the "Love Premonition" constellation?
No, I didn't know that.
It's common knowledge for girls.
This month's lucky color is red.
Red, huh?
Cheval, is something wrong?
It's nothing.
Just… Lute and I have always been together.
The village was always at peace.
At least, until that day…
And then I sought power.
Because I didn't want to let that tragedy happen ever again.
It blinded me into believing Manelger's words.
And because of that…
I drove the world to the brink of destruction.
If it wasn't for Lute, I'd be…
Oh?
This time I have to work hard… for Lute's sake.
You're right. Let's do our best and save Avinia.
– Now how about an Energy Drink!?
– Ah…
M-Maybe I'll…
Here, my specially made Energy Drink!
T-Thanks.
So that's an Energy Drink?
You've never drank one?
Nope. I didn't know it had such sweet, tasty aroma.
I have to try it out.
Wait, it was meant for Cheval!
I-It's hot!
It burns from the inside!
My coolness is melting!
He became very energetic indeed.
Lilia's Energy Drink lives up to its name.
The weather's nice this morning!
Alright, let's go.
Today's my lucky day.
So many Kinship Stones.
Even if they're all worthless garbage.
Gildegaran is that way, right?
I guess it's time for us to split up.
Take care, Fifi.
You too, Cryo.
They don't have any powerful Kinship Stones, right?
It seems there's a bit of a wall between us.
I guess you're right.
I can't really say there isn't one.
It's for the best.
Let's keep this relationship cool.
Left or right?
If I were to make a calm judgement, it's probably better not to go right.
Right, huh?
If it was Navirou, he'd probably choose left.
So, let's go right.
We should've turn left after all.
You're the ones who beat Riders around here
and take their Kinship Stones?
Eh? You know about the Ebon Riders, mister?
Huh!?
You know about the Ebon Riders, mister?
Who are these Ebon Tigers!?
He has a Kinship Stone, maybe he's a Rider?
My ears can still hear you!
We are not the Ebon Riders.
But we are looking for them.
I'm not giving this Kinship Stone to anyone!
Come!
Ride On! Aptonoth!
She's my Aptonoth.
She can crush rocks with her Slipping Dive.
It's a waste to Ride On for guys like you.
I will take you on myself.
Tarba's fist: Velocidrome Stance!
Wow.
So many openings.
Barioth Stance!
Next time right is for escapes only.
Agreed.
Ah, ow-ow-ow!
Mister!
My own back surprised me.
You can't win against time.
I wondered how it was going to end.
I definitely didn't see that coming.
You owe it to that blunder
that I didn't kick your butts.
Did you not understand that we aren't the Ebon Riders?
Who are these Ebon Tigers?
Clearly you didn't.
We're looking for the Riders that snatch Kinship Stones.
Hmm?
Young one, you have a sharp look.
Alright, then. I'll take you on as my disciple!
Eh!? What?
Nobody asked for your opinion.
Don't hold back. As long as you stay with me,
your skills will surely improve.
– We're—
– Hahaha, no matter, no matter.
Besides, I can't walk without help now.
I guess it can't be helped.
Hey, folks!
I brought a new disciple!
They don't look all that thrilled.
Well, villagers do have a tendency to hate strangers.
You two! This way!
Y-Yes!
This is my mansion.
Mansion…?
Listen well.
My disciples…
Welcome to Wakadoka Village.
Found them.
Ride On!
Rathian!
Help yourselves.
– Dig in!
– Don't be shy.
We're sorry.
Mr. Tarba must've been a bother to you.
As you can see, he's a stubborn old man.
He makes youngsters into his "disciples" and brings them here all the time.
But at least we get to see new faces in the village quite often.
That's just how it is.
Even though grandpa Tarba
is a little crazy, our village needs him.
Whenever a monster comes out of the forest,
he drives them out with his Aptonoth.
I have something to ask you.
Have you ever heard of the Ebon Riders?
Who are those Ebon Tigers?
No, I can't say I have.
They rob Riders of their Kinship Stones.
I've heard about that.
The village to the south seems to have been hit hard.
Ebon Riders, hm?
We need to be careful, right, Mr. Tarba?
Who are those Ebon Tigers!?
It's no use. He's completely drunk.
Hey, aren't you from Hakum?
How's Gamigami?
He's, um, doing fine.
He and I are close friends.
Eh?
We used to compete a lot when we were younger.
A younger Mr. Gamigami…?
Grandpa, you just sit here and drink all you want.
You know nothing about my younger days.
Listen, you see… I…
You've traveled a long way. What brings you here?
Well…
I see.
You've had it rough.
I hope you find your friend soon.
It's the Ebon Riders!
Everyone, go back to your homes!
Somebody save us!
Who do they think they are,
those Ebon Tigers.
As long as I'm still standing I…!
Mr. Tarba, it's no use!
No use, you say? I protect this village!
Hey, disciple!
Protect the village in my place.
Understood.
Hey, are you sure about this?
I'll do what I can.
I'm Mr. Tarba's disciple after all.
Ride On!
Rathian!
I don't like it.
To think they'd actually stand up against me.
Rathi!
Where are they?
Cheval!
Running away?
There!
Cheval!
Their Nargacuga is fast.
I can't catch up to them.
Tsk!
A Sonic Bomb?
Did they escape?
I don't like it.
To think that a mere boy could make me serious.
Sync Ride!
It feels so good!
Impossible!
A Nargacuga can't use lightning attacks!
That's the power of the Rite of Channeling!
Lightning Breath!
What's wrong?
You're just running around in circles!
It's no use.
We'll switch to personal combat.
There!
I have to admit, boy.
Pretending to run aimlessly, spreading branches and leaves all over the place, and then standing in the center.
Getting close without making
a sound is difficult, even for me.
Cheval…
Don't worry about me.
This is one noisy Felyne you've got.
Aren't you the boy who wanted to become Redan?
Who are you!?
Me?
I'm one of the four Ebon Riders…
Shadow.
Where's Avinia?
Avinia?
Ah, that little girl. She's doing fine.
Unless that fool Wrath killed her off, that is.
Now, how about you hand over that Kinship Stone of yours?
What's your goal?
Why are you collecting Kinship Stones?
Deep inside, you understand us, don't you?
We want to become stronger.
Strength by all means is justice.
Weakness dies out, but the strongest always prevail.
You're wrong!
Strength alone is worth nothing.
I know that the best.
Strength isn't justice.
It's your virtues that makes you strong!
I don't like it.
Why don't I just finish you off already?
Uh-oh. Just try taking another step.
And see what happens to this Felyne here.
Tail Crush!
Impossible!
Did she just teleport?
It can't be.
Thought a combination attack with your Felyne could beat me?
I don't like it.
I don't feel like bullying you anymore, boy.
Strengthen your Kinship Stone before we meet again.
I might consider stealing it then.
Are you okay, Cheval?
Are you hurt?
No…
I'm fine.
– But…
– Hm?
Thank you for saving our village.
I told you, he's my disciple!
Of course he'd protect us all.
We got it already.
Be careful on your journey to find your friend.
Next time my back gives out,
don't hesitate to come save us again.
I will.
Cryo, let's go.
Okay.
Drop by anytime!
We'll pray that you find your friend!
Stay safe!
You were my best disciple!
And also…
…the best duo I've seen!
Thank you very much, master!
Take care!
Cryo.
Hm?
I need the Rite of Channeling, too.
So that I can protect everyone.
How long are you going to keep this up?
If you don't eat, you'll wither away.
Nariki here!
I'm training every day from dusk till dawn with my Monstie, Drome.
But it's not going very well.
Just then… eh!? The Ebon Riders again!?
Next time:
"Hang In There, Velocidrome!" Ride On!