These kids are Riders.
And they form kinship with Monsters.
Riders known as the Ebon Riders keep challenging our heroes one after another.
Gale and his Monstie Dusk…
…have already defeated Lute and snatched Kinship Stones from Dan, Nole, Genie and Stone.
Meanwhile, Riders of Hakum Village are targeted by another Ebon Rider.
And so the crisis continues…
So, Hakum Village is at the foot of this hill, huh?
Just you wait, Lute.
Monster Hunter Stories: Ride On
Bokura kyou mo ikiteiru
We are still living today
Bokura kyou mo waratteru
We are still laughing today
Sore dake de mou nanimo iranai
We don't need anything more
Ima sugu ni RIDE ON
Just RIDE ON
Bokura sugu ni motomeru
We're quick to want
Yokubarina ikimono sa
This feeling is only natural
Nanimo motazuni umaretekita no ni
We're born without anything after all
Shiawase wa
Happiness is
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakatte kureru hito e
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun o miushinaisou ni naru kedo
To lose sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Onaji sora no shita onaji sora o miagenagara
We're under the same sky, we look at the same stars
Utsukushii iro no kizuna kazoeteiyou
Let's keep this beautifully colored bond
Shiawase wa itsumo
Happiness is forever
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakattekureru hito e
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun o miushinaisou ni naru kedo
Of losing sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Episode 53
Hang in there, Velocidrome!
Listen up!
Try dodging my attacks!
And do it as if it were an actual battle!
O…kay.
Geez, what's with that lousy response?
I mean, it's my first time
I'm partnering up with a Felyne.
Relax. It's my first time partnering up with a Rider too.
How is this supposed to make me feel better?
Hey, hey, that's why we're training in first place, right?
We'll build trust between us through blood, sweat and tears.
Let's aim for the sky!
But sweat stinks.
Kids these days…
Nevermind, just Ride On.
Mkay…
Ride On!
Velocidrome!
What's that?
Nariki! Look closely at the attacks!
O-Okay.
All right, one more time!
Yeah.
Looks like Nariki's nibbling on the basics.
Hang in there-nyaa.
Spex.
Ah, it's you, Mille.
What are those two up to?
They're training.
Beats is trying to fire Nariki up.
Even if your Velocidrome can dodge it,
it's no use if you can't dodge it too.
Listen!
A Rider and their Monstie must be one in both mind and body!
Got it?
Y-Yeah.
Alright! Next!
This time we'll train your jumping.
Jump over that obstacle while running at full speed.
Got it.
Good luck-nyaa…
You can do it, Drome.
All right, let's go, Drome!
Alright! Jump!
This should be okay for now.
Are you okay?
Y-Yeah…
– Pat!
– Argh!
Ah, sorry.
I guess you're not okay…
Tsk.
How pathetic.
Beats…
Nariki is still learning.
Be a little more understanding.
I have to be tough on him.
Beats…
Don't you get it?
The Ebon Riders are still hunting for Kinship Stones.
And we can't get help from Lute or anyone else.
Pampering isn't a luxury that Nariki gets right now.
You sure are strict.
I feel sorry for Nariki-nyaa.
Hmph.
You know, Drome… you could listen to me a little more.
Okay?
Me, Mille and Hyoro are the only ones
in the village with Kinship Stones.
So we can't take it slow right now.
Are you even listening?
What's wrong, Nariki?
I heard you sighing.
Dan.
I know you want to get strong right now,
but you shouldn't rush it.
Don't rush it, huh…
Aren't Velocidromes pretty weak?
Hey, hey.
Velocidrome is a nice and easy to handle Monstie.
I can't handle it at all though.
He has no breaths and he can't fly either.
No much how hard we try, this Monstie…
Hey! A Monstie's strength doesn't come from its attacks.
It's built on the kinship with their Riders.
Besides, Velocidromes are much
faster than most monsters.
Beats-Senpai says so too,
but tapping into that speed isn't easy.
I have no talent for it.
I'm sorry, Nariki.
I'm the one who dragged you into this.
Normally the defense of the village is our job.
But, we let them take our Kinship Stones…
Mille and Hyoro will also leave the
village soon to help Lute's group.
At that time you will be the only Rider left in this village.
So I know how hard it is, but please do your best.
I understand.
I will do my best for the sake of our village.
Sorry.
Come on, come on!
Increase your speed!
Drome, let's go faster!
Stronger…
I need to get stronger.
When that happens, we'll be able to get our seniors' Kinship Stones back.
T-This is bad!
When you go that fast,
you have to give out orders sooner!
Drome! Righ—
R—Ow!
…l-left.
Drome! Left! Right! Left!
Hey, Drome!
Why don't you listen to me?
Do you even understand me?
Don't take out your anger on him, Nariki.
It's not Drome's fault.
Ah…
You're trying to become faster and stronger, but…
…unless you change your attitude…
…Drome will never listen to you.
What's important is strengthening your kinship.
Everything else will come naturally after that.
You got that?
Hey, I can't hear you!
I get it…
…but you're getting on my nerves.
I said, you're getting on my nerves!
Ah, is that so?
What the hell!?
Look at you, acting so big!
Kinship this, kinship that! You're not even a Rider so what do you understand about Monsties?
Oh, now you've said it!
Ah yes, I did!
All right, fine, do whatever then!
Yeah, just watch me!
I wonder how Nariki's doing?
He's fine. He's very motivated-nyaa.
Right, Mille-Mille?
As his senior, I can say that he'll be at this for a
while. New Riders just have to deal with training.
Beats?
Where's Nariki?
Like I care!
And here I was trying to do something for him!
Damn. Damn. Damn!
Drome, you're an idiot!
And Beats-Senpai, you too!
Hey.
Who are you calling an idiot?
Hey, youngster.
Do you know which direction Hakum Village is in?
An Ebon Rider!
Ride On!
Rathian!
Nya-ow!
Hey, youngster.
Have you seen any Riders around here?
It's strange.
You've got Monstie's smell on you.
It's not like I'm going to eat you!
So don't be letting out those anxious odors!
Say, youngster.
Do you know a guy named Lute?
I heard he has one hell of a Kinship Stone.
But I guess you don't know where I can find him?
I see.
You don't, huh.
Then where's Hakum Village?
T-That way.
Hmm?
But Hakum Village is this way.
Don't you lie to me, you damn brat!
Whatever!
Gland and I are just getting hungry.
So I'll save Hakum Village for later.
You're probably living in Hakum, aren't ya?
Go on home and tell this to your people:
As soon as I'm done eating, I'm coming for you.
And if you try to hide Lute…
I'll smash your entire village!
Ride On!
Deviljho!
A Deviljho as a Monstie…
I can't leave things like this!
Ride On!
Velocidrome!
What should I do?
Well, I guess I should tell the village first.
Wait a second, Nariki!
Beats-Senpai.
Don't you go thinking I came here searching for you.
I just happened to be in the area.
We've got more important things.
Yeah, I know! I'll go tell Hyoro and Mille!
Until then, keep that guy out of the village!
But I can't do anything alon—
You're not alone!
Eh?
Drome.
That's right! You've got your Monstie!
Listen up.
Nothing can match Velocidrome's speed.
Use that to your advantage!
Run around and tire him out!
Y-Yes sir!
Also, Nariki!
I don't think that stubbornness of yours is all that bad, y'know!
I believe in you!
Y-Yes sir!
You, me and Drome are going to settle this!
Yes sir!
Alright, let's do it, Drome!
Damn.
I can't find any food around here.
What!?
Who are you?
I-I'm Lute!
You're Lute…?
But I heard you're flying a Rathalos?
My Rathalos has diarrhea!
Diarrhea!?
Y-Yeah! He ate too much!
Whatever!
Lute! I'm Wrath, one of the dreaded four Ebon Riders!
Give up your Kinship Stone!
Heh! Are you nuts?
If you want it, you gotta catch me!
Let's roll, Drome!
Gland, catch them!
Good, Drome, keep it up!
Is that all you've got?
I've caught up to you already!
He's so fast…
Beats-Senpai, hurry up!
– Are you serious?
– Nariki!
I am! He's all alone!
Hyoro, let's go!
Yeah!
Ride On!
Seregios!
Zinogre!
H-Hey, take me with you!
A Rider and their Monstie must be one in both mind and body!
Beats-Senpai…
Drome! I want to protect the village!
And so do you, right?
I guess that's the limit of Drome's stamina…
Say your prayers, Lute!
Let's do it, Drome!
Veloci-slash!
Yes!
Eh, that was disappointing.
Lute, I'm going to take your Kinship Stone.
Huh!?
Aren't you that brat from before!
And you fell for it!
You're so stupid you thought I was Lute, and chased me all the way here!
Say what!?
I'm going to rip that cocky mouth of yours off!
Actually, whatever. I'm taking your Kinship Stone.
And your Velocidrome will serve as a lunch for my Gland.
S-Stop it…
This ends now!
You held out well, Nariki.
Mille-Senpai!
Hmph. More Riders?
Hyoro-Senpai!
What!?
Now we're talking!
He's strong.
Come at me, you cheeky brats!
Don't underestimate us!
Dragon Breath!
Geez, fighting such a boring battle on an empty stomach.
Your three measly Kinship Stones don't make up for that.
After we're done here, I'm going to Hakum.
It's hopeless. Everything's over…
That's right.
No matter how much you brats struggle,
nothing's gonna change!
Nariki! It's too early to give up!
Tadaa!
…a sound effect?
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Beats-Senpai!
Eat this!
A Barrel Bomb!?
Get down!
Hey.
I wonder if we made the fuse too long?
You pesky Felynes!
What are you doing?
It's all part of the plan!
But you did well, Nariki.
So now, just leave it to Beats!
Whatever it is, please don't!
He's too strong!
Fighting back is reckless!
You idiot!
Have a little faith in me!
Huh?
The flame within me cannot be extinguished!
Just watch me!
Beats-Senpai!
Idiot!
You didn't even reach me!
Beats-Senpai!
Did you see that, Nariki?
With enough spirit, you can do anything.
I believe in you.
Beats-Senpai!
Did he get him!?
Sync Ride!
Deviljho is breathing flames!?
The Rite of Channeling!?
My Gland with your Monsties?
No way, no way!
Not in a hundred years!
Alright, let's have your Kinship Stones.
After what you did to Beats-Senpai?
Not in a hundred years?
You're in for disappointment!
You're the one who's in for disappointment!
Oh no, I'm so hungry…
It's no use.
Gland can't fight on empty stomach…
And I can't fight off hunger either!
Did they just…
…escape?
Beats-Senpai.
What a strong guy you were.
Don't kill me off just yet.
Senpai!
Beats-Senpai, I'm sorry for saying all those things.
How are your injuries?
This ain't nothing.
It just itches a little.
But more importantly, thanks to you and Drome…
…we were able to fend off the Ebon Riders.
Y-Yeah!
Too bad I didn't get to see it myself this time.
So how about we go all out again tomorrow!?
Yeah!
Let's aim to be the best team in the world!
I'm Debli!
Not Deb. Debli!
What!? Avinia's kidnapped?
I can't leave things like this!
Ooh! Avinia!
I'm coming for you!
Next time:
"For Avinia!" Ride On!