These kids are called Riders.
And they form kinship with monsters.
One day, Avinia was suddenly kidnapped.
Avinia!?
Mysterious Riders who call themselves the Ebon Riders appear one after another.
Defeated by Gale, Lute meets with Dede Geezer,
known also as the Channeler.
There, in the snowy mountains,
he obtains a Channeling Gem…
…and learns how to combine skills with other Monsties.
Meanwhile, Debli is worrying about Avinia.
I wonder how's Avinia doing?
I hope they didn't do anything to her…
Like taking away her food…
Thanks for the fooo…?
H-How cruel!
O-Or maybe…
They put her in a haunted house…
I'm scared!
Or maybe…!
Something like this…?
How terrible these Ebon Riders are!
Wait for me, Avinia.
I'm going to save you!
Ah… wait a second.
Where's Avinia again?
Can Debli really save Avinia!?
Monster Hunter Stories: Ride On
Bokura kyou mo ikiteiru
We are still living today
Bokura kyou mo waratteru
We are still laughing today
Sore dake de mou nanimo iranai
We don't need anything more
Ima sugu ni RIDE ON
Just RIDE ON
Bokura sugu ni motomeru
We're quick to want
Yokubarina ikimono sa
This feeling is only natural
Nanimo motazuni umaretekita no ni
We're born without anything after all
Shiawase wa
Happiness is
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakatte kureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
To lose sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Onaji sora no shita onaji sora wo miagenagara
We're under the same sky, we look at the same stars
Utsukushii iro no kizuna kazoeteiyou
Let's keep this beautifully colored bond
Shiawase wa itsumo
Happiness is forever
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakattekureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
Of losing sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Episode 54
"For Avinia!"
Alright, let's try asking people first.
Did you see this girl?
Can't say I did.
Girl…?
Never seen her.
Is it a human?
We don't know.
A Monstie?
There are no clues at all…
Hey, mister.
Have you seen her before?
Doesn't ring a bell.
Did something happen to her?
Her name's Avinia…
…and is actually my girlfriend!
Huh?
…or so I wish. We're friends.
I see. Well, I don't know her. Excuse me.
Ah, Ebon Riders…! Do you know anything about them?
Ebon Riders?
They suddenly kidnapped Avinia.
They're super-bad guys.
Really? Kidnapping is really terrible.
What's their name again?
These Ebon-something guys.
Mister, you seem to get it!
Of course I do. I hate such scum too.
Oh, looks like we'll get along well.
When I think about how Avinia
must be all alone and scared…
I can not bear it any longer!
I get it. I get it!
It's unforgivable to be mean to girls!
That's why I want to find those Ebon Riders…
…and save Avinia!
Wait a sec.
Now that I think of it, I think I saw one.
I mean, one of those Ebon-something guys.
Really?
What did they look like?
Please tell me.
– I think he had this here, and that there…
– Yep, yep.
– Ah, and of course it was like this!
– Yep, yep!
Oh, so that's the guy?
I see. He truly looks up to no good.
I think I got his features right.
Thanks for everything, mister.
Nah, it's nothing.
Good luck.
Yeah.
You're one nice guy.
I won't forget this kindness.
By the way, I'm Debli.
Deb…
…la?
It's Debli!
De-b-li.
Ah, sorry.
I'm off. See you.
What was with him?
Deb… something.
Beats me.
Hey!
People of Glidegaran!
Did someone see this guy?
He's super-bad.
– What?
– Don't ask me…
Huh?
Hey! Come on, look at it!
– I just said he's a villain!
– Hm?
Doesn't anybody know him?
What are you doing, Deb…
– Eh.
– …li?
It's Debli! Don't make weird pauses!
So what's with that picture?
Ah, this?
It is a portrait of an Ebon Rider.
I see.
No matter how you look,
this picture completely represents Debli.
Eh?
But I'm not an Ebon Rider.
We know it, of course.
Oh?
Then why did he draw my face?
Um… in short, the person who painted
this picture was teasing you, Debli.
Huh!?
I-It can't be…
That guy seemed super nice!
Ah, damn it!
And here I was thinking I finally
had a clue how to rescue Avinia!
Lilia, what's the status of your research?
I've estimated their location on the map
from looking where they appeared.
W-What!?
So you got it?
Avinia must be there.
Let's hurry up and go save her!
Ah, I'm afraid we can't rescue Avinia that
easily just by knowing where they keep her.
Why?
Ebon Riders are not ordinary Riders.
They're using the Rite of Channeling to obtain new skills.
Rite of Channeling?
Using the Rite of Channeling lets you awaken
slumbering kinship genes of Monsties.
Huh…?
In short, you can power up your Monstie.
The Rite of Channeling is awesome.
Lute is training with Dede Geezer, too.
Ah. I can't stay idle.
I'll go too, for Avinia's sake!
But as far as I know you don't have a Monstie?
Ahaha! Don't look down on me.
Watch closely.
Ride On!
Great Poogie!
Oink oink oink oink!
Hey, Poogie!
Well, Debli is not a Rider in the first place.
What are you saying?
I'm almost a Rider at heart.
I may exceed regular Riders!
– Huh?
Besides, this Great Poogie here and I
are connected with a firm bond.
I'll do the Rite of Channeling with him
and beat the Ebon Riders!
Then…
Do you acknowledge my superiority?
Yes sir!
Master Debli, please forgive me!
Debli, forgive him!
Very well. Your kind and pure heart
has saved this troubled soul.
I am saved!?
Listen well. Don't commit any evil…
…ever agai~n.
Yes sir!
Debli, the best in Gildegaran!
Debli, thank you, you were awesome!
Ah, it's nothing.
All right!
Let's go, Poo…gie?
…he's not here!
Where did he go?
Oink oink oink oink!
Hey! Wait!
Somehow that image makes me worry.
You said it…
Damn, he's fast!
Chance!
Ride On!
Great Poogie!
Oink oink oink oink.
Hey, Poo…gie?
Yes, good boy.
Oi~nk!
What the heck?
I wonder if Debli's doing fine.
Lilia?
Ah, I'm sorry.
He's with Fifi, so it should be okay.
But I'm surprised how Fifi followed Debli.
Yeah, it's understandable.
Perhaps she just doesn't know Debli enough?
– Ah.
Here you go.
Eh?
It's Lilia's handmade Hot Drink.
I've heard stories about it.
I'd rather endure it rather than drinking something like that.
Well, it's not like anyone forces you to drink it.
We're nice and warm, though.
Oink.
What's the magic word?
Sorry-please.
That's better.
This is all for Avinia.
Here goes!
I knew it, it's super bitter!
Oh, I feel hot.
But it's so bitter!
But it's nice and warm!
I wonder if following him was a mistake.
Is anyone home?
Are you Dede Geezer?
Yup.
I'm Dede Geezer.
I have a favor to ask.
Do the Rite of Channeling on me and this Monstie.
He's my partner, a Great Poogie.
Okay.
But you need to solve my riddle.
Riddle?
Okay. I'll get any question right!
For Avinia's sake!
Ride On!
Rathalos!
Nya-ow!
What is it, what is it?
The answer is Nargacuga.
Boo-boop.
Eh, again?
This is 20th incorrect answer in a row.
The next question is the last one.
Pin-pon, pin-pon!
It's your chance time.
If you can answer this question, I will teach you.
The last problem is worth 10000 points! You're a kind guy.
Okay, bring it on!
The Rite of Channeling needs a Monstie,
a kinship with the Monstie and one more thing.
And what is it?
What is it?
H-H-H-Hey! Of course I don't know it!
I came here because I don't know it!
Boo-boop.
Ehh!?
Are you okay, Debli?
Hey, old man! Give me one more chance!
I absolutely need the Rite of Channeling.
Please, Dede Geezer! Open the door!
Damn…
Let's get back to Gildegaran and make a fresh start.
No, it's no good! I will not budge
until I learn the Rite of Channeling!
Huh? That's…
– Hm?
– Oink?
What is this thing?
It's so pretty.
This will…
Huh?
…sell for a high price, I think!
Huh!?
Alright, I'll sell it and earn at least the living expenses.
Let's go back to Gildegaran and make a fresh start.
He-Hey!
You just said you won't budge!
It can't be helped. I need money to work ahead.
– Eh…?
– You need to look at the reality more.
Ah. I wonder if I can sell it for 1000 zenny.
Are you seriously planning to sell it!?
A gem?
That's correct.
He couldn't answer a single riddle, and picked up a precious stone instead.
It was a transparent empty egg, though.
When lighted on, it shined so nice and beautifully.
Hey, Fifi…
You found that gem beside Dede's Geezer's
hot spring inn, didn't you?
Yes.
I asked him how can he just pick
up things without permission.
But then that boy was like, "what I pick up is mine!".
He wouldn't listen to reason.
Ah, just thinking about it makes me tired…
Err… that gem…
…can't be a Channeling Gem, right?
Eh? Of course not.
Hm?
We're in trouble!
Everyone!
Debli's shop now offers a super-rarity.
A beautiful sparkling and shining
precious stone has just surfaced!
First come, first served!
Debli!
Yo.
Where's that gem?
Ah, I sold it already.
Hold your breath - for whopping 2000 zenny at that.
– We're too late…
– Huh?
What's wrong?
That gem wasn't just an ordinary precious stone.
It was a Channeling Gem.
Huh?
Channeling Gem?
It's a stone necessary for the Rite of Channeling.
I-I-I'm going to get it back!
There he is!
Hey! Mustached mister!
Mister, I'm sorry.
Please, let's undo the trade.
Ah!
I already sold that gem to someone else.
Say what…? W-W-Who did you sell it to?
To the inn keeper.
The inn keeper, right?
All right!
This is the place.
Excuse me…
Oh?
There it is! My Channeling Gem!
What's the racket?
That gem is mine, actually.
Can you give it back?
What are you saying?
It's mine, since I just bought it.
I paid 4000 zenny for it.
Eh? 4000 zenny!?
Won't you sell it for 2000 zenny by any chance?
Don't be absurd.
I finally found a gem that matches it perfectly.
Please, I'll do anything!
I need that gem no matter what!
I need it to save a friend dear to me!
Save a friend…?
Please.
I'm begging you!
All right…
…you can work off the 4000 zenny.
Eh? Really?
I'm happy for you, Debli.
When did you get here?
Work hard under the landlady.
If you split the work between you two,
you'll save twice the time.
Ah? Between us two?
Ah, I'm…
Ah, okay, okay. Very well.
All right!
Wait for me, Avinia!
For Avinia's sake, I'll take on anything!
Hey, it's reckless.
I-If you compare it with Avinia's suffering…
…th-this is nothing!
That boy's pretty strong.
I like that look.
Ah, by the way…
I bumped into someone looking for you.
What was he called again… Deb… something.
Debli.
Ah, yeah, yeah. That kind of name.
He seemed worried a lot about you.
But it won't be of much use to you.
Here you go.
Hooray!
Thanks!
Don't mention it. You worked well.
All right!
Wait for me, Avinia.
Let's go to Dede Geezer's place once again!
Yeah.
The Rite of Channeling needs three things.
It's a Monstie and a kinship with it.
And the last thing… is this.
Correct.
The Rite of Channeling needs that Channeling Gem.
Hooray!
So you'll do the Rite on us, right?
You can make my Great Poogie strong, right!?
But why are you holding it anyway?
Huh?
Why is it, why is it?
I-I-I picked it up.
Stare.
I'm serious.
Uhm…
It's true that this boy lies here and there…
Hey!
But he's now desperately trying to become
strong in order to save his important friend.
That feeling alone isn't a lie.
Please, lend him strength.
Please.
Eh?
Okay.
Give me the Channeling Gem then.
Do you really want me to do the
Rite of Channeling on you with this?
Yes. Please.
Really…?
Really!
Really-really…?
Really-really!
Okay.
All right!
What is it, what is it?
What is the Rite?
That which can combine two kinships…
…what is it?
Slumbering power, wake up.
All right, come, my Poogie!
Oink…
Huh?
What does it mean? He seems like usual.
Of course he does.
It's empty.
The Rite of Channeling can't succeed like this.
Ah, tell me that before!
That's why I asked you earlier.
"Do you really want me to do the Rite of Channeling?"
Argh! What's with you? What's with you?
I remember. Argh!
Here.
I'm formally giving you this Channeling Gem.
Work hard and you'll learn it too.
Learn?
Hey!
Hey, wait! My Poogie!
Debli?
Why?
He went through the Rite of Channeling.
Eh? Before us?
Yes, but it failed.
Good luck with your studies.
Thank you as well, Dede Geezer.
Really… what a troublesome boy.
Did you…
…too come to learn about the Rite of Channeling?
– Yes.
Hm.
Then you hold on to these too and go to the snowy mountains.
So that's the Channeling Gem…
It's beautiful.
But they're still empty.
Your task is to learn how to fill them up with the kinship power.
Lute's studying too.
Oh?
Hey! Wait for me, Poogie!
How far are you goin—
Ow-ow-ow…
I can't help Avinia this way…
Damn!
I want to be stronger!
It's okay.
If you stay that motivated,
you will definitely get stronger someday.
Avinia.
I'll surely get stronger and go save you.
Wait for me, my Avinia!
Lute here!
To obtain the new power, I need to meet with Kirin.
Eh? I have to defeat you if I want that power!?
No, I don't want to fight you!
Next time:
"The Bolt Rathalos!" Ride On!