These kids are called Riders.
And they form kinship with monsters.
To face the Ebon Riders, who have kidnapped Avinia…
…Lute seeks a way to perform
the Rite of Channeling with Ratha…
…and visits Kirin, a phantom monster he met before.
Acknowledged by Kirin,
Lute managed to awaken the kinship genes.
Meanwhile, Cheval, spared by Shadow's mercy…
…goes to visit Dede Geezer in order to obtain the power to face her.
Monster Hunter Stories: Ride On
Bokura kyou mo ikiteiru
We are still living today
Bokura kyou mo waratteru
We are still laughing today
Sore dake de mou nanimo iranai
We don't need anything more
Ima sugu ni RIDE ON
Just RIDE ON
Bokura sugu ni motomeru
We're quick to want
Yokubarina ikimono sa
This feeling is only natural
Nanimo motazuni umaretekita no ni
We're born without anything after all
Shiawase wa
Happiness is
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakatte kureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
To lose sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Onaji sora no shita onaji sora wo miagenagara
We're under the same sky, we look at the same stars
Utsukushii iro no kizuna kazoeteiyou
Let's keep this beautifully colored bond
Shiawase wa itsumo
Happiness is forever
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakattekureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
Of losing sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Episode 56
"A Lukewarm Kinship"
So that's a Channeling Gem…?
We can use this to contain other monsters' kinship genes, correct?
Yep.
So where can we meet such monsters?
You need to find them by yourselves.
Each kinship is different.
Looking for it is part of your studying.
But…
We need to act fast for Avinia's sake.
Okay.
There's a rumor that a very strong monster is on the other side of this mountain range.
You'll find something there, for sure.
Go on and try it.
Should we? With such ambiguous information…?
Thank you very much.
Let's just head in that direction for time being.
Very well.
What matters is the kinship.
So far there's only a snow-covered road up ahead.
I didn't see any people or villages around here.
I see…
Why don't we use Rathi?
We may miss some monsters from the sky.
It might take more time, but I think it'll be more effective to go by foot.
I see.
By the way, Cheval.
We share a pretty good relationship, don't you think?
For example, our fight with that Ebon Rider back then.
We didn't win, but I think it was pretty good team work regardless.
Yeah.
I think so too.
Things went unexpectedly well for our first fight.
I'm glad you agree!
If we awaken new powers within Rathi…
…I think in our next run-in with that Ebon Rider,
we'll fight with much more composure.
Yeah.
It's also to protect everyone.
But we can't let our guard down.
Cheval, you're quite careful.
Which is exactly why it'll be okay.
Just like our kinship.
It's an unbreakable kinship, just like the one between Lute and Navirou.
Like Lute's…?
That's right.
With our cool and hot kinship, we'll surely be able to save Avinia.
I'm counting on you, Cryo.
I'll do my best.
Just leave it to me.
Cryo.
Do you happen to have any Hot Drink with you?
I am strong against the cold, so I didn't bring any.
I'm sorry.
I see.
It's okay.
I can handle it for now.
I've already made a blunder… I'm sorry.
For time being, I will go check the situation ahead.
I'll go with you…
I'm sorry.
I'll definitely come for you later.
Oh, I found a fugitive.
No, no, no.
It won't work without a proper key.
Please give me that key!
Hey, don't be so impatient.
Hold on for now.
You'll understand their goal soon enough.
What…?
What do you mean…?
Who knows?
If you value your Monstie,
you'll return to your cell without making a fuss.
It's getting hard to see…
Let me lead you.
It's time for my cold resistance to prove useful.
Watch your step, Cryo!
This is a snowstorm.
There's no telling what will happen.
I'll be fine.
Please leave everything to me.
Are you okay?
Don't move!
Cheval…?
I'm sorry, Cheval.
You saved me!
Cheval?
Are you hurt?
I'm fine, but…
All right.
Then let's go.
Cheval!
Are you okay!?
I'm fine.
I was thinking that you've been acting strange for a while…
You have terrible fever!
It's not a problem.
Let's go.
You're being too reckless!
We need to rest somewhere.
I…
I need to do something…
Rathi!
Thank you so much!
But…
This snowstorm just won't stop…
"Please leave it to me", my paw!
I'm…
I'm completely useless!
I'm going to search for something useful to Cheval!
In the meantime, please take care of him!
Ride On!
Rathian!
What was that?
What is this place?
Don't tell me…
It was a village…?
What on earth has happened in here?
That's…!
An alchemist shop signboard!
An alchemist shop should have materials for restorative medicines.
I can save Cheval with those.
A Barioth!?
What's it doing here!?
This is bad!
Rathi…?
You protected me…?
Where's Cryo?
Rathi…
Can you find Cryo?
Ride On!
Rathian!
It won't attack…?
Cheval!
Rathi.
Let's go.
Why…?
Why does it have so many scars?
Why won't it fly?
Rathi!
Hold on, Rathi!
I won't let you!
I won't let you lay a claw on Cheval!
Wait, both of you.
Cheval?
I won't harm you or this village anymore.
So please, let's just end this battle.
I don't want to fight with you.
Please believe me.
We just want to save our friend.
We want to save Avinia.
Do you know her…?
What's that?
Could it be… the binding genes?
Perhaps…
The Barioth went away…
Cheval!
It's a recovery medicine I obtained.
You should feel a little better you if you drink it.
How is it?
I feel much better.
I'm glad to hear that.
Rathi is exhausted as well.
So, let's spend the night here and head back tomorrow.
Good idea.
Cryo!?
Thank you, Cryo.
Thanks to you I'm feeling much better.
I'm glad.
What about you, Cryo?
I feel good as new.
But really…
What has happened to this village?
There's no one here, so I guess it wasn't the snowstorm.
Yes…
It's almost like it was destroyed by a monster…
Surely you don't think that the Barioth did it!?
No, that's not it.
He's guardian of this village.
Guardian?
Yes.
He had a lot of old scars, so he must have fought a lot.
He also didn't move at all.
I guess he must have kept on protecting this village, even now.
That means, he…
…protected this village all alone,
even though there's nobody here anymore?
Hey!
Lute?
What are you doing here?
Dede Geezer said you stopped by.
And there was a snowstorm, so we got worried about you.
But looks like you're doing fine.
It's thanks to Cryo.
No, no.
It's all thanks to Cheval.
By the way…
What is this place?
We're not sure.
We only know it was probably a village.
Cheval, did you come here to train too?
Do you use snowmans?
Lute can handle up to two snowballs.
What kind of training are you putting yourself through?
Ah, the head…!
Lute, you brute!
Hm?
There's something here.
What is it, I wonder?
What's written on it?
Did you finally get so dumb that you can't even read, Lute?
I can't read it because it's all scratched. Stupid Navirou.
What!? That's rude!
Stupid Lute!
Stupid, stupid Navirou.
Stupid, stupid, stupid Lute!
Stupid, stupid, stupid, stupid Navirou.
Stupid, stupid, stupid, stupid, stupid Lute!
Stupid, stupid, stupid,
stupid, stupid, stupid…
…stupid, stupid, stupid, stupid Navirou!
Heh.
Do you have anything to say?
Yes, "poof"!
Knock it off!
Ah, it stinks!
What are they doing…?
"In ancient times…"
"…handing down…"
"…the secret art…"
"…the flying ones…"
"…crystal…"
"…song…"
"…cannot became one."
"The flying ones' crystal…"
I wonder if it's referring to Kinship Stones?
Maybe this was a Riders' village?
Cheval.
Yes.
It's an inscription dedicated for the Barioth guardian.
Furthermore, something destroyed this village.
Looks like it's related to Avinia, doesn't it?
What are you talking about?
Lute wants you to lower the conversation level so he can understand you.
I understand just fine.
Can you lower it for Navirou, though?
What's your problem?
Wanna take a sniff of Navirou's fart again?
Did you two meet a Barioth, Cheval?
Yeah.
Oh, by the way…
You put kinship genes into your Channeling Gem!
You can go through the Rite now!
O' slumbering kinship…
…awaken!
Rathi has blue tint now!
Cheval…
…Rathi got a power up!
Yep.
Rathi!
Ice Cyclone!
Whoa!
That's a Barioth's Ice Cyclone!
You did it, Cheval.
Yep.
Then…
…let's go save Avinia!
Cheval.
I will assist you the best I can.
Yeah.
I'm counting on you, Cryo.
Roger that!
I'm Pappan.
The Royal Paleontology Scriveners' vice captain!
I'll finally be getting some screen time and…!
…what!? I'm going to a dangerous place with Lilia!?
Captain Simone…!
Next time:
"It's Hard Being a Vice Captain!" Ride On!