His name is Pappan.
He's part of an organization that studies the ecology of monsters and unravels the mysteries of the world.
The Royal Scriveners' vice captain.
Behind the success of Lute and the other Riders,
who saved the world from the Black Blight…
…stands none other than Pappan himself, assisting them despite his simplicity.
Normally, Pappan tends to hide
in the shadow of Captain Simone…
…but the time has come for
the spotlight to hit this simple character.
You're using word "simple" too much.
And now, after waiting until the time
is ripe, he's going to face new mysteries.
And that…
…are the Ebon Riders.
I will solve the mystery behind you!
Monster Hunter Stories: Ride On
Bokura kyou mo ikiteiru
We are still living today
Bokura kyou mo waratteru
We are still laughing today
Sore dake de mou nanimo iranai
We don't need anything more
Ima sugu ni RIDE ON
Just RIDE ON
Bokura sugu ni motomeru
We're quick to want
Yokubarina ikimono sa
This feeling is only natural
Nanimo motazuni umaretekita no ni
We're born without anything after all
Shiawase wa
Happiness is
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakatte kureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
To lose sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Onaji sora no shita onaji sora wo miagenagara
We're under the same sky, we look at the same stars
Utsukushii iro no kizuna kazoeteiyou
Let's keep this beautifully colored bond
Shiawase wa itsumo
Happiness is forever
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakattekureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
Of losing sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Episode 57
"It's Hard Being a Vice Captain"
I see you're working hard there, Pappan.
Captain Simone…?
I brought you something to drink.
I was just getting thirsty.
It's from Lilia.
You should've told me that earlier!
Sorry.
Are those portraits of the Ebon Riders?
The portraits I got from Lilia were a bit too… illegible.
So I drew new ones that capture the features reported by witnesses.
You did great. They're very detailed.
That's my Pappan.
Thanks!
They call themselves the four Ebon Riders.
Mad.
Wrath.
Shadow.
And Gale.
Apparently there's a mysterious figure reigning over them at the summit. I'm investigating that right now.
Who are the Ebon Riders and what is their goal?
I'm going to find that out in my own way.
Lilia seems to have caught a clue about them as well.
Could you go assist her with her research?
Why don't you go, Captain?
I have other businesses I must attend to.
You're extremely capable.
I'm counting on you.
Oh, thank you!
It'll be my pleasure!
Scrivener Journal Entry #21567.
Reporter: Pappan.
Survey day 1. It's sunny with no clouds.
I'm in Gildegaran waiting for my traveling companion.
Captain Simone is away today.
I have to take care of my junior well.
Vice Captain!
Sorry I made you wait!
Good morning.
Long time no see.
Where are we going to first?
Would you care for a stylish cafe?
J-J-Just kidding! Hahaha…
Ah, are you hungry?
Did you eat your breakfast?
Should I make an Energy Drink?
Oh, um, thank you, but that's okay.
So where are we headed?
We're going to Omi Valley.
Speaking of Omi Valley, it's said to be a Hunters' training ground.
It is a place where you can find ferocious monsters in clusters.
We'll be fine.
Oh, so you have a plan?
I knew one could rely on you, Lilia!
But I don't have one.
Then why are we going there?
Just my intuition.
Eh…?
My companion is enthusiastic about research.
But sometimes she's kind of reckless.
There's also room for doubt in her planning ability.
It's going to be a long journey…
Ah?
W-What?
I've never understood it.
Why the Ebon Riders have been collecting our Kinship Stones.
But after investigating an old document,
I found out about a village…
…where the secret art of syncing with a monster using
the power of Kinship Stones was passed down through generations.
I'm not sure about the location of that village.
But there's an important lead.
The painter of the picture is called
Mr. Pollock and he's from the Omi Valley.
Even though it's a pretty old picture,
there might still be people who know him there.
They might have more valuable information as well.
So the Ebon Riders are collecting the Kinship Stones
in order to obtain that secret art?
I don't have any evidence for that.
Hmm.
Intuition is important, but our Scriveners' job
is to draw conclusions based on scientific evidence.
It's dangerous to depend on your intuition too much.
I'm sorry.
Ah…
There's nothing to apologize for.
I didn't say it to make you depressed.
What Vice Captain Pappan wants to say is this:
The work of the squadron is to transform insight into evidence through steady research.
But insight is always the first step behind every great discovery.
Ah, Vice Captain!
I'll do my best!
Ah, sure!
Good luck!
Thank you very much.
Pushing your own opinions onto children will only make them dislike you.
Uh, I guess I still have a world to learn.
Wait, what are you doing here, Fifi?
You didn't know about it?
About what?
Captain Simone asked me to support you since she was uneasy leaving you alone.
Eh!?
Why are you looking away!?
Huh…?
I'm not trusted…?
You're extremely capable.
I'm counting on you.
Why did she smile like that?
Don't be so down. Think positive, positive!
Kira-kira-nyaa!
Oh…?
End of the survey day 1.
The number of traveling companions has increased unexpectedly.
There are different opinions about
the circumstances for it. This will be a long journey.
However, one effective way to improve collaboration between fellow travelers is through communication.
Lilia.
Would you like to eat mushrooms together?
No, I'll pass.
A-Are you sure? The taste is so great I could eat it forever…
I have something I want to investigate.
Excuse me.
Communication with companions: failure.
Tonight I feel I can't connect with today's youth anymore.
I can't believe it.
When I was young, it was unthinkable to refuse my seniors' invitation.
Middle management has it hard, doesn't it?
As someone affiliated with the organization,
I can understand your feelings.
Here you go. An Oiled Mushroom.
Thank you very much.
Only Fifi understands my feelings!
I understand you well.
You seem lighthearted at first glance, but you're unexpectedly serious, Vice Captain Pappan.
Kids these days don't have a single bit of respect!
Pappan is pretty small-minded, isn't he?
Don't you get tired of it?
What's so interesting about the vice captain's job?
Well I'm sorry for being small-minded, alright!
Life's not always rainbows and unicorns!
I am not as charismatic as Captain Simone.
I don't have Lilia's intuition either.
That's why I need to do old fashioned boring work, step by step, step by step!
Is it that bad? That's just how I work!
Well said!
Thank you so much.
Tonight let's drink to our heart's content!
Let's not.
We need to get up early tomorrow, remember?
Ehh?
Please let me drink.
Wake up, Vice Captain!
It's time to depart!
Come on, now, get up!
Are you okay, Vice Captain?
O-Of course.
Sorry I kept you waiting.
Eek!
S-Stand behind me!
Are you okay!?
O-O-Of course! Leave it to me!
I wonder if we really can…
Everyone, don't move!
I-I will p-protect you!
Huh!?
I brought lots of stuff for this sort of situation!
I just need a good item…
So why can I only find useless junk now!?
Please calm down, Vice Captain!
Mr. Reverto!
Yo.
It's been a long time.
L-Long time no see…
Ride On!
Rathalos!
Nya-ow!
Everyone, take cover!
Under that tree!
Yeah!
Hey, Vice Captain Pappan, please walk too!
S-Sure…
As expected from Mr. Reverto.
He's so cool…
You can take an example from him.
Mr. Reverto!?
What's wrong!?
Uh, I drank too much yesterday…
Don't tell me he ran out of steam?
Sorry.
Hey! Mr. Reverto, are you okay?
Could be better…
It's going to attack again…
W-What should we do?
It'll be alright!
Don't say it's your intuition again!
I said we'll be alright!
Look!
Energy Drinks can't help us now!
We should find a place to hide instead!
Behind you!
Oh?
Get down, Lilia!
Mr. Reverto!
Mr. Reverto! Mr. Reverto!
Look, it's an Energy Drink!
Thanks.
That's the best item there is.
Do you have more?
I was prepared for this.
There's a lot left.
B-But that's…!
Hmm?
That last one really hit the spot.
There's still a lot left!
Preparation grants salvation.
That's my traveling motto from now.
It was this event that made me realize that no Energy Drink means no journey.
Hey!
Get over here and eat.
After my pathetic display out there,
I don't feel like I have the right to eat.
So you're upset that you weren't able to stand upright despite fear?
Well, you were up against
a monster, so it was only natural.
But someone in my position should protect their juniors.
I never expected you to protect me.
Eh?
I can take care of myself.
Using my wisdom.
Here, have a donut.
Thank you…
You too. You were amazing.
Consider this a token of my gratitude.
Ah, thanks.
By the way, what are you doing here, Mr. Reverto?
Are you on a quest?
Yeah… Technically, it's a covert quest, though.
Covert quest?
I was given it by your boss.
By our Captain?
I guess I'm not trusted, after all.
Even though I'm a vice captain.
I don't think it's related to you.
My quest deals with Ebon Riders
and some channeling art.
I'm supposed to investigate what's the extent of their power.
It's a special quest that normally I wouldn't take, but after I heard that Hakum was targeted…
I couldn't stay silent any longer.
I went around several villages where they hunted for Kinship Stones to get some information.
That's how I heard that they seem to be collecting Kinship Stones to do a certain ritual.
Ah!
That ritual…
It seems to allow a rider to synchronize with a monster and strengthens their power.
So Lilia's intuition was right!?
What do you mean?
Well, it's like this…
I see.
There might be someone in the Omi Valley
who knows about this ritual.
But that place is a difficult area even for experienced Hunters.
Isn't it a little too high level for you?
I'll go with you.
– Oh?
– Terrific!
Really?
Tell your boss to get a proper reward ready.
I don't do freebies.
Ah!
Thanks! It'll be my pleasure!
Scrivener Journal Entry #20332.
Reporter: Pappan.
During an ecological survey of monsters
in a certain village, I witnessed a fight between Riders.
Why would a Rider fight a fellow Rider?
Riders bond with monsters using Kinship Stones.
What happens if one were to collect a lot of said Kinship Stones?
Can Kinship Stones, such as the ones belonging
to the Hakum village's Riders, serve another purpose?
If so, does the count matter
and is it the reason why they keep stealing them?
What on earth are they going to do with the Kinship Stones they have gathered?
At any rate, Kinship Stones seem to be at the center of it all.
Hello.
Here are the documents you've requested.
Thank you.
I wonder if Pappan is doing alright?
What makes you worried about him?
Well, recently he seems troubled
about getting out of touch with his juniors.
Isn't that the reason why you asked Fifi to accompany him, Captain?
What I was worried about wasn't Pappan's competence.
Pappan might not look the part,
but he's a serious, capable man.
There are times when he overthinks things and runs around in circles, though.
I thought I could get him to enjoy
the survey and relax more if I sent him with Fifi.
I see.
You sure do understand Pappan, don't you, Captain?
Well, he is my right hand, after all.
Survey day 3.
We're pushing forward to Omi Valley.
Also known as the Hunter's training ground, it was once inhabited with variety of monsters and just as many Hunters.
However, this has changed completely
over time and, now, there's nothing to be seen.
Looks like there's no one around here.
In the past, it was a valley filled with many monsters
and vibrant villages full of Hunters…
Excuse me!
Is anyone there?
Doesn't look like it.
Yeah…
We can't do anything about it.
Sometimes things just turn out like this.
But let's not admit defeat just yet.
We'll continue the investigation.
All right.
Oh?
There seems to be someone inside.
Are you okay?
Excuse me, I'm coming in.
Who is it?
Are you okay?
Thank you. It got easier.
What on earth brings you to this village?
I'm Lilia of the Royal Scriveners.
I came here looking for clues about this picture.
Is that…
Well, if it isn't the picture my grandfather painted!
Eh!?
When I was young, my grandfather told me stories about the village in this picture.
That village seems to have passed down a certain ritual for generations.
It was performed in secret,
deep in the unexplored area of the mountains.
What kind of ritual?
A secret art passed down to a village named Kuang, which no longer exists today.
Secret art!?
A rite held in secret?
So Kuang village means that…
I heard that it was destroyed several years ago.
It was subjected to the Black Blight.
But I've been hearing some gossip about it lately.
Seems that someone from Kuang village
survived the destruction.
That person is said to have a mysterious kinship with an ice-type Barioth.
Miss Avinia!
Avinia survived Kuang!?
That means…
The Ebon Riders abducted Miss Avinia…
…to obtain Kuang village's secrets?
What if that secret art falls into bad hands?
A calamity will happen…
Kuang village is over that mountain.
The path is severed, so it's not going to be easy.
We'll be okay.
Eh?
Why? Your intuition again?
No. I know that I can't make it,
but I'm positive Lute and Cheval can.
I will return to Gildegaran
and tell them about Kuang village.
Thank you very much.
It was very helpful.
Be careful on your journey back.
We will.
Oh, and one more thing. A few years ago
a group like you visited this village.
What did they ask you about?
They also asked about Kuang village survivors.
They were desperately looking for them.
The group who visited him back then must have been Avinia's acquaintances.
They might be Kuang survivors too.
…it's just my intuition though.
"Every great discovery starts from an insight", was it?
I think that our Vice Captain's intuition is quite sharp.
That's right!
I'm proud to have you as my senior!
You really mean that!?
But the one I respect most is Captain Simone.
Lilia didn't mean that in a bad way.
Well, she's proud to have me. That's plenty.
Alright, we're going back to Gildegaran.
Yeah!
Survey report.
I didn't manage to solve the mystery
behind the Ebon Riders.
However, I obtained a few important clues.
And I know that, some day, these clues will aid in solving the mystery of the Ebon Riders.
I am searching for the Kinship Stones
of priests from your hometown, Kuang village.
Kinship Stones?
You're a survivor from Kuang village.
You should know of those Kinship Stones.
Or maybe you possess one yourself?
I have no idea about what you're talking about.
Besides, you took away my Kinship Stone.
I don't remember my childhood.
Nothing…
Not even my family.
I want to remember it all myself!
I know…
I know about Kuang village's priests
as well as the secrets that they control.
I know you.
Sooner or later, everything will fall into my hands.
Ladies and gentlemen, it's Navirou!
What a pleasure! Next week
we get poo-poo-poo… peep!
"What the heck?", you say?
Well, you'll find out next week!
Next time:
"Navirou's Great Fart Plan!" Ride On!