These kids are Riders.
And they form kinship with monsters.
A group called the Ebon Riders kidnapped Avinia…
…and keeps stealing other Riders' Kinship Stones.
Lute and Cheval went through the Rite of Channeling
and acquired abilities of other monsters.
On their search for the Ebon Riders' hideout, they decided to split.
Cheval headed to the Trese Desert.
Cheval…
Like I said, I'm fine.
Monster Hunter Stories: Ride On
Bokura kyou mo ikiteiru
We are still living today
Bokura kyou mo waratteru
We are still laughing today
Sore dake de mou nanimo iranai
We don't need anything more
Ima sugu ni RIDE ON
Just RIDE ON
Bokura sugu ni motomeru
We're quick to want
Yokubarina ikimono sa
This feeling is only natural
Nanimo motazuni umaretekita no ni
We're born without anything after all
Shiawase wa
Happiness is
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakatte kureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
To lose sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Onaji sora no shita onaji sora wo miagenagara
We're under the same sky, we look at the same stars
Utsukushii iro no kizuna kazoeteiyou
Let's keep this beautifully colored bond
Shiawase wa itsumo
Happiness is forever
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakattekureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
Of losing sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Episode 59
"Darkness and Kinship"
It was a terrible sandstorm.
Are you okay?
I am not good with hot environments so it is hard to tell…
It is certainly better than a volcano.
I'm fine.
Then…
Lets go.
We found no clues about the Ebon Riders here either.
Yup.
Where can their hideout be located?
Huh?
Oh?
Fahali!
Let's see…
Who are you again?
Just kidding.
You give completely different impression compared to back then.
I'm sorry.
Back then, I was a little, err…
There's nothing to apologize for though.
Are you on a quest, Fahali?
Yeah.
The caravan party was being attacked.
Mister Charming over there was the culprit.
Did you see anything out of ordinary around here?
Let's save this for later.
A meal comes first.
Ebon Riders?
That's right.
They're evil Riders who are robbing other Riders' of their Kinship Stones.
I haven't seen such Riders.
Can you recall any suspicious buildings?
Nope.
I see.
Cheval…
Perhaps the Ebon Riders' hideout is outside desert zone after all?
Yup.
I'll let the Royal Scriveners know as soon as I notice anything suspicious.
Thanks.
I'd like to ask you another question.
Perhaps you've seen any Nargacuga around here?
A Nargacuga?
Yes.
My Monstie's a Nargacuga.
I haven't seen any.
Did it stray?
No…
I have done terrible thing to him.
Dark Thrash!
Heh.
Why, you…
After it! Get it, Nargacuga!
What are you doing?!
Run!
Run, you slowpoke!
After it, Nargacuga!
You, too, huh?
Another useless Monstie!
I don't need you, either.
Get out of here.
That's a sad story.
Yes.
At that time, I was just looking for ways to acquire new strength.
Your heart was caught in darkness.
In darkness…?
You're right.
I lost myself and felt into darkness.
I would never have guessed you were doing such things to Monsties, Cheval.
Did you come to dislike me?
No, not at all.
As if.
What I wanted to say is that I can hardly believe that person was you, Cheval.
How did you escape that darkness?
Ah.
Right…
Lute and Ratha.
My friends…
…opened my eyes for me.
You came back from the darkness thanks to your friends, huh?
That's correct.
They've chased the darkness away with their light.
Nargacugas don't live in deserts.
Eh?
My guess is that an abandoned Nargacuga would return to its birthplace.
Ah…
If it manged to stay alive, that is.
Ah. How annoying, how annoying.
Ah. How irritating. How aggravating.
It's his fault that we still can't find Lute.
Mad is disgusting.
Wrath is dead stupid.
We can't find him because he went into hiding.
Gale is cheeky and self-centered.
"It's not my fault", he says!
Am I really the only reliable member in our group?!
When I'm in such a bad mood…
…it's time to hunt.
This is the place.
This is where I bonded with him.
It seems that this forest is home to many monsters.
I'm afraid it'll be difficult to locate a single Nargacuga in here.
Perhaps…
…my kinship with him isn't fully gone yet.
Ride On!
Nargacuga!
It's no use…
He may just be somewhere else.
I hope you're right.
Since we're already here…
…why don't we look for some clues regarding the Ebon Riders?
Good idea.
Let's look around.
What was that?
Ah!
Nargacuga!
It's you?
It looks really agitated!
Are you sure it's your Monstie, Cheval?
Yes.
No doubt about it.
I'm sorry for that time.
Ah.
Cheval!
I really regret my behavior.
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
It's gone.
It's only natural that he hates me.
I'm all right with it.
I'm glad just knowing that he's still alive.
I see…
We just can't seem to find the Ebon Riders, do we?
Yeah.
What about the rest?
Wish I knew.
It's a good night for hunting.
A prey?
Purple Water Beast
Purple Ludroth
A Purple Ludroth?
I hoped it would be something more interesting.
But I guess I'll play with you for a bit
after that introduction.
I'll play with you a lot!
What could that be…?
Monsters are fighting.
What a boring opponent.
Roaring Wyvern
Tigrex
Now those fangs look like they're not just for show.
Looks like it'll be fun!
It started again.
This time it's a Tigrex.
Ride On!
Rathian!
Someone has slain a Purple Ludroth.
Maybe it's a Hunters' quest?
Hunters don't usually go for a kill.
Ah!?
I wonder if I can find something even more fun to play with.
Found something?
Aww.
Now who could be your owner?
Were you left here to die?
You're not very cute, little fella.
How about I show you some tender love!
And now a Tigrex.
They just kill and leave them like this.
Looks like they just slay monsters for the sake of it.
Hunters wouldn't do such thing.
Then who?
Ah!
Cheval, it's an Ebon Rider!
She's Shadow!
Stop it already!
Oh, it's you, boy.
We're meeting like this, isn't this fate?
You're the one who has slain those monsters?
It's a pleasant night, so I went hunting.
Monster hunting is great fun.
That's not hunting!
But you were once like me, weren't you, boy?
That was long ago…
Then maybe this time you become my opponent, boy?
Ride On!
Rathian!
Have you become stronger?
I'll play with you.
Storm!
Cheval!
She'll launch a surprise attack again!
Get out of here.
Rathi!
It's Nargacuga's thorns!
Watch out!
Where is she!?
Argh!
When did she get behind me!?
It's happening again.
That Nargacuga is too fast.
It's a poison spike!
She's not here?!
Lightning Thunder!
Argh!
Cheval!
We think she's in front of us, she's behind us.
We think she's on the right, she's attacks from the left.
How fast can she be?
She's not only fast.
This attack… is strange.
Noir!
Hunting for Riders…
…is fun!
Grief!
All right!
There?
Let's go!
Too slow!
Ah!?
You…!?
Ice Cyclone!
Rathian using Barioth's abilities.
You didn't fail me, boy.
Ice Cyclone!
Try aiming better.
Are you trying to tire out your Monstie?
Ice Cyclone!
So that's how the kinship with your Monstie looks like, boy…
I'm disappointed.
I guess he's finished.
Let's finish them, Storm!
What's wrong?
What!?
Cheval didn't make Rathi cast
all these Ice Cyclones for nothing.
Now, better watch your step.
The ground is frozen and slippery like an ice rink.
That's why I told you to watch your step.
As Cheval's partner, I sensed his intention and helped freezing the ground.
Looks like you can't use your high speed movements anymore.
Storm!
Get a grip!
Let's go, Rathi!
Let's go.
Scorching Slice!
Ah!
Grief!
No!
How…
How did you know?
That there is two of us?
I felt your blood lust.
No, that's not it…
I sensed your malice.
I learned that when I was wrapped in darkness.
I saw your darkness.
Where is your hideout?
Like I'd tell you!
For him… for a mere kid… to humiliate me…
To humiliate me this much!
Next time I won't go easy on you, Cheval!
There's nothing special about this smoke bomb!
Cheval?
We can't pursuit them, Cryo.
Rathi is at her limit.
I-I see.
It was two-on-one after all.
But you did great finding out there's another one.
Did you really sense her malice?
I felt… something.
But they were too fast.
I always thought that something was wrong.
Which is to say, it was two-on-one before too!
I can't stand how she— they were talking big back then!
Really!
Cryo, you're losing your cool.
Because…!
Huh!
Excuse me.
Ah!?
Oh?
Be careful!
Nargacuga.
You… you did…
You came here to help me?
Cheval?
Will you forgive me?
It seems he's telling you to get on.
To pursue them.
Nargacuga.
You're hurt too, aren't you?
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry…
Please become my Monstie again.
Nariki here!
Finally it's time for Monstie Race!
A battle royal where anything can happen!
This time participants will be…
Eh?!
These guys?!
Next time:
"Return of the Monstie Races!" Ride On!