These kids are Riders.
And they form kinship with Monsters.
Avinia was kidnapped by mysterious Riders called the Ebon Riders…
…who also attacked Hakum Village.
Gale defeated the senior Riders of Hakum Village
and robbed their Kinship Stones.
The pursuit of the Ebon Riders continues on.
Come at me, you cheeky brats!
Dragon Breath!
The young Riders, wanting to save Avinia…
…left Hakum Village for a journey
to learn about the Rite of Channeling.
During their quest to find the kinship genes,
Mille and Hyoro receive a letter.
Are you Mille-nya?
Hmm?
This is a letter from Mr. Gamigami of Hakum Village.
Thank you.
I hope nothing bad happened.
Let's see…
"We're holding the Monstie Races."
"Get back here ASAP"!
I thought we should focus on getting to know the Rite of Channeling…
But I guess Gamigami will give us
an earful if we don't go back.
Ah, geez!
Now that could be useful.
Monster Hunter Stories: Ride On
Bokura kyou mo ikiteiru
We are still living today
Bokura kyou mo waratteru
We are still laughing today
Sore dake de mou nanimo iranai
We don't need anything more
Ima sugu ni RIDE ON
Just RIDE ON
Bokura sugu ni motomeru
We're quick to want
Yokubarina ikimono sa
This feeling is only natural
Nanimo motazuni umaretekita no ni
We're born without anything after all
Shiawase wa
Happiness is
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakatte kureru hito e
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun o miushinaisou ni naru kedo
To lose sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Onaji sora no shita onaji sora o miagenagara
We're under the same sky, we look at the same stars
Utsukushii iro no kizuna kazoeteiyou
Let's keep this beautifully colored bond
Shiawase wa itsumo
Happiness is forever
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakattekureru hito e
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun o miushinaisou ni naru kedo
Of losing sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Episode 60
Return of the Monstie Races!
Welcome back, everyone!
Lilia and Fifi, you're back too?
Sure am.
We got a letter from Mr. Gamigami.
You did too?
Yeah.
Oh, you're back!
Oh?
We were waiting for you.
Good you're here.
Um…
Are we really holding the Monstie Races?
Of course we are. It's a village tradition after all.
Yeah, but the only one new Rider this year is Nariki, remember?
Heh.
I think we had two more Riders.
Eh?
A-Are you referring to us?
But we're not newbies anymore.
Besides, we should be focusing on saving Avinia and learning about the Rite of Channeling.
I know all that, there's no need to remind me.
But the village has been low on morale
so the Monstie Races are needed even more.
This village needs something to brighten up the mood.
I'm asking you, too.
After the Ebon Riders robbed Dan's group
of their Kinship Stones…
…they all look so grim.
I see…
But still…
I'll participate in the Monstie Races!
Huh?
Hoho, you'll do it? That's the spirit!
Yes sirs!
It'll make the people in the village happier.
You're entering too, right? Hyoro? Mille?
Yeah…
We can't disappoint Nariki.
I guess you're right.
But don't expect us to go easy on you!
I wouldn't want it any other way!
Now that's settled, let's take care of the preparations!
Yeah!!
Master Gale!
Master Gale…!
Hey, you minions.
Have you seen Master Gale anywhere?
I saw him going to see that woman prisoner.
Again?
And just when I got some good information on those Hakum Village Riders.
What that's about the Riders at Hakum Village?
Master Wrath! Just what might you be referring to?
You smell tasty, you know.
If you keep secrets from me…
I'll eat you!
I remember! I remember! I remember!
They're holding Monstie Races!
So everyone will be at the Hakum Village!
Well, I guess they'll be tastier than this hairball.
We've got skewers!
It's a Hakum Village's specialty!
I highly recommend our mushroom skewers!
The race is about to begin soon.
Make sure you win.
Roger that!
That said, Mille and Hyoro
have fought against the Black Blight.
You won't beat them through normal means.
Why would you say that before the race?
Don't panic.
We decided to give you a handicap.
A handicap?
How can you give someone
a handicap in a Monstie Race?
We're the ones who built this course.
What's that got to do with me?
It means we can share some tricks with you.
There are so many people here.
Yeah, it even looks like Riders from other villages came to see the race this time.
I guess Hakum Village became famous because of the whole Black Blight thing.
I see.
By the way, where are the Numbers?
They said they had some job related to the race.
What kind of job?
Beats me.
Welcome, welcome!
How about a Kinship Stone
as a souvenir from Hakum Village?
The best Kinship Stones, shiny and sparkly!
How about one?
Deb…li?
Debli?…
Say it normally!
Why are you here?
Heh.
Where there's people, there's money.
And where there's money, there's Debli!
Forget that. You can't sell fake Kinship Stones
as Hakum Village's souvenirs!
I can't? Figures…
Of course you can't!
Damn.
I was hoping I'd get something more from it…
The Monstie Races will begin!
Participants, get to the start gate
of the village square!
A splendid prize is waiting for you this year, as well!
Mille, we need to go.
Yeah.
And you, clean up this junk.
Okey-dokey.
"Splendid prize"…
Hello to everyone here under this clear blue sky!
The day we've looked forward to the whole year is here!
A Hakum Village's specialty.
The Monstie Races are about to begin!
This time your live reporter is full of brilliant passion!
Number One!
Beats, at your service!
And this year's commentary will be provided by native girl to Hakum Village.
Lilia, say hello to the viewers.
Nice to meet you!
And we have another famous guest!
Ahem.
The history of the Monstie Races is quite long.
It is said that it continues to this day
ever since Hakum Village's establishment.
I, Gamigami, participated in the Monstie Races
during my young days, as well.
This scar from back then
is still like a medal to me now—
Eh, because the story seems to be long:
the famous guests are old folks from Hakum Village!
That explanation is sloppy.
Now on to predictions about the winner.
Lilia, what's your opinion?
Let's see. Although Nariki's Velocidrome is perfect for speed, I heard that it's still lacking in stamina.
And it seems that Mille and Hyoro will participate with Seregios and Zinogre respectively.
I think Mille's Seregios will have an advantage if she can make use of its flying ability.
I see. So Mille is your favorite?
Let's try asking our guests as well.
I think Mille, Hyoro, Nariki.
Mille, Hyoro, Nariki.
The grandpas made themselves clear.
Mille, Hyoro, and then Nariki!
– Nariki.
– Ah.
If you're too nervous, it'll affect your Monstie.
I was like that too.
This still is a festival, so it's okay to relax.
Roger.
The illustrious Debli is going to race too!
Huh?!
Whoa! A wild participant appears!
Wait. Is he even a Rider?
Hey grandpas! Are entries this late allowed?
What to do, hm…
Is that even his Monstie to begin with?
Well, I'm not sure, but looks like he can at least Ride On.
The race will be more exciting with more participants.
All right, entering late is okay!
"Okay!"
We got an "okay"!
Now that a dark horse known as Debli has joined the race,
I can't predict how things will unfold anymore!
Heh.
The glorious prize is already mine.
I guess that's what I expected…
Whatever, but he'll be sorry if he underestimates the Monstie Races.
All right, time to Ride On.
We're starting the race.
Yeah!
Got it.
Okay.
Ride On!
Velocidrome!
Zinogre!
Ride On!
Seregios!
Hyoro's Zinogre and Mille's Seregios!
Each contestant is wearing full armor to match their Monstie.
What a sight!
You're as cool as I thought!
Well, we did come all the way back here.
And remember that I told you I won't hold back.
I better do my best, then!
No matter how strong your monsters are…
…when it comes to riding on the ground, you're no match for my Great Poogie!
I won't lose.
Let's do our best.
Yeah!
Hey, don't ignore me!
Let's begin the Monstie Races.
I am looking forward to giving the winner our wonderful prize.
The start signal is this sound bomb—
All right, all right! Start!
And they took off!
Who will win the glorious prize!?
My start signal…
Ride On!
Rathalos!
Mille is already in the lead!
Then Hyoro, Nariki!
And then…
Debli goes after them!
Mille was calmly watching the timing of the start.
Let's take a look at what awaits our contestants.
Here's an introduction to the course!
The longest course
in the history of the Monstie Races.
Point One is the main street running through the center of the village.
Speed is everything in this long, straightforward segment.
Point Two is Borde Hills.
Our reporter at Borde Hills, Spex, will keep us up to date.
Spex!
I hear you loud and clear.
This is Point Two.
And I'm Spex, reporting live from Borde Hills.
Despite its name, this is a pretty rocky area so jumping abilities will be very useful.
The third point is Cakse Woods right ahead of Borde Hills.
We have Fifi over there.
Fifi, over to you!
This is Fifi from Cakse Woods.
The contestants will have to dodge the forest trees.
Fifi? Is something wrong?
Hmm…
Just my imagination, I suppose.
And the last point is a turnover…
…located at Gasha Hill which crosses Cakse Woods.
We have Floof over there.
Let's connect.
Floof!
Hm?!
Hey, Floof!
Floof!?
I think he's sleeping.
Figures.
Anyway, after that the contestants fold back at Gasha Hill…
…and whoever gets back here first wins the race.
I see.
It certainly is a big course.
Beats, Beats.
They're already at the Point Two near Borde Hills.
All right!
Hey— Poogie?
Where are you going?
Hm?
The belated contestant, Debli,
has taken a turn in an unexpected direction.
Mille, Hyoro and Nariki, in that order,
have reached the rocky part of Borde Hills.
Beats.
There's a sign here that says "No need to pass through the rocky region".
"No need to pass through the rocky region"?
What the heck does that mean?
I wonder if it's true…
This mountain is perfect for Legion's flying ability!
Mille, watch out!
What the heck?!
Whoa! Contestant Mille…!
She was taken down by
a surprise Barrel Bomb launcher!
Nariki!
Listen carefully, Nariki.
You can quickly overtake them at the rocky part
of Point Two with your jumping.
Roger that!
Jump, Drome!
Zinrai, follow Nariki!
We can't lose to a newbie, Legion!
Finally, it's Point Three.
The Monsties have reached Cakse Forest.
Beats!
Beats…?
Can you hear me?
At least answer.
I wonder what's wrong…
Oh? The thread was cut…
What's that…? How disgusting!
Everyone! Wait!
Oink! Oink!
Fifi?
What's the situation at Point Three?
Hm? This is bad!
We're experiencing technical difficulties!
This means we won't know how the race is going until someone comes back…
Look like the live broadcast doesn't know what's happening.
How realistic.
Yeah.
You're not getting away, Nariki!
Heh! You'll be eating my dust in no time!
Huh?
Someone's here!
You're Wrath!
What are you doing here?
Haha!
We meet again, kid.
You're that Ebon Rider from before?!
Looks like it.
This time I'll get all three of your Kinship Stones!
Sync Ride!
Breath's coming!
Sorry, but my Legion won't give in so easily!
How powerful…
I'll take you on!
I'll go with you!
So strong…
What do we do?
We can't take him on even with the three of us…
I have an idea.
Eh?
Come on and give up your Kinship Stones nicely!
Huh?! I won't let you escape!
Oink…?
Where are the others?
Huh?
They were behind me…
Which means I'm the first?!
Huh?
Did we have another contestant?
Oink…
Oink!!
Where are you off to again, you crazy pig?!
Don't run in the middle of the course!
We can't run in the middle of the course!
Got it.
It should be okay if one doesn't run!
Give up already!
There's a cliff ahead!
A pitfall!?
Go~!
Veloci-slash!
Shooting Star!
Cross High Bolt!
Did we get him?
I'd like to ask him some questions.
Oh?
You're not getting out of it.
No way! How can he still stand after that!?
He still wants to fight us?
So hungry…
Time for a gastronomical retreat…
Fa-thud.
But I'll get your Kinship Stones next time for sure!
We… won?
Yeah.
Your strategy won, Nariki.
Really?!
All right!
But, Nariki…
The race is still on!
You said it!
Hey, wa— that's not fair!
Whoa!
The Monsties and Riders are finally back!
Who's gonna be the first one to cross the finish line!?
Ah!! Slow down!
Eh?!
What's this! Contestant Debli is in the lead!
And… he crosses the finish line!
He was last but now he's first. A round of applause for…
Debli!
Huh?
I'm first?
For real?!
All right!
Glorious prize, here I come!
You've gotta be kidding me…
What?
You were attacked by an Ebon Rider!?
Yes, sir.
We got him to retreat somehow.
If we were to face him again…
We really have to get stronger.
Otherwise we won't be able to save Avinia.
Hey!
Oh?
You guys!
Lute?
And Cheval too?
I got a letter that the Monstie Races
were being held again.
Yeah.
I got a letter, too.
All right, let's race!
The race… has just ended.
What!?
Huh…?
All right. As a prize, you get to be the village leader for a day.
All right!
Wait… village leader for a day?
It's a great honor.
It's also a great duty filled with odd jobs.
Here, take this cleaning set.
Huh!?
What the heck is this?!
Ladies and gentlemen, it's Navirou!
That Itsy-Bits guy came to ask Navirou about the Numbers.
But if he wants answers, he's gotta bring me 1,000 donuts!
Next time:
"The Revival of Doctor Manelger?" Ride On!