These kids are Riders.
And they form kinship with Monsters.
A group called the Ebon Riders has kidnapped Avinia and tried to steal Lute's Kinship Stone.
But recently, Hakum Village held their annual Monstie Races…
…in order to reignite the morale before saving Avinia.
The Numbers have also united to become good partners to their Riders.
Let's save Avinia!
Yeah!
Hey guys!
Good, you're all here!
You're Itsy-Bits!
What did you come here for?!
Don't tell me it's about Kinship Stones again…
No, no, not at all!
Then what is it?
You're not with Manelger?
Actually, about that… I came here to request a favor of the mighty Numbers.
Huh?
Monster Hunter Stories: Ride On
Bokura kyou mo ikiteiru
We are still living today
Bokura kyou mo waratteru
We are still laughing today
Sore dake de mou nanimo iranai
We don't need anything more
Ima sugu ni RIDE ON
Just RIDE ON
Bokura sugu ni motomeru
We're quick to want
Yokubarina ikimono sa
This feeling is only natural
Nanimo motazuni umaretekita no ni
We're born without anything after all
Shiawase wa
Happiness is
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakatte kureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
To lose sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Onaji sora no shita onaji sora wo miagenagara
We're under the same sky, we look at the same stars
Utsukushii iro no kizuna kazoeteiyou
Let's keep this beautifully colored bond
Shiawase wa itsumo
Happiness is forever
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakattekureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
Of losing sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Episode 61
The Revival of Doctor Manelger?
So?
What's this favor you were going to ask Navirou?
I hope this isn't some kind of trap.
Not… not at all!
Traps are the only thing you ever do.
You're not in a position to ask us for anything.
Please, anything will do.
For example, any advice…
It's about Dr. Manelger.
About Manelger?
Last time Navirou met you, it was like…
"I lost my research drive! I lost my motivation!"
Or something like that.
Yes, it was already pretty serious back then.
But I still had some hope left
while I searched for new research themes.
But now…
Even though I've always believed in the power of science…
Huh…
Every day he went to the laboratory, and just sighed.
Um, excuse me, Doctor.
How is the research going today…?
Research, huh…?
How nostalgic.
What have I even been researching about these days?
I can't remember even that, Itsy-Bits.
Eh?
But… Doctor, you always said that there's nothing impossible for science.
Hmph.
Why did I say such a thing…?
It's already a story of the past.
Eh…
Huh?
The Doctor has completely lost his motivation for research and his purpose in life.
That Manelger?
You don't say.
That sucks.
Yes! It sucks a lot!
Like I care!
Did you think Navirou believed you for even a second?
Huh?
I can't believe it at all.
I got somewhat sleepy-nyaa.
Good night.
Hey!
Please don't go to sleep!
You're the ones who modified him to do that!
A-Anyway…
With the Doctor being like this,
I have no idea what to do from now on…
So please help me.
Please believe me!
Believe you? How can we, when the trust between us and the two of you doesn't span even a single millimeter?
We're not obligated to help you.
So cruel and cool…
Like I said, you modified him so!
Don't make me say it over and over!
Oh!
That's right!
Everyone here was modified by the Doctor.
In other words, you owe your solid bond to the Doctor!
Huh?
Now, let's all get Dr. Manelger motivated again!
Don't joke like that.
Besides, Navirou is already busy saving Avinia!
We have no time to deal with you.
Oh, by the way, it seems that the Doctor has obtained information where Avinia is being held…
What!?
Well, the last time we met the Doctor,
he did know about the Ebon Riders…
Right, right?
If you help the Doctor's get back on his feet,
I'm sure he'll be able to help you!
Now, O' great Numbers!
Let's cheer up your creator, Dr. Manelger, together!
This is the place. Over there!
First of all, you're hungry, aren't you?
Before seeing the Doctor, we'll have a welcome lunch.
Of course, we have a special donut for Mr. Navirou.
A special donut!?
It was hard to make a donut of this size.
It truly is a special donut,
made with great craftsmanship.
Thank you for the food!
Actually…
Since the Doctor's hasn't been researching anything,
our income is at zero these days.
This is our welcome lunch…?
Balloon donuts, huh…?
So where is Manelger and what's he up to?
I think he's in the laboratory.
Or rather, former laboratory…
"I think"!?
You don't even know what your boss is doing!
Do you have that thin of a relationship?
No, that's…
Hmph.
Compared to that, me and Cheval are perfect!
And I'm doing pretty good working with Nariki!
I love Mille-Mille-nyaa.
I am a good match with Hyoro as well.
Navirou and Lute won't lose either!
For example, when there is only one donut left…
Navirou always thinks to share it with Lute!
(But then I eat it myself anyways.)
So you don't share it with him after all?
It's the thought that counts!
I trust and respect the Doctor, too.
But he's so closed off to everything now.
That's why, as his assistant for many years…
It only tells you what kind of bond there was between you and the Doctor.
I feel sorry for you.
W-Wrong!
The Doctor and I are connected by bonds of research.
So if he regains his motivation again…
Whatever, enough with the talking!
The important thing is that I'm still hungry…
I know.
I can summon the smell of donuts thanks to the Navirou Burst Fart I acquired with the Rite of Channeling.
Anything but that!
Then what should I do about my hunger?!
Is there any food in here?!
Manelger!
Buh? Bwe?
Donuts!
Hand them over to Navirou!
"Lost his motivation", my butt.
He definitely looks pretty lively to me.
And his skin is a picture of health too.
Actually, when the Doctor loses motivation,
he channels it to overeating.
What?
We have no income, so dealing with his appetite is a real pain…
So that was why you couldn't give us a proper lunch?
Now do you understand how serious the situation is?
Hmm…
We're going home!
W-Wait a moment, please!
You didn't lie about being troubled.
We got that, all right! But…
Frankly, we can't help you out.
At the very least, it doesn't seem like he's up to something again.
Also, he doesn't seem to know…
…anything about Avinia-nyaa.
And I definitely don't have any business in a place with no donuts!
Please don't be like that. Help me out!
I'm begging you!
What was that sound?
Manelger, what's wrong!?
Are you up to no good again!?
This is…
…an empty can?
Oh, it crumbled again.
Gotta rebuild.
Eh?
Actually, when the Doctor loses motivation,
he channels it to building tall structures.
Oh…
We're going home for real this time!
W-Wait a moment, please!
I hope we don't meet again!
See ya.
I-It can't be…
Thanks to that detour we wasted a bunch of time.
It's so annoying when he does strange research…
…but he's even more annoying when he's "lost motivation".
What a troublemaker.
Since it's highly improbable we'll get any information on Avinia or the Ebon Riders from him…
…I'll return to Cheval as soon as possible.
I want to see Mille-Mille too-nyaa.
Emergency!
Hmm?
A monster!
What!?
Over there!
It's a Tigrex!
It has a receiver on its forehead!
So he's been modified too!
Don't tell me some of Manelger's modified monsters were still alive?
We can't go home like this.
Come on, Numbers, let's catch it!
Yeah!
Ride On!
Rathalos!
Where did it go?
I can't see it anywhere.
Ah!
Looks like footprints of a Tigrex!
If we follow them, we'll find it for sure-nyaa.
This is where the footprints end.
Damn!
Where did it disappear to?
Great…
What should I do now?
Huh?
Oh, it's you guys! You came back.
We had no choice.
We have a use for your Manelger.
Excuse me again.
Huh?
I'll keep a lookout here without going to sleep-nyaa.
Hey! Manelger!
Hmm?!
Eh… after I managed to arrange it so high…
This isn't the time for crying!
U-Um…
What do you mean?
One of his modified monsters has survived.
Hm!?
No way!
There's no doubt about it.
We saw it in the nearby forest.
Hey, Manelger.
That's your modified monster out there!
It'll be very dangerous if it comes near any of the towns.
Please stop it.
Hey, Manelger!
Answer us!
Um…
I'm sorry to interrupt…
But, unfortunately we got rid of all the remote controls for the modified monsters.
What!?
Then what are we gonna do now?!
I don't know…!
Doctor!
What should we do?
It doesn't matter to me.
– Tsk!
– Oh! It fell down again!
Get a grip, Manelger!
You've got things to do!
And I don't mean overeating or stacking empty cans!
You have to stop your modified monster!
Exactly.
The monsters you modified are…
…your rewbonshibility!
Take responsibility, Manelger!
Or else you'll get a taste of my new technique: Navirou's Burst Far—
We told you already, anything but that!
Research almost always leads to results.
But sometimes a blunder can't be avoided.
The researcher doesn't need to take responsibility for those, though.
What the heck!?
Do you have any idea how many people you've troubled with your research!?
But instead, the researcher can be challenged to do anything!
Doctor…?
Trouble-nyaa!
The remodeled Tigrex appeared again and is causing chaos everywhere-nyaa!
What!?
Don't worry.
We still have this.
Eh? Doctor!
You mean, we still had it?
Researchers are supposed to consider every possibility at any time.
Even when they lose their motivation and get depressed.
It's no use. I can't even graze him!
But the town is done for unless we stop it!
No need to worry! Leave it to Navirou!
Hurry up and stop it!
Manelger!
Hmph.
I don't take instructions from the likes of you.
Researchers work at their own pace, with their own will, and spirit of inquiry.
That's our Doctor!
Fine, fine, but could he hurry up?
Hmm…
Doctor, what did you do?
After careful consideration, this is reusing an abandoned research product.
In other words, this isn't a challenge.
Huh!?
I don't understand what you're getting at!
Just stop the monster already!
Yes! And undo the modification.
Make it like it was before-nyaa.
You're the only one who can do it.
Hey! Manelger!
Can you do it? Or is it too difficult?
Hmm…
Eh?
Wha-aaat!?
Hey, what was that about?!
Reusing past research projects is retrograde.
In other words, it's regression.
Something researcher's pride won't forgive!
Nobody cares about your pride!
The modified Tigrex has noticed us!
Fine, it looks like we're the only ones who can stop it!
I won't let you go anywhere with my flames!
Po-poppo-poop!
Over here, over here!
Navirou's donuts-smelling farts!
Fart navigation! Come on!
Eh?
Why does the remodeled Tigrex react to his fart?
Everyone loves donuts!
Please leave it to me.
And next up is me!
Kira-kira-nyaa!
Alright, Floof!
Now's your turn!
Got it-nyaa.
It felt asleep nicely.
We did it!
All right!
United as always!
We're… the Numbers!
This… is something that research can't do.
The power of friendship!
Manelger, do us a favor.
Turn that modified Tigrex back to the way it was.
It's enough…
…if we're the only ones modified.
I fully agree.
Please.
Please-nyaa.
Hmm…
Doctor?
Very well.
Let's restore it.
Really!?
It's not like I'm doing this because you asked me to!
I heard there's a group called the Ebon Riders
wandering about these days.
Wait, you really knew…?
About the Ebon Riders.
Of course I did.
But they weren't very interesting,
so I didn't focus on them in my research.
But it'll be pretty troublesome if such shady characters got to use my modified monsters.
And that's why I'm restoring it.
I'm glad.
The Tigrex is better off in that form.
Then let's restore you guys as well.
What did you say!?
In short…
Let's turn you all back to how you were before the modification.
Hey! I wanted to say it!
Oh, I'm so glad.
That's my usual Doctor.
I refuse.
Why?
Huh?
Are you sure?
Navirou likes how he is.
Yes.
I like my current form as well.
I do, too.
We owe it to the Doctor that the six of us met.
Precisely.
Mille-Mille says she loves the current Floof, too.
So I'm good with this form-nyaa.
Hmm?
Just kidding! You can't be restored either way.
But I can always modify you further to make you cooler.
Hey!
Navirou's plenty cool as he is!
Exactly!
A bright flame is a testimony of passion!
Number One!
Beats!
Hot on the inside, cool on the outside.
Number Two!
I'm Cryo!
Kira-kira-nyaa!
Dazzling flash is a proof of beauty.
Number Three!
Fifi's here.
These glasses aren't just for show.
The Brains of the Numbers!
Number Four!
Spex!
For a brighter tomorrow, leave it to Navirou!
Number Five!
Navirou!
A well-slept child is a well-kept child.
Number Six!
Floof.
The six of us are…
The Numbers!
Hahaha!
In the end, my research work is wonderful even for failed works like you!
Don't call us "failed work"!
Then instead…
I am giving you this.
What's this?
If you press that remote control button,
I'll come to help you, but just once.
It's called…
A Resqusto-Manelger switch!
That's what I wanted to say!
Eh…
What a useless thing.
Well, keep it anyway.
I'm sure it'll come in handy some day.
Somehow my head is overflowing with ideas now!
He looks really energetic.
Okay, let's accept it just in case.
All right!
We're going back to Lute's group
so we can look for Avinia!
Yeah!
Oh, one more thing!
Everyone, please have this.
What's that?
You're looking for Miss Avinia, right?
Well, through frantic examination, I was able to obtain this map showing her whereabouts.
Say what!?
Nya-ow!
It's too rough!
Lute here!
I finally have a run-in with Gale again.
Gale, why do you not believe in kinship?
You're a Rider just like me!
Next time:
"Lute VS Gail Again!" Ride on!