These kids are Riders.
And they form kinship with monsters.
Lute and his friends finally infiltrated
the Black Castle and succeeded in rescuing Avinia.
However, Anvis has already planned his next step.
Master Anvis doesn't ease up on his workmen.
Just you wait, Hakum Village Riders.
I'll teach you a lesson this time!
Monster Hunter Stories: Ride On
Bokura kyou mo ikiteiru
We are still living today
Bokura kyou mo waratteru
We are still laughing today
Sore dake de mou nanimo iranai
We don't need anything more
Ima sugu ni RIDE ON
Just RIDE ON
Bokura sugu ni motomeru
We're quick to want
Yokubarina ikimono sa
This feeling is only natural
Nanimo motazuni umaretekita no ni
We're born without anything after all
Shiawase wa
Happiness is
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakatte kureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
To lose sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Onaji sora no shita onaji sora wo miagenagara
We're under the same sky, we look at the same stars
Utsukushii iro no kizuna kazoeteiyou
Let's keep this beautifully colored bond
Shiawase wa itsumo
Happiness is forever
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakattekureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
Of losing sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Episode 67
Anvis's Plan
Master Gale.
Master Anvis performed the ceremony, didn't he?
Master Gale?
Be quiet, will you?
Well, well. Looks like Master Gale is in a bad mood.
Nuts…
What is it, Master Gale?
You…
…are so cute!
Geez, what's this all of a sudden?
I'm sorry for making you help me search for an egg, Dan.
Seniors are there to help their juniors when they're in need.
In top form!
That's right. Riders help each other.
Yes, but Mount Celion's cold weather
is starting to getting to me.
And we don't have any more Hot Drinks.
I'm reaching my limit.
Alright, then. Let's split up so we can find something faster!
– Yeah!
– Okay!
Everyone grew up to be quite reliable.
It's a good thing that we have the Numbers with us, too.
We'll find an egg and return to Hakum village in no time.
Ever since I teamed up with you, I can organize my thoughts a lot better, Spex. Thank you.
Me too. I'm a bit weak but I'm glad I have you, Hyoro. You're kind to everyone and you have a strong backbone.
A Velocidrome isn't bad, but if we want to face
the Ebon Riders, another Monstie will come in handy.
Well said, Beats.
Remember, there are still all sorts of things I have to teach you.
Aren't you exaggerating?
I feel like I'm catching up to you.
What did you say?
What's wrong, Nariki!?
Beats! I found an egg!
Master Anvis.
What's going to happen with Noir?
You knew this would happen and yet you still carried on with the rite?
Do you have a problem with my methods?
I am Anvis, and I possess power that surpasses every Rider.
Get out of my sight. Don't come back until I give you my instruction.
Those Hakum village brats are in for a surprise.
Are you sure about that?
What? You guys!
We expected you to come here.
Well, that saves me the effort of finding you.
We're not gonna let you do as you please!
Eek!
Heheh! How are you going to stop me?
I'll take you on.
Oh? How have you been, little girl?
Ride On!
Barioth!
Let's go, Frostfang.
Hmm… his Deviljho seems to be stronger.
I don't think Avinia will lose,
but I don't think it'll be easy either.
Ride On!
Rathian!
Sync Ride!
That's not fair, you cowards!
A Rider's power lies in the strength of their kinship.
Our true power comes from combining everyone's power!
Geez… I'll let you go for today.
But I'll be back!
O' holy Kinship Stone…
…bind thou together our's and these slumbering souls.
And now, the moment of new life:
Awaken!
It's a Brachydios!
Right on!
Awesome, Nariki!
It's so cute…
I'll call this little fella "Blow".
Very nice! That's a good name, Nariki.
Deepen your kinship with Brachydios
as you deepened it with your Velocidrome.
Okay! Roger that!
Master Gale. What's going to happen now?
Nuts. I don't know Master Anvis's true goal even though
I've worked here with you for a while now.
I think it's to make the power of the Sync Ride stronger…?
Yeah.
It seems that the Ebon Riders' Sync Ride originates from a ritual done in a certain village of Riders.
I see, I see.
It may even be related to the rite performed on Noir.
Do you want that power too, Master Gale?
Nuts. Why do you think I've joined the Ebon Riders?
Ah… I'm sorry I asked a bad question…
Gale, do you have a moment?
What's up, Sis?
The reason I gathered you all here is because Avinia wanted to tell you something.
I deeply apologize for all the inconveniences I've caused for you all.
But you didn't do anything wrong, Avinia.
So why apologize?
Thank you, Navirou.
But I don't think the Ebon Riders kidnapping me was a coincidence.
Is it really that strange that I've decided
to leave the Ebon Riders?
I guess. But why did you tell me about it?
Because I feel like you're the only one
who will understand.
You're also pretty disgusted with all of this, aren't you?
How did you know…?
Right on mark, huh? Call it woman's intuition.
I can't deny that.
You joined the Ebon Riders with your own ulterior motives, didn't you?
You're awfully transparent.
Oh? You've seen through me for that long?
Your ability to read people is scary, Sis.
Hah. Don't try to flatter me.
I can't eat so many donuts at once…
Lute… can you sleep?
No. I'm thinking about what Avinia said.
About the Ebon Riders' goal?
Yeah… That too.
But also about how Avinia has just seemed really sad ever since I met her.
I'm glad I get along with you, Cheval.
Yeah, me too.
Yes, I'm hungry. Thank you for the donuts…
A lot has happened. But if it hadn't, we wouldn't have met each other.
I suppose so.
Fate is such a strange thing.
If Manelger hadn't modified me,
I wouldn't have met everyone in the Numbers.
I would've never guessed that bubbly, little Navirou had such a dark past.
I don't have any regrets, though. We'll just keep moving forward.
Well said.
Now, let's get some sleep.
We have to get up early tomorrow.
Ride On!
Rathalos!
Anvis…
…I'll stop you.
At last you revealed your true nature.
It's just like I told you, Master Anvis.
Master Gale is a traitor.
Nuts…?
Actually, I didn't tell you…
…but I am a faithful subordinate
who reports directly to Master Anvis.
Your daily actions were reported to Master Anvis, one by one.
Gale. I didn't trust you right from the beginning.
Oh, really?
You inherit the rite of Kuang village.
How could you think…
…that you would ever get what you wanted?
Put him in jail.
Dan?
Can Nariki Ride On his new Monstie already?
Yeah.
It's a little early, but we thought to do a mock-fight with Mille.
Nariki's new Monstie is amazing!
All right! Are you two ready?
But this isn't a real fight.
Kinship Techniques are prohibited.
– Okay!
All right, begin!
Ride On!
Seregios!
Brachydios!
A Brachydios!?
You've got an awesome Monstie.
It may be a mock-fight, but I still won't hold back.
Save those lines for after the fight.
This armor looks cool, don't you think?
An opening! Split Claw!
Great Tackle!
Ah! Too fast!
As expected, Brachydios has awesome power.
That Nariki… He hasn't strengthened his ties with Blow yet?
Nope. He can't handle him at all yet.
What's wrong, Blow?
What are you doing?
Calm down, Nariki! Don't let Blow's power overwhelm you.
You're 100 years too young beat me in a fight.
Damn! Let's try a Kinship Technique!
Blast Blow!
Huh?
I told you… 100 years too young!
That hurts…!
All right, stop!
What the hell was that?
Why were you trying to use Kinship Technique in a mock-fight?
Sorry…
Nariki. Brachydios is a great Monstie,
but there's no point if you don't have any kinship.
You've got to deepen your bond more.
The Ebon Riders are strong,
but we put up a good fight, too.
You're right.
Besides we don't just have individual power,
we also have the power of our kinship combined.
Yeah, so even if all four of them were to gang up on us, we wouldn't lose.
Master Anvis. They are certainly getting stronger.
After they have gone through the rite of channeling,
their Monsties are on par with our Sync Ride.
I don't like it…
Hm?
The Ebon Riders were supposed to be overwhelmingly strong Riders, right?
Shadow! Watch your tongue before Master Anvis.
Where's Gale?
I don't like your attitude either.
What did you say?
Hahaha! Interesting. What are you trying to say?
Thanks to your rite, Noir—
Doesn't matter.
I've had it! Ride On! Nargacuga!
Ride On!
Kushala Daora!
Sync Ride!
I can defeat worthless scum like you even without Sync Ride. It's easy, like taking a candy from a baby.
Capture Shadow!
Uh-oh, what a shame.
You bark was bigger than your bite.
How unlady-like. Certainly not beautiful at all.
Gale betrayed me.
What?! Unbelievable!
Master Anvis. Please let me get rid of him.
The four Ebon Riders suddenly became just two!? Hahaha!
Heh. Things have gotten interesting.
I knew Gale was in a position
to know the rite of overlapping.
Huh?!
Now I have all the pieces regarding the rite.
All there's left to do is to put them together.
Will you lend me your strength? Wrath!? Mad!?
Yes sir!
Let's see…
Looks like everyone's here.
Every now and then, it's good to drop the pretense…
…and have a honest talk while eating a pair of donuts.
You know what? Why not?
We've all been having a pretty rough time lately.
That's true.
I think so, too.
There are plenty of things I'd like to ask you, Avinia.
Huh?
I also want to ask my seniors how to deepen my kinship with my Monsties.
Yeah. Looks like somebody's motivated.
I'll evaluate that attitude.
Recently it's just seemed like one problem after another.
A lot things happen when you live for a long time.
It is a bit regrettable that we have to rely on the younger generation.
Let's just do what we can.
You're right.
They're all doing well for themselves.
They're good kids.
Can't argue there.
This again!? I hate when you get like this, Lute!
You're always like, "me, me, me!"
You pay no attention to anyone but yourself!
Oh, and you're any better? You're always like,
"donuts, donuts, donuts! Give me more!"
Well I hate how you're always too honest!
Words can hurt, you know!
I hate how you say everything that comes into that pea brain of yours without thinking!
Lute's worse!
Navirou's worse!
I'm sorry you have to put up with this, Avinia.
I had doubts about Lute and Navirou when we first met…
Listen, I'm telling you,
you can't do this on that leg.
If you have to hurry on ahead,
wait until after your injury is healed.
Stubborn, aren't you?
You see? I told you so, didn't I?
I understood their kindness even back then.
Avinia!
You understand us, right?!
It's ironic, isn't it?
Are you listening, Gale?
I'm sorry, Sis…
Not that it's my business, but…
…you've got something complicated going on there, don't you?
I tried to do the right thing, but got the opposite results.
I'd recommend against trying to do the right thing when you're so young.
You're too earnest.
I'm sorry to interrupt your chat.
Master Anvis is calling for you, Master Gale.
Please don't look at me like that.
I just did my work the best I could.
It's not like I don't like you, Master Gale.
But Master Anvis is my boss.
I had to watch you, Master Gale…
…and of course I had no choice but to report your betrayal.
Why did you call me here?
Bring me Avinia's Kinship Stone.
Huh? Why would you ask me such thing now?
Master Gale, please watch your words.
If you refuse to, I'll kill the Shadow sisters.
What will you do now?
Come on, Master Gale, give your answer.
About my hometown… I can't tell you more about the rituals held in Kuang village.
I really don't know much about my childhood.
The only thing I know is that, somehow, the Ebon Riders gathering Kinship Stones and the ritual are connected.
The Ebon Riders place their Kinship Stones on their foreheads, unlike ours.
And once they call "Sync Ride", their movements get much swifter.
Do you think any of that is importance, too?
I wasn't convinced at first.
But now that I've learned new things,
I think I see the truth.
It's like not being able to know how a donut tastes
until you actually taste it with your own tongue.
No, it's not like that.
Nya-ow!
Me and Ratha will definitely stop Anvis's right in his tracks!
Yeah.
All of us Hakum village Riders will join forces.
My Legion went through the rite of channeling.
I won't let you be the only ones who look cool.
My Zinrai's also powered up.
Doesn't Anvis expect me to run away?
That would be rude,
but it's also why he sent me with you.
I'm here to help Master Gale and to make sure you don't betray Master Anvis any further.
Hm?
You…
…aren't cute anymore.
Let's go, Master Gale!
Along with Master Anvis faithful subordinate, Nuts!
Shut up!
Ah! How scary! Master Gale is extremely scary!
Come on, Master Gale! Be serious about this!
Let's go!
Ride On.
Rathalos!
Lute here!
The Ebon Riders suddenly
lead an attack on Hakum village.
But I won't let them capture Avinia again!
We'll protect everyone in the village, no matter what!
Next time:
"Assault of the Steel Dragon" Ride On!