These kids are Riders.
And they form kinship with Monsters.
Against his will, Gale performed the Rite of Overlapping on Anvis.
However, he didn't chant all the necessary lyrics.
I am power itself.
Everything, every Monster will bow down to me!
Where is Anvis going to, now?
Judging from the direction he flew…
…he might be heading to Geo-Fulkright.
Can Lute and his friends stop the assault
of the dreadful Kushala Daora?
Monster Hunter Stories: Ride On
Bokura kyou mo ikiteiru
We are still living today
Bokura kyou mo waratteru
We are still laughing today
Sore dake de mou nanimo iranai
We don't need anything more
Ima sugu ni RIDE ON
Just RIDE ON
Bokura sugu ni motomeru
We're quick to want
Yokubarina ikimono sa
This feeling is only natural
Nanimo motazuni umaretekita no ni
We're born without anything after all
Shiawase wa
Happiness is
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakatte kureru hito e
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun o miushinaisou ni naru kedo
To lose sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Onaji sora no shita onaji sora o miagenagara
We're under the same sky, we look at the same stars
Utsukushii iro no kizuna kazoeteiyou
Let's keep this beautifully colored bond
Shiawase wa itsumo
Happiness is forever
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakattekureru hito e
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun o miushinaisou ni naru kedo
Of losing sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Episode 71
Kushala Daora's Charge
Ratha, try to catch up!
Navirou! Hold on tightly!
That's easy for you to say! This wind's crazy strong!
What is that?
Huh?
What a tremendous gale!
A tornado!?
No… it's Anvis.
It's getting thinner…
Is his power weakening?
Now's our chance!
Let's catch up to him!
Lute!
Here comes the wind!
Alright!
We should be safe at this distance.
Just a moment, Avinia.
Alright.
The only thing left is…
That's it! Let's get you some water.
Ah… Avinia?
You're awake?
…Deb…li?
…Debli?…
Just say it normally…
But still, Avinia, I'm glad you're awake. Are you okay?
Yeah… what about the others?
Lute, Cheval and your brother went after Anvis.
After Anvis…?
We can't fly in all that.
Looks like we just have to wait for the wind to weaken.
We can't afford waiting.
The town will be destroyed.
We'll stop him before that.
Yeah, but how do we do that?
He's going to destroy himself.
What makes you think that?
I'm sure we'll get our chance to attack him.
But I want to finish him off myself!
You sure about that?
You were Anvis's servant until just recently.
Maybe you're just pretending to be our friend?
W-What?
Do you want to make a donut bet?
Huh?
Hey! Gale!
Stop it!
S-Stop… Stop it…
Stop…
Your fur feels good.
Navirou, it's fine.
I believe Gale.
I told you already.
Gale told me his real name.
We became friends in that moment.
Lute…?
Yup.
I also believe in you.
Cheval…?
What's all this, you guys? Staring at each other.
Navirou wants to be your friend, too.
Oh?
Gale, I told you to stop…
Everyone! The wind got weaker!
Looks like we can fly now!
Alright, let's go!
Yeah!
Hmm? The town is unusually quiet today.
What? What on earth…?
Dmir!
Come here!
What's that?
Looks like trouble.
Evacuate everyone from the city to the houses!
Yeah!
Alright.
Avinia.
I got you some water.
Wait, you're already up?
I'm going after Anvis, too.
But you should be resting now!
You just regained your consciousness!
I'm fine.
No!
Gale told me directly:
"I trust you."
"You're the only one who can take care of my little sister."
And I promised him to do so!
I really appreciate that.
…Thanks, Deb…li.
…Thanks, Debli.…
I asked you to say it normally…
Huh?
Ride On!
Barioth!
Avinia!
Let's go, Frostfang!
Wait a second! Avinia!
Alright then! I'm going with you!
Ride On!
Great Poogie!
Alright! Onwards, Poogie!
Pssh-oink!
I will engulf all of this world with my wind.
We won't let you!
Yeah!
Anvis, you scum! Just you wait!
Hey, Navirou!
Don't stand up!
See? I told you!
It's swallowing everything on the ground…
If that tornado attacks the city…
Dammit!
Don't, Lute! Don't attack him!
Ratha! Savage Fireball!
Ratha!
Go, go, go!
Okay! Great!
I bet that must've roasted his bottom!
Ah…!
What?
It came back!
Another one!
As if that could hit us!
I told you not to stand up, Navirou!
Nya-ow!
There was still one left!
Every attack just seems to come right back.
Hey! Gale!
When's that "chance to attack" coming up?
Hey, everyone!
How about targeting the top?
There shouldn't be any wind in the eye of a tornado.
How about we rush into the windless area
at the top and attack from there!
Brilliant as always, Cheval!
Sounds good to me.
What do you think, Gale?
Let's get started from here!
Yeah.
I agree.
Ratha!
Rathi, let's go, too!
Dusk!
You can do it, Ratha!
If we don't hurry up, the city…
Rathi, I'm counting on you!
I can't… hold on…!
The turbulence of the air current is much more intense up higher!
Hurry up!
Don't let your children out!
Let's show it to everyone in this town.
The mighty power I've gained!
Is everyone okay!?
Hey, Dmir! Look at that!
What?
A Kushala Daora…
Is that the cause of that huge tornado?
Dmir. Us Hunters will take care of preparations.
Okay! I'm counting on you!
A Dragon Wind Pressure near a volcano…
That can't be good.
At this rate the town will be destroyed!
You'll get hit by rocks that are caught in the wind!
Everyone! Let's get down to the ground for the moment!
Okay!
Easier said than done.
Navirou! Don't let go!
- Ah!
- Navirou!
Nya-ow!
Gale!?
Don't let go.
I don't mind if you doubt me…
…but for now, please trust me!
Gale…?
You…
Cheval!
Gale!
Hold on tight!
Ride On!
Rathian!
Lilia.
Was there any report from Lute after that?
No.
Last thing I know is that they were headed for Black Castle to rescue Avinia.
Ah.
Captain Simone! Trouble!
Vice Captain Pappan.
A monster attacked Dovan Volcano and Geo-Fulkright.
We have received reports of massive damages.
What!?
That monster is…?
Probably…
…it's Kushala Daora.
Kushala Daora…
Its whole body is covered with scales as strong as steel…
…and its ability to fly is amazing.
It can control the weather…
It's an old dragon species of mysterious origins.
Pappan. You said "probably"?
Yes.
It seems that it's not just Kushala Daora…
Ah!
If I remember right, Anvis had a Kushala Daora!
Which means…
Yes.
The Rite of Overlapping…
Simone!
Reverto!?
I heard that Geo-Fulkright is in trouble!
Us Hunters are going to reinforce them soon!
We'd like to ask for detailed data on that Monster!
Very well. I will ask for it immediately.
Lilia, inform Captain Gentor about this matter immediately!
Pappan, collect any information you can!
Yes ma'am!
This is bad.
Please…
Don't involve the people in that town.
Avinia!
I will protect you!
I'm sorry…
It's impossible to get to the top.
It can't be helped.
Still, there must be a way to get past that whirlwind…
Uhm… Gale…
You saved my life just now.
Don't mention it.
If this keeps going, Geo-Fulkright will be destroyed!
We'll stop it for sure!
Yeah!
This is where Dmir lives!
That old man gave me donuts!
Alright!
Let's try it one more time!
We have to, even if it seems impossible!
Yeah!
What's wrong, Gale?
No…
It's nothing. Let's go.
We'll protect the city.
Yeah.
What did Lilia write?
Things are looking grim.
What do you mean, Chief?
It seems that the Ebon Riders finally went through the Rite of Overlapping.
The Rite of Overlapping?
It is a secret ritual passed down the generations
in Gale's and Avinia's home village.
Yes…
Chief Omna.
What happens once one performs that Rite?
They will obtain the ultimate power.
Ultimate power!?
We have to go…
We have to go help them!
Yeah!
Chief Omna!
Please let us go!
Please!
They're right.
Now is the time to gather all Riders…
…and go stop Anvis.
Chief!
Alright! All the Riders, get ready for departure!
Yes sir!
Let's try entering alongside the tornado!
It should be doable if we go with the air current.
Alright, got it!
Everyone! Over there!
It's a Kushala Daora.
We're almost there!
Yeah!
Let's go, Ratha!
Fire!
What's that?!
Huh?!
It's Lute!
Now!
- Ratha!
- Rathi!
Dusk!
It's useless… we can't even make a dent!
Why… Why?!
It should be obvious.
I command the ultimate power now.
You ought to understand it the best.
Anvis! These people have nothing to do with this!
Don't involve them just to satisfy your bloodlust!
It's too late. I am already the ruler of this world.
The world is already mine!
You're insane!
Gale.
I haven't thanked you yet.
I appreciate that you gave me this power.
Really, you have my thanks.
You're still a good servant.
Don't be silly!
Gale is no longer your servant!
He's one of us!
Navirou…?
Anvis!
Don't… Don't involve people of the town!
Dusk!
I guess it can't be helped.
Let's play for a while.
Anvis!
Gale!
Watch out!
Avinia!
Are you okay now?
Yes.
It's all thanks to Debli.
He stayed with me the whole time.
Gale!
I kept my promise!
Looks like everyone's finally here.
Anvis!
We won't let you go any further.
Yeah!
I will stop you!
We won't let you go to the city!
What fools.
I'll make it so that you don't insult me ever again.
Get crushed by my Dragon Wind Pressure!
Be careful, everyone!
It's coming!
The Kushala Daora's Dragon Wind Pressure!
Stop it already!
Lute!
This is hilarious!
Everyone is blown away
and I haven't gotten serious yet!
I'm done playing with you.
It's time to go to Gildegaran.
Fahali!
What is it?
Please look!
Is that…?
Judging from his course, things are really bad!
Please contact the Hunters Guild immediately!
Yes!
Simone!
The reinforcements heading to Geo-Fulkright were canceled!
What on earth are you doing!?
I am sorry, but Anvis is no longer in Geo-Fulkright.
What!?
We've received a message from Fahali.
Anvis is heading for Gildegaran right now.
What did you say?
Raise the Gildegaran's alert level to the highest.
Everyone is to prepare for the worst.
I understand, Guild Master!
Who would think it'd ever come down to this.
Yeah. Things are bad.
I-I wonder what will happen?
The Ebon Riders will probably attack Gildegaran to show their power.
If Gildegaran falls, we're doomed!
The Ebon Riders are still Riders.
Only a Rider can stop another Rider.
I'm counting on you!
Yes sir!
I want each one of you to be careful.
We'll be okay!
Let us take care of it!
We leave village in your hands.
Very well.
Lilia! Pappan!
I'm going to attend an emergency meeting.
Contact me as soon as you find out anything.
Yes ma'am!
Understood!
The emergency meeting to defend against an Elder Dragon is hereby opened!
Lute here!
Geo-Fulkright has been destroyed by Anvis's overwhelming power.
A large-scale strategy meeting will be held at Gildegaran in response to that!
Next time:
"Emergency Strategy Meeting" Ride On!