These kids are Riders.
And they form kinship with Monsters.
Anvis's Monstie, Kushala Daora,
powered up through the Rite of Channeling.
Lute and his friends try to fight it.
But they're powerless before its overwhelming power.
Can Anvis be stopped?
Monster Hunter Stories: Ride On
Bokura kyou mo ikiteiru
We are still living today
Bokura kyou mo waratteru
We are still laughing today
Sore dake de mou nanimo iranai
We don't need anything more
Ima sugu ni RIDE ON
Just RIDE ON
Bokura sugu ni motomeru
We're quick to want
Yokubarina ikimono sa
This feeling is only natural
Nanimo motazuni umaretekita no ni
We're born without anything after all
Shiawase wa
Happiness is
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakatte kureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
To lose sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Onaji sora no shita onaji sora wo miagenagara
We're under the same sky, we look at the same stars
Utsukushii iro no kizuna kazoeteiyou
Let's keep this beautifully colored bond
Shiawase wa itsumo
Happiness is forever
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakattekureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
Of losing sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Episode 72
Emergency strategy meeting
You're awake, Lute? We've been worried!
Thank goodness…
What… What about Anvis?
We don't know.
He flew off to somewhere.
But where?
Aren't you still sore all over?
No, I'm fine.
Here, drink up.
It's a recovery potion.
Thanks.
I'm sorry I dragged you into this.
Ahh!
Don't sweat it. I'm doing this of my own will.
Hey! Lute!
Dmir?
I've been looking for you!
How's Geo-Fulkright?
It's destroyed for the most part.
But we'll rebuild it no matter how many times it takes.
We live in the shadow of a volcano.
We're used to that kind of risk.
Anyway!
I'm here to tell you about that Kushala Daora.
It flew over the sea, straight in that direction.
Isn't Gildegaran in that direction?
I'm afraid so.
He's going to Gildegaran!?
Let's go. We need to stop him.
The emergency meeting to defend against an Elder Dragon is hereby opened!
Thank you for coming here on such a short notice.
This is an emergency.
First of all, I'd like the head of the Royal Scriveners
to explain why you've been gathered here.
Sir.
I'm Royal Scriveners' captain, Simone.
I'll be leading this meeting.
Fahali here reported sightings
of an Elder Dragon heading to Gildegaran.
An Elder Dragon?
Yes.
An Elder Dragon…
Kushala Daora.
According to the report, after bringing huge damage to Geo-Fulkright…
…it's getting close to bring upon a disaster here in Gildegaran.
Kushala Daora?
Are you certain it's headed to Gildegaran?
I saw it with my own eyes.
It was heading straight here.
To support Fahali's testimony, us Scriveners also dispatched our observation troops.
We received similar reports.
However, an Elder Dragon is still a wild creature.
Why would it head from town to town?
Certainly, the attack of the Elder Dragon has been regarded as a natural disaster until now.
However, it can be said that the situation is somewhat different this time.
This is human action.
Human action?!
This Kushala Daora isn't just a Monster.
It's a Monstie.
A Monstie, as in a Rider's?
Yes.
In other words, it's going to Gildegaran by its Rider's will.
An Elder Dragon as a Monstie?
Is that even possible?
It is.
It seems that an Ebon Rider called Anvis is manipulating Kushala Daora through a forbidden technique.
If Kushala Daora is going here from Geo-Fulkright with the shortest distance…
We don't have much time.
We need to prepare countermeasures as soon as possible.
Don't worry.
Gildegaran is protected by a solid wall.
Yes.
Gildegaran can withstand any Monster assault,
be it Kushala Daora or whatnot.
Yeah!
If we stay here, we'll be okay.
We can use the wall as a shield…
You seem to be forgetting one thing.
The walls of Gildegaran do not protect the Hunters.
It's there to protect the civilians inside.
Then what should we do?
Escape while there's still time?
Do we stand any chance against it?
Don't worry.
Look around.
We have the best Hunters around here in Gildegaran.
Kushala Daora won't lay a claw on anyone.
Don't you think?
Y-Yeah.
Let's hunt!
Yeah!
Well said.
We'll meet with Kushala Daora outside the fortress.
– Please wait.
– Hm?
Please think this through.
There are many Hunters here in Gildegaran indeed.
However, there are few Hunters who have dealt with Kushala Daora before.
As Simone says, few of us may have the experience.
But we have accumulated vast knowledge in the history of hunting.
You know I'm right, Simone.
You're certainly right.
The Scriveners have collected a lot of information on Kushala Daora.
Tell us more about the information that you have gathered.
Very well.
Let's clarify all the information of the squadron.
Originally, it was impossible to tie the Elder Dragons to any specific ecosystem.
These unknown Monsters were named so mainly for convenience.
One thing we've been sure: we couldn't find out anything about their origins.
Still, through the accumulated experience of many Hunters…
…we've gained some information related to how to fight them.
Such as that Kushala Daora always appears within a storm.
Or that Kushala Daora sometimes wraps itself with a tornado as a form of protection.
Unlike many dragons, it has strong front and back legs apart from its strong wings.
In addition, because Kushala Daora is entirely covered with steel-like scales and crust shells…
…the body is so strong that it is called a Steel Dragon.
Finally, Kushala Daora's biggest weapon is…
…a Breath of a tremendous wind power that spits out of its mouth.
According to Hunters' reports of past encounters…
…it was said to be so strong that one couldn't move anywhere near it.
I have also heard of it.
It's called Dragon Wind Pressure.
It's said it makes it difficult just to approach it.
In other words, one can't attack unless
the Dragon Wind Pressure is taken care of…
In any case, every Monster can be defeated, even an Elder Dragon.
Every living thing has a weakness.
Hmm…
Does it, now?
Yes.
Kushala Daora's weak point…
…are its horns.
Horns?
Now that you mention it, I've heard something similar from a Hunter that fought with Kushala Daora before.
He said the storm ceases when you break its horns.
I thought it was just a folk story, though.
According to our research, Kushala Daora's ability to control the wind involves the horns on the back of its head.
Therefore I think it's safe to say that if one broke its horns, it couldn't use its Dragon Wind Pressure anymore.
In other words, we should aim for the horns.
But as long as that Dragon Wind Pressure is there, we can't get even close to the horns.
Yeah…
Can I have a moment?
Hm?
The Hunter who told me about his fight with Kushala Daora said this:
"You can suppress the wind by attacking with poison."
I see.
If we poison it, its control over wind will worsen…
Poison, huh?
Then you can count on us Gunners.
We'll shoot poison bombs at it.
Then the course of action has been decided.
The only thing's left is to make detailed strategy.
Yes sir.
We invite all the Hunters in Gildegaran to join us.
Is that okay, Guild Master?
Yes.
Hm?
What's wrong? Is there anything more you're worried about?
Yes, just one thing.
I wouldn't be anxious if we were up against just a Kushala Daora.
But this time it's a Monstie.
That's to say, a Rider.
We can't be sure what kind of attack to expect.
That's what I'm worried about.
I see.
We have no experience of fighting Riders.
I wish we had at least that bunch with us…
Ah, you have a point.
They'd be of great use.
These guys, huh…
I'm sorry we're late!
We, the Riders of Hakum Village,
would like to assist you on the battlefield as well.
Oh? They're here.
Huh? Is something wrong?
No, no! Everything's just perfect!
Good to see you here! Hahaha!
I know it's sudden, but please tell me about your Monsties' abilities.
Huh? Right now?
R-Right away…
I don't understand it very well, but…
…at any rate, we seem to have made it in time.
Hey. Where's Lute?
I can't see Cheval with you either.
Yeah. What happened to the Riders who stopped the Black Blight?
Figures. They're not here yet.
What do you mean?
It'll be fine!
Lute will come for sure!
Nariki?
Uhm…
I don't know where Lute and Cheval are.
But they'll definitely come, no matter what happens.
They're just that kind of people.
Lute's junior?
I agree. He'll come here for sure.
There's no doubt about it.
Yeah!
All right then, now we'll discuss a strategy to hunt an Elder Dragon
and cooperation between Hunters and Riders.
Yeah!
Ride On!
Rathalos!
After we cross Trese Desert, it's Gildegaran.
We pushed it crossing the ocean.
We have to rest for a while.
Otherwise we won't be able to fight Anvis.
I know that.
It'd be great if there was a way to get there faster…
We have to eat, too.
Yep.
Thanks.
You too, Brother.
Can I talk to you for a bit?
What did you want to talk about?
Turn around and fly back.
Why would I do such thing?
Your Kinship Stone…
Did you know that it's the Stone that Dad used to wear?
Yes.
I heard it.
Dad kept always saying…
"You'll grow up to be a great Rider some day."
Really?
Dad was kind.
Too kind for his own good.
That's why men like Anvis could take advantage of him.
You resemble Dad.
That's why I don't want you to fight.
Avinia…
Please protect that Kinship Stone.
For Dad's sake.
I'll go with you.
I was born to our family as a priest as well.
Avinia!
I understand.
Dan's group should arrive in Gildegaran by now.
Will things go well?
There's no use in worrying.
I'm sure they can handle the task we had given them.
They all grew to be so strong.
They remind me of us in the old days.
What do you know?
They have long surpassed us.
In every society, it's youth that pushes the world forward.
But now the village is defenseless.
Pfft! I'll drive away any Monster that tries to get close!
Exactly! We're old but we're still Riders!
Did you already forget how you had your butt handed to you the last time?
You didn't need to say that.
Please protect them…
Vlau.
Hurry up with that ballista!
Heave-ho!
Keep pulling! Aptonoth!
This is spectacular.
I've never seen a battlefield of this size.
Yeah.
It's truly in top form.
We're up against a Kushala Daora.
A Monstie, on top of that.
That alone might be not enough.
Ah, I feel nervous and my head is blank…
Hey, hey.
Don't forget you have an important role.
Thinking about it doesn't help.
Captain Gentor.
They're nervous. Could you explain them the strategy once more to calm them down?
Sure.
I just adjusted the operation progress.
The aim of the first stage is to stop the invasion of the Elder Dragon.
We deployed a squad of Gunlancers equipped with shields on Kushala Daora's invasion route.
Shield Wall!
Yeah!
They won't be blown off so easily.
Keep calm and don't let go!
Attract the enemy and aim precisely!
Yeah!
Then, once we manage to stop Kushala Daora's advance…
…a team of Heavy Bowgunners will carry out a poison bombardment.
Can we have any assistance from the air?
I understand.
You'd like to attack it from both ground and the sky.
I see.
The wind will weaken from the poison bombardment.
Then we can concentrate the simultaneous attacks of the ballista troops on the horns.
Monsties who are capable of long range attacks will also participate.
It's a good plan.
I'd like to add smoke balls and poisonous smoke balls somewhere.
Will these have any effect on an Elder Dragon?
Well, it won't hurt for sure.
It was a suggestion from our reinforcements.
Reinforcements?
Yeah. Seems like they've just arrived.
Ah! Them!?
We're sorry we made you wait.
Meow! Meow! Meow!
They're Felynes from Pawpad Place!
Felynes?
Hahaha!
We'll lend you a paw in this battle.
When we heard about the crisis in Gildegaran, we rushed here to help.
I'm sure we'll be of help to you!
I'm leaving the implementation of the strategies you suggested to you.
You can count on us!
We'll begin with our preparations right away!
Once we break the horns, it's time for stage two.
We'll switch the ammo in ballista to restrain nets and we'll pin Kushala Daora to the ground.
Then we'll attack it from all sides.
We'll lead the Riders' team.
Good.
Until Kushala Daora… no… Until Anvis collapses, I want you to keep attacking at full power.
What about you, Reverto?
I was assigned to the commando unit.
We'll observe the situation and act accordingly.
I think Reverto will work best when we give him freedom.
Thanks.
As a leader of the commando unit,
I'd like a little more firepower, though.
Don't be like that.
I can't cut you anything more.
I know, but still…
Hm?
Is something wrong, Spex?
What can you see?
Looks like something's approaching from Trese Desert.
Ah! Don't tell me it's Kushala Daora already?
It's earlier than we calculated!
Ah!
Spit it out already!
It's not a Kushala Daora! It's a group of Hunters!
Hunters?
They're…
Hunters from Albrachs Village!
Thanks for coming here.
You Riders saved our Albrachs Village during the Black Blight crisis.
Time to return the favor!
Yeah!
I'd all of your Hunters to join my commando unit.
Sure!
With your men I don't need to worry about our firepower anymore.
Good.
Wave attacks of Hunters and Riders will give it a hard time.
We can win!
Don't worry.
Lute will come for sure.
Yeah.
Hey! Everyone!
Ah, that voice just now! It was Lute!
Hm?
Look up!
Lute!
How did you manage to arrive earlier than Anvis?
We owe it to them.
Hm?
I noticed that a strong wind was blowing towards Gildegaran at a higher altitude.
We flew with the wind and arrived here earlier.
Good job, Cheval.
I see Navirou's teachings didn't go to waste.
I don't remember you teaching him, though.
Nya-ow!
Well then, now we seem to have everyone.
Wait!
Ah! Stop!
Oink oink oink!
I hope you guys didn't forget about me.
li.Deb…li.
li.Debli.…
It's not like anybody missed you.
It's Debli! Say it right!
Oink?
Anvis is here.
Brother…
Listen up, Hunters!
It's a battle that decides Gildegaran survival!
Here, on Monsone Plains, is located our last defense line.
We, Hunters, along with our fellow Riders…
…will defeat the Steel Dragon, Kushala Daora!
Yeah!
We'll stop him no matter what!
Lute here!
Riders. Hunters. Scriveners. Felynes.
Everyone joins forces!
Let's do it, everyone!
This is the final battlefield!
Next time:
"The Arrival of the Steel Dragon" Ride On!