Welcome back, Gale… err, Michael.
Lute…
Thank you, everyone.
Yeah!
It's me who should thank you.
And apologize, too.
I put everyone in danger.
But, thank you, really.
I felt the power of everyone's kinship…
Brother!?
Episode 75
Kinship
Will Avinia's brother be okay?
We tried what we could,
but he still hasn't woken up yet.
It seems you have made reasonable efforts.
Do you suppose it's Anvis's revenge?
He did lose his way back then…
Well, it's all in his hands now.
In order to not repeat Anvis's mistake…
…one must calm their heart and believe in kinship.
Yeah.
Alright, everyone!
We're gonna help people in need!
Yeah!
Doctor!
Hunters and Riders are working together.
Things have changed, don't you think?
Yes, even look at how hard Numbers are working!
Those Numbers might just be the most superior masterpiece I've ever created.
Exactly, Doctor!
Which means we have to bring forth
new Numbers to this world!
Exactly, Doctor! Exactly!
I agree so much, I said it twice.
Well then, for the sake of the society and the people,
let's get to it right away, Itsy-Bits!
Yes sir!
Michael hasn't woken up yet…?
Yeah, even though it's been three days…
He'll wake up soon, for sure!
And once he does, make sure
you give him my special Energy Drink!
Thank you, Lilia.
I'll give it to him as soon as he wakes up.
Alright then, I'm off to investigate the Ebon Riders some more.
– Alright.
– See you.
Take care.
I know!
Oh? You want to take Michael to Hakum Village?
I think that it would be better for him
to stay in a Rider's village when he wakes up.
Hmm. In that case, I'll contact Omna.
Alright, Ratha.
We're taking Michael to Hakum Village.
That should do it.
Hm?
Dusk!?
Dusk…
I get it. You wanted to carry Michael yourself.
Dusk, try to avoid shaking too much.
It'll be fine.
Dusk understands my brother more than anyone.
Wait, isn't that Mad?!
And he's with Wrath!
Let's go, Cheval!
Yeah!
What are you up to?
We'll stop you!
Well well, who do we have here?
It's you guys again.
Alright, that's enough.
You've improved, pipsqueaks.
We're members of an organization.
Now that Anvis is gone, we don't have a reason to fight with you anymore.
Yeah, what he said.
See you later, brats!
That's it…?
You're fine with that?
We're on our way to join
the Ebon Riders' main troops. Excuse us.
Ahh, I'm starving!
What?!?
Why?! Why?! Why?!
Lute went somewhere without telling Navirou anything?!
Unfortunately, Cheval didn't contact me either.
Same with Avinia.
Hyoro and Mille are still here in Gildegaran, though.
I feel bad for Navirou.
Argh! That Lute!
He's always like "kinship this, kinship that"!
But what about kinship with Navirou?
Cheer up, Navirou!
Let me show you our bonds!
A bright flame is a testimony of passion!
Number One!
Beats!
Hot on the inside, cool on the outside.
Number Two!
Cryo!
Kira-kira-nyaa!
A dazzling flash is the proof of beauty.
Number Three!
Fifi here!
These glasses aren't just for show.
I'm the brains of the Numbers!
Number Four!
Spex!
For a brighter tomorrow, leave it to Navirou!
Number Five!
Navirou!
A well-slept child is a well-kept child.
Number Six!
Floof.
Always bright and positive, a friend of everyone!
Number Seven!
Nuts!
The seven of us are…
The Numbers!
Wait, that's not it!
Tee-hee.
You all sure worked hard.
We're back, Chief Omna.
I'm glad you returned in one piece.
Welcome back, Avinia.
Hello, Loloa.
Chief Omna.
Thank you for allowing us to stay in Hakum Village.
I think my brother will be calm here.
Stay here as long as you want.
Our village has a lot of elderly people
familiar with medicinal herbs.
I brought you this.
They have a very pleasant scent.
Thank you.
I'm sure my brother will love these.
Hang in there, Michael.
Everyone's waiting for you.
When will Michael wake up?
Loloa, I'll walk you back.
He'll be fine, Avinia.
Michael will definitely wake up.
I know…
Michael. Don't make Avinia worry too much.
Wake up already.
Dusk is waiting for you, too.
Believe in the power of kinship.
Brother!?
He woke up?
A light… guided me…
I'm so glad.
I've been worried sick for days…
You have?
I'm sorry, Avinia.
Where are we?
We're in Hakum Village.
Lute and Cheval's hometown.
Hakum Village?
Lute!
What's the matter, Navirou?
"What's the matter"… my paw!
Why did you go to Hakum Village without me?
Don't tell me you completely forgot about your teacher and partner, Navirou?!
I guess I kind of did.
Nya-ow!
Do you have anything to add?
A-ny-thing - at - all?
Uh, I'm sorry.
Ah!
Michael is awake!?
Ride On!
Rathalos!
What a feast.
It was all harvested at Hakum Village.
I can vouch for it.
Go ahead and eat whatever you want.
Come on, Brother.
Thanks.
This flavor brings me back…
It's a taste of home.
I just remembered some of the time
I spent with you back when we were kids.
You were always wearing a mask,
but I knew there was a kind face behind it.
So you do remember some things?
I'm sorry I haven't stayed by your side.
But we were able to meet again.
Master Michael.
Nuts?
He told me he wanted to see you,
so I brought him with me.
Master Michael, I'm really sorry for all the inconveniences I've caused you.
Just "Michael" is fine.
Time is passing slowly in our village.
Hopefully you can regain some of the time you lost here.
Thanks.
Nuts, your life may have been full of mistakes till now.
But don't abandon hope.
Everyone makes mistakes.
Oh, except for Navirou.
A mediocre Felyne like you
will definitely make more mistakes in the future.
But that's one of great truths of life…
What are you talking about!?
I'll reflect on it later! Take this!
Acting like you know it all!
They're quite similar.
No kidding.
But there's nothing we can do.
Similar how!?
Heh.
Brother…
Avinia, are you crying?
I'm sorry…
This is the first time I've seen my brother smile.
Avinia…
Oh, right! It's about time we fed our Monsties.
Huh? Are you sure about that?
See you, Lute.
You guys, too.
I put you through hell.
Not at all. I'm proud of you.
You've been kind from as far back as I can remember.
Avinia…
You're my beloved brother.
You're a precious member of my family.
Thank you for everything, Ratha.
Hey, hey! Stop! We'll crash!
Debli?
Looks like it.
You guys!
Not a single word of greeting?!
Isn't that cold-hearted?!
We're home!
Welcome back!
How is Michael feeling?
Actually, he woke up a little while ago.
That's great. Avinia must be thrilled!
Yeah.
I see, I see. I'm happy for them!
Alright, time to give my regards to my future older brother—
Ow, ow, ow, ow!
You're not going anywhere.
But why?
When I get married to Avinia, Michael will be my older brother!
What a beautiful forest.
It really is…
The scenery is totally different, and yet it resembles our Kuang Village. I wonder why?
Maybe that's the reason why Hakum Village felt so nostalgic.
I wonder what's going on in our village these days?
I don't think anyone lives there anymore.
Now that you mention it, we met a Barioth
with an old wound in Kuang Village.
It seemed like it was protecting the village.
Like a guardian?
It must be Frostfang's parent.
His parent?
Yes.
Maybe he's waiting for us?
For us to come home.
I'm sure it's waiting.
A kinship once bound can never be broken.
A Monstie and its Rider will always be connected through kinship.
I want to rebuild Kuang Village.
Then let's go!
We'll help you out!
Yeah. We've rebuilt Hakum Village once before.
To tell you the truth, I didn't feel any pleasure or accomplishment from defeating Anvis.
I finally accomplished my long-time goal.
But I only caused trouble
to so many people in the process…
Still, I…
I know how you feel.
Huh?
I'm walking the right path again thanks to Lute.
I want to help you the same way Lute helped me.
Cheval…
Isn't that how it should be?
Everyone should think and act on their own!
Even when we're apart,
we're bound together through kinship.
We'll be always together!
That's our kinship!
I see. So you've decided to return to your hometown?
Yes. Thank you very much for taking care of me.
Thank you very much.
No, no. Riders help each other in need.
Chief Omna. I decided to go with them
to help rebuild Kuang Village.
It seems you also met new friends by coming to our village, Debli.
Trust your judgment.
Yes sir!
Well then, Chief.
Lute, Cheval… each of you are going to embark on a journey, yes?
Yes sir!
When youngsters are determined
to go on a journey, no one can stop them.
Chief Omna. We'll remain in the village for now.
There's something we want to do here.
I'll go with Lute—
It's too early for you!
Tsk.
That's one difficult junior.
Lute.
What is it, Navirou?
I heard you've decided to go on a journey again.
That's right.
I saw people handling their Monsties differently than me.
And I thought to myself:
"I'd like to see more people."
"What other forms kinship can take."
Here we go with your "I want to see more stuff".
Navirou wants to take it easy for now.
Then chill here at Hakum Village.
Besides, shouldn't you go visit Pansy?
You promised her.
Yeah. Exactly.
That's why, sorry, but this time
I can't be your navigator.
Well, that's fine.
Your navigation is right only 1% of the time.
What? It's 2% and you know it!
Whatever. Besides, I'll have Ratha with me.
Oh, I see, I see. Well, bye then.
You sure about that?
It can't be helped.
If you want me to come, now's the time to ask.
I'll be fine, I'll be fine.
Really? Are you really sure?
Are you really, really, really, really, really sure about it?
Lute.
Navirou.
Let's go together, Navirou!
Lute!
Oh, if you insist! I'll go with you!
I'll go with Cheval, too.
I'm counting on you.
We discussed it between us and decided.
Each of us will stay with our Riders.
I'm looking forward to working with you, Beats!
Leave it to me!
Mille-Mille, take care of me.
You can count on me, Floof-Floof!
I think the two of us can show the Numbers' strength the most.
I'm so glad you think that!
I'll support you however I can, Avinia.
Thank you.
So there's also kinship like this, too.
Michael…
Can I stay with you?
Yeah.
Let's build our kinship, too!
I want a Felyne partner, too!
And the boys set off on a journey again.
Each one with their own goal in mind.
Lute! Cheval!
Lilia!?
I received a letter from Loloa and rushed here.
Why didn't you tell me?
I haven't decided where to go yet,
so I thought about letting you know later.
I bet you just forgot.
I'm sorry.
Cheval, you too!
I'm sorry…
Alright. I'll let it slide.
At least I got to see you again.
When you two decide your future goals
and work to accomplish them…
…I will support you on your way!
Lilia.
Thank you.
Cheval. Avinia. Michael.
Time to go.
See you!
Take care!
Good luck!
Please be careful!
Bye bye!
Lute! Cheval!
See you again!
Take care!
I'll drop by Kuang Village!
Till next time!
Let's rebuild Kuang Village just like Hakum Village.
Yeah!
Hey!
Leave it to me, Michael!
Hey! Wait for me!
Bye for now, Lute.
Yeah! See you, Cheval!
We'll probably get into some trouble again.
But I'll protect you, Rathi!
Cheval, don't forget that you have me.
Thanks, Cryo.
Lute's gone again…
Come on, now, Nariki.
Cheer up!
What's the matter?
I found eggs!
That's a Rathalos's…
And Rathian's egg!
Somehow I feel like celebrating.
We have to tell Lute and Cheval.
A new kinship is born!
Great!
For the longest time,
Hunters' and Riders' culture went separate ways.
But looks like that wall has finally crumbled.
Yes.
That Lute from your village is one peculiar boy.
He's a boy born from a strong kinship that originates from ancient times.
Perhaps he's going to change the world even further.
I look forward to it.
Monster Hunter Stories: Ride On
Bokura kyou mo ikiteiru
We are still living today
Bokura kyou mo waratteru
We are still laughing today
Sore dake de mou nanimo iranai
We don't need anything more
Ima sugu ni RIDE ON
Just RIDE ON
Bokura sugu ni motomeru
We're quick to want
Yokubarina ikimono sa
This feeling is only natural
Nanimo motazuni umaretekita no ni
We're born without anything after all
Shiawase wa
Happiness is
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakatte kureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
To lose sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
Onaji sora no shita onaji sora wo miagenagara
We're under the same sky, we look at the same stars
Utsukushii iro no kizuna kazoeteiyou
Let's keep this beautifully colored bond
Shiawase wa itsumo
Happiness is forever
Soba ni atte chikaku ni atte
To be by your side, to be close to you
Taisetsuna mono hodo mienakunaru kedo
Not to lose sight of what is really important
Kansha shite
To be grateful
Nani ga okitatte wakattekureru hito he
To the person who understands no matter what happens
Dare ni datte nigetakunatte
Everyone is afraid
Jibun wo miushinaisou ni naru kedo
Of losing sight of oneself
Ai wa kanarazu kimi no kokoro ni aru yo
But you will surely find love in your heart
Bokura issho ni aruiteikou yo
Come walk with us
How long are you going to lie there?
Come on, we're leaving.
Don't panic, don't panic.
Let's depart after a round of donuts
and settling our minds.
I can't believe you.
Ride On!
Velocidrome!
Yian Kut-Ku!
Basarios!
Glavenus!
Tigrex!
Rathalos!
Let's go, my Monsties!
Our adventure is just beginning!
Wait! Don't leave Navirou behind!
These kids are Riders.
And they form kinship with Monsters.
The End