苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 006—
Make it through! Attack duo
Well, how will it be?
Answer me.
Are you going to do the practice game or not?
You finally have a chance to get back at me.
Heheh.
Even though it's just a practice.
Your opponent is Matsushima Middle School. They're out of your league.
Matsushima Middle School…
Eh?
How is it?
Will you accept it nonetheless?
Your faces say it all.
Heheh.
There's no way you can win.
After all, your opponent is just too strong.
What do you think? Can you win?
If you win, good. If you lose, you'll acknowledge the need for training.
Expect it to get even more strict than now.
If you win…
If we win?
I'll turn in my resignation immediately.
You'll quit coaching us?
That's correct. I'll step down.
But you need to win with Matsushima Middle School.
But, unless a miracle happens, it's futile.
Hahahaha.
If that's what it takes to make you quit, we'll win, be it with miracles or not.
We'll win with our power alone.
Do you think you can win with your current strength?
We'll, we won't know until we try it.
Do your absolute best.
I'm surprised. It's like he's eager to see us lose.
He must have fun working us to the bone.
That's why he offered such conditions only after choosing Matsushima.
W-What does he know. If we're to repeat such a practice, we'll win even if it kills us.
I don't like it either…
If this keeps up, I'll quit.
– Yeah. Me too.
– Me too.
Let's win this. Or do we want to let him coach us?
I wonder if professor Hongou tries to rip our club apart?
If that is the case, we can't lose here.
Hey, Ayuhara-kun!
Ah, Tsutomu-kun!
I've heard from Hayakawa-kun that your opponent is Matsushima?
They're pretty formidable.
I don't care. Formidable or not, if this gets professor Hongou to give up coaching, we'll win without fail.
Y-You look scary.
I think professor Hongou might have chosen them to make you better.
He might look kind, but he's a demon inside.
I can't leave our club to such a demon coach.
Hey.
Ayuhara-san.
Don't get so worked up.
Besides, there's nothing to worry about.
Thanks to me, our victory is set in stone.
Hayakawa-san, do you still intend to put on airs?
You're pretty arrogant.
What did you say?
Did you forget already that thanks to you, we lost the last match?
That was different.
What was different?
If you only think about putting yourself in a spotlight, it'll work against you.
Hey, hey.
Cut it out, you two. It isn't the time for this.
How about postponing this until after the game?
Tsutomu-kun's right.
The problem is winning the match.
City Gym
We leave it to you.
Do your best!
Here!
Got it!
Play!
Let it go!
You did it. Amazing spike!
Katsuragi-san, give us a good serve.
Leave it to me.
It's coming.
Ayuhara-san!
Roger.
Fujimi ・ Matsushima
Time!
Hayakawa-san, excellent! Keep at it!
Hayakawa-san's showing her bad habit again.
However, it seems to work.
Looks like we can pull it off.
Listen. Mark their best player, Hayakawa.
The last serve was good. Keep tossing to me.
Eh? That was for Ayuhara-san.
The problem starts from now.
A mistake will be fatal in consequences.
They'll probably start taking Matsushima lightly.
But I can't use this strategy time.
It's a pinch. I want to tell them.
Make sure to block precisely.
They have figured it out already.
Ayuhara and Hayakawa don't know it. I want to tell them…
Hey, look at professor Hongou.
At this rate we'll win. He must be sad he won't get to bully us anymore.
Hey, professor Hongou.
It's timeout.
– Come on, one more!
– Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Ayuhara-san.
Me!
Fujimi ・ Matsushima
Nice, nice!
Hayakawa-san, you're marked.
What now? Just one more point. It'll be all right.
I'll pass!
Leaving it you!
Fujimi ・ Matsushima
It's no good. She's completely marked.
How about I try throwing it to you, Ayuhara-san?
Kashiwagi-san.
Toss it to me. It'll be all right.
Ah, jump's too quick!
Fujimi ・ Matsushima
– Take this!
– Nice!
Fujimi ・ Matsushima
We won.
All right. Good, good.
I let you win…
Too bad, but this set goes to you.
At this rate we might lose the second set as well.
We have to do something.
This is where the coach should come up with an advice.
But with our coach…
Everybody, it's a pinch.
A pinch!
But you can survive this.
If you do, your enemies will respect your power.
Ayuhara-kun will surely think of something. I believe it so.
Look at him. He's laughing at us.
How vexing.
Don't look at him.
What are we gonna do without a coach?
All right, good going.
Keep it at that.
Marking Hayakawa was a success. Now they'll surely switch to Ayuhara.
Mark these two thoroughly until the end.
Got it?
– Yes sir.
Your blocking is well established in junior high.
Believe in yourself.
– Yes sir.
This is embarrassing, but I'm thoroughly marked.
I'd like to try to attack in turns with Ayuhara-san.
What do you think?
Yeah. It's not like we have other options.
Hayakawa-san, the tables will surely turn in our favor.
Yeah. Let's try this.
After all, if we lose this set, we lose the match.
We gotta do something.
Keep the serve!
Yeah.
Yeah!
Here it comes!
– Nice serve!
– Don't mind!
Hayakawa-san and I are completely marked.
All right.
Let's try feinting.
Nice, nice!
I've got this!
Chance, chance, chance! Catch the ball!
Damn!
Feinting didn't work either.
Fujimi ・ Matsushima
What do we do?
From tomorrow, I guess it's sayonara to volleyball.
Referee, time!
Go, go, Fujimi!
Ayuhara-kun asked for time.
I wonder what strategy she comes up with.
The problem is whether the others agree to it.
Hey, Hayakawa-san. Listen carefully.
Me and you are completely marked.
I know that already.
Plus their block is impenetrable.
Their form is at its best, too.
Finally their coach knows our weak points very well.
The question is who attacks next.
That's right.
When it is me or Hayakawa-san who hits the ball, they block it completely.
Isn't that right?
A-And…?
Now, if we destroy their focus, we destroy their defense.
We need to break that focus.
Right?
Yes but how?
First, me and Hayakawa-san move away from the ball, then we swiftly attack.
Come closer, everyone.
Keep that defense. Got it?
– Yes sir.
Looks like Ayuhara-san's plan is settled.
Professor Hongou's still smiling.
It's our chance to smile, too.
Play ball.
Get the serve back like planned!
Nice serve, please!
Here it goes!
What?
– We did it.
– We did it!
There it is, the long-awaited attack duo.
W-What is it, professor?
All right, it's my serve.
Keep the serve.
– Yeah.
– Yeah!
Keep the serve!
– Yeah.
– Yeah!
Let's make it a point!
All right!
– Ike-chan, please!
– Roger!
Here I go!
Don't mind, don't mind!
One more point.
Nice serve!
Attack.
How vexing!
Wha—
Fujimi ・ Matsushima
Fight back, girls.
Don't lose it here.
Attack!
Fujimi ・ Matsushima
Professor, the tables have turned.
It's the set point.
Chance!
Ayuhara-san, awesome!
We got to the final set.
It's wonderful, right, professor Hongou.
When did they become so strong?
I see.
If Kozue-chan's team wins, professor will have to give up coaching.
I wasn't mistaken after all.
What an amazing strike.
Plus Ayuhara and Hayakawa managed to form a duo.
Who would've think.
But…
Look at professor Hongou's face.
He seems unhappy with our victory.
Serves him right.
Ah.
I'm jealous of Matsushima, which has a proper coach.
All right, let's do best in the last set.
This set decides the match result.
I don't need to see the last set to know the outcome.
They'll win for sure.
City Gym
But…
I was naive for thinking I could raise the Japan's best volleyball team.
No matter how strong we are, if we aren't united, we won't accomplish anything.
I'll keep my promise.
I'll withdraw from coaching.
What are you doing?
Fujimi ・ Matsushima
Looks like we can win this.
I feel this for the first time.
All right, match point.
Do your best.
– Yeah.
Don't mind, don't mind!
Fight!
Here it goes.
Katsuragi-san!
Leave it to me.
Got it!
Defense!
– Ike-chan!
– Got it!
Attack!
We won.
It's our victory.
Professor…
It's so painful…
All right, cry all you need.
But don't be sad about this loss.
Let's do our best to defeat Fujimi Academy in the future.
– Yes sir.
– Yeah. We'll do our best.
We'll get back at them for sure.
That's the spirit.
This is our Matsushima's volleyball club.
– Yes sir.
From now, let's do our best!
Fight!
– Yeah!
This is our victory.
What is it, everyone?
It's nothing.
But after seeing how Matsushima Middle School is united with their coach…
I'm a little jealous.
You might've lost the game, but your teamwork was splendid.
– Yes sir.
All right, let's go home.
I feel like I woke up from a bad dream.
Hey, why do you think we won this easily?
I think it's because Hayakawa-san stopped playing solo and formed an attack duo with Ayuhara-san.
That's of course a reason too.
But the biggest reason is that because our team grew strong, isn't it?
What do you mean?
I mean that we won because of our hard training.
In other words, it's thanks to professor Hongou.
I think so too.
I see.
It's thanks to the practice that
I
was able to do anything.
Professor Hongou cared about us after all.
Yeah. He wanted to make us strong, and
that's why he put up such a training.
I'm glad. It's the first time I
see him in such a cool light.
Speaking of coolness, the chief's spike—
What is it, Hayakawa-san?
Hayakawa-san.
Ayuhara-san.
I need to settle this with you.
In front of the others, too.
Eh? Do you still intend to fight?
Girls, you too listen.
I've been thinking about it for a while.
About the real importance of
the
teamwork to volleyball.
This time I finally saw it clearly and it clicked.
Ayuhara-san.
I was completely mistaken.
I won't ask for your pardon, because I don't think I can be forgiven…
Let's end this. Just slap me.
I'm sorry. I lost my cool.
Thank you, Ayuhara-san.
I'm relieved.
Hayakawa-san, with this we finally become proper team mates.
I'm really happy you're saying this.
But there's another thing I want to settle here.
There's more?
Yeah.
Our Fujimi Academy volleyball club's captain can be no one other than you, Ayuhara-san.
What do you think, Kashiwagi-san?
I agree.
I think it's for the best too.
– Agreed.
Will you do it?
I will.
Let's aim for the Japan's top.
Hayakawa-san.
Everyone. Thank you.
Captain Ayuhara, banzai!
Ayuhara-san.
From today…
…I entrust my goal to you.
Hayakawa-san, you understand now.
But if it wasn't for you, we wouldn't have come this far.
We've decided the captain, now let's get professor Hongou to agree.
Yo.
Congratulations.
I'm surprised.
You've become this strong…
Tsutomu-kun, do you know where professor Hongou is?
He said he'll withdraw as promised and left when the final set started.
What do we do?
Do we get him to give up like he promised?
I got it.
You're probably thinking the same.
In the end, our club needs professor Hongou.
Professor must be at school.
Let's head back and stop him.
– Yep.
– Yeah.
Let's go.
Teachers room
– Professor Hongou!
Professor Hongou!
– Professor!
– Professor Hongou!
Professor!
He's nowhere to be found.
We still haven't looked in the club room.
Professor Hongou!
Professor!
L-Look at this!
As promised, I've withdrew from coaching.
Rejoice, weaklings.
If you're not busy laughing at me, do your best from now on.
Hongou.
It can't be.
He doesn't really want to withdraw.
That's why he came here alone.
That's right.
"Quit the club"… "weaklings"… nothing changes the fact he gave his best with us.
Let's try his home.
We need to convey our feelings to him as soon as possible.
– Yep.
– Yeah.
He's said to have gone to the beach.
All right, let's go.
Ah, isn't it him?
All right, let's call out to him.
Professor Hongou!
– Professor!
– Professor Hongou!
Looks like we've finally united.
It's the first step for the Japan's best volleyball club.
You weaklings!
What did you come for?
Please coach us!
Professor!
Professor Hongou!
It's the birth of a wonderful team.
All right.
I'll make you into the strongest team!
Having reunited with the demon coach, Fujimi Academy volleyball club picks up the training.
But a new problem appears
– a possible merging with Hamaki Middle School.
The girls, having finally caught a breath, are disturbed again.
One day, Kozue and the girls meet four members of Hamaki Middle School.
"You're the Fujimi's volleyball club, right?"
The gang of four unpleasantly laughs and leaves.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.