苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 007—
Meeting The Big Four
For the first time, we've won a public game.
Everyone regained their confidence as if they were born anew.
One more time.
Got it.
Toss!
I think our club has changed.
We've got our own first victory.
It feels different.
Ah, thank you.
One more.
Volleyball is about teamwork, right?
Indeed.
Fujimi volleyball club's teamwork is the best in Japan.
My hunger's strong, too.
All right, girls.
The warm-up time is over.
Professor Hongou gets back soon.
Let's go to the club room.
– OK.
– Let's go!
– Sorry, sorry.
– Oh, it's Tsutomu-san.
Why are you in such a hurry?
Newspaper club has an emergency meeting.
Calm down.
It doesn't suit a good newspaper club member such as yourself.
It's the merge.
We're merging…!
Merging?
Who's merging with whom?
The academy's upper management has a
lot of problems. You heard about it too.
Most of them stem out of the low student numbers.
Even with our tuition fees, the school recently cannot afford many expenses.
So just now the board has decided that we'll merge with another school.
Eh?
Who will we merge with?
That I still don't know.
Well, I'm in a hurry. Bye.
Just because there's few students, the management goes bonkers.
Municipal schools are going to the dogs.
What does merging mean?
It means joining with another school.
We know that much.
She's asking how it's going to look like.
I'm not really sure myself either.
When we merge, there will be no more Fujimi Academy, right?
Th-That's ridiculous.
I can't imagine the school to
disappear. There's no way it'll happen.
But the academy will certainly change.
Ah?
Professor!
– Professor!
Is it true? The whole merging thing.
Yep.
Professor, which school are we merging with?
That's not decided yet.
Does it mean Fujimi Academy will be no more?
That… that's still…
If that school has a volleyball club too,
what will happen to ours?
The exact form of the merge…
…is still undecided yet.
Just when we've united, more troubles.
I wonder what happens now.
Beats me.
Ah.
Whatever it is, let it happen already.
I mean both the school and our club.
Ah.
Ah!
Wow.
These girls…
You. You're Fujimi Academy's volleyball club?
Correct. What about it?
Hahahaha.
I presume you're from Hamaki Middle School.
You're in a volleyball club too, no?
"You're in a volleyball club too, no?"
…she says.
Hahahaha.
Gee, this is good.
My.
Don't you know us?
I can't blame you.
You dropped out the first in the tournament.
Yeah.
It makes you the best losers, no?
Hold it.
Whoa, what now?
You're not going to beg us for a match now, are you.
Hahahaha.
– Hold on—
– Let her be, Kakko.
Actually, Hamaki…
…was placed second in the tournament.
Ayuhara-san.
It's Katsuragi-san.
What's the deal with these girls?
Nothing particular.
Do you know these girls?
No.
It's those four.
They advanced from an
unknown school to the finals…
…and quickly gained fame as Hamaki volleyball club's "Big Four".
Eh?
"Big Four"?
So they're the Hamaki's Big Four…
I've heard rumors about them.
Their attack duo is famed to be excellent.
Ah.
When we don't know what will happen to our school…
I don't feel like practicing much.
We shouldn't take breaks from the practice.
Right, captain?
Captain!
Trouble!
What is it?
They decided who will be merging with.
It's the Hamaki Middle School.
Hamaki?
That's right.
Hamaki is coming to us.
What about the club?
The Big Four comes to us too.
Yeah.
Heave-ho.
All right, good.
Hey, you're late.
Sorry, sorry.
Hey, Katsuragi-san's not coming to practice today.
She has a preparatory meeting before the graduation ceremony.
Graduation, huh…
It'll be lonely without Katsuragi-san.
In exchange, we'll have Hamaki's Big Four join us.
It'll get tough.
Ah, also, professor Hongou…
…since it seemed that the teachers meeting will prolong…
…he told us to start by ourselves.
All right then, let's begin.
Let's go at it with full power.
We can't lose to Hamaki's Big Four.
Yeah. We won't lose.
Not to these girls.
Fight.
One more!
Th-The Big Four?
Captain.
They're here.
Ah.
So-so, I guess.
Equipment looks new too.
You've got a better gym that I expected.
We should be able to practice here.
I want to try it out already.
Yeah. I doubt this place has seen much action anyway.
Hey, they're the Hamaki's Big Four?
If we practice here, the gym might become amazing too.
Yeah.
All right.
Kyouko.
Hold on.
I'm Fujimi Academy volleyball club's captain, Ayuhara Kozue.
We've met before, but…
…let's have a proper introduction.
I'm Hamaki's captain. Izumi Yuri.
Kudou Keiko-chan.
Ozawa Yukie.
Katori Yoshiko.
Some people apparently call
us The Big Four of Hamaki.
Hahahaha.
We came to see if we could practice here.
Since we're merging, we're in the same club, right.
Let's work together.
Well…
I'm not really sure if we'll be able to work together.
What do you mean?
Our volleyball is intense.
Yeah. There you have it.
I doubt you'll keep up.
Wh-What?
Say it again!
Naka.
We'll practice in our own way.
If you keep up with us, good.
Hmph. After merging with us, you're part
of Fujimi's volleyball club, aren't you.
You should obey captain Ayuhara-san.
That's impossible.
After all, the difference in our skills is too vast.
Are you picking a fight?
Hold on.
Everyone's crazy.
Wait, wait.
Stop it already.
I can't graduate with a
peace of
mind in such a mess.
Doesn't merging mean we get to be friends with each other?
I'm a third year student, Katsuragi Imi. What is going on?
We didn't intend to pick a fight with you guys.
It's true that we become a
single club after the merge.
We'll do our best as the club's members.
But we can do volleyball in our own way only.
Eh?
– In our…
– …own way only?
– Let's head back.
– Bye.
Katsuragi-san, I apologize.
I'm surprised.
You were looking daggers so much.
It's going to be difficult, all right. But I urge you.
Please make a good club with them.
That way I'll graduate with no regrets.
Please.
35th graduation ceremony of Fujimi Academy Middle School
Congratulations.
Thank you very much, sir.
Katsuragi-san, congratulations.
Thanks.
Protect the club's tradition with everyone.
Please.
Make a great, strong team.
The club's safe in my hands.
Katsuragi-san will probably join Fujimi high school volleyball club.
I'll join it next year too.
Me too.
We need to do our best.
We need to do our best…
What's that?
It's our girls university's club.
Whoa, awesome.
Amazing training.
Their team once won the All-Japan tournament.
– Wanna try?
– Yeah.
Right at you, sweetie.
Got it.
You've got what it takes, sweeties.
Fujimi Academy, right?
Yes.
I'm Ayuhara Kozue of the volleyball club.
I'm Hayakawa Midori.
I'm their captain, Oohara Mari.
Great.
You both have very good qualities.
Wanna play with us for a while?
Ah.
– Please treat us well.
We're ready.
All right, I won't hold back.
Trouble.
Spring break started this morning. What are your plans?
Hmm.
I still haven't decided anything.
Won't you be going home, to Tōkyō?
I guess.
Ah, got an idea.
Let's talk to Oohara-san and practice with them.
With university girls?
Will she let us?
We'll have to ask—
Captain!
Captain, trouble. Serious trouble with the club!
Why are you flustered?
"Serious trouble"… Ofuku, you always make fuss over most mundane things.
What are you saying?
If this isn't serious, I don't know what is.
They occupied the gym.
They're practicing now.
The Hamaki's Big Four…
– Eh?
Since Hamaki came here, they said they can't use the city gym anymore.
And now that the other gym is under renovation…
…they got nowhere to practice.
That's why they went to us…
But their practice is awful.
They act as if they owned the place.
What about Kakko and Naka?
They promised not to fight until Katsuragi-san graduates.
Until now they were patient.
But there's no telling what they do now. Let's hurry.
Ah, captain.
Look at that.
Our court…
Come at me.
The Big Four, my foot.
How arrogant!
Hold on, Naka.
Izumi-san, let's practice together.
We're still in the middle of the training.
Just wait there for a bit.
This is everyone's court.
It's okay if we all do it, right?
Eh.
You're getting in our way.
You just don't get it.
If we practice with you, you'll only hinder us.
Wow.
If you're free, go fetch a ball or something.
That's fitting for you.
Yeah, yeah.
You're all good girls after all.
Hahahaha.
Ah, Midori-san.
Now you did it.
If you wanna fight, we'll fight.
Damn. How shameless.
Midori-san, what did you do…
Do you want to stay silent when they make fun of us?
I don't intend to.
So you do want to fight us.
All right. It can't be helped.
No.
We'll settle it with this ball.
Heh, how interesting.
We'll finally figure who's stronger, no buts.
Let's do a four players match.
Do you know how it works?
Don't look down on us!
It's a system often used for training by Russian teams.
We know that much, okay!?
Very well.
Let's start.
Though it's not very challenging if it is you who challenge us.
We'll win with these arrogant missies.
You girls.
I'll be your referee.
Professor Kajioka.
I'm Hamaki volleyball club's coach, Kajioka. Nice to meet you.
After the merge, looks like I'll take care of you too.
Eh?
But we have professor Hongou.
I led Hamaki's team to the championship finals.
It's only natural that I become your coach as well.
When was that decided?
Eh?
– Ah, professor!
– Professor!
I'm Hongou.
Ah. I'm Kajioka.
Err… it wasn't decided, but that's not to say it couldn't happen.
Good that I called him over, right?
I filled him with the details.
You're holding a game, no? Good luck.
Now that you said it, I want to see the
strength of professor Hongou's team.
But… about refereeing…
Is it all right if I do it?
Go ahead.
Professor, how many years have you been coaching volleyball?
Well, I started only recently.
Is that so? I've been coaching for five years already.
How spiteful.
Well then, decide the serve.
– Rock, paper.
We'll serve first.
Begin the match.
Do your best!
Show them!
Here I go.
Yeah!
Leave it to me.
Don't mind, don't mind!
Sorry.
I haven't seen such a curve ball before.
Let's keep this pace.
Pull yourself together.
It comes!
Midori!
Nice going, nice going. We'll end it in to time.
Captain!
Ow.
Don't strain yourself, now.
How cute.
They're on a different level.
We might lose.
Ayuhara.
Good luck.
You know how to work until the end.
Me and you girls started it together.
Fight with all you have.
Do your best!
Ayuhara.
I'll do it.
Captain.
Don't sweat it.
Yeah.
Come on, come on, come on.
Get it together.
Too weak!
Let's win and get the gym already.
What's wrong?
Good.
– Hey!
– Nice.
Ow, it hurts.
Let's get the serve back.
Chance, chance, chance!
One more point and it's over.
No good.
Do you understand our power now?
It's coming!
Captain!
How is it? No more complaints, I hope?
I guess we won't be seeing you in the finals.
Too easy.
We lost.
Complete defeat.
But we can start again.
Move on to the next goal, acquire new strength.
Ayuhara.
I will be coaching you.
Now then, the match's over.
You did well.
We can start a new club here, right?
Let's do our best.
How vexing.
It's vexing, but…
We lost through and through.
Ayuhara-san.
We lost it…
For our power to be so different…
I won't step back.
I'll surely show them.
Oh, are you going so soon?
Yes.
The spring break has just started.
But you don't take no for an answer.
– Take care.
– Yes, auntie.
If you need anything, call me.
Be safe.
It's first time I go to a training camp.
On top of it, it's an university training camp. It must be tough.
How annoying.
I won't lose to The Big Four.
I'll attain new power without fail.
Now that I got a special
permission from the captain Oohara…
I'll give it a go.
How far can I go?
I'll find out.
Ahem.
Is this seat free?
Go ahead.
Hey, Midori-san!
I am going too.
To the university training camp, that is.
How did you know?
It's easy.
You had that "what should I do" look.
I called captain Oohara-san, too.
She told me about your request.
Then your aunt disclosed the departure time.
Midori-san.
Ayuhara-san, let's fight together.
No matter how tough it'll be.
Yep.
We'll fight.
I'll show them how to play.
While Izumi Yuri's curve ball technique remains a secret…
…Kozue-Midori attack duo participates in Fujimi all-girls university volleyball training camp.
Captain Oohara, seeing through their goal right away…
…doesn't go easy, even though they're middle schoolers.
About to collapse, they get reprimanded by Oohara.
But they endure the training desperately.
Finally, they start seeing through the curve ball.
Please look forward
to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.