苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 008—
The secret behind "falling leaf"
We'll be there soon.
Fujimi All-girls University Volleyball Club Training Camp
What a splendid mansion.
Excuse us.
I wonder if they're out.
Ah, there they are.
You're right.
Good morning, Oohara-san.
Thanks for your permission.
Thank you very much.
Welcome.
You really came here.
Yep.
Our training camp is very strict.
We won't hold back even if you're mid schoolers.
Got it?
Please look after us.
I'm glad we came here.
When we're like this, I feel like on a school field trip.
Well, I'm sure it'll get tough tomorrow.
Bring it on.
Come on, wake up, wake up.
How long do you want to sleep?
Eh?
Oh, it's still six o'clock.
What are you saying.
We're readying for the morning training already.
Eh?
This early?
I feel weak in mornings.
Pull it together.
We'll leave you behind.
Come on.
Amazing.
The university training's truly something else.
Now.
You two, step out.
– Yes.
– Yes ma'am.
– We'll practice together from today. Got it?
I won't show any mercy.
Yes ma'am.
Do your best, girls.
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Keep at it!
Keep it up.
Ah.
Get it together.
What's wrong?
Bring the ball back!
Yes ma'am.
Come on.
Don't space out.
Ah.
Come on, stand up.
Keep at it, keep at it!
There's more!
Ah!
Come on!
More, more!
I won't lose here!
Get a grip, Mako.
Ahn.
Come on, win already.
Ah, she's strong!
The little one's has it together!
I'm losing…
Come on, come on!
Ahh, I lost.
Amazing, Ayuhara-san. It's your fourth victory.
All right, I'll be your opponent now.
Oh?
Oohara-san.
Ah, I don't think I can go on.
– But if we go with left hands—
– Huh, so you have a strong left hand?
Yep. I'm pretty confident about it.
Well then, let's try it out.
Do your best.
Save our honor.
This is interesting.
Ayuhara-san.
Be strong.
Captain, you too.
Ready? Here I go.
Be my guest.
Good luck, little girl.
Captain, go for it.
Ah, I lost. Oohara-san, you're amazing.
Right back at you!
With a left hand this strong, you can become an excellent ambidextrous attacker.
Ambidextrous attacker…
Ah.
Amazing attack.
Just as I thought.
Once she perfects it, I'm not sure if we'd be able to protect against it ourselves.
Who would've think.
Aren't attackers that can use both hands very rare?
But that's not enough.
I still don't think we can win with Izumi-san.
That's right.
The problem is how to receive that curve ball.
We have five more days.
What to do?
So that's how it was.
Oohara-san.
I figured there had to be a reason as to why you wanted to participate in our camp.
Ah, that's not it… err…
That's not all what we came here for.
She's right. We also wanted to improve our focus.
Don't push yourselves.
There's nothing shameful in training to win.
Yes ma'am.
We've heard somewhat about that "Big Four" ourselves. Are they really this amazing?
Yes.
Captain Izumi-san's serve is particularly good.
Her serve?
Yep.
It falls before eyes like a stone.
It's a really remarkable curve ball.
Falls before the eyes…
Come with me for a bit.
Now then.
Try to receive my serve.
– Yes ma'am.
Here I go!
Oh…
That's it!
That's her curve ball.
Figures.
This serve…
We call it "falling leaf".
"Falling leaf"…
Yes.
But Izumi-san is a remarkable person if she can use this curve ball.
But don't you worry, sweeties.
With your skill and a little practice, you'll learn how to serve it in no time.
Wanna try?
Yes ma'am.
But rather than learning how to serve it, we'd prefer to learn how to receive it.
She's right.
Please tell us how to receive it.
– Please.
I refuse.
All right, hurry up and collect your bags.
Come on.
Oohara-san, please wait.
We're begging you.
Please teach us how to receive that curve ball.
No matter the difficulty, we'll endure. Please tell us!
No.
Why is it?
Aren't you two missing something?
Don't you know the proverb, "the attack is the best defense"?
No matter how good you are at
receiving, it won't win you a game.
In volleyball…
The best way to win is to use your opponent's techniques against themselves.
Everyone is shocked when they see their enemy able to use their techniques.
Got it?
In the court, the serve…
…is the prime weapon. Don't you forget that.
As expected, an experienced captain is something else.
Now that you get it, it's serving practice.
Yes ma'am.
All right!
Uhm…
What is it?
What kind of strike should I go with?
You should discover it by yourself.
Eh?
But… for us, that kind of curve ball…
What are you saying!
Think you'll learn it just by having it described to you?
Then same goes to school exams, no?
You really need to put in an effort.
Focus on the basics.
I'll give you one hint.
The secret behind this curve ball…
…is in the way the hand hits the ball.
The way the hand hits the ball?
What is the way?
All right! Let's see you try it!
Yes ma'am!
That's not it.
It doesn't sway one bit.
The wrist. Use your wrist.
Yes ma'am.
All right, switch with Hayakawa-san.
That's no good, you two.
You won't win with Izumi-san this way.
Do it more seriously.
Yes ma'am.
Well then, try 100 serves now.
Got it?
– Yes.
We won't lose.
If we can't do this, there's no
way we'll win with the Big Four.
Ah!
Ah… ah.
How is it? If you're frustrated, win with me.
I'll do it.
I'll win with you!
Ah!
Raise and shine.
Ah…
It's no use.
No matter how I try…
Ah!
Huh?
The ball didn't rotate and it sank.
Until now, I thought the proper rotation was crucial for it to fall early…
…but I haven't tried giving it no rotation.
That must be it.
Midori-san, let's try once more.
Can you receive?
Very well.
Ah!
You did it, Ayuhara-san!
Let's try it once more.
All right?
Ah.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Midori-san, let's rest for a while.
No. You're getting the hang of
it. You can't lose your focus now.
Let's continue.
Thank you, Midori-san.
Ah.
Ayuhara-san!
Midori-san!
You did it.
You did it!
Yep…
We did it.
Finally!
Ayuhara-san.
– Hooray!
– We did it! We did it!
– Ah… I'm crying…
– Why are you crying?
Ayuhara-san, you truly are an amazing person.
Midori-san, you'll figure it out soon too.
You did well.
What's left is the power.
The key to make the falling leaf the most effective is the proper speed.
With that, it'll be perfect.
You really did well.
Good girls!
Fujimi Academy
Hoo?
Then professor Hongou, are you saying you want to be the volleyball club's coach no matter what.
That is correct.
As of now, the club…
…is like cats and dogs.
They don't work together at all.
I noticed that much myself.
What is it then?
Are you saying it is my responsibility?
No, professor Kajioka.
I think you're biased in your treatment of Fujimi's and Hamaki's students.
– No matter what—
– Please wait.
It's a misunderstanding, professor Hongou.
For me to be biased…
Misunderstanding? If that is the case, fine.
But at any rate, the club's in pieces right now.
Until they've reunited, even if we make it to the spring All-Japan Tournament…
…there is really no hope for winning.
Oh?
So if you become a coach, you'll lead them to a victory?
Yes. I want to try it.
What if you fail?
Of course, I'll take responsibility for that too.
Responsibility?
Ah, professor Kajioka.
Why don't we…
…leave it to the young and ambitious professor Hongou?
Very well.
Let's see how far he can get.
Well then, excuse me.
Will it be all right, professor Hongou?
After all, professor Kajioka, having raised the
famed Hamaki's Big Four, is a powerful person.
Of course, I understand that part very well.
But the teamwork is the most important.
If Ayuhara and Hayakawa make up with the Big Four, they'll be invincible.
Hmm… the problem is how they get there.
Indeed.
That is exactly the problem.
Ayuhara.
Hayakawa.
I have big hopes for you.
The school starts in three days.
After that, it's your turn.
I'm counting on you.
苦しくたって
Even though it hurts…
Kurushikutatte
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると、胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
涙も、汗も、若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
Oohara-san, thank you very much.
I thought you'd drop out quickly.
You both worked hard until the very end.
If you keep up this attitude, you won't lose to anyone.
Work hard.
Yes ma'am.
But had we more time, I'd have a chance to learn much more.
Too bad.
Nah, it's okay.
There's nothing practical I can teach you anymore.
Well then, take care.
Yes.
You too. Please stay safe.
Thank you very much.
Bye-bye! Till next time!
Just look at us.
Tomorrow the school starts. We'll shine in the court.
Ayuhara family
I'm home.
Huh?
Kozue-chan.
Papa! Mama!
Hey. Welcome home.
Welcome home.
Don't be surprised, Kozue.
From today on, me and your mom will live with you here in Fujimigahama.
Wah, is it true?
It's true.
Papa's company transferred him here this time.
Wah, I'm so happy! We'll be together forever from now on, right?
Looks like we can't win to the actual dad and mom.
Fujimi Academy
Year 3 class 4
With that, the class representatives will be Ichinose Tsutomu-kun and Ayuhara Kozue-san.
Nice! Congrats!
Congratulations, Ayuhara-san.
Give me a break. I'm not fit for this position.
Don't be like that.
We've all earnestly elected you after all.
– That's right.
– Yeah.
Troubles again, chief!
What's wrong, Kashiwagi-san?
It's the Big Four…
What about the Big Four?
They've completely occupied the gym.
We can't use it anymore. What do we do, chief?
– Midori-san, let's go.
– Sure.
Hey, hold on.
Professor Hongou.
It's official. I've been chosen as the club's coach.
– We'll continue as before.
– Eh?
But I want to make one thing clear.
I didn't became the coach to
exclude the Hamaki's bunch.
I understand.
I see. Very well then.
The new club needs new teamwork.
To realize it, I want you to make
up and unite with the Big Four.
I understand that well, professor.
But to call a truce, there's something we must do first.
Something you must do? I see.
Don't just sit there.
Why don't you fetch us that ball?
Eh?
How rude.
You can do that yourself, no?
What was that?
Don't you know that fetching balls is a substitutes' work?
We're substitutes?
Who decided that?
Professor Kajioka.
He declared all members from Fujimi to be our substitutes.
Do you understand?
The coach's orders are absolute.
Do you really think so?
Sorry to disappoint you, but our coach is now professor Hongou.
– Eh? That's ridiculous.
– What about professor Kajioka?
He's said to be track and field club's coach now.
How about you all join track and field club too?
– Hahaha.
– Izumi-san.
Don't worry.
No matter the coach, what really matters is the skill.
Ah, th-th-that's right.
In the end you're all worth to be just substitutes.
Don't get ahead of yourselves.
To become regulars, you need to defeat us first.
But it's impossible for you.
You can't receive a single Izumi-san's serve.
Oh, is that so?
Midori-san.
Finally, it is our turn.
Yep.
Your turn? What do you mean?
We want to repay for the last time.
Do you really think you can win with us?
We won't know unless we try.
Are you serious?
It's time to test the results of the training at university volleyball camp.
Falling leaf.
It's time to see what impact a falling leaf can make.
Since the Hamaki merge, there's been a conflict between the attack duo and the Big Four.
But now that professor Hongou is the
coach, the conflict only deepens further.
Izumi puts up a particular opposition, surprising the other club members.
Professor Hongou acknowledges that skill is crucial…
…and thus the girls hold a match to prove whose skill is greater.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.