苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 011—
Tears sparkling in sunrise
Coffee Shop "Alice"
Thank you very much.
Ah.
It's okay.
They did come after all.
She brought the girls from Tōkai's volleyball club.
What does the former member of
the
Hamaki's Big Four want from us?
Please tell us.
What is this "talk important to our club" about?
Actually…
I want you to win the tomorrow's district qualifiers—
What are you saying?
Are you serious?
Yes.
That's awful.
I won't forgive her.
Did you know?
I quit the volleyball club.
We heard about this.
I wondered why you quit the club myself.
You too?
Yeah.
To be honest, I didn't really want to quit.
But when we merged with Fujimi Academy, their team saw us as a hindrance.
They conspired to drive me, a captain, out.
Cruel, don't you think?
It felt terrible.
Just remembering it is painful.
I ended up in tears.
Hmm.
You have my sympathy.
What happened next?
The originators were Ayuhara
Kozue and Hayakawa
Midori.
These two want to keep Fujimi
Academy's volleyball club to themselves.
What a thing to say!
Shh!
Be quiet.
If this concerned only me, I'd endure it in peace.
But… but…!
I can't allow such people to be elected in the district qualifiers and proceed to the All-Japan Tournament.
You're right.
Trying to seize the club for oneself is unforgivable.
That's…
That's why I'd like you to win the tomorrow's match.
To ensure it…
…I will tell you the Fujimi's strategy and members' weak points.
These six are their regulars.
By all means, you need to mark both Ayuhara and Hayakawa.
Katori's aim is precise.
But she's weak with side attacks.
Her right side is particularly bad.
Moving on to Kudou.
How low!
No matter how much she wants to see us fail,
betraying her friends is unthinkable.
What do we do?
Do we stop them?
Nah.
Rather than taking them on now, we
should focus on the tomorrow's match.
Yeah.
We won't lose.
Tōkai district middle school volleyball championship
City Gym
Ah, how frustrating.
Good going!
Do your best!
Fujimi · Tōkai
Yet another captain Ayuhara Kozue's splendid spike hits the court.
Having advanced to the All-Japan's final district qualifying match…
…Fujimi Academy continues to attack fiercely.
Good!
Today's Fujimi's performance cannot be compared to yesterday's match with Sone.
What are you doing?
Yay!
Fujimi · Tōkai
Good luck.
Good going, Ayuhara-kun!
Keep it up!
Do your best!
What's going on?
The strategy was changed.
It's almost as if they figured out my plan.
At any rate, Ayuhara Kozue sure is strong.
That's why I hate you so much.
Looks like shuffling the squad has paid off.
At this rate we've already won.
The opponent has trained for All-Japan games too.
Don't let your guard down.
What happened?
That's not what she promised to us.
They went with different players. The strategy's wrong too.
We have been tricked.
I thought it was strange.
No one would betray their school.
It's painful, but we're fools for having believed her.
It's too late.
Just one point left.
Let's try until end.
We can't do much else.
Let's go.
– Let's do this!
– Good luck!
Whoa!
Maria!
Ah!
Midori!
Fujimi · Tōkai
Yay!
Yahoo!
We won, we won!
I'm glad.
– Professor!
All of you! You did well.
With today's victory, we became our district's representatives.
This doesn't mean you can take it easy now.
One week until the All-Japan Tournament.
The participants will be the best schools in the whole country.
The truly difficult games are yet ahead.
Don't forget that.
– Got it?
– Yes.
– Yeah.
– Yes sir.
– Congratulations!
You did well.
I'm glad!
Congrats!
You made it to the All-Japan Tournament.
Weren't you together with Izumi-san?
Eh? Err…
I wonder where she went to.
I think I saw her come here.
There's no way she'd come, no?
Eh? What do you mean?
You see, Izumi-san thinks we should lose.
It can't be. Izumi-kun is not like that.
Izumi-kun is—
Enough.
Tsutomu-san, I don't want to listen to it.
We had a chance to see her true colors yesterday.
Right, Kozue-san?
Yeah.
Girls…
What in the world are we doing here?
Please be patient.
We want to show you something, Tsutomu-san.
She's here!
She's here.
Oh?
Izumi-kun!
We'll show you what kind of
person Izumi-san is really like.
Huh?
Izumi-san.
Ah?
Izumi-san. Did you see our match today?
You wanted us to lose and here we are, having won by a landslide. Disappointed, hm?
Huh?
Hmph.
Don't make me laugh.
Do you really want to boast to me this badly?
You even came to ambush me in such a place.
That must be it.
But anyway…
Even if you won, what of it?
If you think the tournament will be as
easy as today, you're terribly mistaken.
Is that so?
Do you want to see us lose so much?
Whether you win or lose doesn't concern me.
I'm not in your club anymore. Remember?
Don't play dumb!
Ah, what do you mean?
How long will you drag this farce?
This is absurd.
Who did you spy for and for how long?
Spy?
Don't make weird accusations.
Izumi-san. We went to the same coffee shop yesterday as you.
We saw you meet girls from the Tōkai's volleyball club.
Eh?
You told them the Fujimi Academy team's strategy and the members' weaknesses.
What the hell are you doing?
Uh.
Izumi-kun!
What they just said is true!?
How about you say something?
Izumi-san, did you forget our time together in the volleyball club?
And it's not just about us.
What if your friends, what if Kudou-san, Katori-san heard us now?
How much effort did every one of us put into that club?
You know it very well.
Aren't you ashamed of your actions?
Did losing to us hurt you so much?
Then why… why don't we settle it through volleyball?
Why don't we work together? Why don't we play volleyball together and form a strong team?
Izumi-kun.
Why did you do such thing?
Leave me alone.
Even though I quit, I didn't want to!
But I went through it anyway.
Tsutomu-san, you know it the best.
I understand that part.
But this doesn't mean it justifies what you did.
You don't understand me.
Izumi-kun.
Izumi-kun!
No one understands me.
Tsutomu-san.
What did she mean?
Did something happen to Izumi-san?
Izumi-kun didn't quit because she has lost to you.
Well, the shock from it surely played some part.
But the main reason is that she couldn't bend her wrist.
Eh?
The wrist?
My hand.
It hurts…!
So she must've hurt it around that time when she hit the ball.
Nah, it was aching from time to time even before that.
The doctor said she put too
much stress on her wrist.
Ah. That's how it was.
I heard the doctor ordered her to
take a break from volleyball.
But instead, Izumi-kun…
Ah… it hurts.
Yuri.
Are you playing again?
You shouldn't do this.
The doctor has said it too.
He ordered you to take a break from volleyball for half a year.
Stop it.
I am returning to the club as their captain.
This means I must get stronger than anyone else.
A break is the least what I need now.
Can't you endure it for half a year?
– Stop it!
– Oh!
Ah.
Give the ball back!
Ahh!
Yuri!
Are you okay?
Leave me alone.
You understand nothing about volleyball.
This time we're constructing a dam.
It's near the mountains so
I won't be home for a while.
Don't make your mom worry too much when I'm out.
You'll give up that volleyball thing, no?
I won't.
What?
It healed already. See?
Yuri.
Do you still not get it?
The doctor told you to stop, no?
Okay?
Got it?
I realized who has asked the
doctor for such a diagnosis.
It's a certain someone who hates me.
What are you saying?
That's right.
This woman hates me.
That's why she tries to make me part with volleyball.
How dare you speak like that to your mom?
What?
This woman isn't my mom!
My mom…
…was nicer and had a gentle heart!
Yuri!
Wait!
Your right hand's…
Dear!
She fights with her current mom so much.
She sees her to be inferior to the biological mother, who has passed away.
She won't settle for taking a six months long break.
Plus she fights with her mom.
When I talked with her…
I didn't really know what to tell her.
Come on, stop crying.
If people saw us, they'd jump to conclusions.
I don't care.
I just can't take it any more.
Don't feel down.
Stay calm, okay, Izumi-kun?
Okay?
Izumi-kun.
Hey, Izumi-kun.
I misjudged you back then.
Hey, let's talk to her again.
Yeah.
Yuri.
Please.
What? What do you want?
I don't feel like going to school.
That's it. Leave me be.
I can't let you quit the school and go to Tōkyō.
I won't forgive it.
Hey, Yuri.
Please, listen to what I'm saying.
No!
I won't listen to you.
You'd be better off if I wasn't here, wouldn't you?
– I know that—
– Yuri!
You don't care what happens to me after all.
Yuri!
Yuri.
She was jealous of you, who could play volleyball.
That's why she did it all and betrayed you
– she wanted you to feel the pain too.
Izumi family
Ma'am!
Ma'am.
Ah, Ichinose-san.
What happened?
I…
…argued with Yuri…
…and all of the sudden, she fled home.
We'll look for her.
I'm counting on you.
Okay.
Ma'am.
I should have told her clearly.
But I just couldn't.
What do you mean, ma'am?
Izumi-san.
We heard it from Tsutomu-kun.
We had no idea about your wrist condition.
Why didn't you tell us?
What's the point?
I don't want your sympathy.
We don't intend to be sympathetic.
Your wrist is no good. You quit the volleyball club and it can't be helped. Am I right?
Ayuhara-san.
That's why you entered the track and field club.
Then why don't you try your earnest in your new club?
Why can't you do that?
Ah, I see.
In the volleyball club, you had your Big Four fame.
But in the new club you'd start from scratch.
You were anxious whether you could repeat this success.
This is why you had no motivation.
That's not it!
When I found out I couldn't play volleyball, I
wanted to give the track and field club my all.
But I couldn't forget about volleyball.
But you chose the track and field club.
You were confident you could run well, no?
However, when you joined, it turned out to be more demanding than you thought.
So your motivation dropped.
What a bummer.
Ayuhara-san!
What is the matter?
You're pretty rude!
But I'm right, am I not?
Your way of thinking is naive.
If you go further, I won't keep silent.
What are you going to do?
How about we compete right now?
I wonder if you can win, though.
My time for 100 meters is 13 seconds.
Are you scared?
I won't lose.
I won't lose to the likes of you.
Let's do this.
Okay.
Then…
The first to circle that tree and returns, wins.
It's right about 100 meters.
Midori-san, please give us a signal.
Very well.
On your marks.
I wonder if Ayuhara-san plans to lose on purpose to help Izumi-san regain her confidence?
I won't lose.
I will surely win.
Get set!
I won't lose.
I won't lose!
I can't lose!
I won't lose…!
I won't lose…
Ah!
Winner is Ayuhara-san.
I should have known losing on
purpose isn't Ayuhara-san's style.
Looks like I won.
No matter how hard…
No matter how harsh…
Doing something with all your might feels great.
It's the sensation of sportsmanship.
People using traps aren't entitled to it.
Even though your mom cares about you, you
don't understand her feelings and fight her.
You fight with your mom.
You don't get sportsmanship.
A person like you has no business with either volleyball or track and field club.
Let's go.
Ayuhara-san!
I…
…will keep running.
I won't quit!
Izumi-kun.
It's about your wrist.
You suffer from arterial occlusion.
If you continue volleyball,
your wrist will give out completely.
Eh!?
Eh?
What do you mean?
You can't do volleyball ever again.
The doctor has made himself clear.
But your mom couldn't tell it to you.
Instead, she softened it and told you to stop for half a year.
She planned to talk you out of it
somehow during that period.
Izumi-kun.
Mom.
Mom!
If you don't hit the ball hard, it's okay.
I should have told you the truth from the start.
But I was unable to tell you to give up volleyball forever.
Mom!
Yuri.
I…
…will try.
I'll do my best in the track and field club.
I'll put in the same strength I put into volleyball.
The first match in All-Japan Tournament draws near.
"You have what it takes to win."
— professor Hongou encourages the girls.
The Fujimi Academy team goes to Tōkyō.
The nostalgic Tōkyō.
Kozue visits the Meihō Academy.
In the Meihō's gym, she meets powerful peers from Fukuoka Middle School in the middle of practice.
One of them knows a receive technique way above middle schoolers level.
Kozue's confidence quickly collapses.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.