苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 012—
An ominous enemy
Let's go with attack!
OK!
Fight!
Hey, Ikezaki-san!
What's with that practice?
I see no power at all.
Is this how an All-Japan Tournament contestant trains?
You can't rest just because you got elected.
When you lose, it doesn't matter if you're placed second or last.
Some people say that mere participation is plenty.
I disagree with that.
Sports are all about winning.
Saying that you've participated is just to avoid regret after losing.
I won't tolerate taking it easy.
Understood?
– Yes sir!
Well then, tomorrow we're going to Tokyo.
Let's hold a final drill.
Got it?
– Yes!
– Yes sir!
Here I go!
Go!
More, more!
– Look out!
– Yes sir!
What's that!
Take this!
What's with your receiving?
Looks like we've got no business with Tokyo!
The ball's too fast and too far away.
Don't whine!
We need to defend a 9x9
m² court with just 6 people.
No matter what, you need to be able to receive a ball at 3 meters by yourself.
Asking for 3 meters is unreasonable.
Yeah.
We can't be this precise.
Then how do you want to defend?
In the court…
…if you're unable to accept the ball wherever it flies, you're useless as a player.
Tell the school if you're dissatisfied with what I say.
There's no point in dragging you to Tokyo.
How will it be?
I'll do it!
I'll do it too.
And the rest?
We'll do it!
We'll do it!!
Very well. Let's start over.
Got it?
Here I go!
What's that!
Ahh!
Ah!
Ow.
Take this!
Ah…
Good.
Let's wrap it up.
Rest well today. We'll depart tomorrow.
I want to win no matter what.
Can we do it though?
Don't worry.
You already have the power it takes to win.
I guarantee it.
Eh?
Eh? We can do it.
We can win!
That's right.
All that's left is to use 100%
of that power during the game.
Do you understand, girls?
All right. Dismissed.
Can you believe it? Professor Hongou said victory's within our reach.
Ayuhara-san, looks like our skill didn't go unrecognized.
Yep.
He's counting on us. We cannot let him down.
It's for the best.
They absolutely need to believe in themselves.
Ah.
Ayuhara-san!
Ah, Izumi-san.
Tokyo at last, huh?
Do your best.
Sure.
I'll do my best for your sake.
Izumi-san.
Ayuhara-san.
Thank you.
Thanks to you, I gained my motivation to start over in the track and field club.
I'll work hard.
– Now that sounds like Izumi-san.
– I'm happy for you.
In return, show us a great victory.
That's the plan.
But we don't know how strong the All-Japan Tournament participants will be.
It'll be okay.
You can totally win with your present form.
We'll do our best.
Ah, my shoes!
Ah, you still were here, professor?
Y-Yeah. What's the matter, Ayuhara?
I forgot my shoes.
Ayuhara.
Yes?
Sir? What is it?
Are you going to use these shoes in the tournament?
Yes sir.
Hm.
And the rest?
I heard they'll wear new shoes.
Is it bad if I show up in such old shoes in the matches?
Nah.
If you prefer going out in worn-in shoes, it's all right. Are you worried?
Yes…
Everyone seems to have confidence…
…but when it comes to close combat, you're the most reliable, Ayuhara.
Both players and the coach leave the last point to the captain.
That's volleyball.
Remember:
I'm always just outside the court.
All right.
Go home and sleep.
We can't have you oversleep.
Yes sir.
P-Professor, can we really win?
You can.
Or rather, you must win.
You're not unlike those old shoes.
And that ball.
If you put forth effort, you can certainly win.
When you laugh, the ball laughs.
When you cry, the ball cries.
Do you understand, Ayuhara?
You can't win by buying new shoes alone.
It's all about the ball. About this ball!
Professor…
Yeah.
Rest well tonight.
Yes sir.
Fujimigahama station
Good luck, Fujimi!
Easy victory
Ayuhara-san's late. I wonder what's up?
I hope nothing happened.
We're screwed if she doesn't make it on time.
Ah!
She's here!
You're right.
– Ayuhara-san!
– You're late, captain!
Ah, I'm glad I made it on time.
We're sorry. She overslept.
Very well.
Now everyone's here.
Thank goodness.
Well then, professor Hongou, I leave it to you.
Sir.
I'll do my best.
I'll come and cheer for you this Sunday.
Be sure to stay in until the finals.
Thank you. We'll try our best.
Captain Ayuhara.
We're counting on you.
We'll hold a huge celebration party.
Yes sir.
Midori.
Give us splendid victories.
Of course.
Kozue.
Papa's busy with work and won't be able to come. But I'll surely watch you on TV.
– Okay.
– Stay out of trouble.
Yes, I will.
Do your best!
– Show what Fujimi Academy is made of!
– Good luck!
Bye bye!
We'll do our best!
Ayuhara-san!
Ah, Izumi-san.
I barely made it.
Please take this.
Ah.
What's this?
It's a present from me.
Open it when you get to Tokyo.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
I'm happy.
All right, good luck to you all.
Yeah. To you too.
Stay safe!
Bye bye!
We'll be in Tokyo in 2 hours.
My heart is racing.
Wah!
As expected, cars are everywhere.
Look at all those buildings!
Girls, make sure not to get lost while you look around.
Ayuhara-san, you was still here in Tokyo a year ago, weren't you?
Yeah. It feels nostalgic.
It feels like it was 10 years ago.
Hotel "Yamato"
All right then. Listen, girls.
We're not here on a school trip, so show self-restraint.
If you overeat and lose your form before an important match…
…we would extremely embarrass ourselves. Keep that in mind.
Got it?
Yes sir.
Good. The next four hours are leisure time.
The curfew is at six.
Don't be late.
Yay!
– What do we do?
– Let's go shopping in Ginza.
– Hey, why don't we go see Ginza too?
– Sounds good.
Professor, I want to visit Meihou Academy.
Oh.
That's your old school, right?
All right.
They're one of the favorites in the championships…
Ah, whatever. Go ahead.
Thanks.
Ah!
Watch out!
Wow.
Amazing!
I can't believe she did it.
Meihou Academy
How nostalgic.
These trees.
These flowers. This smell.
I remember it all.
How pretty.
Ayuhara-san.
You did come here after all.
Eh?
Isn't it Yoshimura-san!
We've been waiting for you.
We knew you'd return some day.
My.
We heard about you.
You're the enthusiastic captain of Fujimi Academy.
It's been a long time,
why don't we go see the others?
Yeah…
But today is—
It's okay! Let's go to the court.
Let's do this properly. Got it?
Hey, girls! It's Ayuhara-san!
Whoa.
We missed you.
She looks more fit, don't you think?
Totally. She seems to have gained weight too.
Is that so? I wonder how much.
You're scouting us out already?
Eh?
Right on the mark.
What are you talking about?
Wow, you know nothing, don't you?
Ayuhara-san's here as a member of Fujimi
Academy, the Toukai's representative.
Eh?
So she'll show up in the tournament tomorrow?
That's right.
I'm afraid we'll have to fight each other soon.
Oh, really?
I thought you were here on a school trip.
Too bad, but that's not the case.
It can't be helped.
I'd rather avoid having to face a famous attacker like you.
Ah, what are you saying?
Same goes for you. Aren't you the tournament's number one favorite?
I'm not sure about this anymore.
Why?
We've met an unexpectedly formidable enemy.
Eh?
A formidable enemy?
Yeah.
I guess there's no harm in warning you.
They're in the middle of practice in our gym.
Don't just stand there!
Take this, damn it!
You rascal!
What's with your posture!
Got it!
Hey!
What's that!
You fool! What are you doing!
They're great, don't you think?
They're Fukuoka Middle School from Kyuushuu. We lend our court to them.
Ah! Revolving receive!
Hey, it's her.
That was it.
She must have used this receive back then.
Huh? You know her?
Nope, I only saw her briefly before.
She's amazing, don't you think?
She's Fukuoka's captain, Kakinouchi Yoshiko.
Fukuoka, huh…
Indeed, that's one heck of an enemy.
Hmm.
Fukuoka Middle School, huh.
Yes.
That revolving receive is way beyond middle schooler level.
Combined with their spike and quick attack…
…I don't think we'll be able to stand our ground.
I see.
What do we do, professor?
Should we find a court somewhere and hold a practice?
Nah, wait.
It's no use to practice at this point.
More importantly, Ayuhara.
Don't tell anyone about Fukuoka.
Eh?
Well then. Don't worry. We'll win.
We can't lose our spirit before the match.
Someone had to find out about Fukuoka at some point. I'm glad it was Ayuhara.
What's with you girls!
What?
What are you saying?
Haven't you started it?
Yeah. We were only walking down the corridor.
What are you saying?
You shoved my shoulder.
We're Kyuushuu's representatives, Fukuoka Middle School.
How about you introduce yourselves too.
– Hey—
– Ahh! We'll introduce ourselves all right!
We're Toukai's representatives, Fujimi Academy.
Ah, if it isn't the debuting team.
– Hahaha!
– What was that?
Say it again!
I can't stand it anymore!
– Get over here!
– What—
– Stop it!
– Ayuhara-san!
We can't fight here, girls.
Let's head back.
But they were so rude to us.
You were the ones who were rude!
Both of you! Knock it off!
Ah! Captain.
What are you doing, fighting before the match?
How stupid.
Go back to your rooms.
All right.
Hmph.
What a yapping bunch.
Please forgive them. I'm Fukuoka's captain, Kakinouchi Yoshiko.
I know.
Eh?
Actually, this is the third time we meet.
Third time?
Yes.
The first time was when you saved the girl at the crossing.
The second time was when you practiced in Meihou's court.
Ah.
I'm Ayuhara Kozue of Fujimi Academy.
Ayuhara-san.
It's you!
Eh?
Do you know my name?
Of course I do.
You're that ambidextrous attacker.
My.
We'll probably meet in the tournament anyway.
Don't be too hard on us then.
I'd like to ask you the same.
As expected from Kakinouchi-san.
She has it together.
She properly knew Ayuhara-san's name.
Yeah.
Our captain is famous already.
That's not it.
I'm pretty sure Kakinouchi-san researched our debuting team.
Ah.
Ah, now that I think of it, they seemed to know us Fujimi.
Hmph.
The braids girl did call us the debuting team.
My.
So they know us all?
We're in trouble if they do.
We've cheerfully entered the contest without doing any research on the other teams.
What about professor Hongou?
Looks like professor Hongou didn't research them deeply either.
After all, he didn't know about Fukuoka.
"Know your enemy, know yourself
and you shall not fear a hundred battles."
My grandpa used to say it.
I guess he was right.
Yeah.
Oh no!
It seems I've undermined their confidence.
This is probably what professor Hongou feared.
It'll be okay!
In the end, the skill is the most important.
Had we been weak, all information
in the world wouldn't help us win. Right?
Exactly. Exactly!
Professor Hongou surely wants us to win without external aid.
We need to believe…
Looks like you caught on, Midori-san.
Thanks.
By the way, Ayuhara-san, what did you get from Izumi-san?
Eh?
Ah, I've forgotten about it.
I wonder where I put it.
Ah.
Found it.
This is it.
I wonder what she put inside.
Oh. It's a memo.
What's written inside?
Ah!
All-Japan Tournament participants memo
My.
It's a participating teams memo.
Winning candidate teams
The favorites are Meihou, Fukuoka and Okuyama.
Whoa, our Fujimi's after them.
I wonder when she did collect this data?
She must have wanted to enter the tournament back in Hamaki.
That's probably when she started it.
I see.
There was no telling when it could prove useful.
She gave it to us when she no longer needed it…
Thank you, Izumi-san.
We'll work hard for your sake.
She wrote the member names too.
Wow.
Yoshimura-san's the best in Meihou Academy.
Figures.
As expected, Fukuoka has Kakinouchi.
Hurry, show us what's next.
Players' strong and weak points
Yoshimura Satomi. Expert at serving.
Be cautious when receiving her serves.
However, she's poor at receiving.
Therefore, Meihou has a strong offensive, but a fragile defensive.
I can vouch for it.
Back when I still was there, it held true.
Arai Kazuyo, Naniwa Middle School.
Expert at feinting.
Be cautious of her blocks.
However, offensive is poor.
Team focuses on defense.
They're like Meihou's opposite.
Kakinouchi Yoshiko, Fukuoka Middle School.
Her specialty is revolving receive.
"Revolving receive", it reads!
Huh? Really?
I wonder if it's true.
This revolving receive is an
university-level technique.
Beware her line-grazing hits and intense spike.
What are their team's weak points?
This team is proficient with both offensive and defensive…
Weak points: none!
Wow.
Aren't they way better than Meihou then?
What do we do?
We need to tell professor Hongou at once!
Yeah. Let's show him this memo. Come on, girls.
Let's go.
– Go!
– There's no need to.
– Professor!
– Professor Hongou!
Professor Hongou.
I already heard about Fukuoka from Ayuhara.
Then, what's our strategy?
None.
Eh!?
So you really want us to win without any help?
Yep.
It will look better this way.
But I think it might be a gamble after all.
Ah.
Professor!
This is not the time to tell jokes!
She's right.
Izumi-san put so much effort into it. We should respect that.
Professor, please hurry and read it.
This is it.
Ah!
Whoa!
It's unneeded.
We don't need such thing.
Professor!
What are you saying?
Professor, you're just too cruel.
Yeah. I'm shocked.
All of Izumi-san's effort went down the toilet.
Forgive me, Izumi.
I appreciate your good will.
But that good will clashes with my plans.
All that information…
Don't you pick it up!
Eh?
If you can win with intel alone…
…you don't need a coach!
I will think of something.
You're disappointing me!
Stay put and leave it to me!
Got it?
That's awful!
He's taking it way too far!
Ah, all those precious notes.
How could he do it?
Even I don't know what he's thinking.
But it should be okay if we just follow him.
If we do, the road will surely open.
We can't waver now.
Izumi-san, just watch us.
Your good will certainly won't go to waste.
We'll definitely bring you a splendid victory.
What's the deal with Kakinouchi of Fukuoka Middle School?
Kozue wants to research Fukuoka's style,
but coach Hongou doesn't let her.
Finally, the semifinals.
Fujimi Academy keeps winning with the "falling leaf".
The next game is the prestigious Meihou Academy versus Fukuoka Middle School.
But Hongou, rather than taking the girls to
see the match, makes them listen to music.
Meanwhile the match is unfolding with Meihou girls wanting to look away.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.