苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 014—
The deciding serve
All right. The real match begins now.
Do your thing. That is all. Go!
– Yes sir!
The second set begins.
Each team assumed positions.
The Kantou's representative, Meihou Academy, due to captain Yoshimura's and four players'…
…worsening state from the match with Fukuoka, will abstain from the third place play-off.
Eh?
Therefore the third place goes by walkover to the Hokkaidou's representative, Sapporo.
Yoshimura-san's state worsened?
What did they mean?
Hey, Kakinouchi-san. What happened to Yoshimura-san? You know it, right?
I don't know.
But the announcer just said Yoshimura-san's condition has worsened.
What happened there?
I dunno.
The announcer said they're in a bad shape.
But I don't think it's anything serious.
That can't be said about their mental state though.
They went crazy on their own.
It's not our fault.
Kakinouchi-san!
You better watch yourselves too.
Wh-What was that?
See, you're losing it already.
The second set begins.
Each team assumed positions.
Good luck, Fujimi Academy!
Ayuhara-kun! Do your best!
Oh? Are they calling for time?
They are! They are calling a timeout!
What do you think it means, Yamaguchi-san?
They called a timeout without even a single serve.
I'm not really sure.
You don't see it very often.
You certainly don't.
While it is true that they haven't called a timeout even once in the first set…
…I have no clue as to what their coach is thinking.
Ayuhara.
You know why I called a timeout, don't you?
I don't, sir.
You've already lost to Fukuoka without putting up a fight.
Eh?
I can't let you go into the second set like this.
That's why I called a timeout.
Close your eyes, girls.
Eh? Why?
Just do it.
Come on, try it.
Remember the record we listened to earlier.
Come on.
Hear the shouts in the hall change into the brilliant dynamics of the orchestra.
This should be okay.
All right, go win the second set.
Go, girls!
– Yes sir.
Well then, the time is up and the second set resumes.
Do your best.
We're counting on you!
There!
Fujimi ・ Fukuoka
Good luck!
Do your best!
Fujimi ・ Fukuoka
12 to 10!
Fujimi Academy gained a lead by two points.
– Good going!
– Keep at it!
Good luck!
My pace, my pace!
Let's go for it!
Yeah!
Now Fukuoka calls a timeout as well.
It's only natural.
It's because Fujimi Academy finally broke out of their slump.
By calling a timeout, Fukuoka disrupts the opponent's enthusiasm and streak.
It's a very normal tactic.
What's with you? Where's the pace from the first set?
Don't forget our tactics.
You'll recover these two points in no time.
– Roger!
– Aye!
Well, sooner or later, they had to ask for a breather.
Use this time to rest yourselves.
Got it, girls?
– Yes sir.
– Yes.
The match resumes.
It's Fujimi Academy's serve.
Here I go!
Fight!
Don't get so cocky!
Oh?
So that's where it came from?
S-So dazzling. I can't see anything.
Out!
Don't mind!
Don't mind, don't mind!
Don't sweat it.
It's okay.
Thanks.
Let's get them.
A block-out! Fujimi Academy shows a great receive!
Nice receive, Katori-san.
Really?
Fujimi ・ Fukuoka
What the heck!
Good going, Fujimi!
The second set goes to Fujimi Academy.
Since Fukuoka won the first set…
…the set score is now 1:1.
It's 1:1!
Well then, Yamaguchi-san.
The third set will be the final battle that decides the outcome.
What are your expectations?
I don't have a favorite at all.
I'd say it has become a battle of willpower.
Katori.
Sir.
Your excellent receive spiced the team up. You did well.
That's the spirit!
But professor, I kind of hit it without thinking.
I don't even remember how it happened.
It's okay.
That's good!
Your judgment is the most important.
If you didn't even think, it says all the more about your skill.
Yes sir.
Listen well, girls.
Katori says she doesn't remember how she did it. But this is it!
Every one of you does their volleyball.
You need to feel it!
Don't think about strategies or the enemy!
– Got it?
– Yes. – Yes sir.
If you realize your mind goes astray, close your eyes.
But professor, if we close our eyes, we won't see the ball.
It doesn't matter.
Eh?
By now you should be able to tell the ball's location with your noses.
Haven't you practiced enough to do so?
Am I right?
By the way, the world's best team came to watch your match.
Eh?
Th-The world's best?
It's a school from the Soviet Union.
They came to Japan for a guest match.
See?
They're at the stands behind you.
Huh?
They're the Soviet Union?
They came to Japan to play with a high school team.
Their uniforms look better than ours, don't you think?
The All-Japan middle school girls volleyball championship reaches its decisive stage.
The third set is about to start.
Will the title of Japan's best go to Fukuoka Middle School from Kyūshū?
Or will it go to the Toukai's representative, Fujimi Academy?
Fujimi ・ Fukuoka
No good.
She received an out.
I can do the revolving receive as well!
Ozawa-san!
Ozawa-san.
Hang in there. Are you okay?
Come on.
My back hurts.
Professor, I'm sorry.
Hey, Fukuda.
Quick, take her to the infirmary.
Yes sir.
Ikezaki. You replace her.
Roger!
Fukuoka ・ Fujimi
Do your best!
Fujimi! Good luck!
Fukuoka ・ Fujimi
Both teams are drenched with sweat.
The battle is becoming of a
decisive championship game.
Fukuoka ・ Fujimi
Finally it's a match point in the third set for Fukuoka.
Is Fukuoka going to win?
Or will Fujimi still make a come back?
Things got interesting.
Keep it together!
Hey, hey hey hey!
Did it go in? Or was it an out? We await the decision.
A strong spike from Kakinouchi.
What will it be? Safe? Out?
O-Out!
It's an out!
Too bad.
Unfortunately it went behind the line.
Had it go in, we'd be celebrating Fukuoka's victory now.
Truly regrettable!
They won't forget it quick.
What a lucky turn of events for Fujimi.
Fukuoka ・ Fujimi
But the score still remains 15 to 14.
It's the match point for Fukuoka who leads by one point, but…
…but the right to serve goes to the Fujimi's player, Katori.
They can't let their guard down yet, do they, Yamaguchi-san.
It became a breathtaking game in the truest sense of the word.
What lies ahead of us is a competition of the willpower.
We have a very exciting final to see.
Get a grip!
It was a true life saver.
Yep.
Looks like the fortune smiled on us.
It's our chance.
Katori is about to deliver a serve.
Oyoshi!
It'll be okay!
Show them your best!
All right!
Ayuhara-san!
Wah!
Hooray!
Fukuoka ・ Fujimi
It's a tie. We got a tie!
Fujimi Academy captain's, Ayuhara Kozue's feint strategy has landed them a point.
It was an excellent play.
It was well thought out. You don't see it often at middle school level.
Great! It's our comeback!
Nakazawa.
Sir?
Pinch serve. Change with Katori.
Understood.
Oh. Fujimi Academy is changing their server.
Yamaguchi-san, why do you think they did it?
Well, it's like this.
It's probably because of Katori's small stature.
Just to be safe, he chose Nakazawa as a pinch server.
But I'd say it's a very risky move.
Naka, we're counting on you!
Be strong!
– It's our chance!
– Yeah!
We're betting our victory on this serve.
Naka can get scary when she's serious, you know!
Here goes nothing.
All right!
Yay!
Fukuoka ・ Fujimi
It's 15 to 16! What an excellent service.
Yamaguchi-san, looks like the decision to change the servers was right after all.
Indeed. At any rate it was a truly great serve.
Well then, this time it's a match point for Fujimi.
Fukuoka finds itself in a deep pinch.
Ah, timeout!
The coach got up and called a timeout.
Fukuoka's in a deep pinch.
Well, Yamaguchi-san.
It was a tough game so far. How will Fukuoka manage to get out of this pinch now?
They're in a real bind now.
We've come this far, we can't lose it now.
Ayuhara.
We came this far without a strategy.
Thanks to that, the opponent couldn't read us.
They're confused now.
Yeah.
But now it's just one serve.
We need to bet everything on that serve.
We're betting everything we've done so far on that point.
You understand, right?
Yes sir.
All right, girls. It's the last point.
Yep.
Just one point.
That's it.
Hey.
Ayuhara-san, what is it?
Ah, Ayuhara-san!
Ayuhara-san.
Hey, Midori.
Can you toss a ball here?
I need it to be a little high and very precise. Okay?
Eh?
Okay, I'll try…
What's up?
Listen, girls.
Make sure Midori can precisely aim at this spot.
Please.
Okay.
What was that?
What's on your mind?
I just thought of something. Be ready.
Let's do our best!
Yeah!
We leave it to you, Naka!
Take it easy!
Good luck!
Stay focused.
Will the next serve become the serve that settles it all?
Or…?
Ah.
Please, win us the match.
Here I go!
Here!
It's coming!
Whoa!
Now's our chance!
Got it!
Go for it!
Nice!
Attack!
Leave it to me!
Ah…
We did it!
We won!
– Midori!
– Ayuhara-san!
We did it!
We really won!
Congratulations!
Girls!
You did well!
Congratulations!
Fujimi Academy seizes the victory.
What a surprising turn of events!
To all our listeners…!
Please listen to this great, inspiring cheer!
Fujimi Academy, having debuted in this championships…
…has defeated all teams one after another.
Finally, they became the Japan's number one team.
The loud cheering for Fujimi Academy continues on.
I'm glad.
Kozue-san.
Midori-san.
Okei.
Oyoshi…
They did it, they really did it.
– What do you think, Yamaguchi-san?
– Excuse me.
Just like you said, it was an amazing match.
But I am surprised.
How should I put it, err…
was it a win out of desperation?
Was it a win without a plan?
Ah, looks like I can't express it very well…
Professor!
– Professor.
Yeah. Yeah!
You… you did well!
Ayuhara.
I saw your last serve clearly.
Right.
What was your plan about?
Yeah, we want to know it too.
Please tell us.
Hey, hey.
What is it, girls?
You don't understand your own captain's serves?
That's right.
She only asked for a precise toss.
You see, it was like this…
It's so vexing!
We were so close.
How could she just use that window and hit it exactly under that sunbeam?
Also how could she hit it so fast?
What an amazing technique.
Fujimi Academy's Ayuhara Kozue.
I will never forget you.
Fujimi
Fujimi Academy's banner is raised on the central pole.
Let's be happy for Fujimi Academy.
There are tears.
The tears are flowing.
Let's not forget the opponents.
You fought well, Fukuoka Middle School.
More tears.
But those are not tears of regret. Those are tears of pure feeling.
Pennant reception ceremony.
Fujimi Academy Middle School…
…captain Ayuhara Kozue.
The championship title…
…goes to Fujimi Academy Middle School…
…a girls volleyball team.
The committee hands in the victory pennant.
It was a battle of 32 teams.
All-Japan Middle School Girls Volleyball Tournament ends.
Victory
The winner is the first-time participant, Fujimi Academy.
This victory was possible thanks to the attack duo's activity.
But it's safe to say that the most contributing factor was captain Ayuhara Kozue's hard work.
You did well, Fujimi Academy.
The applause lavishly continues on.
Having won in the All-Japan championships, the volleyball club's popularity explodes.
The girls want autographs and the boys want to become friends.
Kozue becomes the school's queen.
But for some reason, Tsutomu starts to give her a cold shoulder.
Kozue decides it's a prejudice coming from someone who has never done sports.
With many freshmen, the volleyball club becomes the biggest club.
Because of this, the gymnastics club has to give up the gym.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.