苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 016—
High life
Fujimi ・ Fukuoka
Good luck, Ayuhara-kun!
Fujimi Academy captain's, Ayuhara Kozue's feint strategy has landed them a point.
Here!
Whoa!
Now's our chance!
Leave it to me!
Got it!
Attack!
Fujimi Academy seizes the victory.
What a surprising turn of events!
To all our listeners: please listen to this great, inspiring cheer!
Fujimi Academy's banner is raised on the central pole.
Let's be happy for Fujimi Academy.
There are tears. The tears are flowing.
Let's not forget the opponents.
You fought well, Fukuoka Middle School.
More tears.
Those are not tears of regret. Those are tears of pure feeling.
If the goal in sports…
If the volleyball's goal…
…is just to win…
…I've already accomplished that goal.
Then why do I feel so depressed? Why am I sad?
Album
Hey.
Ah, dad.
What is it, Kozue?
You're back already? You're sooner than usual.
Yeah.
You seem down.
What's wrong?
It's nothing.
Hey, mom.
We have a guest.
– Good morning.
Welcome.
I'll go call Kozue.
Kozue.
It's Tsutomu-san.
Really?
He's with a girl called Nozawa-san.
Never mind then.
Kozue.
Tell them I'm not here. I don't want to see them.
Don't say it so loudly.
Let them hear it.
They should respect what I say.
If I say I'm not here, it means I'm not.
Nozawa-kun. We should probably retreat.
I agree. Shame, though.
I wanted to continue our conversation from back then.
Kozue, it's not like you.
What's with your attitude?
Well, they…
If you want to be arrogant, don't drag your mom into it.
It's bad to use others as couriers for your excuses.
My.
Kozu—
She's acting weird. They were getting along so well.
You know, that Tsutomu-san's friend, Nozawa-san…
…is a looker and seems to be bright too.
Eh?
Ah.
I see. So that's how it is.
Shh.
Even without the table tennis club…
…Takahashi continues to do what he loves the most.
Isn't that a true sportsmanship?
I think it's the essence of the sports.
That's not it.
That's not it!
Doing it just because you like it is just a play.
Sports isn't just that.
I can't say it well, but there's something more.
It's something bigger, something more steep and wonderful than just a play.
Come on, come on, come on!
What's that, what's that!
Don't lose it!
Come on!
Shoot!
Ugh. I lost.
Next is the head ball practice. Don't slack!
Captain, give us a break.
At least five minutes.
What are you saying, you idiot?
Wanna embarrass us before the volleyball club?
We need to give our practices our best.
But you?
Crocks tired from just this much should take a lesson from the volleyball club.
Volleyball club's room
Whoa.
What are you doing, girls?
It's time for our practice.
Hey, Kozue-san. Come here for a bit.
Don't be silly. We need to go to the practice.
Come on, just a second.
What are you doing, anyway?
A public poll.
A public poll?
Fufu.
It's to decide who's the most popular in the school.
How silly.
Chief, don't you want to know Tsutomu-kun's position?
As if.
But you sure are a little curious?
Nope. It's stupid.
It's stupid all right, but who's at the top?
Ha, she's hooked. I knew it.
I'll announce it.
According to the computer statistics…
…Ichinose Tsutomu-kun seems to be our favorite for this year.
However, badum-badum-badum, the black horse is Mitamura-kun.
Mitamura-kun, huh?
Yep. The captain of the soccer club.
He's so cool.
Especially his pose when he does his long pass.
Ah, him. Yeah, I guess.
– I'm not surprised the girls chose Mitamura-kun.
– Yeah, I guess so.
Professor!
Professor, hello!
Professor, good morning.
That was awful.
What's this?
Practice was supposed to begin long ago.
S-Sir.
You're late and you call yourself a captain?
I'm sorry.
You've grown soft.
What's with you?
Don't be full of yourselves just because you won.
Yes sir.
Professor, don't be like that.
Nobody's full of herself here.
That's right. We practiced properly like you expected us to.
If you feel you need to control us so much, why did you go to Tokyo?
You don't know why I traveled to Tokyo?
Not really.
Heheh.
You see…
…I found you a new opponent.
– Wah! I've waited for this.
– I was itching for a match.
Practicing only gets quickly boring.
Right on.
But who will we be playing against?
A high school, right?
High school?
Heheh. What gave you this idea?
We're the Japan's number one middle school after all.
Middle schoolers stand no chance with us.
I see.
Too bad. You'll be playing against a middle school.
Talk about disappointment.
Our victory is already decided then…
Professor, tell us, which school are we playing against?
It doesn't matter.
All you need to do is to do your best.
Anyway, there's something I want to ask you myself.
What are you playing volleyball for?
Ayuhara.
You first.
I don't know, professor.
I've been thinking about it for a long time, now.
Isn't it obvious?
It's to win.
I think that it is winning that gives meaning to sports.
So if you lose, there's no meaning to your play?
Really?
Yes sir.
Then you're saying you'll of
course win the next match.
– Yes, of course.
– Isn't that obvious?
Very well.
I guess I can say your opponents' name now.
What if…
What if…!
That's a match with girls middle school team…
…from the Soviet Union, the volleyball country.
Huh?
Awesome.
Just as I thought.
Girls.
Look.
The world's best team watches your game.
That's their captain, Shellenina.
I thought it'd be hard on you, so I kept silent.
Do you believe in yourselves?
Of course.
I think we can win.
We'll defeat the Soviet Union.
Yeah. We'll bring us a victory.
We'll become the best in the world.
Nonsense!
There's no way a team who doesn't even know why it plays volleyball can win.
Whatever.
Until you find your reason, I won't coach you.
Ayuhara, I leave it to you.
Professor!
Why did he get so angry?
Did we say something wrong?
He's just in a bad mood probably.
He kept babbling about winning and now he's saying victories are insignificant.
Yeah.
Ah! I got it!
Eh?
What is it, Midori?
It's his tactic.
By saying that we'll lose,
he wants to boost our ambition.
Ha, I see.
If it wasn't for this, we could take the match too lightly.
So we give it our best and win with the Soviet Union.
So that's his strategy.
It's a trick as old as the world itself, but whatever.
Let's get along with it and become the best team in the world.
– Let's do this!
– I agree!
We'll win without fail.
I don't think that's how it is.
I think professor Hongou was serious about no longer coaching us.
But if I tell them, I'd just lower their morale.
Then there's that question.
"What are you playing volleyball for?"
Why, indeed?
Why am I playing volleyball?
Why…
Library
Volleyball
Ow.
Hey, watch it.
I'm sorry.
Ah, it's you? It's okay then.
Oh?
You're Ayuhara-san of the volleyball club, huh?
Y-Yes.
I wanted to talk to you some day.
You see, I'm…
Hehe. Mitamura-san of the soccer club, right?
Nice to meet you.
Oh? Why do you know my name?
You're pretty famous, you know.
Huh? Me, famous?
Never mind. Let's focus on you.
I wanted to talk to you about volleyball.
Ah, same goes for me. I wanted to ask you some questions about soccer.
Heh, I see.
All right. Let's go outside then.
It's better than books anyway.
Yep.
Ah, Kozue-kun.
I wanted to talk to you.
Get in the line.
Let's go.
Mitamura-kun, huh?
Whoa, what's with that lolling.
And you call yourself a girl?
Well, I'm popular with boys.
Does it make me a girl?
Did you make up with Tsutomu-kun?
Why would I?
I'm not talking to that sports illiterate.
You're still upset.
Huh, it's 3:00 PM already.
Ah, it's this late?
What's up?
It's the match with the Soviet Union.
Looks like your boyfriend is still volleyball.
Shellenina's spike got in.
It's Soviet Union's serve.
How will it be?
Block!
Nope!
They can't receive it at all!
As expected from the world's best team, the Soviet Union.
Our Japanese boys' high school cannot keep up with that spike at all.
Beautiful play.
Even a high school cannot keep up with them.
Even a high school…
Come on, come on, come on!
Keep it!
Pull it together, Ayuhara-kun.
You can't know the outcome until it's over.
Wimps that from the start are afraid of losing…
…are destined to fall.
Ayuhara-kun, the gam—
Keep your eyes on the ball, you idiot!
Even if the chance to win is just one percent…
…or 0.1%, you will win.
I think this kind of willpower is what gives the sports meaning.
Heh, I'm preaching to the choir here.
That's not the case.
Thank you.
As expected from Mitamura-san.
Heh, knock it off.
When I'm complimented, I
get serious pretty quickly.
Look out!
Eh?
Ow!
Y-Y-You idiot! Watch it!
We're going to win.
We'll show everyone a splendid victory.
Yes. That's the spirit.
We have to believe in ourselves.
To keep our honor as the Japan's best team, we must show a magnificent victory.
To accomplish this…
…you guessed it. Practice! Got it?
Okay!
– Leave it to us.
– Midori, let's go.
Okay!
– One more!
– Roger!
Keep it up.
Finally it's Ayuhara-san we know.
Good. Provided that we stay focused, we will win.
Yeah. We can do this.
I feel like it more and more.
We have to win.
I want to answer Tsutomu-kun and professor Hongou without a shadow of a doubt as well.
Ayuhara-san, the principal asks for you.
The principal?
Principal's room
Do you need anything from me, sir?
Nah. How's the practice going?
Sir. Everyone puts their heart into it.
Hm.
But before you hold the match with the Soviet Union…
…you'd probably want extra 30 minutes or even an extra hour of practice, wouldn't you?
Yes, of course.
But we don't want to trouble other clubs too much.
This is why I called you here.
I talked to Ooyama-san, a
member of the city council.
He said it's the first time our city's team is the best in the Japan.
We feel obliged to support you as much as possible.
Thinking of the future, what do you think about building a gym just for you girls?
Eh?
Are you serious, sir?
Whoa, whoa.
After we've reviewed our budget, it certainly seems to be doable.
Whoa! Awesome!
Hehe. It's too early to celebrate though, we haven't reached a final decision.
When will it be decided?
Let's decide it on the next club presidents' meeting.
Th-Thank you, sir.
Wah!
Long live volleyball club!
Now we're sure to win.
Let's keep this momentum and crush the Soviet team.
– Yeah!
– All right!
Wait. It's still not official yet.
It might as well be.
The principal is on our side. It gives us a
free pass in the club presidents' meeting.
Right?
Hey!
Girls, listen!
– Trouble!
– What is it, Naka?
Check this out.
It's our newspaper.
What about it?
Let me see.
"Our academy's volleyball club…
…has become very arrogant these days."
Arrogant…!
What the heck?
Whoa.
That's not true.
"Furthermore, it seems that most of the sports section's budget will go to the volleyball club.
Is this a good thing, we wonder?"
How impudent.
Who the heck wrote this?
Wait a second!
Wow.
Chief!
Ayuhara-san!
"The volleyball club exists for the school, not the other way around."
Whoa.
Where is Tsutomu-kun?
Do you need anything from Ichinose-san?
Tsutomu-kun is the one who wrote this, right?
It wasn't just Ichinose-san.
I coauthored it.
Eh?
I should've known.
Let me ask you then: who exactly has become arrogant?
Of course everyone in your club, including yourself.
What the heck?
For example, consider the plans to build a gym dedicated to your club.
But that's something our principal has proposed.
Adults have their statistics to meet.
Even a person such as yourself knows it.
But you've grown conceited ever since you become the Japan's number one team.
You should know yourself how pretentious this idea is.
But we won the championships.
I don't see anything wrong with such an offer.
See? Here you have your arrogance.
But…
This is a feeling shared by any person that does sports.
It's not like I aimed to become popular since the start.
Our fame has just happened to come along the way.
The meeting is tomorrow.
If I were in your shoes…
…I'd tell the principal to withdraw from building the new gym.
Huh.
You're bright people.
You're our Fujimi Academy's honor students.
But all you can do is to write your newspaper, not knowing a thing about true sports.
You think you're so smart.
Hmph!
Ichinose, you bastard!
You idiot!
Ah, Mitamura-san.
If you're a man, fight!
I hate wimps like you.
Stand up.
You wuss.
You write your stupid articles without knowing the first thing about sports.
You bastard!
Stop it! Knock it off, Mitamura-san.
Leave us.
I'm teaching him a lesson about his newspaper on behalf of the sports section.
I-I told you to stop!
Shut up.
It's not a girl's business.
Ichinose.
Do you have no shame, you coward?
Why don't you fight back?
I'm not a coward.
What was that?
Hit me all you want.
I won't budge.
As a sports section's representative, you use your fists.
As a newspaper club member, I fight with my pen.
You silver-tongued devil.
Knock it off!
Move aside.
I'm not going anywhere.
It's not a girl's—
…business, right?
I'm the one who the article was about. It is my damn business.
Don't you think?
If you have to hit someone, hit me.
Wait, what?
I want to hit Tsutomu-san myself.
But he'll just write even worse things about me if I do so.
Isn't the tomorrow's meeting that matters the most?
Mitamura-san, please.
Let's stop this.
When you put it this way, I have no choice but to withdraw.
Ichinose.
What?
Let's settle this tomorrow.
Good call, Mitamura.
Let's settle this at the meeting.
Very well.
All right. See you soon.
Meeting room
Today we'll discuss the construction of a gym dedicated to the volleyball club.
Today's topic: construction of a new gym
I want to hear everyone's opinion on this.
What do you think?
I agree.
I completely agree to the construction of a new gym for the volleyball club.
I think it's uncalled for.
What?
You don't have to be so loud. I can hear you well.
Volleyball club can practice outdoors.
I think it's all right if they use the gym only on rainy days.
Such a big budget should be put into other clubs.
Hm.
Ayuhara-kun, what is your opinion?
Sir.
In sports, the strong prevail.
To become strong, one needs to practice.
If we can secure a place to practice, we'll stop inconveniencing other clubs.
I think it is very efficient.
That's right.
The strong prevail.
She has the skills to pull it off.
Is it skill if they won just once?
What? If that wasn't skill then what was it?
Nothing lasts forever.
What was yesterday a breeze,
today might be a loss.
Then we just have to win more, right?
Exactly.
We will win.
We will show you a victory with the Soviet team.
Huh?
Win with Soviet Union?
Even if it's Ayuhara-san, they can't possibly do it.
Nope. We don't know that.
If she wins, you will have no choice but to acknowledge her power.
How's that, Ichinose?
If they win, they won't be first in Japan, they'll be first in the world.
But she sure is confident.
All right.
Let's postpone the decision until after the match with the Soviet Union.
Are you fine with it, Ayuhara-kun?
Yes, sir.
We have to win.
I will show our power to Tsutomu-kun and professor Hongou.
In order to do so, Shellenina-san…
…we will win with you.
Kozue aims to win with the Soviet Union at all costs.
The club members don't seem to be happy.
Without coach Hongou, they hold a desperate, fierce practice.
Kozue feels the greatest anxiety of them all.
But she doesn't let it show before the press.
Can they win with the Soviet Union?
Finally, the day of the game.
Kozue gains a lead by using the "falling leaf" technique…
…but the Soviet team doesn't seem to be worried.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.