苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 017—
Victory is not everything
Eh?
You wagered the construction of the new gym on winning with the Soviet Union?
So if we don't win with the Soviet Union, there's no gym?
Yep, that's right.
This is why we have to win with the Soviet Union no matter what.
Eh?
No matter what?
Precisely.
Let's win.
Why are you so quiet all of the sudden?
Where's the usual "Yeah! Let's do this!"?
Yeah. You all were so enthusiastic in front of professor Hongou earlier.
Or do you want to say you lost your confidence?
Hey, Kakko.
What about you?
Well, I am confident all right.
But…
But what?
But saying that we have to win no matter the costs is a little too much.
But I doubt prof. Hongou left us as a part of his strategy like Hayakawa-san said he did.
Hayakawa-san, do you really believe it?
You don't, right?
No way. Nope.
Our opponent is the Soviet Union that even our high schools can't win with.
No matter how confident we are, we're a
little worried without professor Hongou.
Yep.
That All-Japan tournament was a good example.
We stand no chance without professor Hongou.
We can't say for sure that we will win by ourselves.
No matter our confidence. Right?
Yep.
This is bad.
I feared it would come to this.
Girls, aren't you forgetting something?
Fujimi Academy's volleyball club is the best in Japan.
So what if they're the Soviet Union?
If our seniors can win with them, why can't we do the same?
As long as I believe in myself, I won't lose.
Or better put, I will win.
Yep. I think we can win too.
– Really?
– Yep.
I watched the last Soviet Union's game on the TV.
Because of it, I am sure we can win.
No. There's no way Fujimi Academy can do anything but win with the Soviet Union.
Let's do this, girls.
– Yep. – All right.
– Let's do this.
– Yeah, yeah.
– All right.
– Let's do our best.
– Right.
Let's practice the spike. Assume positions.
Okay!
– Here I go.
– OK.
All right!
Come on, come on, come on.
Whatcha doing?
Here I go!
Don't lose your focus!
Ah!
Pass!
Don't be such a klutz.
I won't lose.
Naka, we won't win with the Soviets like this.
We won't win with the Soviets like this…?
What if?
No, it can't be.
But what if we lost by any chance?
No.
No, but…
But…
Ah.
You lost to the Soviet Union after all?
You're hopeless.
– I thought you were confident you'll win?
– It's a goodbye to the new gym then.
You won a single championship and you got this conceited already.
You don't know your place.
You should just disband the club!
Disband! Disband!
Stop it.
Anything but disbanding it.
Please.
Disband.
Stop!
Disband!
What's wrong?
– Are you feeling unwell?
– It's nothing.
Come on, girls. Let's get at it.
Kozue.
Do you really think you can win with the Soviets?
If I lost, I couldn't face the others.
We'll win.
We will show you a victory with the Soviets.
I was sure of this back then when I said those words.
Even though I believe in us, one can't know the outcome until after the match.
But I went ahead and said that already.
That's right.
I've declared our win in front of everyone.
There's no going back.
Besides, the club members still believe my words.
At this point there's no option but to win.
We'll win for sure.
We'll triumph over Tsutomu-san and people who've underestimated our club.
But professor Hongou's resignation just before this important game was unfair.
There's no way I could answer on the spot as to why I'm playing volleyball.
The match that is right in front of our eyes is much more important than that.
And yet.
And yet…
If it only was one of his usual strategic tricks.
Ah.
If only that was the case.
No, it's no good.
I must stay strong.
A willpower to win is crucial.
With or without professor Hongou.
We will win.
We will win!
Japan Times
Don't fall asleep.
– Keep it together!
– Yeah, yeah, yeah.
The match with the Soviet Union takes place in two days. Do you feel confident?
Yes.
Eh? What do you mean by that?
Surely you don't mean you will win?
Precisely, I do.
I am confident we will win.
I'd like to remind you that even the Japanese high schools are no match for your opponents.
Even though Fujimi Academy's the best in Japan, they're the best in the world.
Of course, you're aware of that already, aren't you?
That is correct.
You don't say.
We'll show you a victory.
The anticipated Japan-Soviet match is tomorrow!
Check this out.
Wow, so cool.
But can they really win?
Of course they can.
Our school's heroine Kozue-san declared it so, so it will be this way.
I'm looking forward to this game.
We'd better reserve good seats.
Please get one for me too.
I'll cheer her on with all might.
She'll lead our school straight to a victory.
Wah, she's here, she's here.
– Ayuhara-san!
– Do your best!
– Good luck!
We'll be seeing your game!
Ayuhara-kun.
Yo.
Oh, Mitamura-san. Good morning.
Morning.
Ayuhara-kun. Do your best tomorrow.
I believe in you.
Thank you.
Yoohoo.
So cool!
You look sweet together.
Good going, Romeo and Juliet!
– Hahahaha.
– I'm so jealous.
– See you around.
– Bye.
Ah, Tsutomu-kun.
It wouldn't hurt for him to encourage me a bit.
Today is the final practice.
We'll hold a practice match.
Our opponent is the Soviet Union. Let's do this properly.
Got it?
Yeah!
Receive!
Good!
Ah, professor Hongou.
– Professor Hongou!
– Professor!
Girls.
I heard you promised to win with the Soviets.
That's correct.
Do you think you've got what it takes?
Eh?
Let me ask again.
Do you really think you can win with the Soviet Union's team?
I do.
– We do.
Very well.
Well then, I'll be seeing your game tomorrow.
Eh?
Don't forget that spirit.
Got it?
P-Professor, wait.
Listen, Ayuhara.
I'm leaving everything to you.
I'll be cheering for you from the seat.
Why is the teacher so cold towards us? Towards me?
That's unfair!
What is professor Hongou thinking?
We can win with or without him.
On the contrary, we might do better without him.
Yeah.
Let's continue the practice.
Yeah!
All right.
I'll bring us a victory even if it kills me.
Hongou-kun.
Sir.
I heard you're no longer coaching the girls. What gives?
It's not only the practice.
I don't intend to coach them in the tomorrow's game too.
As if.
You know, this is not funny.
The opponent is the Soviet Union. Soviet Union!
I am aware.
No, no, no. Looks like you're not.
This game isn't just some championship.
It's our chance to challenge the Soviet Union as a Japan's representative.
I understand this.
If you understand that much, then why?
It's for the sake of the girls.
W-What?
In order to let the girls grow bigger from now on…
…I'm willing to sacrifice this match.
T-Then, our school will lose…
…or win – we can't be sure until we see the game.
A coach cannot be this irresponsible.
I'd like you to take that back, sir.
I believe I made myself clear when I asked to become the coach.
I asked to let me run things my way.
H-Hmph.
I…
…love these girls.
I hold them dear.
And that is why…
…I'm doing this.
Finally we're here.
Now is the time to go all out.
What is it, girls?
Where's your spirit?
B-But they're so tall.
They have this varsity vibe around them too.
What are you saying?
We can't lose now.
We're the best team in Japan.
Yeah. We'll show everyone we're different from the other Japan teams.
The Soviet junior team, having annihilated all higher education teams in Japan…
…today for the first time plays against a Japanese middle school.
That middle school, the Fujimi Academy, won this year's spring All-Japan volleyball tournament.
Looks like both teams don't intend to take a single step back.
Ladies and gentlemen, will it be Japan or the Soviet Union who wins?
The game spans five sets.
At last, the game starts.
The first serve goes to Japan and will be served by captain Ayuhara Kozue.
– Ayuhara-san, good luck!
– Let's show them!
Ayuhara-san.
All right, here goes.
Let's start with the curve ball right off the bat. It'll crush their confidence.
О, нет!
Keep it up, Kozue-san.
Good going.
Let's get another.
Okay.
Amazing spike.
Let's get back at them.
Don't mind, don't mind!
Don't mind.
Got it!
We won't lose!
Good, Ayuhara! Keep it up!
I'm glad.
– Let's continue like this.
– Yeah.
As expected from captain Ayuhara.
She's better than the others thus far.
You're the Soviets' captain, Shellenina, no?
Don't be surprised by this much. I'm going to show you even more.
Receive!
Japan ・ USSR
Haha.
Awesome.
Cheer up, won't you?
I'm worried about how it goes from here.
The Soviets just let their guard down.
One set is nothing for them.
We might win the first set, but it'll reverse very soon.
Why are you so pessimistic, Hongou-kun?
How can you talk like this when you're their coach?
Who exactly are you rooting on?
Come on, look.
Japan ・ USSR
Contrary to the expectations, Japan wins the first set.
Hooray!
Yahoo!
We did it, we did it.
They understand our true power now, don't they?
We won the first set just like that.
It's like captain said, we can win this.
Oh?
What is it, Kozue-san?
Nah…
I'm just curious about something.
We're doing our best, so what's with that picture?
They're so calm as if this was just a practice match.
W-What? Aren't they just unwilling to accept defeat?
Yeah, yeah. The second set is ours.
Maybe then they will open their eyes.
Damn.
Rather than leading them, on the contrary, I'm saying weird things.
While they stay positive on the outside, I bet I made them uneasy.
The second set will be opened by Soviets' captain Shellenina.
Let's see how the game unfolds.
– Yoshiko!
– Yeah!
Excellent serve.
This is what gives "drive serve" its name.
– Don't sweat it.
– Sorry.
Good luck.
Let's stay strong.
Yeah!
It's about time for us to get serious.
Kozue-san!
Kozue-san.
Awesome spike.
Japan ・ USSR
W-What a fight.
I couldn't see it at all.
When they're so tall and strong…
…it's a miracle if we can hit it.
We need to do something.
We'll lose at this rate.
Don't take it personally, but we've already won.
The reason, captain Ayuhara…
…is because something's troubling you.
And you're too proud to admit it.
Of course you can't play well.
Professor.
What should I do?
Please, tell me.
H-H-Hongou, you need to do something about this.
Accept!
Higher!
Ayuhara-san, do your best!
Come on!
You can do this!
I won't say I knew this would happen.
I feel sorry for the girls.
However. However!
This is something they need to learn the hard way.
But still.
Ayuhara. Good luck!
Hayakawa, you too!
One point until Japan needs to admit defeat.
The match became completely one-sided.
It's the first time when I can watch Kozue's game.
Who'd think it'd end up like this.
I can't watch it anymore.
Let's go.
Finally, Japan's representative, Fujimi Academy collapses before the Soviet Union's team.
Soviet's junior team is stronger after all.
We completely lost.
We lost without using half of our tricks.
Ah.
Ah, my dream is over.
Ayuhara.
I hate to say it, but…
…but I've been waiting for this day.
For this situation.
Captain Ayuhara.
Eh?
The power your team has shown us in the All-Japan tournament…
…wasn't there today.
Yours especially.
Ayuhara, let's meet again.
Eh?
Good bye.
До свидания.
Shellenina wants to play again in the future, but…
But…
…no matter how you look at it, it's over.
– You said we'll win.
– You call yourself captain?
You were so full of yourself.
I was thinking about this all night long without sleep.
Professor, I've decided.
Please disband the volleyball club.
Say what?
It's hopeless.
Without the new gym, our club cannot go on.
Everything is over.
Ayuhara.
Y-You still don't get it, do you?
If that's all you're thinking, be
my guest and quit volleyball.
But the club isn't for you only.
If you quit, do it by yourself.
Understood?
Yes.
Cool down for a bit and think why you were playing volleyball thus far.
Do not come back until you figure it out.
Ayuhara.
When will you understand?
When?
When?!
This felt refreshing.
I assumed responsibility.
Who are you kidding?
You just ran away.
That's not it!
I assumed my responsibility as the captain.
With this, I bid my farewell to volleyball.
Hahahaha.
Do you really think you can quit volleyball?
I can quit.
"What are you playing volleyball for?"
That doesn't matter anymore.
Who cares.
The Soviet Team's coach unexpectedly approaches Kozue…
…and sends her to the pine grove, where Shellenina is waiting.
Shellenina speaks harshly to Kozue.
"I can't forgive you the yesterday's match."
"What is volleyball about?"
—she proclaims and declares she wants to show their last game in Japan.
The opponent is a high school boys' team.
Shellenina shows Kozue the match.
It unfolds to be a terrifying game.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.