苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 018—
A promise to Shellenina
Oh, what a beautiful ocean.
And such pretty mountains, too.
Japan is such a small country, but still so beautiful.
Still, I can't get over yesterday's match.
Ayuhara, for some reason I don't want us to part ways like this.
I'm Ayuhara Kozue.
I'm the Soviet Union's junior team coach, Rudolph.
Captain Shellenina wants to speak to you alone.
Huh? Where is she now?
She's waiting for you in the pine grove.
In the pine grove?
What does she want from me? Especially now that I've quit volleyball?
We don't have anything to discuss.
And yet…
Why did you call me over?
Shellenina-san.
Ayuhara-san.
I'm sorry to trouble you.
But I just wanted to talk to you one more time.
About the yesterday's game, I mean.
Eh?
You won, didn't you. Aren't you satisfied?
No.
I'm not satisfied.
Not with me, but with you.
Me? What did I do wrong?
Your team's playing.
It doesn't always have to be about winning or losing.
I believed in you.
But you weren't playing seriously at all.
You forfeited the game right from the start.
You've got it all wrong.
We did our best.
We really did!
You were just too good.
There's a clear difference in our power.
We lost because of the skill difference.
Skill?
Nonsense.
I don't think you showed even half of your skill to us.
You showed us such a splendid game during the All-Japan championships.
I refuse to believe that was the full extent of your skill.
Ayuhara-san.
Be honest with me.
What were you thinking about on the court yesterday?
Were you only thinking about victory?
She's scary.
She can see right through me.
Sensing my weakness flawlessly.
Rather than focusing on the game, I was thinking about the gym construction and the club's politics.
Ayuhara-san?
Something's troubling you, right? Something big.
And that occupied your thoughts during the game, didn't it?
I'm sorry. You're completely right.
But how did you know?
We're both volleyball players.
We hit the same ball.
Of course we understand each other.
And after hearing your answer, I'm relieved.
It's just like I thought.
You and your team weren't yourselves yesterday.
But I…
What?
It doesn't change anything.
It's all over anyway.
I quit volleyball, after all.
Ayuhara-san.
You'll be serious the next time we play, won't you?
I'll be looking forward to it.
Ayuhara, I'm positive…
…that you will become my strongest rival.
Your rival? Isn't it a bit sudden to decide such a thing?
You'll surely become my rival.
And if you don't…
If I don't…?
I won't forgive you for that game for as long as I live.
Do you understand me now?
Yes. I understand.
Thank you.
Please come to Tōkyō tomorrow.
I want to show you our last game in Japan.
Why?
You'll understand when you see it.
See you tomorrow in Tōkyō.
USSR · Kitakawa
Ayuhara-san.
Our opponents is a high school boys team. You must be surprised.
But, it'll all make sense soon enough.
Their opponent is Kitakawa, a high school boys team within the best eight teams in Kantō.
They're far better than the previous opponents.
But, so far, I don't see anything too out of the ordinary.
Is this the game Shellenina wanted to show me?
USSR · Kitakawa
Nothing has happened.
Maybe something will in the second set?
USSR · Kitakawa
Time.
Pinch server, Borchinskaya.
Borchinskaya, let's do this just like we practiced.
Borchinskaya hasn't been in any of the official matches because of her inability to stand upright.
But she's under Shellenina's strict training as her secret weapon.
What do you mean?
Take your pace.
Nothing happened during that serve.
Does Borchinskaya's power manifest in the attack?
USSR · Kitakawa
Borchinskaya's finally on the attacking position.
That must be it.
Strange. It was still pretty ordinary.
What exactly did Shellenina want to show me?
Ayuhara-san. You seem disappointed.
Let me give you a hint.
Pay attention when Shellenina gets in the center.
In the center?
Chance ball!
Ah!
– What's wrong?
– Hey, what's wrong?
– Are you hurt?
– You okay?
My hand. My hand…!
Should I call for help?
What a destructive power.
Shellenina, you really are a scary person.
That must be devastating. There was no defending that.
Ayuhara-san.
How was it? Do you get it now? Why I wanted to show you our game?
I want to reignite the Japanese attacker's passion within you.
Borchinskaya can't use her right leg very well.
She hurt it when she was little.
In volleyball, one needs a good jump the most.
But even though she can't jump that high…
Borchinskaya still wants to play no matter what.
That is why she and I thought of our own technique: the "cross toss".
Cross toss…?
Yes. A cross toss.
It happens when Borchinskaya hits the ball low.
That's why I need to make it powerful with a curve ball.
When I'm in the center, I give rotation to the ball and pass it to her.
Borchinskaya accepts it and hits it with even stronger force.
Ayuhara-san. I'm going back to Russia.
There, I'll train cross toss and Borchinskaya even more.
And I'll also be waiting for your letter of challenge.
Very well, Shellenina-san.
When we meet again…
…let's meet on the court. Farewell.
Good bye.
"There, I'll train cross toss and Borchinskaya even more."
"And I'll also be waiting for your letter of challenge."
Shellenina.
Thanks to you, I understood something.
I can't go on without volleyball.
I have to return to volleyball… To our club.
Here I go!
Roger.
Once more.
All right.
I thought Ayuhara-san quit volleyball?
I guess it was just a rumor.
Of course it was.
There is no Ayuhara Kozue without volleyball.
Again!
Come on!
Here!
I'm sorry.
Ah.
I want to talk to you for a bit.
I'll be waiting for you on the shrine's premises.
Oh.
Tsutomu-kun!
What exactly did you want to talk about? I need to go back to practice soon.
Well?
It's just…
I thought you had quit volleyball?
Whether I quit or not has nothing to do with you, now does it?
I'll keep playing volleyball no matter what people think.
Hmph. Then you'll wave the championship pennant again?
No, I don't have such a small goal anymore.
The Soviet Union's captain, Shellenina, is my rival now.
Shellenina?
Kozue-kun, you still don't get it, do you?
Say what you want.
I made a promise to Shellenina-san.
When we meet again, my team will win for sure.
Win?
Oh, how sweet.
I see that the volleyball club's goal is still just to win.
Knock it off!
You don't understand me at all, do you?
Kozue-kun.
Tsutomu-kun.
You'd be overjoyed if I quit volleyball, wouldn't you?
What?
I get it.
If I quit our club… you wouldn't have to oppose building of the new gym anymore.
You idiot!
Yeah, I guess I am an idiot!
So leave this idiot alone.
Kozue-kun!
Let go of me!
What I do is none of your business!
What did you say?
Ah!
You… you're only…
Hey, Ichinose.
Don't lay a hand on Ayuhara-kun.
What's so wrong about winning in sports?
What the hell do you know about any of this?
You think you're in any position to preach to Ayuhara-kun?
I'm not preaching to her.
I'm just worried about her.
Tch, you bastard.
Bring it on.
Now you did it.
Fight back, you coward.
Stop it.
I said, stop it!
Stop it right now, you two!
If you have to fight, take it someplace where I can't see it.
Your fight is an eyesore.
Thank you for worrying about me.
But you don't understand anything at all.
But I do understand you.
No, you don't.
I'll be doing what I want regardless of what either of you say.
Don't interfere with my life anymore.
Goodbye.
Ayuhara family
"What are you playing volleyball for?"
"Ayuhara. You first."
"The volleyball club's goal is still just to win."
That's right.
I'll win against Shellenina.
I'll win, for sure.
No matter what anyone says.
Kozue.
It seems you're unable to focus on your true goals now.
Hm?
Oh, welcome back, papa.
I want to show you something.
Come to my room.
What does he want to show me?
What's this?
It's a German dictionary.
German?
– But it has no contents?
– I tore out the pages and threw them away.
Why would you do that?
It's a story from my days as a student.
I wanted to remember all of the words inside.
But remembering five hundred pages worth of words is no small feat.
Still, I focused really hard.
Each time I finished remembering a
page, I tore it out and threw it away.
And when I'd torn the last page…
…It felt like I had conquered the world.
This dictionary without pages has been my treasure ever since.
Do you see what I'm getting at, Kozue?
It's about having the courage to confront the impossible.
Isn't that what youth is all about?
Even if it ends with failure, you should approach your goals with full power.
What matters the most is having a positive attitude.
What's wrong, Kozue?
Papa, I think I understand.
Professor, I understand it now.
Hm?
I know the answer to your question about why we're playing volleyball.
All right, let's hear it.
It seems that we forgot something important in the craze of winning the championships.
I can't quite find the words, but… I think we should've been aiming for something else.
Winning was the reason we practice so hard. We pushed our bodies to their limits.
That's right.
And victories are the compensation for that hard work.
People keep saying "victory, victory". But the moment you win, it becomes the glory of the past.
What's important is to aim for one's own goals and maintain a positive attitude.
Isn't that right, professor?
Exactly.
But Ayuhara…
Did you really come to this realization by yourself?
Well, my dad helped me.
Oh? You've got a good father.
I'm sure you're one happy girl.
I am.
Then there's you, Shellenina.
Shellenina, I finally understand.
Your kindhearted strength…
It showed me that I can't possibly escape the world of volleyball.
Whoa, awesome.
Our chief sure looks different today.
Of course she does. She actually looks happy for a change.
It's only natural. Right, Kozue?
Yeah. But make no mistake, girls.
Winning the autumn's All-Japan championships isn't the only thing on my mind anymore.
I have another objective.
Really? Because I intended to make winning this championship my primary objective.
Winning this, winning that. That mindset will get us nowhere.
It'll just leave us in a hole that we can't climb out of.
A hole?
Yep.
The road we travel will be full of holes. But for our club, the end of that road is nowhere in sight.
Hey, Naka.
I hope that the other clubs will come to understand our feelings.
Me too. If they do…
…there will be no one to oppose building a new gym for us.
How about we give up on that?
We have no right to ask for a new gym after losing to the Soviet Union.
Club meeting
We will now resume the debate about the construction of a gym for the volleyball club.
If you have an opinion, go ahead and speak.
I do.
Before that, please hear me out.
Eh?
Please withdraw the construction.
Oh?
Just like Nozawa-san and Ichinose-san said…
…we will practice outdoors from now on.
That's all.
– Huh?
– What's the meaning of this?
– How surprising.
– I never expected that from her.
Excuse me. I have a question for Ayuhara-san.
Go ahead.
Why the sudden change of heart?
Did you forget that some of us already agreed to it?
It's just… we can play volleyball pretty much anywhere.
We were wrong to demand such a privilege.
Chairman. I agree to the construction.
– Eh?
– That was unexpected.
How could you betray us?
Settle down. Ichinose-kun, go on.
Sure, up until now I've opposed the construction.
"We can't practice without a gym of our own."
"We won an All-Japan tournament, so give us money."
If the volleyball club had continued with that attitude, I'd still oppose it.
But now, Ayuhara-kun…
Ichinose, what are you trying to say?
…says she doesn't need the gym anymore.
I think that for the first time we heard from our volleyball club's captain…
…saying that her club is qualified to have its own gym.
Her love for the club is so pure.
Same goes for her love for sports.
So much that she doesn't need anything else.
So that's why I think we should agree to the construction of a new gym—
That's right!
It's just like Ichinose says.
It's a shame for us to say there's no place for them to practice…
…to the team that roared our school's name to the world.
Yeah!
Nice, Mitamura!
Thank you, Tsutomu-kun, Mitamura-san.
What's everyone else's opinion?
– Agreed!
– Nobody opposes?
Then it is an unanimous decision.
Very well.
The final decision on the volleyball club's very own gym will be reviewed at the next staff meeting.
Tsutomu-kun, thank you very much.
You too, Mitamura-san.
Today I saw a new side of Ichinose.
You can say nice things once in a while.
Let's shake on it.
Yep. However…
It doesn't change that Mitamura and I are rivals.
Hm? Y-Yeah. Sure.
Hahahaha.
This is a great honor to us.
But it also leaves heavier responsibilities.
The next All-Japan championship is right around the corner.
So the upcoming practices will focus on that tournament.
From now on, I will have Ayuhara lead the way.
I'd like you all to listen to her.
I'm sure Ayuhara can handle it.
Treat her orders as if they were mine.
I want you all to train hard.
Understood?
– Yes sir!
All right. That's it for today.
The captain will decide the schedule from tomorrow.
Got it, Ayuhara?
Yes sir.
Dismissed.
Kozue, take it easy.
Midori, you'll help me out, right?
I don't think I can do it alone.
Don't be silly.
You will do just fine.
Exactly. Practicing with Ayuhara-san will be much more fun than with professor Hongou.
This really is great news.
That's right.
Professor Hongou will be shocked with the results.
But what's he planning to do by leaving coaching to you?
I'm sure he has his motives.
It reminds me of the "strategy without strategy".
Ayuhara-san.
Yes?
There's a letter for you.
Eh? Where from?
Fukuoka Middle School
Kakinouchi Yoshiko
It's from Kakinouchi-san at Fukuoka's Middle School.
Huh?
What did she write?
Oh…
It's a letter of challenge.
All right, Shellenina.
There is someone else I need to fight before we battle each other.
Kakinouchi of Fukuoka Middle School delivers a letter of challenge.
Kozue makes a promise to coach Hongou to fight with a new strength.
Midori suggests spending summer vacation camping in Karuizawa, but Kozue rejects it.
Instead, she wants to hold strict training sessions every day.
And the girls aren't thrilled with the severity of Kozue's training, including Kashiwagi and Midori.
And so, a rebellion arises!
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.