苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 019—
The revived rivals
All right, girls. Today's practice is over.
Yes sir.
Ayuhara-san, there's a letter for you.
Thanks.
It's from Kakinouchi-san from Fukuoka Middle School.
What does she want, I wonder?
We haven't forgotten about how you beat us in the spring championships.
So we're working hard to defeat your team the next time we meet.
What did Fukuoka's captain write to us?
Yeah, what is it?
What's in the letter?
Huh? A letter?
– Midori, read it to us.
– Yeah, read it.
All right, here goes. "Students of Fujimi Academy, have you been well?"
"We're already thinking of the upcoming fall championships and are training every day."
Hoho, nice, nice.
Hahaha.
"We haven't forgotten about how you beat us in the spring championships."
"So we're working hard to defeat your team…"
So they acknowledge they have a
long way before they catch up to us.
It's a form of a respectful greeting.
It's your usual "please treat us well".
That's it.
"We hope to win the qualifiers and meet again in the final match."
They're nice, aren't they? Going all the way to pay their respects to the champion.
All right then, let's take them on.
Yeah. We need to act like proper champions.
Yeah.
That's not it.
Although our team was said to have good defense, we completely lost to your attack, Ayuhara-san.
We placed our bet on the offensive.
Rather than focusing on defensive patterns,
I want to make a team that has a strong offense.
Now that we've learned from our mistakes, we turn to Fujimi Academy…
…and challenge you again, Ayuhara-san.
Professor! Professor Hongou!
What is it? Did something happen, Ayuhara?
I went to the teachers office and they said I could find you here.
You had to see me right this second? Is it urgent?
Ah, it's nothing urgent, but…
Hehehe.
All right. Calm down, we'll talk.
Yes sir.
I see.
Looks like Fukuoka Middle School is busy as well.
Professor.
The girls say this letter is like a greeting to a champion.
Isn't it good that they haven't forgotten about you?
I don't think this is just a greeting.
Hm?
Then what is it?
A challenge, and a confident one at that.
So what? Are you anxious?
Yes, I'm anxious.
We might have won the spring championships, but it wasn't easy.
Finding an opening in their defense was really difficult.
They were such a formidable team.
We still won, but we were centimeters from defeat.
That one serve decided it all.
Chance ball!
Leave it to me!
Attack!
We did it! We did it!
– Midori!
– Ayuhara-san!
– Ayuhara.
– Sir.
Look at that bird over there.
Do you think I can hit that bird?
Huh?
Why don't we make a bet if I can hit it or not?
Haha, looks like I lost.
Ayuhara. That ball was a bet too, wasn't it?
It was a brilliant serve that had to be served very precisely and from the right angle.
But it was extremely difficult to get right, which made it a desperate gamble.
We don't know if you'll be able to pull it off ever again.
It's very possible that you might not.
I know.
I know that I probably couldn't.
Look, betting is necessary.
That bet led you to victory, after all.
But a bet is still a bet.
When you fail, there are no second chances.
It's the same with that bird. I can't try hitting it anymore.
Fukuoka's adding offense to their excellent defense.
What kind of team will they become?
I will admit that it is scary.
But it's also kind of exciting, isn't it?
What team will they become?
Professor, our spring victory doesn't matter anymore.
Since Fukuoka is working to become a better team, we'll do the same.
One-two! One-two!
– Captain sure is motivated!
– She looks scary.
Hey!
You idiot! Skirt chasers have no business playing football.
– Sorry, I let my guard down. Captain.
– What is it?
Those aren't just some girls. They're the best volleyballers in Japan.
Yeah. They're Tōkai's witches.
That's some impressive training.
They'll win the next championship for sure.
Yeah, I think the s—
You idiots, get back to work!
Let's go!
Shut up already!
You don't like it? Well, it's music to my ears.
The sweet sound of a new gym for our champion team.
It's great accompaniment to our practice.
Now, let's continue.
– Shoot!
– Got it!
All right, listen up!
Time for light passes, so get ready.
Captain, I've had enough.
Me too!
Please let us rest for a moment, captain.
Oh, stand up. Come on!
Eh?
All of our rivals have already started training for the autumn matches.
Are you okay with being behind the curve?
From now on, we will train every day.
Every day!
And each day I'll make it a little harder.
– Eh?
– Harder?
More than it already is?
Hey.
What's wrong?
Ah, professor!
Hahaha. Seems like some of you aren't taking too kindly to captain Ayuhara's true colors.
If you have a problem with it, then drop out now.
Members who can't obey their captain are of no use to the team.
So save everyone's time and quit.
I'm sorry, but I won't step in.
What happens on the court is up to our captain.
– Ah.
– Got it?
Well? Do you understand or not?
– We understand.
– Very well.
All right then! Ayuhara, resume!
Yes sir! Let's start with passes then.
– All right.
– Okay, okay.
– Heave-ho.
– Here we go.
It'll be finished soon.
Yeah. It's practically done already. All but of a few finishing touches.
It'll be done before summer vacation's over. It's a wonder they built it so quickly.
I want to practice on the court already.
Hey, girls.
– What's up?
– Something happened?
Captain said to go ahead by ourselves.
What? She won't be joining us?
She's discussing our summer schedule with professor Hongou.
Really? I wanted to talk to her about that myself.
What for?
It's just… I have my own plans for summer vacation.
Oh? What kind of plans?
Well, I wanted to consult it with the our captain first.
Come on, spill it. Don't be such a tease.
– Yeah.
– All right.
Well… I guess it's okay to decide it ourselves and surprise her later.
Are you all free now? I'd like to invite you over.
I have a wonderful idea.
Well… I think it's okay.
Yay!
All of you can use it however you like.
Thank you, papa.
I wouldn't allow it if it was just on Midori's whim…
…but I'll be happy to open our holiday house in Karuizawa for your club.
You can use it during the summer vacation.
Yay!
Girls, let's form a plan together, okay?
Yeah. Let's decide where to start first.
– Let's see…
– Hahahaha.
I will cover any necessary expenses.
Have a good time, girls. Excuse me.
Wah.
Thank you very much.
– First of all: food.
– Do we cook for ourselves?
Of course we do. What do you think?
– Then we need to take turns!
– I've never been there. Say, what is Karuizawa like?
Karuizawa is all about tennis.
Wait, you've been there?
Nope. But it's basic knowledge.
Doesn't it have horses too? I've seen some in the photos, right, Midori-san?
Horses? I didn't know about this.
Horses and tennis are nice, but we can't forget about vol—
Yeah. That's the most important.
But it'll only take up three hours of our afternoon.
We'll make a campfire at night.
I bet the stars there are pretty.
You can fish there too, right? I'll whip us up some tasty fish.
Tasty fish would be good after volleyball.
The cycling routes must be great too.
Hey, hey, do they have a pool?
We can't do all of this in a single day. We need to come up with a plan for the whole week.
– Don't you think?
– Yeah. Wait a moment. I will write it down.
We'll start with the departure.
Oyoshi, what was that? You didn't even accept two serves. Come on, stand up!
– Next!
– That's me!
Our captain is on fire today.
– Here I go.
– Bring it on.
Oyoshi, are you okay?
I'm okay.
I feel better when I think about going to Karuizawa.
Hey, are you going to tell our captain about Karuizawa after the training?
Because I'm starting to wonder if that's a good idea. Especially when she's so focused on practice.
I'll tell her after the briefing.
And it's not like we won't be practicing in Karuizawa, so she should be happy.
You're right.
That's it for today.
Gather around, girls. I'd like to announce our schedule.
The gym will be finished the next week and we'll be finally able to start using it.
We'll be able to practice more than ever.
Summer vacation starts next week. We'll practice every day in the new gym till the district qualifiers.
Got it?
Eh?
In the new gym?
Practice will start at 8 o'clock in the morning.
What's wrong?
During the vacation… every day?
Yep. Is something the matter?
Bu-But…
But what?
We kind of have plans, right?
Yeah. It's vacation after all.
Please cancel these plans.
Us volleyball players have All-Japan championships in the September.
It's only natural that we train every day during the summer.
– But, but…
– This is absurd.
Midori, Kakko, you understand, right?
You too?
Actually, I wanted to talk to you about it before.
All of us were planning to spend the vacation in Karuizawa.
Karuizawa?
Yep, papa has agreed to open a
vacation house in Karuizawa for us.
We wanted to go camping and have some fun.
So, we all decided to suspend the practice.
I'm sorry, but you'll have to cancel that trip.
We've just received a brand new gym.
We should use it.
Look, volleyball is important to us, too.
And nobody's objecting to the training.
But we should take a break during the summer, don't you think?
It's not necessary to be so strict.
It is necessary.
We're not alone.
Both Fukuoka and Meihō's schools are just like us.
All of you chose volleyball, so own up to your decision.
Practice for summer vacation will start at 8 o'clock every morning!
Those who don't want to participate are free to quit, just like professor Hongou said.
Kozue-kun.
Oh? Ah, Tsutomu-kun.
Yo. You still have training?
Yeah, what about you?
We still have meetings during the summer vacation. But it's nowhere near as difficult as your training.
I wonder about that.
Now that the gym is finished, you'll probably train every day, huh?
Seeing your practice, it's obvious that you'll win the autumn tournament.
What's wrong? Are you tired from practice?
No, that's not it. It's just that the girls say my training is too hard.
Huh?
They don't want to practice every day during the summer.
Even Midori and Kakko are against me.
It's not like our opponents just sitting around during the spring. Everybody's stronger now.
To keep up, we need to practice more.
And as their captain, I wanted to do my best.
I hoped that they would follow my spirit.
That alone is a difficult training.
Youth always wants to rebel.
But it's the captain's role to pull the team together, right?
Sometimes a captain has to be hated by everyone. It's a lonely position.
If not, then they won't be able to fulfill their role.
Don't you agree?
Yeah.
You're right.
All right, 8 o'clock. Assume positions.
Wah!
Oyoshi, Ofuku, you're late.
We're sorry.
All right. Let's start.
Roger.
I'm exhausted.
Naka!
Captain, this is bad.
I can't move.
And yet you can move your mouth just fine.
Come on.
Here goes.
Next!
Okay.
Are you okay?
Somehow.
Don't sleep.
Ah!
What's wrong?
I hurt my knee.
A wound that small is nothing.
You can still move, so you'll be fine.
Get ready.
What are you doing?
Come on.
Stop it. Knock it off!
What is it, girls?
It's as you said. We can't accept 100 or even 50 balls, not if you throw them all at once.
Humans have their limits, you know!
There is a line between hard training and stupidity and you've crossed it.
So this training is stupidity?
Yes, try to deny it all you want, but this is absurd.
If you tried it, you'd get it.
– Yeah. See for yourself.
– Exactly.
Okay then, let's do it.
I'm ready. If I can do it, you can do it as well, right?
Very well.
I can do it even if I'm alone.
Strike all you can.
Here I go.
Knock it off!
No matter what our captain does, ganging up on her is sick!
Kozue!
Are you finished?
You still haven't reached 100 yet. So get on with it.
The district qualifiers for All-Japan championships begin.
With their eyes set on victory, Fujimi Academy passes the qualifier.
But for some reason, Kudou's playing is particularly bad.
Coach Hongou leaves her in Kozue's care.
But then, in the middle of a special training, Kudou suddenly collapses.
Turns out, the special training is too much…
…and Kozue's frustration flares up again.
Just then coach Hongou gives her a
shocking order: "forfeit the title of captain".
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.