苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 020—
Unforgivable special training
Kozue. I know you can do better.
Is that all? Are you finished?
It still hasn't been 100 serves yet.
What are you waiting for?
Kozue, that's the spirit. The real struggle begins now.
All right, sixty balls, forty to go.
Here goes!
Got it.
Are you going to just stand there?
You serve too. Make it like rain.
O-Okay.
We're not finished. Continue until full hundred.
Roger.
100.
You did well, Kozue.
Captain.
W-What should we do?
Haven't we gone overboard?
Hey, Midori.
We didn't have to go that far.
Don't shift the responsibility to me alone.
All of us are in it together.
It wasn't just me.
Ah, captain…
We're not over yet.
I'll show you I can still accept another 50 serves.
All right, this is where it stops.
That was plenty enough.
Okay, Ayuhara-kun.
See that, girls? Satisfied yet?
Ayuhara, as your captain, as your leader… did what was only natural.
What Ayuhara can do, you can do as well.
Understood, professor.
Kozue, I'm sorry for being so harsh on you.
We were wrong.
Thank you. I'm glad you understand.
We thought it would be sufficient if we only protected our title.
But captain has bigger plans for us.
I see that now.
We can't rest on laurels.
In my opinion, when one accomplishes a goal, one should then strive for something even bigger.
We just blamed the captain for everything.
The struggle is the same for everyone.
The approach to that struggle is what makes champion different from other people.
Yes sir.
Kozue has been different lately.
Day after day…
…she grows more mature.
Professor, we were thinking about summer vacation too much.
Hey. There are no summer or winter breaks for the volleyball club.
Hahaha.
Captain, here.
Oh, I forgot about it.
– I'll tie it for you.
– Okay.
– Make it look cool.
– Roger.
All right. Qualifiers for the championships start tomorrow.
Consequently, the whole team is to stay here at nights from tomorrow on.
– Overnight?
– That's right.
This new gym has its own bedroom.
You'll be able to train and sleep in here.
Got it?
Hooray!
I'll bring my jersey.
Nice accomodation.
Are you ready for this, girls?
I'm done.
Captain, please look after us.
– Let's do our best, Naka.
– Yep.
City Gym
Japan's best attacker,
Ayuhara Kozue, is on fire
The number one
Unrivaled Fujimi Academy
Fujimi Academy advances
with irresistible force
Fujimi Academy
Today was an easy win as well.
I'd say we're doing fine.
Really.
Tomorrow's Kaimei Middle School. After we win with them, it's semifinals.
The semifinals are not a problem.
The goal is to continue our spring streak and win the whole thing.
Right, Kozue?
And the arch nemesis is Fukuoka, all right.
We almost lost with them in the spring, didn't we?
It'll be okay. We have the best attacker in Japan after all.
– Darn right.
– Don't be careless.
Look at this.
"Will they become first?
Fukuoka Middle School."
"From defense to an attack team."
"Megaton-class destructive power of Kakinouchi's attack."
Is it the same Kakinouchi-san?
That's right.
I got this newspaper from a friend of mine from the university times, who's now living in Fukuoka.
They're changing their model from defense to a powerful attack.
They'll be nothing like in spring.
Looks like they weren't just all talk in their challenge and have indeed become a wonderful team.
I bet they're convinced they can win with us.
During this championship they will take our Fujimi Academy much more serious.
We won't lose, right, Kozue?
We won't lose no matter what.
Fujimi ・ Kaimei
Give us a good serve, Midori.
Don't mind, don't mind!
Midori, good luck!
Fujimi ・ Kaimei
Don't mind, don't mind.
One more.
Pull yourself together.
Yeah.
Fujimi ・ Kaimei
Hey, Okei, what's wrong?
I-I'm sorry. I'll get better.
It's our chance.
Yeah.
Come on! Accept it!
Got it.
Last hit!
Good luck, Fujimi!
Okei, pull yourself together.
I'm sorry.
– Fukuda.
– Sir.
Ofuku, we're counting on you.
Wow, so cool!
Nice, Fujimi!
Changing room
– Wait for me.
– We'll do our best tomorrow too.
– Let's get on the bus.
– Okei.
Okei.
What was that?
It's almost as if you weren't there.
I apologize.
I brought us shame.
Kudou.
Commence special training as soon as you get back.
Yes sir.
Ayuhara, you will coach Kudou.
We can't have her play like that in the next match.
I'm very sorry.
I won't be able to go back with you.
I will come to the gym tomorrow morning.
I understand.
Continue with the traning.
– Yes sir!
All right, Okei, let's get started.
Please.
We can't lose to Fukuoka no matter what.
I won't forgive anyone poor play.
That is why we're doing this. Okei, get ready.
I'm ready.
Here goes.
Fukuoka combines their impregnable defense with a strong attack. They're about to become invincible.
But Kakinouchi's spikes are said are no less inferior to Ayuhara's.
In order to win, we need to stop it with a powerful receiver.
Who will become one?
Ayuhara?
But she's plenty busy with her captain duties.
I just charged her with special training as well.
There's so little time.
All right.
I must leave it to Ayuhara after all.
Here goes.
It's no use. One more time.
More, more.
Next.
Ah, I'm all hungry.
Me too.
Ladies, it's dinner time.
Ah, I've been waiting for this.
I'm starving.
What's on menu today?
It's curry.
Wah, lucky!
Wait for me!
Let's dig in.
What about captain and Okei?
Somebody call them over.
Okay, I'll go fetch them.
They're in the middle of training now.
By the way, Okei seemed off today.
Really.
She's good at receiving. Missing is unthinkable for her.
Okei just wasn't herself today.
The next one will be a curve ball.
Stand up.
Why can't you accept such a simple ball?
I'll repeat the last serve.
Come on! Fight, fight!
Okei is acting strange today.
It hurts…
Okei!
Okei.
What's wrong? Okei.
Captain, I…
I feel weird…
What is it, Okei?
I… I…
I can't see!
Ah! Okei!
Okei, come on.
Are you okay? Okei!
Keep it together!
Okei!
Girls, listen!
What is it?
O-Okei has collapsed!
Eh?
I wonder if she is all right?
What happened?
Ah, Midori.
There's something wrong with Okei.
Okei, hang in there.
Ah, she has terrible fever.
Eh? Whoa, you're right.
Hey, Kozue.
What the heck did you do to her?
She just collapsed in the middle of our training.
Tell us how it really was, captain.
It was your training that has caused her to collapse.
It didn't cause it.
It was terrible.
I've seen it myself.
I-It's not like that.
That's harsh, Oyoshi.
Save excuses for later. We need to take Okei to infirmary as soon as possible.
Naka, get going! Quickly!
Y-Yeah.
Okei, hang in there.
Be careful.
– Ozawa-san.
– Hm?
Get the janitor and bring the key to the infirmary.
– Hurry up!
– Got that!
Kakko, call Okei's house.
– Got it?
– Yeah.
– Ofuku.
– Eh?
– Don't just stand here. Contact hospital.
– Okay, then?
– Get a doctor to come here. Got it?
– I'm on my way.
Midori.
Fujimi Academy
I don't think it's anything serious.
Her temperature is a little high though so we thought it'd be better if we let you know.
Thank you for all the trouble.
Please tell the doctor that I'll be there very soon.
Infirmary
She suffers from extreme fatigue.
I gave her sedatives so she sleeps well. It's better to let her sleep in here tonight.
Thank you for all the trouble.
Her heart has considerably weakened.
I advise you to have her heart thoroughly examined as soon as possible.
Do you think there is something wrong with her heart?
I can't say anything for sure until I see examination results.
But I don't think it's good that you let her do such a strenous exercise.
I see.
Well then, I'll be on my way.
Thank you for coming here so late at night.
What about you, girls?
We'll all nurse her together tonight.
Ah, there's no need. You have your game tomorrow.
I can take care of her by myself. Please go home.
I agree. I called mister Hongou and let him know. There's no need to worry.
Well then.
– Thank you very much.
We'll be on our way then, ma'am.
Thank you very much, girls.
– Please take care of her.
– Thank you.
Excuse me.
Kozue.
We promised to follow your coaching.
Yeah.
However, I think you went overboard this time.
But I had to hold a special training session with her.
Thanks to your training there's no knowing if
Okei will ever be able to play volleyball again.
You are our captain. It's okay if you're strict with us.
But there are boundaries.
I didn't do anything wrong.
I did what was only natural as their coach.
She must have been sick even before.
It has to be it.
There's no way she'd collapse from just that.
How about this, girls?
We'll make it clear in front of professor Hongou tomorrow.
– I agree.
– Agreed.
– Let's go.
– Yeah.
Hmm.
Is that so?
You don't have to worry too much, though.
It was an unfortunate accident.
I am deeply sorry.
There's nothing you need to be sorry about.
All what happens in the club is my responsibility.
Professor.
Hm?
I don't think that's the case this time.
This accident was clearly caused by the extreme training.
I think captain Ayuhara should assume responsibility for this.
Exactly, exactly.
Of course, we know we need hard training.
But there are boundaries. Okei's case shows it well.
Why are you teaming up on me?
We were saying it was too strict from the start.
It was obvious that sooner or later it had to go down like this.
It just happened to be Okei.
Midori, how can you say that?
She fainted during your training.
We just want to avoid repeating this in the future.
Okei was sick even before.
– Really?
– Say what?
That makes it even worse.
You know about it and yet—
Of course I didn't know about it.
But it has to be the case.
That's despicable.
Kozue, you're covering your mistakes with a
made-up sickness and you call yourself a captain?
Fine, what should I do then?
Forfeit my captain title?
Eh? Of course not…
Midori. Be honest with me.
You just want to get rid of me, don't you?
Calm down, Ayuhara.
But that's too much. I don't want to be a
captain, whose whole team rebels against.
Midori, I misjudged you.
I am only expressing opinion of everyone.
Then all is the same.
I don't think you're qualified to play volleyball if you think like that.
What would happen to the club if I quit?
What was that?
– As if.
– Wow.
That was way out of line. I can't follow Ayuhara-san.
Me too.
Us too.
Ayuhara.
Why don't you forfeit the captain title for now?
Professor?
I think it's for the best.
Oh…
Are you serious?
Yes.
Captain…
Ayuhara.
Bear with me. Please be patient.
Professor.
Hm?
It's time to go to the match. Get ready.
– Yes sir.
– Also, Hayakawa.
– Sir.
For time being, you're the captain.
Yes sir.
That's cruel. That was too cruel.
I can't take it.
Not from our professor…
But I have no idea what to do next.
I won't be able to return to volleyball if I lose my captain title like this.
If you take volleyball from me,
what will remain of me?
Ayuhara-san, watch this.
Ayuhara-san.
When will we play?
I'm waiting for you.
No. I won't falter.
I'm not quitting.
There's no way I am.
I am not quitting!
I won't quit volleyball no matter what.
Even if I'm all alone, I will continue playing.
I'll show everyone!
Ayuhara Kozue challenges the world on the cliff.
She goes to see Fujimi Academy's girls university training.
Is it possible for Kozue to recover her captain title?
Captain Oohara holds a hard training session with Kozue.
They train fiercely on a vacant lof of a factory.
However, Kozue is unable to focus, blaming herself for what happened.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.