苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 021—
Captain's responsibility
I'm not quitting!
I'll continue playing, even if I have to do it alone.
It's obviously your fault.
This time it is captain Ayuhara's responsibility.
Exactly, exactly.
Of course, we know that training is necessary.
But there are boundaries. I mean, just look at Okei.
Yeah! You're not fit to be our captain.
Ayuhara.
Why don't you forfeit as captain for now?
I think it's for the best.
Are you serious?
I've lost my position as captain.
How do you expect me to play after all of that?
Here goes!
– Okay!
– More!
Ah, it's her again.
She seems down.
I wonder what's wrong?
Pay attention!
Ah.
Ah…
Ayuhara-san!
What's wrong?
How long has she been here?
Not sure.
But I'm sure it's been a while.
I wonder if she's all right?
It's weird how that ball wasn't received.
Yeah, that is weird.
I am talking about you.
How could you not accept such a serve?
Sorry.
Fujimigahama Municipal Hospital
I'd like to visit Kudou-san.
She was admitted here yesterday.
I'm afraid it's past visiting hours.
Is that so…?
Please hold on. I'll try asking the nurse in charge.
What if…
What if the checkup results turn out bad?
Ayuhara-san, this is all your fault!
Keiko ended up like this because of you!
How do you intend to make up for this, Ayuhara-san?
I'm scared. I'm scared!
I don't have the courage to face Okei.
I see. So it is all right for her to drop by.
Okay. Thank you very much.
Looks like you can go see her after all.
Huh?
Where did she go?
Kids these days…
Flake. Coward. Good-for-nothing.
No matter what I say, there's no excuse.
Why didn't I stay and hear the checkup results?
But…
If the checkup results are bad…
…there will be no place for me to escape to.
Will this hand hit a volleyball ever again?
Thinking about that scares me…
– Ayuhara-san.
– Ah, Oohara-san.
– Why don't we play for a bit?
– Eh?
I haven't seen your spike for quite a while now.
Let's go to the beach.
Don't be swayed by the wind!
I know.
How could you not accept that serve, Ayuhara-san?
You're spacing out, aren't you?
You're not doing yourself any good,
practicing in such a state.
Let's call it quits.
Give me the ball back.
No. Let's play once more.
Sorry, but there's no point.
If I got serious you wouldn't stand a chance.
I can do it.
I think I'm better than your teammates.
Those are some strong words.
Are you serious about that?
Yes. I am.
Very well.
I will train you as you wish.
Let's meet in an hour.
This is my father's factory. Let's step in.
Whoa.
This place is secure from the wind and we can even play at night.
At night?
Yep.
You said earlier you're better
than my teammates, didn't you?
I did.
That means you can do everything they do, right?
Miss?
Sorry to intrude.
But do you think you can bring the first-aid kit in here?
Huh? First-aid, you say?
– Are you hurt?
– No.
Oh?
So that girl is…?
She's still kicking right now,
but she's going to need it soon enough.
Let's get this going.
Don't let it go!
Got it!
– Next!
– Ah!
Come on!
Wow, they're amazing.
Ah, damn it!
Ah!
Oh dear.
I'm a little tired, how about you?
Shall we call it a day?
No… no, not yet.
Not yet, not yet.
You can drop the tough act.
That's not it.
T-This is your special training? Don't make me laugh.
Ours was much, much more difficult.
Let's see what you got. Accept that!
Pardon me, miss, but I think it's best to stop here.
Please don't interfere.
Interfere? What an ungrateful kid.
– Ah!
– There's more!
Don't you sleep!
Not yet.
Not yet, not yet…
Stand up!
Kudou-san.
Oh no! You see, this is why I said to stop.
She doesn't know when to give up.
What madness.
You poor thing…
Eh?
You've gone through a lot, haven't you, Ayuhara-san?
Here comes another.
Stand up. Why can't you accept such a simple ball?
Pathetic. I'll repeat the last serve. Get ready.
Come on! Fight, fight!
It hurts…
Okei?
Okei!
Okei, come on.
Are you all right?
Okei?
Keep it together!
Okei!
Ayuhara-san?
Ayuhara-san!
Oh, thank goodness, you woke up!
Oohara-san…?
It's all right. Don't try to move just yet.
Thank you.
That was scary. You were reckless.
That's not true, mister.
However, miss…
Hey mister, did you play any sports when you were younger?
Yes. Believe it or not, I used to play baseball.
I was just a spare player, though.
In that case, I think you'll understand Ayuhara-san's actions someday.
I can take it from here, mister.
Are you sure? All right. Please get well soon.
You went through a lot, didn't you?
And all by yourself, too.
Eh?
I heard everything.
Your request seemed strange, so I went to your school and met with professor Hongou.
I see.
That's why I knew right away when you tried to provoke me.
I've seen right through you.
You blame yourself for Kudou-san's condition and want to make up for it by going through the same.
Am I right?
I'm sorry.
There's nothing to apologize for.
But what did you think it would accomplish?
Ayuhara-san, do you think it will help anyone if you bully yourself?
If that's the case, you're wrong.
You're not fit to be a captain.
But I guess I'm not one to talk.
Looking at you reminds me of my former self.
Just like you, I kept setting the bar higher and higher.
Because I hate to lose,
I always ended up very serious.
We're the same in that regard.
But I haven't always been such a volleyball addict.
The one who introduced me to volleyball was my middle school classmate.
Her name was Kagawa-san.
She was into it even more than I am now.
No one forced us to do such intense training.
That was our choice and ours only.
But for some reason one day Kagawa-san refused to participate in our training.
Huh?
I'm sorry, but I can't go to our practice today.
Kagawa-san, what's wrong?
Since I have just become captain around that time, I thought Kagawa-san was acting out of jealousy.
No way.
Just "because you don't feel like it"
is not a good reason.
But I really don't.
Are you sick? If that's the case, show me the medical discharge.
Or maybe you have a problem with how I run things? Then just say so.
Haven't we been friends since middle school?
Kagawa-san.
We're friends, right? Then please trust in me.
Of course we are.
Then please don't ask me anything.
Kagawa-san.
I truly thought Kagawa-san was jealous of me.
At some point, I vented my anger on the innocent underclassmen.
It's an embarrassing story…
– Ah!
– Next!
– Come on!
You can do better.
Next!
Captain.
We can't take it any longer.
We're at our limit.
Are you serious?
What will happen if you "can't go any longer"
in the middle of a game? Will you just run away?
You have to be able to cover Kagawa-san's side.
Don't lose your spirit now.
Okay…
Accept it!
Oohara-san.
What?
It's time to stop this.
Then get out. This team has no room for people afraid of intense training.
That isn't intense training at all, that's a farce.
What do you mean?
You're doing it only for yourself. No one benefits from it.
Don't act like you know it all.
Everyone is in low spirits because of you.
It's not my fault.
Oohara-san, you're thinking
of us just as receiving machines.
And what's wrong with that? You can't show your emotions during a game anyway.
A match is like war.
Aren't you the only one who thinks like that?
Eh?
Even machines take breaks.
It is captain's responsibility to know when to take those.
Shut your trap. Don't tell me things I already know.
It's not like I expect you to become the best in a single day.
Already know, you say?
If it was so obvious to you, then you wouldn't be saying we have no spirit.
Step aside!
It is none of your concern anymore, is it?
Don't interfere with our practice.
We're resuming, whether you move or not.
Okay, here goes!
– All right!
– Let's go!
Kagawa-san.
Why are you standing there?
You're meaninglessly disturbing our practice.
Why?
– Why is she just standing there?
– Weird.
Are you trying to show me something?
If so, what is it?
What is it…?
Ah!
Ka…
Kagawa-san!
Kagawa-san, don't tell me…
Ah, I didn't think the ball would come so I just stood here.
Do you… can you see?
You can't, can you?
Eh!?
I can still see a little bit.
I can at least tell your face from the ball.
Kagawa-san, why did you keep this from us?
I developed glaucoma.
I realized I was losing my sight two months ago.
Two months ago!?
And you still continued to play volleyball?
I wanted to play as much as I could.
I kept silent because I didn't want you to worry about me.
But now you know…
I tried to carve our practices into my memory as much as I could, but those memories…
…will disappear in no time, won't they?
I'm sorry, Kagawa-san.
I didn't know…
But that's no excuse.
And I call myself a captain?
A captain.
That's the captain's responsibility, isn't it.
You still need hard training.
You need that intensity.
But it can't just be for the captain's or coach's own satisfaction.
Whether your training does any good depends on how united your team is.
Pushing forward blindly requires neither a captain nor a coach.
Do you understand?
I do, Oohara-san.
I'll visit Kudou-san tomorrow.
Up until now, I couldn't get over Kudou-san's bad performance and forgive her for collapsing.
Somewhere in a corner of my mind, I blamed Kudou-san.
I blamed her weakness
for me losing my title as captain.
I was just thinking of myself.
But now I understand.
I lacked so much while I was their captain.
Oohara-san, thank you very much.
I'm glad you understand.
Let's hope that Kudou-san will get well soon.
Yeah.
I can't lose here.
As soon as visiting hours start, I'll go see Kudou-san.
Kozue.
No matter what the results are,
a responsibility is a responsibility.
Even if it's hard, I can't look away.
Ayuhara Kozue isn't that unreliable a person.
Fujimi Academy members have advanced through the district qualifiers…
…but are still uneasy around Kozue.
Kozue is still determined to return to the club.
However, her resolve breaks down under coach Hongou's words.
"We can win even without Ayuhara", says Hongou.
Does she really not have a place in the volleyball club after all?
Kozue breaks into tears…
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.