苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 022—
Fight in despair
Fujimigahama municipal hospital
Excuse me, I'd like to see Kudou-san.
She was hospitalized yesterday. Is it okay?
Kudou-san? Oh, she's in room 301.
Thank you very much.
Kozue, this is all your fault!
You're supposed to be our captain!
It's your fault!
Everyone's right. I'm to blame here.
I might've run away from Okei's checkup results yesterday, but today I won't.
Oh, it's here.
Please let me through!
D-Don't tell me…!
Okei…!
Okei!
Thank goodness. But…
Yes, come in.
Wah, captain!
Okei, you're up?
I'm being discharged.
Really!? Oh, I'm so happy for you!
I'm sorry for making you worry about me, captain.
Don't be.
We must apologize.
Keiko has caused you a lot of trouble.
Actually, it's the other way around.
Because of me, Keiko-san ended up in the
hospital. How can I ever apologize to you?
There's nothing to apologize for. Keiko has always had a weak heart. She just never told anyone.
If I were to continue playing volleyball, I'd probably be risking my life.
I-It's that bad?
I feel like I was given a death sentence.
After all, I love volleyball so much.
So, I've made up my mind.
Really? So, you'll…
…not quit the club, of course.
I see…
But…
I'll become the manager.
Just because I can't play doesn't mean I can't be of use to the volleyball club.
That's great, Okei!
Captain.
That's a really good idea.
I'm so glad. I really am.
But I'm also a little jealous of Okei.
I didn't have he heart to tell her that I'm not the captain anymore.
Okei might've found her way back in.
But I can't go back after the way I was treated.
Now that I know what the girls think of me.
But even so, I just can't throw volleyball away.
I have no choice but to try and regain my team's and professor Hongou's trust.
Trust is everything. You need to go hand in hand.
That's right.
Just because I am no longer their captain doesn't mean I need to step down altogether.
They still need me for the All-Japan championship.
They'll realize that as soon as they calm down a bit.
And when they do, professor Hongou will see it, too.
What's that,
what's that?
– Don't sleep.
– Yes sir.
Once more!
Yes sir!
Here goes!
Got it!
All right, attention!
Listen. Tomorrow we're playing the qualifier finals.
And yet, what's with that form?
You expect to win the championship this way?
At this rate, even the qualifiers are at risk.
Show some effort.
But professor.
Hm?
Well…
What is it? Say it already.
Well, can we really win without Ayuhara-san?
I'm really worried about it.
Fufu.
Looks like they acknowledge my skill.
Let's make one thing clear right now.
You don't need to worry.
We don't need Ayuhara. You all have what it takes to win without her.
Professor Hongou!
That's right. It's just like professor says, girls.
Even without Kozue, we can definitely win with our skills.
Yup.
What?
Professor Hongou thinks nothing of me.
They don't care about my feelings at all.
I'm… I'm just a fifth wheel to them.
– Captain!
– Ah?
Captain…
– Oh, Okei!
– Okei!
Ayuhara-san.
And that's why I'd like to become a manager from today on.
I see.
It must've been hard to hear that you won't be able to play anymore.
But I'm glad you didn't let it get to you, Kudou.
Hehe.
Anyway.
Currently our volleyball club has no manager, so Kudou will fill that position nicely.
Sir.
By the way, I saw captain just now.
– Ehm.
– Oh?
What is it, girls?
You see, Ayuhara-san…
We had a fight and she's no longer our captain.
Huh?
Say what?
So that's why the captain looked like that.
What the heck, girls!?
Kozue is suffering and you just let it be?
You're right. You're completely right.
I'm going to visit Kozue and apologize to her.
Me too.
I'll go as well.
No, it's no use.
Ayuhara won't be returning to the volleyball club.
T-That's not true.
If we honestly apologize, I'm sure she'll come around.
Yeah. Let's go.
It's pointless.
Huh?
You want me to join the gymnastics club?
Yes. Under these circumstances, saying it's a good opportunity might sound strange.
But I'd definitely welcome you in our club.
Thank you very much.
But—
The members will surely be thrilled as well.
If you can let go of volleyball, you're bound to succeed in the gymnastics club.
They did make themselves clear about it.
I'm no longer needed in the volleyball club.
But…
I don't think I can quit volleyball.
We don't need Ayuhara. You all have what it takes to win without her.
That's right. Even without Kozue, we can definitely win.
Still…
Even though I love volleyball I
don't want anything to do with that club.
We don't go hand in hand at all.
The most important thing in team play is missing.
Ayuhara-san.
You don't have to respond right away.
No. I made up my mind already.
Professor Nakajima, please let me join the gymnastics club.
Really? That was quick, Ayuhara-san.
I'm glad.
Oohara-senpai, I'm sorry.
I no longer have the strength to remain in the volleyball club.
– Hey, it's Ayuhara-san.
– Eh?
She's talking to miss Nakajima of the gymnastics club.
What if she…?
N-No way, she's joining the gymnastics club?
Let's go and see.
All right, come to the gymnastics club tomorrow morning.
Okay, I will.
I'll make a fresh start with the gymnastics club.
Just like Izumi-san.
Kozue.
Kozue, we just met Okei. I'm sorry.
We misunderstood each other.
So, we want to apologize to you.
It's all right.
I don't think anything of it.
Really? That's great!
So then you'll return to the volleyball club?
We're all so anxious without you there.
Well, it's too late for that.
I've just joined the gymnastics club.
Y-You didn't!
It's official.
I am praying for you all to become stronger and win the All-Japan championship.
Kozue!
Well, that sucks.
Hey! You girls!
What happened to your practice?
But, professor.
I give you one finger and you bite off the whole hand.
Have you forgotten about tomorrow?
We need to drill for the tomorrow's qualifiers.
Do you understand?
Are you deaf?
Get back to the court. Right now.
Now!
– Yes sir.
– Yes. – Okay.
Kozue, I just have one thing to ask you.
Can… can you really let go of volleyball?
I'm part of the gymnastics club now.
That's all?
That's your answer?
Fine…
I'll pray for your success in the gymnastics club.
Midori. It's cruel to ask me a question like that.
I've already made a decision, though.
But I still don't want to see you lose to Fukuoka.
But that's volleyball club and professor Hongou's problem now.
Oh, look at me.
Still worrying about the volleyball club's issues even though I'm no longer its member.
I'm a member of the gymnastics club now.
The volleyball club has nothing to do with me anymore.
Good morning. Did you sleep well?
– Yes sir!
Well, today is the qualifiers final.
Let's keep in high spirits and win.
Got it?
– Yes sir!
All right, let's go.
Ayuhara-san…?
In the end, she didn't come.
Okei.
Why did you think that Kozue would come?
Because…
Kozue joined the gymnastics club.
There's no way she'd come.
We can win even without Kozue!
– Whoa.
– Huh?
Ayuhara-san.
Good morning, professor.
Listen, you're a member of the gymnastics club from today on.
Yes. I know.
I just wanted to see them off.
All right.
Come on, everyone is waiting.
You'll be the most talented newcomer our club has ever had.
One-two-three.
Two-two-three.
Three-two-three.
Girls, let me introduce Ayuhara-san. She'll be joining our club today.
Nice to meet you.
– Nice to meet you.
A volleyball team's captain joins our club? Terrific!
This is the first time I'll be doing gymnastics, so please be patient with me.
Don't be silly, Ayuhara-san.
You'll surely lead us to victory in all of our contests.
Oh, please.
All right, that's enough.
Time for practice.
– I assume you're warmed up.
– Yes ma'am. – Yes ma'am.
Let's start with leg spreads.
Go with the jump.
Yes ma'am.
Okay, next.
Ayuhara-san has joined our club.
It seems to have motivated everyone.
Ah!
Ah.
Try not to make a spectacle.
Try again, this time higher.
Yes ma'am!
It's tough.
The always-kind professor Nakajima feels like a completely different person.
Next.
This is no joke. I have to work hard in this club.
While I am good at volleyball, I don't want to admit that I'm poor at gymnastics.
Especially not to Midori.
Ayuhara-san. Try it out yourself.
Yes ma'am.
I will show to everyone that
I can succeed in this club, too.
How skillful.
As expected from Ayuhara-san.
Ah, it's just beginner's luck.
So-so, I guess.
Okay, let's move on to the next exercise.
Good, do not lose the balance.
Ah!
Try it once more.
Yes ma'am.
Stretch out and turn your back.
That's it.
I'm actually doing pretty well in the gymnastics club.
Even though I was forced to face new exercises without having time to catch up.
Ah.
Ah!
Redo.
Before I knew it, I was already absorbed.
I was trying to forget about volleyball, about Midori, and about professor Hongou.
Thank you.
Professor Hongou!?
What's up? How are things at the gymnastics club?
"How are things"?
I'm sorry, professor, but that's none of your business anymore.
Hehehe.
Hey, hey. Don't be so cold, now.
We won the qualifiers, so I thought it would be nice to let you know.
Is that so? Well, you didn't have to go out your way just to inform me.
But congratulations, I guess.
Ayuhara.
You seem to have held a grudge against me for quite a while. Huh?
Oh, you could tell?
It's just that I didn't think that you were such a cold person.
You knew very well what volleyball meant to me.
Well, you might not like to hear this.
But Hayakawa does well in your place.
Same goes to the rest of the girls on the team.
We will be able to win the All-Japan championship, even without you.
We're pretty good, wouldn't you say?
Unbelievable.
You came here just to tell me that?
How is it, by the way?
Gymnastics is said to be pretty difficult.
I don't think that it will go as well for you as it did in the volleyball club.
It will, professor.
You know that I achieve my goals. I'll prove I can succeed in this new club as well.
Oh?
That's right. I'll show you and everyone in the volleyball club that I can succeed.
That's it. That's the spirit.
Ayuhara. You can surely do it.
Good luck, Ayuhara.
I want to play volleyball.
But professor Hongou and the volleyball club members are now my enemies.
The club has done just fine without me.
Why are you holding back?
Everyone's slacking.
Hey, Midori. It isn't the best time to say it, but things are bad.
What is it? Be specific.
The All-Japan championship starts tomorrow, right?
And to be honest, we're still all worried that we can't win without Ayuhara-san.
What? Why are you bringing this up now?
Are you trying to say I'm incompeten—
Far from it.
We're just anxious.
Also without Ayuhara-san,
I feel like we lost our power.
Didn't it feel like each of us played alone, instead of as a team?
I felt it from the very beginning.
We may have won the match today.
But I'm afraid of what comes next.
For the first time, I realize the weight of responsibility a captain carries.
It's a deep internal struggle.
I think I understand now the feelings that Kozue hid behind her hard training.
Even when everyone blames you, you're still expected to push forward.
Even when no one understood her, Kozue believed in everyone and pushed the team to its limits.
Midori?
She may still be there.
Ah, Midori! Where are you going?
To the gymnastics club.
Wait, Hayakawa.
Before you go see Ayuhara, let me relay you her words.
Huh?
Ayuhara said:
If you go to Tōkyō without me, you will lose in the very first set.
Eh?
I can't believe Ayuhara-san said such thing.
Ayuhara now belongs to the gymnastics club.
She's aiming for success in that club.
Got it?
Ayuhara's full of confidence.
It is a new challenge from her.
A challenge?
Yes. Ayuhara thinks that without her, the
self-proclaimed star, our club will weaken.
Do you still intend to chase Ayuhara after hearing this, Hayakawa?
Indeed, Kozue declared herself to be a part of the gymnastics club now.
I wonder if she joined that club just to become a star again?
At any rate, I will not forgive her mocking our volleyball club.
What is it, Hayakawa?
Do you still want to go cry on Ayuhara's shoulder about your lack of confidence?
No.
I've changed my mind.
Really?
I hope it's not all about pride.
That's partly a reason too. However, I
realized that depending on others is a mistake.
Listen, girls.
All of us will win on the merit of our own strength!
All right. That's the spirit!
– Go for it, girls!
– Yes sir!
The All-Japan championships…
this is my own chance to become a star.
You're pretty early, Ayuhara-san.
You look a bit lonely.
Your friends went to Tōkyō, you must miss them.
No, everything's all right.
You won't fool me.
Ah, never mind.
Anyway, Ayuhara-san.
In the next three days, we're going…
…to have you master the forward, backward and sideways somersault.
Forward, backward and sideways?
Yes.
You can already do a front walk over on the beam.
The next step is to learn the somersaults.
How do you expect me to learn it in just three days?
And why somersaults specifically?
You'll understand it soon.
But I did make a bet with professor Hongou.
Professor Hongou?
Actually, professor Hongou said:
"No matter how good Ayuhara was at our club, she can't do gymnastics."
What? How cruel!
This is where I stepped in.
"I will prove you are mistaken and show you that she can master somersaults in just three days."
I think I might have said too much, though.
No, he insulted us.
Anyway, I let the other girls rest for three days.
We'll hold a special training for you.
Please prepare yourself.
Yes ma'am.
Well then, let's start right now.
The most important part is to take a good first step.
– Got it?
– Yes ma'am.
Begin!
Ah!
That was a good fall.
– Redo.
– Yes ma'am.
Use the whole body.
– Once more.
– Yes ma'am.
Watch your timing. Make it quicker.
For some reason, I feel like I'm being manipulated.
But I'll go along with it anyway.
What's the true meaning behind this exercise?
What's wrong?
The famous volleyball club's captain is down with just this?
N-Not at all.
Then hurry and stand up.
T-This is nothing.
Looks like we can make it.
Ayuhara family
"Fujimi Academy adds the first game to its track record."
"Fukuoka Middle School wins its first match by a shutout."
At this rate Fujimi Academy might lose.
What am I saying? I have decided not to worry about the volleyball club.
I am going to focus on mastering the somersault in three days.
But I don't get it.
There has to be some point to it.
Something's up.
And not knowing what it is frustrates me.
I'll keep enduring it, though.
How can I not?
The All-Japan volleyball championship games begin.
Fujimi Academy wins the first round.
Meanwhile, Kozue puts up a solitary fight at the gymnastics club.
She quickly grows to hate the challenge of learning multiple kinds of somersaults on such a short notice.
It's only then when the rivaling Fukuoka Middle School shows off their true power in Tōkyō.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.