苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 023—
What was hidden
Master these exercises as soon as possible!
I am not a robot.
I am Ayuhara Kozue, a living human.
And yet, she expects me to master front,
back and sideways somersaults in just three days.
Why?
There must be something else to it.
Kozue?
Kozue-chan.
I'm here.
Yes, what is it, Mama?
I bought you a new leotard.
Put it on the desk.
Kozue.
All right then, I'll leave it here.
I know I committed to this special training yesterday, but there must be a reason for it.
It's just not normal, expecting a newcomer like me to master those somersaults.
There must be something to it.
All right, then.
I'll try asking Professor Nakajima.
I'm not going to be some gymnastics robot.
– I take it you're warmed up?
– Yes.
Good, then let's start from the front somersault.
Got it?
Front somersault.
I will master it today… no,
I will master it this morning.
I certainly will.
Ready?
Go.
Professor!
Professor Nakajima, I made i—
Ayuhara-san.
I don't remember complimenting you.
Professor…?
You think doing it once means you've mastered it?
Do it again, and this time without run-up.
Eh? Without run-up?
You can do it.
Or are you scared?
But that's too much.
You can handle it if you gradually reduce the distance and your speed.
What are you just standing there for?
We don't have time.
– Professor, uhm, I—
– If you have something to say, save it for a break.
Tomorrow is the promised deadline.
I see. A promise is still a promise even if it's absurd.
Fine, then.
I will master it, even without the run-up.
Start by shortening the run-up by half.
Relax your body.
First the somersaults, now this… what comes next?
But I won't lose.
I will master whatever exercise Professor Nakajima throws at me.
Ayuhara-san.
A promise is a promise.
I want to keep it.
Please don't get disheartened and master this exercise soon.
Go!
All right, once more!
This time no run-up.
Okay.
Your balance may collapse a bit.
Go ahead.
Ah!
Ah.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
She puts up a terrific fight.
She must have a positive attitude to be able to master this on such short notice.
Wait a moment,
maybe Ayuhara-san…
…realized something?
Ah.
Because of Professor Hongou's insult, Professor Nakajima promised to teach me these somersaults.
And in just three days.
She's putting me through such hard training to show that I'm a worthy addition to her club.
It's almost like I'm a wager in a debt.
And if that's correct…
…I'll despise Professor Nakajima forever.
I'll master it right now.
Ayuhara-san.
It doesn't matter what you think of me.
It's only important that you learn this exercise.
But it looks like you're getting close.
The deadline is the volleyball finals.
Ah!
What i—
Maybe this special lesson is in accordance with the volleyball finals?
No, that can't be…
Ayuhara-san.
What is it?
You're almost there.
– Please continue.
– Yes ma'am.
Fufu.
I guess I still have an attachment to volleyball at heart.
I associate arbitrary time frame with volleyball training right away.
Even now, when I'm a gymnastics club member at training.
But what if this special training really is for the sake of volleyball…?
No, that's all just wishful thinking.
But I can't shake off…
…how I was supposed to be putting forth decisive power in Tōkyō right about now.
All right, girls, let's finish this!
– Got it!
– Yeah!
We have to win no matter what.
It's the only way we'll be able to face Kozue.
Okay, I think I've got the hang of it.
This time it will go perfect.
I did it!
I can do it just fine without run-up!
Ayuhara-san!
Ayuhara-san, you sure know how to work hard.
What a wonderful girl you are!
I can no longer complain about anything.
Professor Nakajima.
So you're finally acknowledging that
I have mastered it, just like you told me to?
Yes.
Of course. You can do it perfectly.
In that case, let me ask you something, Professor.
Ayuhara-san.
I thought you already know the answer to that question.
No, I don't know. I'm not your gymnastics robot.
I hated Professor Hongou's claim that I can't do gymnastics…
…like I could play volleyball just as much as you did.
So I went ahead with what you said and learned the somersaults in just three days.
Funny, huh? Well, laugh as much as you want.
But it wasn't you who trained and spilled blood.
You just went ahead on your own and made a stupid promise to Professor Hongou.
I just can't believe that was the only reason for this drill.
I don't want to believe that.
So, please tell me.
Tell the real reason for all of this training.
Why did it have to be three days?
If… If there is another reason to it…
Ayuhara-san, it's just as you guessed.
Huh?
It's volleyball.
It's because you simply couldn't forget volleyball.
Why are you holding back?
Go ahead and play with the ball you like so much.
Go on.
I'm glad.
I'm so glad.
Volleyball.
White like snow.
No…
Glittering like a magic ball.
I feel as if it will disappear the second I touch it…
Slip through my fingers like sand.
Ah, but…
But…
Ah…
Yay!
Volleyball came back to me.
Almost like a bird.
She looks at the volleyball with such joy.
Professor Hongou, I am envious you get to coach a person like her.
But there are still things Ayuhara-san has to do.
It's okay. I'm the happiest in the world.
Ayuhara-san.
Please forgive me.
I cooperated with Professor Hongou.
Huh? But he was the one who pushed me to leave volleyball.
That was his plan.
To motivate you by making you angry.
How cruel.
He didn't have to go that far.
Professor Hongou instructed me to respond to you with this:
"There is only one goal in this tournament".
Kakinouchi of Fukuoka Middle School.
If we learn how to get past her, it's our win.
Fukuoka's Kakinouchi-san.
Yes.
"I'm going to gamble everything on Ayuhara Kozue".
Everything on me?
Th-That's absurd. It's too much of a responsibility.
I don't respond well to such high expectations.
Are you scared?
I don't know Kakinouchi-san,
so I can't tell how dreadful she is.
Either way, there's simply
no choice but to do your best.
The battle has already begun with this special training.
And it's not over yet.
Decide now. Do you want to compete against them and fight, or run away?
We don't have much time.
So let's start with the somersault receive training.
Somersault receive?
Assume position.
Yes ma'am.
Somersault receive.
That was the purpose of this training all along.
I'll do it. No matter what happens,
I'm going to master the somersault receive!
Ayuhara-san, are you ready?
Yes ma'am.
Ah.
It's no use.
I can't even graze it.
You'll learn it in no time.
Ah! Ah.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Ah.
It's nowhere near Kakinouchi-san's level.
Kakinouchi-san showed her revolving receive for the first time at the spring All-Japan championship.
And then there's Kakinouchi-san's spike. It's almost mystical in its precision.
We won the spring tournament,
but this girl possesses mysterious powers.
I can only imagine how much Kakinouchi-san's skills have developed since then.
How effective will this special training really be against her?
I am starting to feel hopeless…
I touched it! I touched the ball!
It won't work if you try to think with your head.
– Use your muscle memory.
– Got it!
Right.
Rather than focusing on the opponent, I should be focusing on myself.
Professor, please keep throwing.
Yes.
Here it comes!
I…
I have to master this.
If I don't, all of our effort will become meaningless.
Ayuhara-san.
Fukuoka Middle School gains another victory by a shutout
Kakinouchi's vivid spike leads to victory
Fukuoka won all the matches by a shutout thus far.
Kakinouchi-san has become a dreadful attacker.
Just like she claimed in that challenge letter.
She traded her summer vacation for severe training.
After a while, Professor Hongou showed me Fukuoka's newspaper.
It praised Kakinouchi-san strength all over.
"Both Fujimi Academy and Meihō Academy are doing well".
But Fukuoka is different.
Fukuoka stands out and seems to always be one step ahead.
Ah, just one more day left.
Even if I go through hell and high water, I have to master it!
No matter what, if I don't learn the somersault receive today…
…I won't be able to respond to Kakinouchi-san's challenge.
Ayuhara-san.
Professor, please keep throwing.
Very well. Ready?
Here goes.
It's no use.
I can't hit it properly at all.
This is bad.
Ah!
Ah.
How can I not master such a simple thing…?
I'm such a dull girl!
I-It's such a simple thing…
Ayuhara-san, you can't rush it.
There's no time, so we need to go step by step and stay thorough. Got it?
Yes ma'am.
Let's continue!
It is too early to lose heart!
No matter what, I must master the somersault receive.
Right here, right now.
You're too late! Make the turn a little tighter!
The ball keeps gradually moving away from me.
Ah, it's hopeless.
I can't do it!
Ayuhara-san, no matter what you do, it's no use.
You can't beat me.
Give up. It's hopeless.
Hahaha.
Hahaha!
She's right.
No matter what I do, I won't be able to master the somersault receive.
It's nothing but a dream.
Ayuhara-san.
Professor…
I can't do it.
I can only do simple somersaults.
I'm not fit to be a secret weapon. You expected too much.
Is that all you have to say, Ayuhara-san?
I'm going to stop this exercise.
After all, I can't m—
Ah!
Professor!
I'll say this once.
Don't be arrogant.
Arrogant?
Professor, I am not being arrogant.
It's quite the opposite. I'm in despair over my skill.
That's it. That's what being conceited is about.
I'm conceited?
That's not true.
You had to let go volleyball once already, didn't you?
Y-Yes.
What were you thinking at that time?
What was I thinking about…?
That I couldn't forget about volleyball.
Exactly.
And you've suffered.
But then you were thinking like this:
"No matter what I do, I want to play volleyball".
"If only I could play volleyball".
Am I correct?
Yes. That's exactly right.
You are forgetting those humble feelings.
All you think about is the opponent before your eyes.
Eh?
If you feel that your cheeks hurt,
you still have a chance.
If not, please get out of here now.
"Conceited"…
"Opponent before your eyes"…
She's right. My head is full of thoughts about Kakinouchi-san.
Professor, please…
Please keep throwing the balls.
Please!
Looks like you finally understand.
Now you see who you really need to win with.
Professor, please.
I really want to master this somersault receive today.
Now that you're motivated, let's resume at once.
Yes ma'am!
Professor Hongou.
I feel I'll be able to fulfill my promise.
All right.
Getting to the finals shouldn't be too hard at this rate.
However.
Fukuoka Middle School.
We'll need Ayuhara Kozue to have any chance of beating that team.
We have no choice but to wait for her arrival.
Well, after that comes Ayuhara. We just have to wait for her.
We're counting on you.
Ayuhara-san…!
Professor!
At last… at last you can do it!
I am sorry for putting you through this.
No, Professor.
Thank you so much.
Have a good sleep tonight.
– And in tomorrow's finals…
– Yes.
I will show the somersault receive.
To Professor Hongou as well.
I've finally mastered the revolving receive.
I finally did it.
I did it!
Fukuoka receives beautifully.
It's Kakinouchi-san.
Fukuoka Middle School thanks to Kakinouchi's excellent play…
…defeats Meihō Academy today by a shutout and advances to the finals.
Tomorrow they will play against Fujimi Academy who has won the spring championships.
Tomorrow, huh?
I'll show it then.
I will respond to the Kakinouchi-san's challenge.
Typhoon no. 15 gradually gains power…
…and approaches southern Kyūshū.
The weather is not important.
What's important is that
I mastered the somersault receive.
All that's left now is to go to the finals…
…and face Kakinouchi-san.
It's gotten pretty bad outside.
It'll be all right.
We'll make it to the game in time.
Yeah. It'll be okay, right?
Ah.
This is a message to the passengers.
Typhoon no. 15 has changed direction and is likely to land in the direction of Tōkai.
The train will slow down to ensure the passengers safety.
Therefore, the expected time of arrival to Tōkyō is expected to be greatly delayed.
Arrival in Tōkyō is delayed?
But if the typhoon gets worse, we might stop altogether. That's can't happen!
What to do?
This is bad.
This typhoon… Professor Nakajima told me she'll get on "Kodama", but I'm still worried.
Kodama - train service
Professor, time to go.
Oh, I will go in a second.
We're counting on you, Ayuhara.
What if the train doesn't make it in time…?
Then all of that work will go to waste.
My blood, our training, everything will be in vain.
I can survive losing to Kakinouchi-san in a proper battle.
But if I lose without even being able to put up a fight…
I can't handle that.
It's okay. Don't worry.
We'll make it.
Kozue.
Oh, dear God.
Please let me make it in time for the game.
I do not want to lose without fighting.
I'd absolutely hate that.
Middle School Women's Volleyball Championships
The audience is watching over…
…as the battle between Fujimi Academy and Fukuoka Middle School begins.
Kakinouchi's intense spike hits the Fujimi team's side again and again.
Fujimi Academy is on the defensive.
It seems that the outcome is already decided.
Meanwhile, the typhoon becomes even stronger and Kozue's train drops its speed again.
Will she make it in time for the game?
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.