苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 024—
Revolving receive
Go! Go! Fukuoka!
All-Japan Girls Middle School Volleyball Championship finals
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Come on.
Fujimi ・ Fukuoka
Hooray! We did it!
Professor, we might lose at this rate.
She's right, professor.
It's just not the same without chief.
Cut it out. It hasn't even started.
Exactly. Volleyball is willpower.
We can't falter.
We need to take them head on.
But really, Ayuhara, what the heck are you doing?
Kozue.
An information to passengers.
As we've just entered the effective range of typhoon no. 15, please be informed…
…that due to the severe weather circumstances we might need to stop.
Huh?
Since the weather has already significantly deteriorated…
…we've reduced the speed to 100 kilometers per hour.
Therefore the expected arrival time at the Tokyo terminal station is at 2 PM.
We're very sorry for the inconvenience.
That's terrible news.
By 2 PM the match will have started long ago.
What should we do, dear?
Hm.
Who would've think we're going to be late by two hours.
You said it. My plans for today are all in pieces.
Mama, say something.
Can't we do something about it?
Calm down, Kozue.
One can't fight against a typhoon.
But, but—
Nobody's at fault here.
It can't be helped.
At this point we have no choice but to pray that we make it to Tokyo on time.
It's all right if it's in the middle of the game.
At very least I want to be there for the last set.
The again the match could very well go bad and have ended already at 12 PM.
What to do?
No, the girls won't lose so easily.
But…
But, what if…
Fufufu.
Do your best, girls!
Fujimi ・ Fukuoka
Fukuoka wins the first set.
Good luck!
One set is nothing!
Don't mind don't mind!
Second set is yours!
Let's keep this pace. The second
set's going to be a piece of cake.
Of course it is.
This match is not fun without Ayuhara-san.
Listen. If you look at them, they're all about Kakinouchi.
You're too tense.
When you're tense you can't play well.
Listen.
Don't think about the contest. Focus on your body and on the ball alone.
Got it?
Yes sir.
All right, girls, let's get back.
– Okay.
– Yeah.
Yeah. That's it. That's the spirit.
Had Ayuhara been here, they wouldn't be so nervous.
Where are you? What are you doing?
Finally, the second set is about to start.
Will it be Fukuoka who emerges victorious?
Or will Fujimi defend its champion title?
We welcome the second set with great suspense.
Serving right goes to Fujimi. The server is Hayakawa Midori.
Today she's bravely fighting in Ayuhara's place.
We need to win this second set no matter what.
Calm down. We will win without fail.
We've already won.
Even if Ayuhara-san was here, it wouldn't change a thing.
I will win this match with these hands.
Right on!
Kakinouchi's curve ball spike beautifully hits Fujimi's court.
Fukuoka straight away reclaims the right to serve.
After finally mastering the revolving receive…
I won't be able to respond to Kakinouchi-san's challenge.
Midori. Girls… please hold out.
Even if it's just one minute or one second, please buy me some time.
Fujimi ・ Fukuoka
Please listen to this applause, to this excited cheering.
It's all a commendation for Kakinouchi's stunning spikes.
It's all for this curve ball attacker, Kakinouchi.
It is a great success after lack of recognition in the spring.
I lost to her curve ball again.
Hayakawa-san, it's not your fault.
I'm sorry, but I can not accept that spike.
Since when was Fukuoka Middle School so strong?…
They were all about defense in the spring.
They were serious in the challenge letter sent to chief after all.
Only Ayuhara can accept that spike.
The question is whether the special training was effective.
But really, Kakinouchi's spike is just as exp—
No, it's even better than that.
Fujimi ・ Fukuoka
And now it's 10 to 3.
Fukuoka dominates the match.
– It's no good.
– It got completely one-sided.
It's just not the same without Ayuhara.
Hey, I heard people talking…
…that Ayuhara got kicked out of the volleyball club.
Tsk. Then it's no surprise they're losing now.
To hell with you, Fujimi team!
Eh?
Mitamura-kun, that was a little too much, don't you think?
Eh, what a pathetic game.
Yeah. I feel you, Mitamura.
I think the same as you.
Well then, next serve will be done by captain Kakinouchi.
Her curve ball serves are what Fujimi Academy couldn't yet find a remedy to.
Well, it is about time.
We will soon arrive at Shin-Yokohama station.
In addition, we got out from the sphere of typhoon's influence.
But because of the strong wind, we cannot increase the speed yet.
We deeply apologize for your inconvenience and kindly ask for patience.
Whew.
Faster. Faster!
Ah.
If I only had wings…
Fujimi ・　Fukuoka
Time!
What's wrong, girls?
I know you can do better.
What is it?
Listen. Don't worry about the championship or the score.
In other words, act like champions you are: be proud and fight as hard as you can.
I understand, sir.
Even if we were to lose here, we must show a good fight nonetheless.
Exactly.
I do not want to play a game that we come to regret at a later time.
Show everyone a good play.
– Yes sir!
Is that it for us?
In the end, Ayuhara never showed.
Attack!
Good! Keep at it!
Fujimi Academy attacks desperately!
Last stretch, girls.
Yeah!
Please hold out a little longer.
Fujimi ・ Fukuoka
Finally it's match point for Fukuoka Middle School.
– All right!
– Hooray!
Will Fukuoka Middle School become the champion today?
Dear God, please don't let the game end.
Right on!
It was close. It was really close.
Kakinouchi's long spike fell just a tiny bit outside the court.
It's our chance.
They're still at it. Thank you.
Fukuoka Middle School easily reclaims the right to serve.
As usual, Fujimi Academy is powerless against Kakinouchi's spikes.
Will Fukuoka Middle School break the stalemate?
We got a match point again.
Damn it. Don't expect us to stay silent.
Go! Go! Fujimi Academy!
What is it, people? I can't hear you!
Where's your spirit?
A-Ah?
Howdy, Tsutomu-kun.
Oh, uncle? Aunt? What are you doing here?
We're here to see Kozue's game.
Huh?
Our train got delayed by the typhoon, but at last we made it to Tokyo.
Kozue is changing into a uniform now.
She will come out any time.
Hey, did you hear that?
Ayuhara's here.
Yup. But isn't it too late?
Fujimi ・ Fukuoka
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Are we done for?
But everyone fought well.
Even without the team's essential part that is Ayuhara.
Ah! Ayuhara!
Professor!
Kozue!
– Ayuhara-san!
Professor, sorry for making you worry.
The train was delayed by the typhoon.
I see.
That's how it was.
I'm glad you made it on time.
Ayuhara-san.
Time!
– What's going on?
– They asked for time.
Oh? Ayuhara-san of Fujimi Academy has appeared on the court.
Kozue. Everyone was waiting for you.
In the end, captain Ay—
Ah.
It's okay, Oyoshi.
Our captain has to be Kozue.
Throughout the game we were longing for captain Ayuhara's return.
Of course that goes to all of us, including Midori.
By the way, Ayuhara, did it go well?
Yep. I've mastered it.
Really? You did, huh?
Okay. Ikezaki, change with her.
Captain, I leave it to you.
Oh?
At the last moment, huh.
Nah, the game is still on.
Do not forfeit the game until the end.
Even if you don't win, don't forget you're a champion and go all out.
Kozue, watch out for Kakinouchi-san's spikes. They're all curve balls.
Curve balls?
There is a member change at Fujimi Academy.
Ayuhara comes out after all.
She switches with Ikezaki.
Ah, Fujimi Academy should play better now.
The expectations on Ayuhara are very heavy.
But the score is 14 to 8 already.
It is probably impossible to expect a
dramatic change from this substitution.
Professor, you asked Kozue before if it went well. What was that about?
– You'll see it in a second.
– What do you mean?
The game is resumed.
– Fight!
– Yeah!
Kozue-kun!
Ayuhara-kun, do your best!
– Ayuhara-san!
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Come on.
Go! Go! Ayuhara!
Kakinouchi-san.
The time has come to respond to your challenge.
Ayuhara-san.
I've been waiting for you.
You are our one and only opponent.
I will pick up any curve ball you throw against us.
I won't miss a single serve.
The victory is ours.
This game will be decided with a single serve.
I dedicate that serve to you.
This is a spike that ends it all.
– Kakko!
– Got it!
Okay! Kozue!
– She did it!
– Good!
Yay!
Good going, Fujimi Academy!
As expected from Fujimi Academy's captain.
Why did they hide her until now?
What's that?
One point is all it takes to scare you?
– Get a grip!
– All right!
Nice, Ayuhara-san!
You're nothing like in spring.
But my spike is better.
– Midori, give us a nice serve!
– You got it!
Right at you, Ayuhara-san!
This is where I get to show my training's results.
She did it!
Ah!
Toss!
Got it!
Truly brilliant and beautiful play.
During the entire tournament, no one could receive Kakinouchi's fierce curve ball spike yet.
Ayuhara wonderfully caught up with a revolving receive.
With her brilliant attack and defense
the girls regain their lost points one by one.
Midori, let's keep putting pressure on them.
Kozue. That was a revolving receive.
That's what was behind joining the gymnastics club, no?
With such an amazing revolving receive, our team is going to be the bomb.
Amazing, that revolving receive.
What? It was just a fluke.
We won't lose to them.
We'll keep striking until we win.
But really, Ayuhara-san.
When did you learn the revolving receive?
Fujimi ・ Fukuoka
Finally, a draw!
Finally, it is a draw!
14 to 14!
Again, blocking landed them a point.
Kakinouchi's spike is completely blocked. Ayuhara really gave the match a dramatic turnaround.
Now Ayuhara's spike hits the court!
Fujimi ・ Fukuoka
Banzai! Banzai! Ayuhara!
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Yay! We did it!
I'm glad!
Great, Ayuhara.
Professor.
Ayuhara, you did well. You met all my expectations.
Even so, it's regrettable for Fukuoka Middle School.
Although it seemed that there was no doubt they're going to win…
…tables have turned at the last moment and they ended up losing the second set.
As expected from Ayuhara, a great attacker.
She's not just an attacker anymore. Now she's a great receiver too.
– Dear.
– Yeah.
Even so, literally a miraculous turn of events.
Fujimi Academy team truly shows their dignity as the spring champion.
Yeah. The one who creates a rift between us and made me enter the gymnastics club…
…was no one other than professor Hongou.
It was all a plan to teach me the revolving receive.
Are you serious?
In other words, yet again the professor has led us around by the nose.
Well, that's awful.
Oh, professor.
Hahaha.
Don't be so mad.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
It wasn't a great way, but it gave us a chance to defeat Fukuoka that no one could stand against.
All right, it's the third set.
Good luck, girls.
Now that captain is with us, we've practically won.
Now we're at an advantage.
Don't let your guard down.
Finally, the decisive third set begins.
Again, Ayuhara's spike bursts in the court.
Fujimi Academy gets a lead.
Good luck, Fujimi
Fukuoka ・ Fujimi
Fujimi Academy undoubtedly leads the game.
Fukuoka Middle School requests strategy time.
What the heck is this?
Will you let them win under your noses again?
Professor.
We'll certainly win.
We haven't trained to end up losing against them now.
Very well. That's the spirit.
Whatever it takes, we're going to win.
Still, my curve ball is useless against Ayuhara-san's revolving receive.
Okay. Let's use the underhand twist. That'll do it.
Captain Ayuhara is the server.
Move!
Ah!
– Oh!
– Captain Ayuhara!
– Chief! – Kozue!
What's wrong?
It worked.
Even you couldn't receive this spike.
Uh. Hit…
Hit. She hit me.
With her spike.
Whoa, she did?
– Ah, captain! Hang in there!
– Kozue!
My ankle hurts bad.
As expected from Kakinouchi-san.
You are a terrifying rival after all.
Kakinouchi's intense spike hits Kozue.
Kozue's right ankle is in bad shape, forcing her to use a supporter.
The successive victory of Fujimi Academy is decided with two points.
Kozue's working hard.
However, with obsessive Fukuoka's counterattacks, it is no longer clear who will win the championship.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.