苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 025—
And the winner is…
Right at you, Ayuhara-san!
Oh!
This is where I get to show the results of my training.
She did it!
Ah!
What a truly brilliant and beautiful play.
During the entire tournament, no one could receive Kakinouchi's fierce curve ball spike.
And yet Ayuhara was able to do so with her revolving receive.
Attack!
Good luck, Fujimi!
My curve ball is useless against Ayuhara-san's revolving receive.
Alright, then. Let's use the underhand twist. That'll do it.
Captain Ayuhara is the server.
Kozue!?
Kozue-san.
Please, stand up.
It's Ayuhara. She'll stand back up.
Are you okay?
I'm fine, I'm fine.
– Let's go.
– Okay.
Kozue, are you okay?
Yeah. The floor is just slippery from sweat.
Please give me a supporter.
A-Ayuhara?
– Here you go.
– Thank you.
Ayuhara…?
Professor…
Ayuhara…
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Come on, only two points left.
– Yeah!
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Kakko!
Ah!
– Hang in there, Fujimi!
– You can do it!
Ayuhara-san!
Do your best!
Here I go!
It's coming.
Kozue!
I have to receive it no matter what.
She sprained her right ankle.
That must be it.
– Ah!
– Jump, jump!
Your revolving receive was so good until now. What's wrong?
Sorry. My timing was just a little off, that's all.
– Let's go. Come on, Midori!
– Okay! – Yeah!
That's weird.
What's weird?
I can't tell for sure, but…
Ayuhara-kun's movements got all…
She's moving differently all of a sudden.
It's really strange.
What's wrong? Captain Ayuhara Kozue misses the ball again.
Go! Go! Fujimi!
My ankle. My ankle…
So that's what it was. You sprained your ankle.
It's nothing. I just jostled it a bit. Don't bother telling the girls.
Fine, then let's win the serve right back. Just two points left.
Girls, we don't have to fear Ayuhara-san anymore. She can't pick up even the simplest spikes now.
She must be exhausted from the revolving receive.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
The victory is ours.
Here goes!
Great! You can do it!
Fukuoka · Fujimi
Third set. The score is 13 to 9.
Fukuoka Middle School makes a come back.
What happened to Fujimi Academy's Ayuhara?
It seems the incredible pace of Ayuhara's revolving receive and intense spikes has been disturbed.
Go! Go! Fukuoka!
Did you do that to protect me? I told you it was nothing.
But…
What would we you do if you disrupted our team's play, Midori?
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Huh?
Okay, let's go.
We only need two points. We're almost there.
Go! Go! Fujimi!
– Okay!
– Let's do this!
Ayuhara-san.
We've challenged you for this match.
And now we're going to win.
We'll certainly win!
Fufufu.
We haven't lost yet.
We're not going to lose.
– I see. Ayuhara-kun—
– Yeah.
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Chance.
This is our chance!
Midori!
– We did it!
– Yay!
We reclaimed the right to serve.
Now it's our turn.
Attack. Attack. Attack!
– Good luck!
– Do your best!
Kozue-kun must have sprained her ankle.
I can't think of anything else.
That's why she can't move that well anymore.
But her revolving receive just now was excellent.
Maybe it's nothing serious after all?
I wonder if Kozue-kun can repeat that receive again.
I wouldn't bet on it.
It looks pretty painful.
She must've hurt it back when she was hit.
Damn it, just when they were about to win.
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Ayuhara, good luck! Hang in there!
Again!
Kozue.
Don't let it get to you!
You can do it!
Ayuhara! That's enough! Stop it!
Are you okay?
– Captain.
– Kozue. – Hang in there.
Don't worry about me.
It's okay! Stop it! Just stop it!
Kozue.
Two points…
Just two points left.
Time!
Coach Hongou of Fujimi Academy has just stood up.
Apparently he has asked for strategy time.
Go! Go! Fujimi!
I know you're probably thinking how the victory is just two points away.
But this is rushing,
and rushing accomplishes nothing.
Don't think about points.
Focus solely on your own playing.
Got it? That's all.
Go! Go! Fukuoka!
Also, Ayuhara. We're swapping you.
Professor?
Ayuhara, you did well.
But that's enough. You helped plenty.
Please listen to the teacher.
Captain. It's reckless with your ankle.
Everyone has been quiet only because you hid it from us.
– Right?
– Yeah. – Yep.
We'll take it from here.
We'll play as well as we can.
We might be not able to win.
But we will try our very best.
Professor. Please let me stay.
Don't make me leave in the middle of the match.
Whether we win or lose, please let me stay until the end.
But your sprain looks pretty bad.
I'm fine.
It's not like I've broken a bone.
Look.
I can stand just fine.
I can jump too.
Look, Professor.
Kozue…
It's okay. Please stop.
Do not push yourself, Chief.
Professor. I'm fine.
See? I can jump just fine.
Ayuhara, cut it.
Professor.
Captain, stop it.
Kozue!
Professor!
That's enough! You've made your point.
But still, Ayuhara.
What if you push yourself to the point where you can't play volleyball in the future?
Go! Go! Fujimi!
If I retreat here, I am going to quit volleyball for life anyways.
So it doesn't matter. If it really came to that, the result would be the same.
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Professor, I'm begging you.
Professor!
Professor, let me play.
Professor, please let her stay.
Let us play with our captain until the end.
Professor!
Please.
Kudou.
Tend to Ayuhara's ankle at once.
Hurry up! We're almost out of time.
Professor!
Kozue.
Midori.
Go! Go! Fukuoka!
Go! Go! Fujimi!
– Captain.
– Let's do our best.
That's great.
Thank you.
Go! Go! Fujimi!
I wonder what's going on.
Don't tell me Kozue wants to continue.
I'm going to check.
Calm down.
You don't need to.
Izumi-san has already gone to them.
– All right. Let's go.
– Okay.
Thank you.
Go! Go! Fukuoka!
Ah, Kozue…
What if…
Kozue-san has hurt her ankle, but she's basically fine.
Kozue-san's fine.
I see.
Hang in there!
Do your best!
Go! Go! Fujimi!
How is it?
She sprained her right ankle.
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Professor Hongou didn't want to let her play,
but she pressured him into agreeing.
Kozue-kun… she went through such a tough practice all by herself for today's game.
She finishes what she starts.
Damn.
She must be in a pretty bad shape.
You idiot.
Ayuhara, you idiot!
Midori!
Dammit!
Fujimi Academy puts up a fierce fight.
They've regained the right to serve.
Here I go!
M-My ankle!
Go! Go! Fukuoka!
Fukuoka · Fujimi
14 to 13.
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Fukuoka Middle School has taken lead back.
Do your best!
Go! Go! Fujimi!
After losing to Fujimi in the spring, will Fukuoka finally become the Japan's champion this time?
Fujimi Academy puts up an excellent fight.
However!
It seems that Captain Ayuhara can't regain her pace.
Good luck to both Fujimi Academy and Fukuoka Middle School.
One more point.
We're going to win this.
Got it?
The last spike belongs to me.
– Everyone, full focus.
– Got it.
Captain.
Kozue.
Yeah.
All right, let's go!
– Yeah!
– Yeah.
Until the end. Until the bitter end…
I won't make it!
Attack!
Kozue!?
Chance.
Chance!
She's going for it!
We won!
We won, we won!
Congratulations!
Ayuhara-san.
You…
Good, good!
We have to make sure we compliment Kozue, Dear.
She tried so hard until the end.
Well done. She really did well.
Yes. Yes…
Kozue went to such lengths…
It's okay if you didn't win.
You played such a beautiful match.
Kozue-kun.
Damn!
Damn it all to hell!
You did great!
Ayuhara-san!
They're praising Kozue.
Great, Ayuhara, great!
Everyone, well done!
Both Fujimi and Fukuoka!
The winner, Fukuoka Middle School's captain,
Kakinouchi Yoshiko.
Waiting room
Fujimi Academy
I am sorry.
If I only hadn't sprained my ankle, we would've won.
What are you talking about, Captain?
We're not crying because we lost.
Yeah.
We're glad we got to play to the end with you, Kozue.
That's right.
Nobody's blaming you.
If it wasn't for you, Captain,
we would've lost in the second set.
We wouldn't have been able to put up
such a great fight without you.
We may have lost the game, but we didn't lose our spirit.
Thank you.
Thank you, girls.
Captain.
It was the last championship match we got to play in middle school.
What will come next?
I will definitely come back here again.
So until then…
Until then, farewell.
Ayuhara-san!
Kakinouchi-san?
Congratulations on your victory.
Thank you.
We dreamed of this victory during our training every day. This time we could grasp it.
But I can not really rejoice.
Huh?
I kept attacking you,
even after you sprained your ankle.
But still, after seeing how you fought to the very end…
…I realized something.
We might be the ones who get to bring the pennant home…
…but you're the real winner here.
Kakinouchi-san…!
If you hadn't sprained your ankle, you would've beaten us.
– We would've lost for sur—
– No. You won fair and square.
Ayuhara lost the moment she got injured.
You should face your opponent in your best condition.
That's a real match.
If you do that, only then you can show a good game.
You guys had an outstanding win.
So congratulations on your victory.
Thank you very much.
Kakinouchi-san, until our next game.
We won't lose next time.
Neither will we.
Even though they couldn't win, the girls feel satisfied after putting up a good fight.
The train takes Fujimi Academy team and heads straight home.
Soon, a mysterious man appears before Kozue.
"That wasn't a revolving receive!" – he says.
Who is this strange man?
And what did he approach Kozue and Hongou for?
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.