苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 026—
A disturbing warning
Shall we go, Ayuhara?
The game is over.
Yes sir.
Hongou-san.
I saw the match.
It was definitely an interesting game.
And you are…?
You're pretty talented.
However, the question is
how far can you go with that talent?
I'd hate to see it end like this.
You're…?
Better find yourself a good coach.
If you'll excuse me.
Haha.
What's with that man? If he wanted to tell us something, he should've been straightforward.
Before the game started, I saw him talking to someone from the Volleyball Association.
Is he with the association?
No, no. That's not it.
I know everyone at the association.
So you don't know him?
– Something bothers me…
– What is it?
Ah, never mind.
Let's go.
The autumn championship is over.
We might not have won, but I have no regrets.
Everyone did their best.
Even I'm surprised at how hard I've been working.
It's all been so hectic.
Same goes to me.
Even now I ache all over.
But I was so absorbed during the game.
Ah, by the way, Captain.
How is your ankle?
Does it still hurt?
Are you all right?
Oh, how awful. You've just remembered that now? Have you forgotten about Kozue's ankle already?
O-Of course not.
I'm fine, Kakko. There's no need for you to worry.
This sprain is nothing.
I'm well-trained.
This will heal soon.
I see.
Oh?
It's that man.
Ookawa?
Hongou.
Ookawa.
So it really was you.
Hahaha.
It's not "Ookawa" these days.
I'm known as Inokuma now.
Inokuma?
You're that Inokuma Daigo?
So you knew?
I've only heard the name.
And that Inokuma advanced an unnamed North Korean team to the world championship.
Also that he was recently called back to Japan.
I see.
What are your plans now?
I'm not sure yet.
But I am a man who can't do anything but volleyball.
How is your right arm?
It's completely useless now.
I can't use it at all.
– Hongou.
– Hm?
I was surprised when I heard that you became a volleyball coach.
Heh. Well, I didn't have any experience in the field.
But I thought I could make it with enough passion and team spirit.
You never change, do you?
Eh?
You're too naive.
Volleyball isn't such an innocent, sweet thing.
Your coaching is no good.
What? What do you mean "no good"?
Calm down, Hongou.
Ayuhara and Hayakawa are good players.
They have what it takes.
But you? You're no good.
You can't help them grow.
But I could teach them so much more.
Oh? And how do you want to do that?
You wouldn't understand.
Say what you want!
But I will still do things my way!
I don't need your preaching.
Very well.
Perhaps that's for the best.
Learning from a man like me would probably be tough for Ayuhara and Hayakawa.
– Professor.
– A-Ayuhara…?
You.
That wasn't a revolving receive.
Huh?
It was just a somersault.
It wasn't a receive.
But do you know what's missing?
Of course you don't.
If we ever see each other again, then…
…I will tell you what it is.
What's with that man, Professor?
You probably saw his name in the newspapers.
That was Inokuma Daigo.
Huh? Th-That…
That coach who has led North Korea's college team to the second place in the world championships?
That's him.
But, Professor, I thought you didn't know him?
I did ages ago.
That's why I didn't know it for sure when we first met.
Professor, what did he mean by saying that wasn't a revolving receive?
I don't know, either.
What did he want to say, I wonder…?
Ayuhara!
Sir?
Your ankle is all healed up?
Yes sir.
All right, then.
Time to practice your revolving receive.
Yes sir.
That wasn't a revolving receive.
Here goes!
It was just a somersault.
It wasn't a receive.
Do you know what's missing?
What are you doing, Ayuhara?
Ah.
One more!
So then this man said "that's no revolving receive"?
Yeah…
It was probably because you sprained your ankle and couldn't perform it very well.
He might've even said it because you lost the game.
That must be it.
I don't think that's it.
I think it's something more fundamental.
But what is it?
Neither me nor Professor can tell.
Even I don't think that my revolving receive is as good as it should be.
That's why I missed Kakinouchi-san's spike back then.
She knew my weakness and used the underhand twist.
But I'm confident I could accept that spike now.
And yet, that man said that it wasn't a real receive…
That Inokuma guy has been all around the world, to places like the Soviet Union and Europe, right?
Yeah.
He seems to have been coaching volleyball for a long time in all sorts of places.
But nobody knows anything specific.
The only thing we know for sure is that
he coached the North Korean college team.
Hm?
Well, different countries have different volleyball.
True. Take Shellenina's Soviet team for example.
There are so many amazing things in
the world that we do not know yet.
Studying during breaks?
You're too much.
Not really. I'm not studying.
It's October already.
We need to take the high school entrance exams right after New Year's.
So we can't stay relaxed, can we.
I have to follow your lead, Kozue.
I told you I'm not studying.
What about this?
"The history of volleyball"?
Why are you reading that book now?
Nothing in particular, I just want to know more about volleyball.
I'd say history has nothing to do with us, though.
But is it really okay for us if we only practice and play matches?
Shouldn't we know more about the sport we're playing?
I guess…
Now that you mention it,
we really do only play volleyball.
There are so many things I don't know.
When was volleyball invented?
Where did it start?
I suppose I'll have to study with you, if you insist so much.
But I never insisted on anything.
Captain!
– Captain.
– What's wrong, Kakko?
This is no time for relaxing.
Naka and Okei want to quit the club.
– Eh?
Quit?
That's right. It's not an easy decision.
I was planning to talk it over with Captain.
We want to enter
Fujimi High School no matter what.
We want to play volleyball at high school too.
But to do so we need to take a
break and study for the exams.
Captain and Midori are safe since they've got good grades.
But I'm not that good. I don't know if I can pass even if I try hard from now on. It's no joke.
– Ofuku and Yukie said the same.
– T-They did, huh?
Let's all meet after school and talk it through, okay?
Yeah. Good idea.
Volleyball club's room
Professor agrees that you should focus on your studying.
It can't be helped with the exams
right around the corner.
I'm also going to study for entrance exams.
At any rate, I'll keep doing my best until graduation.
After all, we need to oversee
the first and second years' practices too.
Then that makes Captain, Midori, and me the only seniors that are left.
That's fine. Everyone, study hard.
I'm not going to high school, so I will take over your duties.
Besides, I'd like to play volleyball all that I can before I graduate.
After that I'll need to help my folks and won't get to play anymore.
Why don't you form a team in your town?
I'll be too busy with the restaurant.
Me too. I'm being sent to another school,
so I won't be able to play volleyball with you girls.
Even if we play volleyball in high school, it's going to fall apart all over again when the school ends.
And the same goes for if we play in university…
Even I don't know how long I can play volleyball.
No matter how much we struggle,
a woman is only free until marriage.
I guess you're right. I'm starting to feel a little lonely now.
"Only free until marriage"? Nonsense.
Don't you know how popular volleyball moms are now?
Geez, a little bit of autumn and everyone gets all sentimental.
You're better than that, girls.
Come on? Ah…
Teacher's office
Nakazawa, Fukuda, Ikezaki.
Ooki. Kudou. Katori.
Ozawa.
Those are all that want to quit?
Yes sir.
Very well. Thank you.
Ah, Ayuhara!
Wait a moment.
Why don't we go together?
Who are you going to enter the Fujimi High School with?
I'm not sure yet, but I think it'll be Hayakawa-san, Nakazawa-san, Kudou-san and Katori-san.
That makes it only half of the current team.
Yeah…
My teammates are leaving me one by one.
It makes me wonder for how long
can I play volleyball myself.
No matter the sport, it isn't easy to keep on with it.
It's a tough and difficult business.
Ayuhara, if you're not in a
hurry, why don't you come by my house for a moment?
I'd like to show you something.
Hongou family
This is it.
Oh, is that you, Professor?
Yep.
From when I was at university.
Do you recognize the person I'm sitting next to?
I don't. Who is it?
Does it ring a bell if you imagine him with sunglasses and a beard?
Sunglasses…
So, he's…?
Yep.
That bright, carefree face belongs to none other than Inokuma Daigo himself.
It feels like that was centuries ago…
…but I went to university with him.
I made friends with him in no time.
He was always funny and cheerful.
He would be late to classes…
And would fall asleep in the classroom.
But that's just the kind of guy he was.
I was in the baseball club.
He was in the volleyball club.
It was once he started playing volleyball that he changed.
As an attacker, he was an excellent player.
He was really absorbed in the practices and became famed as the "Volleyball Demon".
He was fixated on the goal of winning against a rival school that we couldn't defeat before.
It gets worse from there.
That wasn't normal anymore.
Under construction
He behaved so scary that I was afraid to talk to him.
But later I learned that…
…the reason he changed was because
his father got sick and passed away shortly after.
I don't think the grief from his father's death was the only reason, though.
His mother died when he was still little, so he was left alone with his little sister.
Something in him changed forever.
The match against his rival was approaching.
As the team's captain, he became a real demon.
Regular members collapsed left and right.
Many of them were unable to play volleyball ever again.
In the end, the team couldn't participate in the league game that year.
It was because that man destroyed his team.
With his killer spike.
He hurt his right hand in the process, and it seemed he wouldn't be able to play volleyball anymore.
Eventually, he parted his ways with the volleyball club…
…and disappeared without waiting for graduation.
He ended up all alone.
That's the kind of guy he was…
It's difficult to go that far.
It's not the same as simply loving or playing sports.
He made it his purpose in life. Can we really go that far?
How far can I go?
"That wasn't revolving receive."
What the heck is missing?
I don't understand what he meant yet.
Professor…?
Let's go together.
As far as we can.
Yes sir.
– Watch out, here goes!
– Roger!
All right.
That's enough.
Wipe your sweat, girls.
– It's tough.
– Ah, I'm dying.
All right, line up before the net once you've rested.
– Okay!
Kakko, I see you're working hard.
Well, I was serious when I promised to take over the responsibilities.
I'll see it through until I graduate.
After all, we've got just a couple of months left.
Let's do our best!
– Please take care of us!
Let's resume!
Once more.
A little higher.
Kozue.
Let's go.
Ayuhara! Hayakawa!
– Yes?
– Sir?
A letter from the Volleyball Association came in just now.
Ayuhara and Hayakawa were chosen for the Junior High Girls Volleyball All-Japan Best Twelve.
All-Japan Best Twelve?
– That's right.
– A-Ah… Uhm…
What is it, Ayuhara?
By the "Best Twelve", they mean…
Those twelve will represent Japan and for the first time participate…
…in the World Junior Volleyball Championship, which will be held in the United States.
– World Championship?
I have the letter here with me.
But, that's…
To prepare the representatives for the championship…
…there will be a training camp held for one month in Miyazaki, Kyūshū.
You'll hone your teamwork and condition there,
and then fly from Haneda to America.
– Awesome!
– As expected!
Hey, do your best!
You're now Japan's representatives!
I'm so happy.
– Amazing!
– Captain Ayuhara! Congratulations!
Midori.
Kozue.
That wasn't a revolving receive.
That wasn't a revolving receive!
Eh?
Kozue and Midori are chosen as representatives for the world championship.
They participate in the strengthening camp under Coach Inokuma.
Coach makes them do hundreds of receives every day.
But can they form a team that can challenge the world in a single month?
The players' trust in Coach Inokuma is rapidly dropping as he can see nothing but work.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.