苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 027—
11 rivals
Ayuhara! Hayakawa!
Sir.
A letter from the Volleyball Association came in just now.
Ayuhara and Hayakawa were chosen for the Junior High Girls Volleyball All-Japan Best Twelve.
All-Japan Best Twelve?
Best Twelve…
That's right.
A-Ah… Uhm…
What is it?
By the "Best Twelve", they mean…
Those twelve will represent Japan and for the first time participate…
…in the World Junior Volleyball Championship held in the United States.
– World Championship?
I have the letter here with me.
But, to prepare the representatives for the championship…
…there will be a training camp held for one month in Miyazaki, Kyuushuu.
You'll hone your teamwork and condition there, and then fly from Haneda to America.
– United States!
– Awesome!
Hey, do your best!
You're now Japan's representatives!
I'm so happy, I don't know what to say!
– Wah! Congratulations!
– Great!
Midori.
Kozue.
Do your best!
World Junior Volleyball Championship
Ayuhara Kozue · Hayakawa Midori farewell party
Hosted by Fujimi Academy · Student Council · PTA · Teachers office
The fact that both of you were selected as Japan's representatives…
…makes proud not only the volleyball team, but everyone here at Fujimi Academy…
…and is a great honor to all of us.
We pray for the Fujimi Academy's stars' radiance to keep on shining.
Your hard work has greatly contributed to the academy's growth.
We wish you the best results.
Finally, let's give them words of encouragement on the road to Miyazaki.
Go! Go! Ayuhara!
Come on!
Go! Go! Hayakawa!
What is it, mama?
Just look how far our Kozue goes.
She represents the whole Japan now.
It feels like a dream.
World championships.
I bet Shellenina will show up there as well.
No, other than Shellenina, what kind of enemies will we meet?
No matter what, I'll do my best. I'll aim for the glory of being the world's best.
The train restlessly continued its journey.
The first stop was at Miyazaki, Kyuushuu.
But their true destination was far away in America.
What was that?
I just thought of making a poem.
Hey, maybe I have some hidden writing talent?
Hmm.
Who knows, maybe it'd be even better than your volleyball?
Oh? You're pulling my leg.
Hehe.
I can't stop wondering what kind of people will we end up at the training camp with.
I'm sure Fukuoka's Kakinouchi-san was chosen too.
I am a bit anxious about that.
– Anxious?
– Yep.
Can we really make a team with people we barely know in just a single month?
I understand where you're coming from, but that's coach's duty.
Hey, what do you think the coach from the association is going to be like?
I'm fine with tough training, but he must be kind and handsome… at least as much as professor Hongou.
Wah, "at least"? Professor Hongou wouldn't be thrilled to hear you now.
Fufu.
But really, who will we end up with?
It sure feels like south.
Yeah. It's bright and dazzling.
Look, Midori, we're finally here.
Right before Miyazaki Academy's gym.
So this is where we stay for the whole month.
Let's go.
Yeah.
Midori, the others are here already.
– Ayuhara-san!
– Long time no see!
Ah, Kakinouchi-san. And you too, Yoshimura-san.
So you were chosen as well.
I never doubted I'll see you here with us.
I was afraid we won't get to play together again.
I'm so happy.
Let's do our best.
– Yeah!
– Yeah.
– Let's do our best.
– Let's do it together.
Agreed.
Who is this girl?
Why is she looking at me with such a scary look?
Everyone, line up!
– Yes sir!
Ah?
I know, Kozue.
That man… it can't be…
Don't you understand what "everyone, line up" means?
– Yes sir!
I am your new coach. My name's Inokuma Daigo.
Inokuma!?
That wasn't a revolving receive.
Eh?
It was just a somersault.
It wasn't a receive.
Do you know what is missing?
Of course you don't.
If we ever get to see each other again, then I will tell you what it is.
What's wrong?
You were chosen among the best to be Japan's representatives.
On top of that, you're aiming for the world's best.
This camp will train you for a month.
Hopefully you're aware it won't be a normal training.
Be prepared.
What's with his right arm?
Welcome, girls.
My name's Matsumoto. I will be taking care of your classes and everyday life.
Likewise, my name's Kawakita.
I'd like to let you play your favorite volleyball all you want…
…but I'm afraid we can't let you forget your studies for the whole month.
Please don't hate us for that.
You'll be waking up at six in the morning.
Then you'll have five hours of personal practices.
In the afternoon, you'll have classes for four hours.
After that, team training until evening.
On Sundays you'll do practice matches with various teams.
Whoa, not even a single day off?
After you unpack your luggage…
…change into your uniforms.
Then get back here at once.
That's all.
This is where you'll be staying.
Meals are served at the dining hall.
If there's anything you do not understand, don't hesitate to ask me.
– Yes ma'am.
What a pretty room.
Whoa!
Who would think? It's my first time sleeping on a bed.
It's all bouncy.
It's so soft too.
Big deal.
What a country lass.
How did she manage to get in here?
I wonder what coach Inokuma is like.
Kozue, you know him, don't you?
Oh? No, not really.
Hey, hey, what's the deal with coach Inokuma?
I mean, why does he wear sunglasses indoors?
He can't use his right arm. Can he really play volleyball?
He's left handed.
Hey!
What are you gossiping about?
If you've got something to say, I'm all ears.
I heard you before and didn't say a word, but… what was that about having no day off?
You've got some nerve.
Listen well.
I'll say this just once. I'm not here to teach a bunch of princesses.
I don't care if you're girls.
The only thing that matters to
me is to make you world's best.
The best in the world!
Therefore, people who can't keep up…
…and people who are useless will be sent straight home.
Got it?
Where's your response!?
– Yes sir!
Very well.
Well then, introduce yourselves one
by
one and name your special techniques.
I'm Arai Tomoe of Naniwa Middle School.
I'm particularly good at blocking.
Good.
Let's see you block my spike.
Yes sir.
Somebody, toss the ball at me.
Sir.
Here we go!
Ready!
Throwing her a spike with all he's got…
The opponent is a man. A famous attacker on top of that.
There's no way for me to accept such a ball.
A-Arai-san.
– Don't approach her!
– Huh?
Where do you think you are?
This is the court you've gambled your life on.
This is where you need to do your utmost, even if it's practice.
Those defeated by the game shouldn't rely on the help from the others.
If you can't practice without getting help from others, you're not fit for this game.
The playing field is not a bed.
If you want to sleep, then get back to your room.
Arai-san, hang in there.
This…
…is nothing.
Arai-san, you did well.
I'm so dead.
Next!
"Well done" or whatever… just say anything to Arai-san.
What kind of merciless eyes hide behind those sunglasses?
That man destroyed his team.
With his killer spike.
I'm Mishima Junko of Mito Middle School.
My specialty is curve ball.
Awesome curve!
Ah!
Ah…
Next!
Sir.
I'm Kitami Ritsuko of Asahigawa Middle School.
Iwate Academy, Miyatsu Tomoe.
Hiroshima Middle School, Noda Sachiko.
Kouchi Academy, Ootsuki Hitomi.
Gifu Middle School, Shirakawa Teruko.
Meihou Academy, Yoshimura Satomi.
My specialty is receiving of curve ball serves.
All right, let's see.
Ah!
Shoot!
Yoshimura-san, you're bleeding.
I'm okay.
But it was a great serve.
As expected from our representative.
She won't admit defeat to anyone.
But why does Inokuma coach go through all this?
Fukuoka Middle School, Kakinouchi Yoshiko.
My specialty are curve balls.
That's the spike that defeated me.
Yokohama Second Middle School,
Sanjou Michiru. My strong point…
…is long spike!
Sanjou-san, hang in there!
Wh-What?
This is nothing.
Next!
Fujimi Academy, Hayakawa Midori.
My strong point is spike.
Same Fujimi Academy, Ayuhara Kozue.
My specialty is…
…revolving receive, I presume.
– Okay. Show it to me.
– Yes sir.
– Midori, let's not screw this up.
– Yeah.
Ah!
Kozue!
– Ayuhara-san!
– Are you hurt?
I'm fine, thanks.
But this is the first time I see a
spike so fast and powerful.
Everyone has shown their tricks.
Now forget them!
– Eh?
What you think is your specialty…
…in my eyes is your weakness.
A fatal one at that.
Wow.
– What a thing to say.
– Tell us what's wrong with it.
You can't even figure it out by yourself?
Haven't I just showed a hint to each of you?
Well, duh. Of course our techniques won't work against a coach.
Don't you think so too?
Listen.
You'll be under my care from today on.
Therefore, I'm going to train you my way.
The half-baked skills you've learned so far…
…will only get in my way.
Are you serious?
Half-baked, you say?
I'll rebuild your skill from the ground up.
The one who guides you is me.
I'm nothing like your previous coaches.
You won't forget Inokuma for a long time.
Also it should go without saying, but your past experience doesn't matter.
The results of my training will determine the best members.
Best members.
Best members…
Best members!
That's all for today.
The coach's even scarier than what you'd think from the beard and sunglasses.
He's scary, all right.
More importantly, he's so cheeky.
"Your specialty is your worst weakness.", my foot.
Come on. He's just bluffing.
– Bluffing?
– Ayup.
In short, he claims we're full
of weak points to put us on our feet.
I wonder about that.
Ayuhara-san, what do you think?
I hope that's the case.
But for some reason I don't think this is it.
Our coach has been leading us by our noses many times by now.
Also, we've participated in an university training camp once before.
We can get through anything.
Right, Kozue?
The question is, who among the twelve of us will be selected as the best members.
Of course, other than me and Ayuhara Kozue.
Midori, don't.
Ah, right.
Everyone wants to get selected.
Fufu.
Well said, Hayakawa-san.
I understand how you want your captain to be elected.
But I'd rather you weren't in the final six.
What did you say?
I never saw any of your matches.
But I heard about Ayuhara-san.
How she's a tough ambidextrous attacker.
But just because your team won one time and got to the finals another…
…doesn't actually say much about your strength.
In volleyball, individual strength doesn't matter.
I'm a good example of that.
No matter how good I am, because the others weren't good enough has costed me victory twice.
Who is this girl?
She's Sanjou-san from Yokohama.
Ah, I remember.
Had they won in the third round, they'd have to face us.
They had only one good player. So that was Sanjou-san, huh?
Hey, now that I think of it, we heard something similar too, didn't we?
Sanjou-san, why don't we become friends?
Let's work hard as the Japan's representatives.
We're not representatives yet, though.
Until we are, we're enemies.
Enemies?
Everyone is desperate to become regulars.
In other words, everyone except yourself is your enemy.
Everyone except myself is an enemy…
One-two! One-two! One-two!
Come on! One more lapse!
Lift your legs higher!
Hey!
What do you think you're doing?
Are you defeated with just this?
Suddenly making us run 10 kilometers…
We're not in Sparta, are we?
Ma'am!
Please give us some water!
Not a chance.
Eh?
I can't give you girls anything while you're in practice. Professor Inokuma said so.
Ah.
Now we do hundred receives.
Hundred?
What a hard training.
Nice way to put it.
What's with that look?
58.
59.
60.
What's with you?
You can't accept such a ball?
But the ball's too f—
– Don't you complain!
– Yes sir!
Ahh!
– Mishima, pack your things.
– Eh?
Don't you get what you're told?
I'm telling you to get back to Mito at once.
I apologize, sir.
I'll take any training.
I won't complain.
Please forgive me just this once.
All right, who's next?
I'm begging you, sir!
I can't let down my friends at school and my parents expectations.
Please, punish me anyhow, but don't send me back.
Volleyball isn't for schoolmates nor your family's sake.
I'm sure Mishima will understand that well enough in future practices.
I'm making a special exception for you today.
If I ever hear you whining again, you're flying home.
Yes sir!
Good. Next!
Sir!
Day 8
Day 9
Day 10
What's wrong, girls?
Aren't you going to eat?
Maybe they're too tired and don't have an appetite.
Delicious!
Food tastes best after exercise.
Ah…
Let's get her to infirmary at once!
Incorrigible gal as ever.
I guess Mishima lost her chance to get elected as the best member next week.
Ah?
Best member.
Fufu.
I hope everyone gets exhausted.
I will last much longer.
I won't lose.
Me neither.
I will get elected into best members.
But… But I need to do something before.
Enter.
That was Ayuhara Kozue, no mistake.
What the heck?
What's she trying to pull by visiting Inokuma at this hour?
What if…
What if?
Kozue's love for volleyball is challenged…
…by Sanjou, who harbors an irrational hatred to her.
She opposes Kozue not stopping at anything.
Why does Sanjou bear such an animosity towards volleyball?
Sanjou's past reveals an unexpected secret.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.