苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 028—
Between light and dark
Do we really have to practice so hard?
Yeah, it's way too much.
I don't mean to whine, but I'm not really sure if I can do this.
Coach Inokuma.
Unlike the girls, I already knew of his bullying.
That man destroyed his own team with his monstrous training.
He's known as the "volleyball demon".
"Volleyball demon".
Who is it?
Ayuhara Kozue.
I want to speak to you, sir.
Step inside.
Ayuhara-san's entering the coach's room…?
Sir, I know we've been chosen for the world championships.
But we're still middle schoolers. We're just young girls.
Your training is too hard.
At this rate, we'll just…
Ah.
Finish the sentence.
U-Uhm…
I'm afraid we'll fall apart.
That's right. I know all about your hard training destroying a team once before.
I-I want us to become strong too.
But…
But I'd hate to see us fall apart.
What else did Hongou tell you?
That's all I know…
Of course I didn't tell anyone.
So…
So?
Ayuhara!
S-Sir?
What's with this attitude?
Stop being so conceited.
I will repeat it again.
Your revolving receive.
That's no receive. It's a mere gymnastics trick.
A mere trick?
It's just showboating.
And anyone who wants me to acknowledge such thing…
…only makes me sick.
Ah!
M-My revolving receive…?
It can't be!
That's too cruel. How can he call my blood spilling training, everything… a zero?
Revolving receive…
All my effort so far… a zero!
Ayuhara-san.
You're pretty sly.
Sanjou-san?
Oh, you were crying?
I'm sorry.
Looks like your little plan has failed.
Hahaha.
Sanjou-san.
What are you trying to imply?
Nothing in particular.
Don't go getting any funny ideas.
I only—
I've heard enough.
Sanjou-san!
Ayuhara-san.
I'll warn you just this once.
The best members will be chosen based on their true skills.
Huh…?
Sanjou-san!
What the heck does she know?
At this rate it's possible I'll get expelled from this training camp.
I can't believe it.
Telling me to quit volleyball feels like a death sentence.
If this is a dream, please wake me up.
I'm too afraid of tomorrow.
Do your day dreaming somewhere else.
This is a volleyball court.
Here you focus only on volleyball.
Understood?
So it wasn't a dream after all.
Ah!
Ah, Kozue!
Kozue, are you all right?
Who told you to help her?
– You fool!
– Ah!
I don't remember telling you to take a break!
Y-Yes sir!
This isn't a dream.
It's reality.
How pitiful.
Fufu.
Ayuhara-san's already done for.
And the others are trembling too.
But I won't succumb to this.
This isn't the place to be thinking.
I need to keep focused on practice.
That's all there is to it.
Let's go!
He sees every detail despite his sunglasses.
No good!
I won't lose.
Not to Ayuhara-san, not to Kakinouchi-san, not to anyone.
Next!
All right. That's all for today.
Your good-for-nothing receiving skills won't win us anything.
What we need is an aggressive attack.
Especially you, Ayuhara.
And Kakinouchi, you missed a lot too.
Eh?
If this repeats tomorrow, you're going home.
Maybe I deserve it, but Kakinouchi-san?
And Sanjou comes out unscathed again.
Heh.
Kakinouchi. Don't forget my warning.
Dismissed.
Ayuhara-san.
– I'm hungry. Let's grab lunch.
– Okay.
Thank you.
Ah, Kozue.
I'll be in our room.
Yesterday night must have been a shock for her.
Hey, hey, did something happen yesterday?
Huh?
Yeah…
– But…
– It's probably a secret, huh?
Never mind.
It's none of my business.
Well, now I'm curious all the more.
Hey.
Stop beating around the bush.
Spit it out already.
Very well.
I thought mentioning it would shame Ayuhara-san, so I stayed silent.
Your revolving receive
is nothing but a gymnastics trick.
Especially you, Ayuhara. If this repeats tomorrow, you're going home.
No way. I'm not going home.
I won't give up so easily. I won't be sent home.
Kozue, you visited the coach
in his room yesterday, didn't you?
Yes. What of it?
Please answer me honestly.
What were you talking about?
Why are you asking?
Before I tell you, please answer honestly.
Okay.
I talked to him about our training being too hard.
That's all?
No.
He also told me how my revolving receive is useless.
Huh?
So that's what happened.
I was wondering why you weren't yourself.
But that means Sanjou-san…
Sanjou-san?
She said you tried to butter up the coach.
No! She's got the wrong idea, Midori.
Relax, I believe you.
But I can't say the same about the others.
What a backstabber.
I won't forgive her.
So what's your next move, Kozue?
I'll… I will confront Sanjou-san.
I want you to take your words back in front of everyone, right now.
I refuse.
I only spoke the truth.
I can't control how people interpret it.
That's not fair.
Watch your mouth.
Even if it was a misunderstanding, you should think about how you're acting right now.
Like you could ever understand
the shock of being told you're useless.
Everything I've done so far was just dismissed as a failure.
And now you with your little schemes.
Don't be naive.
The coach only told the truth, what's so surprising about that?
– What did you say?
– Am I wrong?
This isn't the place for a princess like you.
Princess?
You should go home.
You're not even fit to compete with me, let alone be picked as a best member.
Hmph.
Sanjou-san!
Ah!
Ah.
Now you've done it!
You don't understand me either way.
What the hell!
You wanna fight?
Kozue!
I'll help you out!
Stay out of this!
How dare you!
You fools!
I don't care who started it.
As a punishment, you're both doing 50 bunny hops.
I won't lose to you.
We haven't settled this yet.
Of course.
I will get back at you. Just wait.
What a vengeful girl.
I won't lose to her.
I'll accept Sanjou-san's challenge any time.
Ah.
Kozue, are you all right?
Yeah. Thanks.
I'm fine.
Ayuhara-san!
We're sorry. Midori-san told us everything.
We completely misjudged you.
I'm really sorry.
It's okay.
As long as you understand.
But really, that Sanjou-san is such a…
Yeah, she saw how we were all nervous and used it to her advantage.
Oh, look, speak of the devil.
Sanjou-san!
Ayuhara-san.
Looks like pity has given you some new followers.
But friends won't improve your skill.
Call me how you want, I'm still stronger.
What a jerk.
She's challenging me.
We're ready to help.
I'll help too.
Wait.
I need to deal with this on my own.
It's between me and Sanjou-san.
That's right. She hates me.
I can't think otherwise.
But, right now, I'm not a worthy opponent to her… I am worthless at volleyball, after all.
Ayuhara-san.
I hate you.
You and your complete trust in volleyball.
Just like this ball.
I'll make you hate it too.
I'll make it so that you won't want to hit this ball ever again.
She passed it to me!
You were dozing off.
This is our battle.
I won't lose. Not to you.
Ayuhara-san!
– Catch!
– Got it!
Hey, you.
Why aren't you passing to me?
Hmph.
It's because you're dozing off.
Fufu.
So be it.
Okay, everyone, come here.
We'll practice receiving.
Receiving.
Finally.
I have a question to you.
The volleyball court measures 9 m × 9 m.
The defensive range for one player is… Hayakawa?
Ah.
Sir. Um…
Um… each person…
…has to cover about… 3
meters, I guess. Right, Kozue?
To be precise, it's 3
meters high and 4.5
meters long.
Wow, how calculated.
That is how you played until now.
But my way is different.
From now on, your zone will span 3 meters in height…
…and 4.5 meters - plus alpha - in length.
There was no "plus alpha" in the defense range professor Hongou taught us about.
That "alpha" comes from how the boundary between the defense ranges…
…are prone to attacks.
Wow, that's impossible.
It sounds nice in theory though.
P-Please forget what I've just said.
From now on, each person will be responsible for their zone.
Got it? Those who can't do it are sent home.
All right!
– Now that we understand each other, begin!
– Yes sir!
I guess I can't use my revolving receive.
I've been pushed into yet another nightmare.
What a useless receiving technique.
Or rather, this exercise will show how far your skill goes, Ayuhara-san.
No matter what I try, it's hopeless.
So let's see how far I can go from the ground up.
Fufufu.
Hit… hit with all I've got…
That is my way.
This is the limit to the volleyball I've believed in so far.
Next!
Everyone avoids Sanjou-san,
and yet she shows so much spirit.
No.
That just might be her reason.
That's not it!
It's almost as if she's battling volleyball itself.
She's desperately trying to fight.
I hate you all.
And this white ball too…
Volleyball too…
Your devotion to it, Ayuhara-san…
I hate you!
What are you holding?
A torn volleyball? Charms don't really seem like your style.
It's none of your business.
Wait.
Leave me alone.
Don't associate with me.
Seeing your face makes me sick.
To be honest, your belief in volleyball is just laughable.
Hahaha.
Sanjou-san?
There's something deeper going on.
There must be a reason why she hates me… or rather volleyball.
And the key must be hidden in that old torn ball.
I hate volleyball.
My brother…
I will never forgive volleyball for taking my brother away.
I was about five then.
Waah!
– Ah, it's the orphan!
– Yo! – Wah!
Oh, where, where are Michiru's parents?
Nowhere, nowhere, cause she's parentless!
Waah!
Why did you come here?
Say something!
Shut up!
Ah, she's mad, she's mad, she's mad!
Adopted kid, adopted kid!
Wait!
Oh, where, where are Michiru's parents?
– Nowhere, nowhere…
– This way!
Michiru!
It isn't playtime!
Once you've collected water, wash the clothes.
Yes ma'am.
I thought about jumping in the river over and over.
Then I'd be able to meet Mom and Dad in heaven.
Brother!
Michiru.
How have you been?
Ichiro.
Tears of joy just for me, huh?
Hehe.
My uncle only took me under his roof. In that house…
…it was my only joy.
I always looked forward
to seeing my older brother, Ichiro.
Is this really possible?
Has your brother ever lied to you?
– Nope.
– Well, there you have it.
Let's be patient. Just six more months.
Then I'll graduate from university.
I've already secured a proper job.
Then I get to live together with you, right?
Yes.
We'll be living together.
Yay!
I'm so glad!
Then, after three months…
I was suddenly taken into an orphanage.
Harmony Preschool
It was about two weeks after
my uncle died in a traffic accident.
Thank you.
Brother.
Save me.
Brother!
I received a letter from my brother's university.
It said that he has gone missing.
The reason has been believed to be linked to an accident in the volleyball club.
Give back my brother!
Give him back!
Give me my brother back!
I hated volleyball.
Volleyball robbed me of my older brother.
Volleyball extinguished my hope.
Shortly afterwards, I entered the Sanjou family.
And I kept the cut volleyball.
I hate volleyball.
Volleyball that took my older brother to God knows where.
That's why I chose the way of volleyball.
It's revenge.
It's to get back.
To avenge my brother.
Damn you, volleyball!
Damn you, bro!
That's Sanjou-san.
Screw this game!
Seems I was right…
Ah.
Who's there?
Show yourself.
Ayuhara-san?
I understood a little about your charm.
What did you understand?
You hate volleyball.
That's why you hate me, who loves volleyball.
Exactly.
That's why people who love it make me sick.
And yet you're playing it yourself.
Why?
That's none of your business.
However…
I will win against you.
That's all.
Sanjou-san.
I won't lose to you.
I won't lose to someone who hates volleyball with all her heart.
I won't lose.
I've always loved volleyball.
Kitami and Shirakawa can't put up with the special training's pace…
…and with the words: "Inokuma's a demon, not a human", escape the camp premises.
Finally, the first dropout that Kozue and the girls were afraid of.
At this rate, they'll lose to Coach Inokuma's training before having a chance to take on the world.
Despair begins to grow within the team.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.