苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 029—
Miserable training
It looks like everyone is getting more and more tense.
It feels like we're falling apart.
Sanjou-san. I won't lose to you or your hatred.
I will protect the volleyball I love until the end.
Ah! It's the coach!
We'll be holding a test now.
It will go as I said before.
You'll be defending a zone 3 meters high and 4.5 meters - plus alpha - long.
Ah.
I expect each of you to put in as much effort as possible.
Let's start. Kakinouchi!
Yes sir!
Here we go!
Next!
Shirakawa!
Yes sir!
Next! Sanjou!
Next! Mishima!
Yes sir!
Ayuhara!
When did she…?
She's actually pretty good.
Arai!
Coming!
Sanjou.
– Yes.
– Kakinouchi.
Sir?
Ayuhara.
You three will practice spikes.
Hayakawa, Yoshimura and Arai will practice serving.
– Yes sir!
The remaining six will do a hundred receives each.
– Huh?
– A hundred?
– Shirakawa!
– Yes sir!
Here we go!
Fiftieth ball!
Ah, wait!
Wait— ow!
No!
T-This is too cruel. I can't keep up.
Stop! Stop it! Ahh!
I'm begging you, please stop, sir.
Shirakawa. Get out of here.
Heh.
– To hell with this!
– Shirakawa-san!
– Leave her! Next!
– Yes sir.
Yes sir!
Let's go!
Pay attention!
Mishima!
Sir!?
You need special training!
Huh?
Rather than plus alpha,
your zone spans minus alpha!
You need to train until you catch up to the rest.
No breaks.
Yes sir…
Poor thing.
– Mishima-san's all alone.
– Ayuhara-san.
But at this rate, Mishima-san's gonna…
Wimps that can't keep up with such a simple training should go home.
Hmph.
I can't stand her.
What a mess.
I said from the start that this training was reckless.
Yeah.
Our coach is a demon.
He's just not human.
Even we have our boundaries.
I get that he's doing all of this to motivate us, but it's all so inhuman.
Wait a sec.
You should've known from the beginning that it was going to be a little hard.
Stop criticizing the coach.
Shirakawa-san, we're the Japanese national team, so stop crying and pull yourself together.
But…
But…!
You can do it. I know you can.
Mess Hall
What's wrong, Mishima?
Sir…
Get a grip!
Yes sir!
Stand up!
Stand up, damn it!
Sir…!
All right. That's all for today.
But you still have special training every day until we get rid of that minus.
– Mishima-san!
– Mishima-san.
Are you okay?
Demon! Our coach is a demon!
Don't lose to him. Come on, you're better than this.
It's hopeless. I can't get any better.
– That's not true.
– I've had enough!
I don't want to play this kind of volleyball.
Don't lose your spirit.
It's no good. I want to go home.
I have no idea how to help her. She's so broken.
Well, it's no surprise.
If I had to practice without breaks, I'd go mad, too.
But, if you go home now, what will your family say?
Hehehe.
Your sympathy doesn't make a difference, Ayuhara-san.
And Hayakawa-san, don't act like you're not happy to see more people fall behind.
Am I wrong?
Sanjou-san, what are you insinuating?
It's simple math even primary school kids can do.
The chance to become a best member gets higher the more people drop out.
Hehe. Hahaha!
Mishima-san. Don't pay attention to Sanjou-san.
Okay?
Us Japanese girls don't have
the physical fitness that foreigners do.
The 3 meters that are so difficult for us to reach, are a breeze for foreigners.
You understand that, right?
To compensate for our stature, we need hard training and the "plus alpha".
We can't afford settling for
the same training our opponents do.
Come on, tomorrow is another day.
Let's rest and do our best in the coach's special training.
Huh?
Kozue!?
Ah, it's just you, Midori. You startled me.
You're one to talk. Where are you going?
– I'm not sure yet. Just follow me for now.
– Okay.
Huh?
– That's…
– Sanjou-san.
Let's follow her.
It's a store room.
What is she doing in there?
Amazing!
That must weight 20 kg.
Why is she doing this?
It has nothing to do with volleyball.
I'll bet she's exercising her arms.
She was probably has practicing this at her own school, too.
Her obsession with volleyball is terrifying.
Why is she so obsessed about it?
I don't know either.
What hides behind her hatred?
I'm starting to feel uneasy.
Come on, let's head back.
Okay, who can solve this problem?
Hm?
Hey! Sanjou!
Sanjou!
S-Sir?
This is not your bedroom.
You should have plenty of time to sleep.
Everyone else is doing well.
So why are you the only who falls asleep?
There's no excuse for your behavior.
I'm going to speak with Coach Inokuma.
T-There's no need to, sir.
It won't happen again, sir.
Ah…!
Shirakawa-san?
Practice proceeds as usual.
Ayuhara, Sanjou, Kakinouchi - spike.
Hayakawa, Yoshimura, Arai - serving.
The others - a hundred receives.
– Yes sir!
Begin!
Ah, it hurts.
Okay, go. Next, Mishima!
Sir.
It's the team Coach Inokuma has destroyed all over again.
Ayuhara-san, it's your turn.
Oh?
Hey! No relaxing!
Stand up!
Stand up at once!
Hey!
Who told you to stop?
Continue with the practice!
You two take Mishima to the infirmary.
– Yes sir.
Hehe.
You all just keep on falling down.
I'm the only one who can put up with this.
Now it's your turn.
Assume positions.
– Ayuhara.
– Sir!
– Kakinouchi.
– Sir.
Go—ow, ow, ow.
Owie.
What a powerful spike.
When did she learn it?
Hehehehe.
Arai.
You don't need to say anything, sir. But Sanjou-san's spike is dangerous.
I'm afraid she'll break my wrist.
What did you say?
It's true that Sanjou's spike is intense.
She's the strongest among those three.
But that kind of spike is completely normal among the foreign players.
What are you going to do if your wrist can't take it?
Coach. Are you saying my spike would be average in foreign countries?
Precisely.
You have the strength of a foreigner.
But your fatal weakness is your lack of jumping power.
I-I can't believe it.
So, no matter how strong your spike is…
…blocking it will be a piece of cake for the tall Soviet Union players.
It's the same for Ayuhara. While she might possess outstanding jumping power…
– …her spike is nowhere near Sanjou's.
– Yes sir.
Humans are full of flaws.
But I will not allow any of them.
Fix your flaws with your power.
Infirmary
Shirakawa-san, what's wrong?
Oh, I can't bear this any longer. It's hopeless.
I'll go crazy if this continues.
I love volleyball.
I have so much fun playing it.
But where's the fun in playing under Coach Inokuma?
There's only pain.
Shirakawa-san, let's get out of here.
Huh?
Let's get out of here together.
If we stay here and continue to
play, our bodies will only break more.
I don't think anyone can take so much training at once.
You're right.
We're still middle school students.
There's a limit to what we can do.
Exactly.
Let's get out of here, quick.
And let's take Mishima-san with us, too.
Mishima-san, we've decided to escape.
Why don't you come with us?
Huh?
Mishima-san, we're doing this for everyone's sake.
Someone has to tell the world about Coach Inokuma's ways.
If the school learns about his outrageously hard training, they won't stay silent.
Yeah.
Somebody has to tell them.
I'm going to see Mishima-san and the others.
I'll go with you.
Me too.
Hmph.
Infirmary
Huh?
They're not here.
Don't tell me…
I think so…
Ayuhara-san, we've got to report this.
Yes. Let's get the teachers.
Why do you care about them?
If you have so much free time, use it to train.
Hmph.
Coach! Coach!
Excuse us.
Huh?
He's not here either?
Ayuhara, jumping power.
Sanjou, spike.
Kakinouchi, attack.
Each one of them possesses a different quality.
And each one has different flaws.
If it goes well, they might form an interesting attack combination.
But I wonder if there's a way to make it succeed.
– Coach!
Coach…!
Coach! We've got trouble!
Um, Shirakawa-san, Mishima-san and Kitami-san have gone missing.
Hm?
– Coach!?
Do you really have time to babysit other people?
If you have so much free time, why aren't you using it to train?
Wow…
There's no choice but to wait for Shirakawa-san and the girls to think it over and come back.
The train going to Ōsaka will be departing in a short while.
This is the final boarding call for passengers.
Mishima-san, hurry up!
We don't have much time!
Mishima-san, what is it?
Mishima-san, what's wrong?
I won't lose. I won't lose!
Ah?
Ah…?
Mishima-san…?
There's no way I'm going to lose.
I'm going back.
Mishima-san?
You too, don't lose to that guy.
The train is departing. Please stand back from the platform edge. The train is departing.
Wait!
Kitami-san.
Shirakawa-san.
Mishima-san?
Ayuhara-san.
You came back after all.
I was waiting for you. I believed in you.
Ayuhara-san.
What about the others?
Are you alone?
Yeah…
I see…
Say, Mishima-san, are you good at gymnastics?
Gymnastics?
Yeah, I'm pretty good at it.
I was the best in my class.
– I see. In that case, let's go to the court.
– All right.
You're getting better.
Mishima-san, try to make it further.
All right.
Very good!
Now you only have to receive the ball.
Ayuhara-san, thank you.
Thanks to you, I've regained my confidence.
But I'm not sure if I'll be able to teach her the revolving receive.
Ayuhara-san.
Sanjou-san is doing super training.
Sanjou-san?
My.
She's been like this for half an hour already.
Huh.
It must've stung when the
coach said her jumping was bad.
She's putting up a real fight.
That must be 2.5 meters high.
You think I'll lose to her…?
All right, one more.
I see, so that's her plan…
She wants to make her arms more powerful.
That's nice and all, but it looks so painful…
No matter how much it hurts, I
won't let go of these chains.
There's no other way to overcome my weakness.
In order to overcome the weak spots Inokuma pointed out…
…the players undergo individual training.
But after looking at the girls, professor Kawakita says that their schoolwork is the most important…
…and announces a test.
Kozue is exhausted from training.
Can sports and learning still be compatible with each other?
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.