苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 030—
Volleyball demon
Kozue.
Are you okay?
I'm fine. Continue.
Here goes, Kozue!
Midori, keep going.
Ah, Ayuhara-san, you're bleeding!
I'm fine, I'm fine.
Midori, keep them coming.
Come on.
Okay.
Okay!
I see, so that was her plan.
She wants to make her arms stronger by wearing heavy chains all the time.
I guess.
There's no way I could wear these all day long…
Hmph.
Don't even compare yourself to Ayuhara-san.
What did you say?
Hehe.
Ayuhara-san is way above all of you.
We can at best try to follow her example.
It's better if I act this way.
The last moment you realize you lost to me…
…will make your regret all the worse.
Well done, Ayuhara-san.
One more.
What's with her.
She compliments Ayuhara-san's passion, but she's pretty crazy herself, if you ask me.
It hurts.
Ah, if she keeps going, she might really improve her jumping.
Say, Kakinouchi-san.
Oh?
Mishima-san…
Where did everyone go?
Try to make it further, as far as you can.
Jump as if you were to fly.
Thank you, Ayuhara-san.
I'm no match for you at all, but I'll do what I can.
I'll do my best.
Fight!
Here goes!
Kozue.
Kozue!
I'm fine, let's keep going!
All right.
Well, if it isn't professor Kawakita.
Hm?
Is this middle school sports today?
We can't stay ssilent
It's today's evening issue.
Newspapers have little to do with training, but please read it anyway.
"Is this middle school sports today?"
"We can't stay silent."
"We couldn't endure the insanity of demon coach's training—said one of the disappeared players."
Naturally it was Shirakawa and Kitami.
Inokuma-san.
Actually, I was thinking what to say…
…but I'm completely on Shirakawa and Kitami's side on this one.
The performance of such young girls has its limits.
These girls are still only middle school students.
Even if it is only for one month, I can't overlook their suffering any longer.
I'm taking this to the Association.
And?
"And?"
If you're finished, let me answer you.
You've just said "still middle school students".
But in my eyes, the girls are already middle school students.
Every person should be able to make their own decisions.
If they hadn't already chosen, they wouldn't be here for the All-Japan.
Don't you agree?
There's no need for you to worry. They've clearly made their choice.
Absurd. This is absurd!
When I hear him talking, it's as if the sports didn't exist for humans…
…but rather humans existed for the sports.
Professor Kawakita, what sports were you into?
Oh?
Did you do any exercise during your junior high or high school times?
Ah, it's rather embarrassing.
I mostly focused on the tests and studying.
I thought that'd be the case.
The truth is, I've been playing basketball once.
Oh? You, professor Matsumoto?
One can't judge a book by its cover.
Sometimes I played to the point I felt nauseous.
Sports aren't just theory.
I see.
However, professor Matsumoto.
Surely you acknowledge that the most of education is studying?
The most?
I'd rather say it's only half.
Half…?
Yes.
Education isn't done just from behind a desk.
In my opinion, it should include physical activity as well.
That is the reason why the minimum score on the tests is 50 points.
50 points?
You're very warmhearted in your teaching.
However I doubt that the girls can get 50 points under these circumstances.
In fact, I'm afraid they might not get even 30.
You don't say.
I really am, that is precisely why I
approached professor Inokuma earlier.
I think you're overthinking this.
No matter how hard they train…
…I don't think it will make their grades much lower.
I wonder about that.
I really want to believe that is the case.
My.
Do you mean that you do not believe in your students?
That's tough.
All right.
Maybe you're right after all?
Listen, girls. Tomorrow there will be a math test.
Eh?
We have to take tests even here?
I'll pretend I didn't hear that.
Those who get fewer than 50 points on the tomorrow's test…
…will be sent back home by coach Inokuma.
Got it?
It's unrealistic.
Yeah, yeah. It's too much.
We didn't come here to study.
We're here to play volleyball.
Exactly.
Silence!
You're forgetting something important!
Listen. You're middle school students.
No matter how skilled you are at volleyball, can you call yourselves Japan's best if you don't study?
Aren't you ashamed of yourselves?
Professor Matsumoto.
We'd like to hear your opinion on this.
Yeah. Professor Matsumoto will agree with us.
You'll surely take our side. Right, professor?
I agreed to professor Kawakita's test.
Really? We're doomed.
Good God.
Aw, it sucks.
It will be painful, but do your best.
Suffering forges a strong will.
That strong will lets you overcome any crisis at hand.
Those who have forgotten it aren't qualified to participate in this training camp.
Professor Matsumoto understands us well.
Even the tests can be combined with the volleyball training.
Well then, I'm looking forward to the tomorrow's test.
So threatening them with a test was useless, huh?
All right!
Oh?
They're lost cases.
They just do what they want.
Midori.
I'm awake. Let's go.
Wah, it's pitch black.
Did you take the candle?
I've got it right here.
Shoot, I dropped it.
Did you find it yet?
Nope. Hey, can't we turn on the light for a sec?
We can't. The light will be seen from the corridor and they'll find us out right away.
What to do?
Ah, we're running out of time.
Ah?
Fufu.
Ka-Kakinouchi-san, you too?
Shh.
I heard footsteps, so I put it out.
I just finished cramming myself.
Heh.
Oh?
A thief?
Ah, I feel alive.
Then now it's my turn.
All right.
Don't hold back.
Hit with all you've got.
Okay.
Ah, that wake me up.
Okay, time to study.
Those guys…
Three more pages and we're finished.
But will it prove any useful, I wonder?
We have no time to think.
Rather than thinking, we need to act.
Hmm. You're way smarter than I am, Kozue.
I, on the other hand…
Stay strong.
What comes will come.
We need to do what we can.
Come on, Midori.
Can you solve this problem?
This one? Hm…
Looks pretty difficult.
Damn.
Ow! Ah!
Was my demand too heavy for them?
No, that's not the case.
Can Japan representatives really afford to repeat a year?
Please don't fail my expectations, girls.
I don't get it. I don't get it!
Midori.
I can't do it.
It's impossible for me.
I'm staring at the notebook and my head's full of volleyball.
How can I take the test like this?
What are you doing?
It's the same what we did before.
You're half asleep.
Half asleep?
That's awful, Kozue.
You're getting ahead of yourself.
Calm down, Midori.
You just told you think of volleyball even though you are now preparing for a test.
Yes, I did.
What of it?
I am going to sound cheeky, but there's your weakness.
Huh?
Midori, what if you thought about the test during the game?
You might lose without being able to demonstrate your ability.
It's the same as this test.
The only weapon one has against a stronger opponent is mental strength.
The power to concentrate on what's before you.
And this time our opponents are the best teams in the world.
Most of the teams are probably way, way more powerful than us.
Heh, you start to sound like coach Inokuma.
Ah? Now that I think of it, I guess you're right.
Seems we caught up to his coaching's pace before we knew it.
At any rate, Midori…
…no matter what happens, let's do our best.
For the sake of our beloved volleyball.
Yes, Kozue. For our beloved volleyball.
In order to protect what we love, as good as we can.
Midori.
There's little time left. Let's do our best.
Yep.
"This unreasonable hard training proves that the sports in schools is heading in the wrong direction."
Hmm.
Say what you like, professor, but it's terrible news.
Yeah.
I'd understand if it were us who have fled.
But these are national team players we're talking about.
At this rate, he'll break our chief…
I mean, captain and Hayakawa-san.
Are you okay with that?
Look.
Inokuma-kun is All-Japan's coach.
He knows what's he's doing.
Professor, do your really believe what you've just said?
Hm?
Wh-What do you mean by that?
Look how this whole Inokuma was selected to coach just for this contest.
When it comes to victory, do the ends really justify the means?
Professor.
What if they get sick?
We can't let it slide. Right?
Yep. We need to do something.
Ayuhara's revolving receive is completely useless.
Inokuma.
Are you planning to break Ayuhara?
Passion and team spirit?
That's naive way of thinking.
Hongou, I see that you didn't change at all.
Hello?
Oh? Nice to talk to you, Ayuhara-san.
This is Hongou.
Ah, regarding the newspaper?
Precisely.
Ah, did you read it already?
Of course, we trust the Association's recommended supervisors.
But the training camp is very far away, so I am a bit worried.
I understand how you feel.
Did you receive any news from Ayuhara-kun?
She was unexpectedly silent and has sent us just a single postcard.
"I am doing fine", "We'll win at the tournament" and the like without any sign of a complaint.
I see.
In fact, the postcard sent to the volleyball club was pretty similar.
I understand.
I'd like to go to the training camp soon and check the actual situation.
"We're doing fine."
"—Ayuhara and Hayakawa", huh?
I hope you're not putting a brave face.
Miyazaki Daily News
Five minutes left.
Did you fill everything in?
Yes, professor.
Are you sure of your answers?
Yes.
Finished.
Midori, did it go well?
Yep. It was a breeze.
Everything was easy.
Giving easy problems isn't like you, professor Kawakita.
Now everyone's going to pass.
It's all about measuring twice and cutting once.
What caused you to change your mind?
Nothing in particular. I realized sports are similar to studying.
If you don't do your best, you won't accomplish much.
Rather than memorizing the material to get the perfect store…
…it's better if they earn only 60 points, but understand what they're doing.
We might be on training camp, but they're still students.
Now all that's left for them is to face their demons.
The volleyball demon.
I'm glad. Everyone passed the test.
I didn't expect it from professor Kawakita.
He gave us the easiest questions.
Yep.
You two there!
Hey!
No gossiping!
It's a special training for you.
– I hope they're practicing now.
– Yeah.
Ah, they are.
Keep an eye on the ball!
Y-Yes sir!
That's awful.
Are they really middle school students?
He looks almost like an animal tamer.
But I don't understand it.
Check them out.
Rather than rebelling, they're fully engaged.
Ayuhara, Hayakawa.
Don't lose to him. Hang in there until my arrival.
The Japanese girls team's coach gets labeled as an "animal tamer"…
…and is heavily criticized by the press.
However, the beliefs of the coach Inokuma remain unchanged…
…and day by day, his left arm throws increasingly violent balls.
"I will win no matter what."
"I will become the world's best."
What turned Inokuma into the demon coach?
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.