苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 031—
The secret of the bad arm
That's not good enough!
Here goes!
Is that all you've got?
Next!
Yes sir!
Keep your eyes on the ball!
How awful.
Are they really middle school students?
He looks like an animal tamer.
Where are your eyes looking?
And you want to play on the national team?
I won't… lose!
But I don't understand it.
Rather than rebelling, these girls are fully engaged.
That man destroyed his own team.
With his killer spike.
Ayuhara, Hayakawa, don't lose to him.
Hang in there until I arrive.
You really think you can protect
the 3
×
4.5 plus alpha zone like this?
Stand up. Stand up right now!
Yes sir…!
It's painful to watch them…
You really can't blame Shirakawa and Kitami for fleeing this hell hole.
The remaining girls are out of their minds.
– At least they're putting a good fight.
– By the end of this camp there will be no one left.
Midori, hang in there.
No matter what happens, let's do our best.
For the sake of our beloved volleyball.
All right, Kozue. For our beloved volleyball.
Hayakawa-san's on fire.
She's not giving up.
Good going, Midori! Great! You're doing great!
All right.
What a relief.
I'm sorry, but I'll have to ask you to withdraw now.
You've got enough material, haven't you?
Like hell we have. We're just getting started.
So far we've only seen middle school students being trained too harshly.
That's why I'm telling you, you've seen enough already.
Inokuma-san, are you even reading the newspapers?
Yesterday's issue had a testimony from Kawakita Teruko of Gifu Middle School…
…and Kitami Ritsuko of Asahigawa Middle School about how they ran from this camp.
The whole world knows about your unreasonably harsh training.
It's just not fit for young girls in middle school.
It seems we've became
the world's gossip before we knew it.
It's because Shirakawa-san and Kitami-san went and complained.
I hope this will make our training a little easier.
Hmph. Running away was unforgivable in itself.
But that move was way over the line.
I see. And your point is?
Our point…?
What do you have to say regarding
Shirakawa Teruko and Kitami Ritsuko's escape?
No use crying over spilled milk.
We can't leave with such a dismissive line.
There's no need for me to say anything more to you. None of you have any relation to volleyball.
But at the very least, we have an obligation to report the truth to the world.
And I have an obligation to protect volleyball.
You can do whatever you want, just do it outside this gym.
Because this is the court these girls have gambled their lives on.
Have some respect.
Depending on the situation, I
might have to confront Inokuma.
But for time being,
I have to see this training for myself.
It's not just Midori. Everyone is putting in their all.
And they're certainly getting better.
Which means…
Okay, next!
– Kozue.
– Y-Yes sir.
Fujimi Academy's duo is doing great today.
I could say the same about you, Arai-san.
Even Ayuhara-san has hard time defending all that.
You can't even accept a single serve.
You still can't go outside the ordinary defense zone.
You're still miles away from reaching "plus alpha".
Miles away, you say? It can't be.
Come on!
How long are you planning to stall the practice?
You… you call this stalling?
Stand up.
Come on!
Next!
Ayuhara!
You're not to miss a single serve.
Or else it's 10 bunny hop laps for you tomorrow.
What?
That's awful.
I can't miss a single ball…? There's no way I can do that.
Of course you can't do it.
Lame exercises like bunny hops suit you well.
Hehe. Hehehe.
What are you looking at?
All right.
I won't let that ever-sulking Sanjou-san keep making fun of me.
I'll receive every serve even if it kills me.
I did it.
I did it!
Kozue!
I did it.
Ayuhara!
Getting a single receive right doesn't mean you can take a nap.
You can be satisfied after you've received a hundred serves.
Ah…!
Even if it's just one, I managed to do it.
I was able to accept that intense serve
with my revolving receive.
Inokuma.
So you do want to break Ayuhara after all?
Just like you broke your teammates at the university.
I'm so happy for you, Kozue.
Your revolving receive was splendid.
That's partly thanks to the iron chains.
You're getting better too, Midori.
If I am, I owe it to those drills.
And, I hate to say it, but maybe it's even thanks to that coach.
You think so, too, Midori?
Huh?
When I saw everyone practicing today,
I suddenly felt that way as well.
Thanks to the coach.
It's not just Midori. Everyone's training fiercely.
And it's obvious that they're getting better.
Which means…
Which means that if you overlook Coach Inokuma's personality…
…his training is at least improving our group's skill level.
Yeah, that's true.
But, to tell the truth, I considered escaping like Shirakawa-san and Kitami-san a lot of times by now.
That just proves how strong we are for staying here.
But what about them?
Hmm, I understand where Shirakawa-san and Kitami-san were coming from.
But this time I have to agree Sanjou-san.
It was unfair for them to complain to the press.
Either way, Midori, we shouldn't be wasting time like this.
You're right. Sanjou-san and everyone's are training as we speak.
Did you come here to lecture me?
Professor Hongou…?
And Coach Inokuma.
Inokuma.
I don't intend to preach to you.
But, I'd like you to understand something as a fellow volleyball teacher.
There are times when I put my girls through training that's above their level too.
But when I do, I don't focus on just teaching them volleyball.
I aim for their growth, but I never forgot to treat them like human beings.
You're still giving me this nonsense?
What are you doing?
All your talk about unicorns and rainbows makes me sick.
What?
Listen, Hongou.
They didn't come to this camp to receive hugs.
They came to play volleyball.
Volleyball!
And I came here to teach them volleyball that'll make them the best in the world.
The best in the world, you hear?
However…
…I hope you realize you might break them long before you accomplish that goal.
Just like you broke your teammates back in college.
Don't you worry, Hongou.
I've gotten a little bit better since my school days.
If I broke these girls…
…we wouldn't be able to participate in the world championships.
I wouldn't be that stupid.
I guess they've known each other since school?
Yep, seems like it.
Who would've thought Coach Inokuma would hit Professor Hongou, though.
I didn't apologize for hitting you earlier.
Yeah.
But why do you get so mad when you hear about affection?
I swore during my college days that such stupidity would never affect me again.
It all started with my old man's funeral.
You were there too.
I was about to be employed by the company my old man was an executive director of.
With a proper job,
I could play volleyball all I wanted.
But then, when my father died,
the circumstances completely changed.
One of old man's coworkers blamed his failures at work on him.
Ookawa
Because of that, I didn't receive my father's retirement funds…
…and of course any chance to getting employed there was gone too.
Soon enough, we were thrown out of the house
we had been living in for many years.
Me and my sister had to turn to my relatives and ask for their help.
My uncle was a heavy drinker.
My aunt was nice back when my father was still alive.
But afterwards she became a very cold person.
It was then when I started practicing volleyball so fiercely.
I couldn't do anything other than volleyball, so my only path was to become a professional player.
And thanks to my intense training…
…I became a renowned attacker, wanted by all the top companies.
I kept looking forward to the day when my sister and I could live on our own.
I pledged in my heart that I would win the upcoming university league game.
As a captain, and as a famous attacker, I wanted to win the championship.
But to accomplish this, we all needed to become volleyball demons.
I had the same expectations for them as I did for myself.
But the result was…
…that you destroyed your own team.
With your murderous spike.
That's right.
I also destroyed this right arm.
I trained too hard.
Do you know what happened then?
All I know is that after you dropped out of university, you went somewhere abroad.
It wasn't an impulsive decision.
After hearing about my arm, my sponsor companies canceled our arrangements.
I was no longer worth anything to them.
Clinging to volleyball was the only option I had.
Even with a single arm, even being called a demon, I had to cling to volleyball.
I left Japan and went
to the volleyball country: the Soviet Union.
Leaving your little sister behind.
What use could an unemployed, crippled older brother be to her?
It was hard for me as well.
There wasn't anything to talk about
until I've had matured.
At that time, I finally realized something important.
The only thing I can rely on…
…aren't other people.
I can't rely on human kindness or their love.
Only volleyball.
In the Soviet Union, I've truly learned the ways of authentic volleyball, in both practice and theory.
One day, I met a Japanese sales representative who had been dispatched to the Soviet Union.
He turned out to be my friend from school days.
I learned from him that my sister was adopted into a rich family.
So I could focus on volleyball completely from there on out.
I traveled from the Soviet Union to Poland, then the Czech Republic, then all over Europe.
At some point, I was asked to coach a certain girls team.
"From zero to hero. Let's make them the best in the world."
That's what I had decided then.
I managed to get them
to the world championships…
…but, as you know, we lost
to the Soviets in the semifinals.
That day, I decided on a new goal.
One day I'll raise a team, doesn't matter who,
and I'll make them the best in the world.
Around that time, the Japanese Volleyball Association offered me my current position.
So I came back to Japan.
This time I will forge the world's best team.
The world's best!
We don't need any feelings to do that.
I just have to pass all of my knowledge onto them, both practice and theory.
Can we let it slide? Japanese middle school women's volleyball camp
A coach… or an animal tamer?
Coach Inokuma's comment on Shirakawa and Kitami's escape: "No use crying over spilled milk."
The Japanese Volleyball Association is finally going to investigate the situation.
Inokuma's unfortunate past made him live for nothing but volleyball.
And now he wants to make the team under his care into the world's best.
There's no mistake, he's very passionate about it.
Still…
Still… is his passion going to bring happiness for Ayuhara and the girls?
What's wrong? Show some effort!
From such a short distance?
And he throws them with all he's got.
That's difficult on its own, but then he extended the standard defense range on top of it?
It might look reckless at first but he's thoroughly calculated the foreign players' power.
It's a surprisingly effective exercise method.
Hey.
Isn't that man over there Professor Hongou?
I guess he doesn't want us to know he's here.
Let's pretend we didn't notice him.
All right.
But, Kozue, what do you think of
their conversation from last night?
There's no way I can follow Coach Inokuma.
It's absurd to bottle up one's emotions.
And I agree with you…
…but let's not jump to conclusions just yet.
Maybe we'll understand him later?
Midori, it's just like we said before—
I know, I know.
It doesn't matter what kind of person Coach Inokuma is. We need to focus on what's before us.
Exactly.
And our will to protect volleyball is just like our coach's.
Even though the coach's method of showing his love for volleyball is warped.
So… maybe Sanjou's hatred for volleyball…
…is actually a similarly warped form of love, too?
She just doesn't want to admit it.
All right. Next, Ayuhara.
Yes sir.
Oh.
She can do the revolving receive, which means…
Everyone really is getting better.
I guess, this time I will leave it to you.
I'll defend you well
from the Association and the journalists.
I'm grateful for that, old friend.
Thanks.
– Make no mistake, Inokuma.
– What?
I'm not doing this as your friend.
Inokuma.
It's true that thanks to you they're getting better.
But I can't call them a team.
What?
It's just a bunch of players.
It isn't a team.
Do you see what's missing?
Well, the answer is…
You dirtbag.
I'm relieved to see that your blood isn't made of ice.
What?
That red blood… that is the response
I wanted to tell you.
Warm, red blood circulating in the human body.
It doesn't flow for the sake of training,
nor for the sake of volleyball.
I won't apologize for having hit you
just like you didn't.
But I sincerely hope your goal for the World Championship isn't solely out of cynicism.
If you have time, think what I've said just now.
This might be conceited, but I feel
I understand what Professor Hongou was saying.
But it's also true that our skills as volleyball players became better thanks to Coach Inokuma.
Professor, what am I supposed to do…?
In the first practice game with Yurigaoka girls high school…
…Sanjou's attack proves to be much more prominent than Kozue's.
Only the winner of the game can capture the position of the captain.
"I have to win no matter what."
"Even if I have to gamble my love for volleyball."
However, Sanjou's score outperforms Kozue.
The results are definitely unexpected.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.