苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 032—
The loved and hated court
Girls Middle School All-Japan Training Camp
I wonder if professor Hongou got on the train already.
Hmm.
Isn't that professor Hongou's train?
I miss everyone. I wonder how they're doing?
Just a bit more patience, Midori.
Right. Time flies faster when we train.
Midori is working hard. I better not fall behind.
It is useless. I have to become stronger.
I have to beat this stupid game.
I will torn it to pieces in front of the people who love it so much.
Heh.
Hahaha.
Ayuhara.
Sir.
Did Hongou leave already?
Yes sir.
Ayuhara. I will say just this.
I am All Japan's coach.
I need you to follow me all the way until the games in America.
I understand. But…
My way is different from Hongou's.
It's completely different.
Completely, hear?
Yes sir.
I met Hongou after all this time.
Say what you want. I'm doing things my way.
Your special training is killing them.
Listen, Hongou. Your happy-go-lucky training…
…isn't going to teach Ayuhara anything more.
I understand, coach.
Go catch some sleep.
We have a practice match against Yurigaoka High tomorrow.
Good night, sir.
Oh?
That posture…
The way his right shoulder's higher…
Bro…
It can't be.
But that posture…
As expected, it was just my imagination.
But who was he talking to before?
Ayuhara-san?
So she's the one the coach was talking with?
Coach and Ayuhara-san…
Ah!
Now that I think of it…
Back then, she has been told that her revolving receive is useless.
That's what she claimed at least.
But I couldn't believe her.
Just a moment ago, I could swear the coach was my brother Ichiro.
But neither his name nor face match.
Bro…
My bro, who was taken away by volleyball.
No, no.
Michiru, you silly girl.
And here I was thinking I let go of these feelings long ago.
It'll be our first practice match here.
My heart's racing.
Oh, is your heart that easy to move?
Eh? You dummy!
I'm a bit worried our first opponent is a high school.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
We're world class players.
Yeah. We'll win and show our All-Japan champions' pride.
Yeah. That's the spirit.
Yay!
Here you go getting carried away again.
Really.
Staying fashionable is tough, isn't it?
Sanjou-san.
Ayuhara-san, I came here to challenge you.
Challenge?
Who can seize more player points during our practice match against Yurigaoka High today?
Let's have an duel as attackers.
What do you think of it?
Competing for player points?
What for?
It's about time regular members roster gets announced.
You understand my goal, don't you?
I aim to become number one and take the position of captain.
And be the best all-round player, I presume?
Precisely.
The first step is make you kneel before my power.
Fine. I don't want to lose to a
volleyball hater such as yourself.
Good. But your love for that game won't make you win, mind you.
Power and technique is what wins the matches.
Power and technique…
Kozue.
Did she do something again?
Not this time.
She challenged me for a score competition in today's practice match.
Huh?
Leave it to me. I'll help you out.
Hold on. This is between just the two of us.
But, Kozue…
Promise me you won't tell about it to anyone.
Okay…
It's not like Sanjou-san to be so upfront.
This might be a chance to resolve some things.
City Gym
Yurigaoka High ・ All-Japan Junior High
A three-set match between the All-Japan team and Yurigaoka High School begins.
Good luck.
Good luck to you too.
Ayuhara-san.
Remember about our contest.
I won't lose, Sanjou-san.
I won't acknowledge victory just through skill from someone bearing such hatred.
I'm going to win this contest.
– Keep the serve!
– Yeah!
I can't hold back. I have to win with Sanjou-san.
Attack. Attack!
Was that supposed to be a block?
I'll return twice the points you made us lose.
Sanjou-san gained lead in points. I better get serious.
What's that? A confrontation between Ayuhara and Sanjou?
Their attacks become dull while they fight each other.
We'll probably win the first set, but then what?
Yurigaoka High ・ All-Japan Junior High
We won the first set!
Yep, piece of cake.
It's too early to celebrate.
You won, all right.
But you need to see the bigger picture.
There are still two sets left. Think carefully how you're going to win these.
"Need to see the bigger picture"…
Sanjou-san has five points, while I have only two.
I have to catch up in the second set.
– Fight! – Yeah!
They're tough.
They don't want to lose to a middle school for sure.
Yurigaoka High ・ All-Japan Junior High
They got a lead.
Why won't the coach ask for time?
Coach.
Kozue!
Another point for Sanjou-san.
But it couldn't be helped.
You won, all right. But you need to see the bigger picture.
At this rate we might lose.
I know.
Sanjou-san.
I won't fight you anymore.
I don't want to lose this match after all.
Yurigaoka High ・ All-Japan Junior High
Sanjou-san, it's your victory.
You won completely.
But I gave up only because of my love for volleyball.
It's a shame that I had to lose to you and your hatred.
Yurigaoka High ・ All-Japan Junior High
Come on, you can do this!
Here, take it.
Thank you.
We're near the finish. They're under pressure too.
Leave it to me!
Got it!
Good job!
Kozue, are you okay?
I'm fine, I'm fine.
Give us a good serve!
Just three points left! Fight!
Yeah!
Hmph. I'll score all three, just you wait.
I've got this!
She did it!
Chance ball!
Yeah!
Go! Go!
Yurigaoka High ・ All-Japan Junior High
Match point!
Attack!
Kozue, we did it!
– We really did.
– We won.
I got 14 points.
You got 9, Ayuhara-san.
You won.
So you acknowledge it, hehe.
Now my skill should get the recognition it deserves.
I'm an excellent attacker ace, better than anyone else.
Hehehe.
Heh.
I won!
With these bare hands.
– Whew, a flawless victory.
– That flawless victory cost me some nerves.
But it's first time I felt so anxious when facing the opponents.
They were so tall after all.
Yeah, but thanks to this game I feel more confident now.
True, true.
Kozue.
I was completely defeated in the score competition.
Sanjou-san is a really great attacker.
We admit your power nonetheless, Kozue.
Everyone says so.
That's right, Kozue. We were able to win because you were in the center.
Exactly. You really have no reason to be depressed.
Thank you. I just got a little tired.
I'll go before you.
Ayuhara Kozue wasn't the best attacker today.
But it is strange.
I don't feel like I lost to Sanjou-san.
We won the game.
As a price, I will be a step behind in the rally to join the best members.
But…
Even so, there was no choice.
Ayuhara-san.
Huh?
Hurry up. Everyone's waiting.
Okay.
You competed with Sanjou-san, didn't you?
Eh?
How did you know?
Aha. You won't fool my eyes.
Nor certain sunglasses.
You mean, the coach knows it too?
You lost to Sanjou-san.
By losing, you won at volleyball.
Thank you, Kakinouchi-san.
What were you doing?
We're sorry.
Everyone, gather up in the gym as soon as we get back.
I have some news for you.
News?
Coach's news…
He's probably going to announce the best members roster.
But as a result of today's game I might not be elected.
Ayuhara-san, you're done for.
Fufu.
I'm looking forward to coach's news.
It's useless to dwell on this.
I did what I could.
And that is enough.
Even if I don't get selected, I'm satisfied that I played my way.
Girls, the coach is here.
I am going to announce best member shirt numbers now.
Number one, the captain: …
…Ayuhara.
Huh?
C-Coach!
Do not disturb, Sanjou.
I'm so glad.
I will not allow any remarks until the end of the announcement.
Number two: Kakinouchi.
Hah.
Number three: Sanjou.
Number four: Hayakawa.
Yahoo!
– Ah… sorry for that.
– Fufu.
Number five: Yoshimura.
Ah.
Number six: Arai.
Wow, barely!
Oops.
These were the best members.
Continuing, number seven: Ootsuki.
Number eight: Mishima.
I am the number one. Our captain.
Somehow, I can't believe it.
That concludes it.
However, being chosen doesn't mean you'll always get to show up in the games.
Keep that in mind.
– I'm so happy for you, Kozue.
– You too, Midori.
Congratulations, captain.
Coach.
What?
Please tell me the reason behind this order of the players.
What? You want my reason?
The basis for this order was today's game.
Of course, your performance in practices thus far has also played a role.
Then why… why is Ayuhara-san number one, and I am number three?
Seems like you have a problem with that?
I can not accept it.
Both me and Ayuhara-san are attackers.
But my score was much better in today's match.
And yet, I—
Ayuhara had 9 points and you had 14, right?
Yes sir.
Furthermore, if you count Kakinouchi in, you form together an unique attack trio.
Coach, you haven't answered my question.
Let me ask you something myself.
Sanjou. Did you ever think about the team during the game?
Well?
You were focused on competing for points with Ayuhara.
But getting as many points as possible leads to team victory.
Am I wrong?
No, you're right.
However, it worked only for a single set.
Only one set?
In the first set of today's game, your attacks, competing with each other…
…turned out to be tactical success.
They couldn't predict which one of you would strike.
In other words, you managed to briefly confuse them.
Confuse?
That's why you won the first set.
But they quickly saw through your messed up attacks.
That's right. The tables have turned in the second set.
Your opponents stuck to team play.
And so they gained a lead in the second set.
But we won in the end.
That's because Ayuhara abandoned the game against you.
Huh? I-It can't be.
So the coach has seen it after all.
My decision at that time.
When they gained a lead on us in the second set.
Kozue!
Got it!
At that time I had completely forgotten that I was an attacker.
Saying it was teamwork just because she was thinking on her feet is a bit of a stretch.
That wasn't it.
That wasn't it! I remembered volleyball basics back then.
And that is teamwork.
That's right. And yet, Sanjou-san…
– …you ignored team play until the end.
– Exactly.
No matter how good you are, you can't win a volleyball game by yourself.
Are you finished?
No, I'm not. One more thing.
It was Ayuhara-san's power that saved us in the second set.
I was like in a trance.
Leave it to me.
She received it in a way I couldn't ever do.
Are you okay?
Just three points left! Fight!
Yeah!
That… that was teamwork.
That is volleyball!
While Sanjou-san thought only of herself, Ayuhara-san already played like a captain.
Yeah, she totally had that captain vibe.
Our new captain.
Captain, banzai!
Thank you. I'll work hard!
I won.
In the end, I won…
My love for volleyball prevailed.
Hahaha.
Sanjou-san.
Heh, what a farce.
This is good.
Sanjou!
What? Look at you coming up with these beautiful stories, thinking I don't know.
Wasn't Ayuhara Kozue already determined to become captain?
What do you mean?
Ayuhara-san, you're pretty good at seducing people.
Sanjou-san!
– What the hell, Sanjou-san!
– You stay out of this!
I know about everything.
About how our coach has feelings for Ayuhara-san.
Sanjou.
To put it clearly, he's in love with her.
Hahaha. What a comedy.
How filthy.
W-What the heck?
Ayuhara-san.
– Kozue!
– No! Let go of me!
I won't forgive such accusations.
That's just too low.
Kozue, calm down.
That's right, captain. Stay calm.
Coach!
Shortly after this announcement, a
weekly magazine reporter came…
…claiming that coach Inokuma's sister is among the best members.
But who is she?
The girls are surprised.
Can the demon coach's sister be really among the selected players?
And why are the reporters researching Inokuma's past?
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.