苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 033—
The scoop
I am going to announce best member shirt numbers now.
Number one, the captain: …
…Ayuhara.
Huh?
Coach!
Do not disturb, Sanjou.
Kozue, I'm so glad.
I will not allow any remarks until the end of the announcement.
Number two: Kakinouchi.
Hah.
Number three: Sanjou.
Number four: Hayakawa.
Yahoo!
Ah… sorry for that.
Number five: Yoshimura.
Ah.
Number six: Arai.
Wow, barely!
Oops.
These were the best members.
Continuing, number seven: Ootsuki.
Number eight: Mishima.
I am the number one.
Our captain.
Somehow, I can't believe it.
That concludes it.
However, being chosen doesn't mean you'll always get to show up in the games.
Keep that in mind.
Coach.
What?
Why is Ayuhara-san number one,
and I am number three?
Please tell me the reason.
Seems like you have a problem with that?
I can not accept it. My score in today's match was 14, while Ayuhara-san scored only 9 points.
I had much higher score, so why…?
Sanjou!
You only competed for the score.
When you lost the lead in the second set…
…Ayuhara abandoned your little game and started playing for the team.
At that time, Ayuhara was already a captain.
– Our coach has feelings for Ayuhara-san.
– Sanjou-san!
Sanjou!
To put it clearly, he's in love with her.
Hahaha.
What a comedy.
How filthy.
W-What the heck?
– A-Ayuhara-san!
– No! Let go of me!
I won't forgive such accusations. That's just too low.
Kozue, calm down.
That's right, captain. Stay calm.
Coach!
Coach…
Michiru.
Ichiro!
Bro!
Don't leave Michiru behind!
Don't leave me alone.
I took responsibility for that accident
and dropped out of school.
Crippled and without a job, what use can I be to you?
I'm no longer your older bro, Ookawa Ichiro.
I'm All-Japan team's coach, Inokuma Daigo.
The only thing I could do for you is to make you into a splendid volleyball player.
I…
I hate volleyball that took my brother.
I hate it.
I hate it!
And yet I can't part ways with it.
Hatred leads only to more hatred.
What to do?
What should you do, Michiru?
Escaping, Michiru?
No. I can't escape.
I can hate.
This is what I can do best.
I will hurt myself even more.
What is that…?
Is this as far as I can go?
Sanjou-san didn't return to our room, did she?
Yeah. Maybe she fled?
I don't think she's the type to do that.
Heh, you're right.
But she was out of bed all night.
Hmm. Where could she go?
Hm.
Sanjou-san.
Ah, that's her.
Kozue.
I know, Midori. I'm not going to make a scene out of it.
But, Kozue…
Ayuhara-san.
I think it's better to let it go.
I know you'll be fine,
but there's no reasoning with her.
Yeah. You're better off leaving her alone.
She disrupts the whole team for her own sake. It's very immature.
– Don't you think?
– I agree.
– She's very immature.
– Just leave her.
Line up!
– Yes sir!
There was a complaint that I had personal feelings for Ayuhara-san.
I will not deny it.
Huh?
I love Ayuhara.
Because she is fit to be the captain of the All-Japan team.
I love her as a fellow volleyball player.
It should go without saying.
Anyone who is dissatisfied with my way of thinking
can leave the training camp at any time.
I won't stop you nor will I say anything.
– Enough. Practice!
– Yes sir! – Yes sir!
Here we go!
What's wrong?
Thanks for showing us their practice.
You didn't see much of it anyway.
Hm?
What do you mean by that?
Practices are not a show.
I guess you're right, but as the officials
of the Volleyball Association…
We should…
That court is a place for me and the players only.
If it wasn't so, we wouldn't be able to train in full.
Practices are where I and my players go all out against each other.
This attitude is the problem here.
Newspaper make an uproar about how you're stepping over the line.
The Association should have means to verify that kind of gossip.
Whether I'm stepping over the line or not is decided by the players.
Players that can't keep up won't be a part of my team.
It's that simple.
And now I have to take care of my team,
so please excuse me.
Let's get going!
Yeah!
Good, you almost got t!
Sanjou-san.
Kozue!
Is that Inokuma Daigo?
Inokuma-san.
You're the coach that the Association announced support for, right?
And you are…?
It'll just take a moment. Newspaper call you an animal tamer and your training Spartan…
…and you responded it's all
to win the World Tournament, right?
Who are you?
I'm with a female weekly magazine, "New Lady".
We have nothing to talk then.
Ah, I didn't want to talk about your training.
Rather, I wanted to focus on you.
Inokuma-san.
Ah, Inokuma-san!
Please wait for a moment!
Tsk!
Ah, the water's so cold, it feels great.
It really does.
The practices are tough,
but it feels so good when they're over.
It didn't feel like this in the beginning.
Yep. We get to eat a lot in here.
I'm happy with many things,
but that one is the most important.
Yeah. Haha.
Kozue. Just let go of Sanjou-san already.
But Sanjou-san is a member of a team too, Midori.
I can't leave it like this.
Hm. She's a great attacker, I'll give her that.
But what can we do?
She just keeps sulking in a corner.
Sanjou-san…
Sanjou-san.
We're different in our ways of thinking about volleyball.
However, it doesn't change how we play together in the World Championship.
Even if the way we think is different,
I don't think we can't become teammates.
Don't bother.
My volleyball is different from yours.
We can't do anything about it.
Sanjou-san.
Sanjou-san!
Kozue.
Did she do something again?
Nah, not really. It's nothing.
Sanjou-san hates volleyball.
I'm sure she hides a deep wound in her heart.
I can't figure out what is the wound
in Sanjou-san's heart.
Ah, ow!
She did it, she did it!
Pff.
Receive - failed!
Haha.
If only Sanjou-san was here, laughing with us freely.
Sanjou-san.
You hate volleyball so much and yet you keep playing it. What's the meaning of it?
I can't understand it.
Ah, the air tastes so good after the training!
That tasty air won't fill your stomach though.
Yo. Practices must be hard for you.
I'm with "New Lady" magazine.
We can't do interviews in the middle of training.
But you have a break now, right?
Say, what do you think about coach Inokuma?
We just do what coach says.
We have no opinion about his practices.
I'm not talking about the training.
I meant the coach Inokuma himself.
What kind of person do you think he is?
For example, like, "he's a very cold person"…
…or, "he's hiding something from us".
That kind of things, dig it?
Say, any of you know what your coach has been doing before he went traveli—
Please stop.
Oh.
Looks like you know something.
Am I right?
We need to get back to practice soon.
Please let us rest in peace.
You're Ayuhara-kun, I believe.
As expected from captain appointed by coach Inokuma himself. You've got it together.
Well, if you put it this way, let me withdraw for now.
But coach Inokuma sure hides a lot from you.
For example, the word is that,
after having undergone a name change…
…one of you girls is a sister to coach Inokuma.
Sister…?
Even with a single arm, even being called a demon, I had to cling to volleyball.
I left Japan and went to the volleyball country, the Soviet Union.
Leaving your little sister behind.
What use could an unemployed, crippled older brother be to her?
We know nothing about coach's private life.
It has nothing to do with us.
We are currently working hard for the World Championship.
So please don't disturb our practices.
They mean a lot to us.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
That's how it is.
Then, see you after your training.
Someone among us is coach's sister? No way.
If that is the case, no matter the circumstances,
the public wouldn't understand.
The world loves scandals. They'd hate the hell of us.
You got that right.
It's a magazine for girls,
it specializes in this kind of gossip.
We can't trust this man.
You're right.
Coach's sister.
I see.
That's how it was.
Time's up.
– Let's go.
What does it mean?
Maybe, just maybe he is my brother.
I know it's just a false hope, but I can't shake it off.
There…
There's no way.
There's no way our cold coach could be my brother.
It's not possible.
His sister must be Ayuhara Kozue.
That would explain a lot.
How she visits him at night.
How she says he loves her in public.
That's it.
Ayuhara Kozue is coach's sister.
His sister…
She wasn't here today.
She wasn't at the practice either.
What is she thinking?
I guess this is it.
She must've lost her motivation.
Ayuhara.
Sir.
When you see Sanjou,
tell her to meet me in my room.
Yes sir.
Inokuma-san.
I was looking for you.
I got a reply from Tōkyō to my inquiries and I thought to talk to you once more.
Inokuma-san.
Or rather, Ookawa-san.
I am very interested in hard training you went through during your student days.
So I asked them to look it up.
I got all the materials here.
I would like to ask you a variety of questions basing on this.
First of all, why did the university's volleyball club end?
And how did you hurt your right arm?
Your materials give you
a good idea about it, don't they?
Feel free to write it in your magazine.
You don't mind?
Be my guest. It's not like I'm trying to hide it from anyone.
People from the Association know all about it.
But the public is in the dark.
If they knew that All-Japan coach during his university times…
…crushed his right arm with his killer spike…
…and destroyed his own team with it, they'd be pretty surprised, wouldn't they?
I don't mind that.
Feel free to let them know.
About Michiru-san too?
Please.
Don't drag my sister into this.
At least not until the championship is over.
But we do not want to deprive the public of anything…
Please.
That's one thing I don't want them to know.
This is tough.
I am committed to my readers. It's my job.
I'll be going.
Not as a brother…
But as her coach, I wanted Michiru to become a great player.
That's all.
That's the only thing I could do for you.
Coach.
Aren't you embarrassed?
Where's your spirit?
Hmph.
No matter how much I look at you, I'm not afraid.
You might be good at words, but you do favor her after all.
Is letting people know you're favoring your sister so scary?
You knelt before some reporter and you call yourself an All-Japan coach?
I've had enough.
It's a joke to think you could teach us volleyball.
Who cares… who cares about volleyball.
Who cares about that stupid game.
You fool!
Ah!
Michiru.
Y-You crossed a line.
Michiru…?
My brother.
Bro!
Sanjou!
Sir!
Those who aim at World Championship need training, training…
…and more training!
I understand, coach!
I will postpone this article until World Championship is over.
Inokuma-san, do your best.
Kozue chooses men's high school Nichinan of Kyūshū as their last practice match opponents.
However Shirai, the Nichinan team's captain, turns that proposal down at first.
But seeing peculiar blisters on Kozue's wrists, he takes an interest in All-Japan team's training.
Shortly after, Kozue's offer gets accepted.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.