苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 034—
A long-awaited smile
– One-two! – Fight!
They combine each others strength.
They set their eyes on one purpose.
Ayuhara.
Kakinouchi.
Toss it to me.
Huh?
A soccer ball?
I want to practice with something heavier.
I understand.
Ah…!?
Sanjou.
Hayakawa.
I'm ready.
Okay.
Yoshimura.
Let's practice long passes.
– You ready?
– Yep.
Arai.
Here goes!
Yeah!
Ootsuki.
Mishima.
Noda.
Miyatsu.
They're shining.
They're all shining!
They're at their top form!
Camp will be over soon.
Yeah. Only three days left.
Now that camp's about to be over
it feels like it was so short.
But then I think back to our practices, and I feel like it was pretty long.
Yeah.
It was really tough, too.
I didn't think I would make it that far.
You're not alone there, Mishima-san.
Yep. Everyone feels the same.
Even Sanjou-san has changed.
Her aloofness is still there,
but she's become much softer now.
Here goes!
That's Nichinan High School, right?
Yeah. They're Kyūshū representatives.
They've participated in the All-Japan tournament 3 years in a row.
They sure have a lot of big players, and every year they're elected for the best 4, aren't they?
That's right.
What a strong team.
Ah… I know!
Huh?
Yep, let's do it.
Do what? What do you mean?
Let's hold one last practice match tomorrow.
Right?
Inokuma
Please.
Nichinan High School, huh?
What we all needed to participate in the world championships was power rather than technique.
Strength and physical fitness got us this far.
I've started from the basics as you have instructed me to.
And that's why…
It's okay. You have my consent.
Yes sir.
This is your last practice match, so I won't instruct you this time.
Huh?
Ayuhara, I'm leaving everything to you.
You're the captain,
so you're in charge of everything.
Yes sir!
Nichinan High School
You're Ayuhara-san of the All-Japan team, right?
I'm Shirai from Nichinan High School.
I'm Ayuhara Kozue.
I'm Hayakawa Midori.
The teachers said that you want to hold a practice match with us?
Yes.
That's correct.
We consulted it within our club and decided to refuse.
W-Why?
The gap between men and women players is just too big.
Also you're still middle school students.
That's the reason.
Please excuse me.
What a snob.
Please wait!
Please wait.
This will be our last practice match before the Junior Volleyball World Championships.
Please play with us.
I get that you're excellent players chosen from all around Japan.
You're all well qualified to participate in a world championship.
Which is why you will be participating in the upcoming championships.
You might even be the hottest topic around town right now.
But…
Thinking that a middle school girl team can take on a high school boys team…
…it's just way out of line!
Huh?
Our club members were actually pretty angry when they heard it.
B-But it's not like we really think we can beat you.
Then why even bother holding a match?
It's not about winning or losing.
We only want to test our training camp's results.
We refuse.
Even if we hold a match with that intention in mind…
…the possibility of a win or a loss
is precisely the problem.
What do you mean…?
If you lose, you'd blame it on playing against high school boys.
But if we were to lose, I don't know we'd be able to admit defeat to a bunch of junior high school girls.
I see…
Winning or losing isn't pretty.
It's an ugly, tough business.
Excuse me.
What's with him?
Let's go, Kozue.
Ow, it hurts!
Hey, watch it…
Huh?
What's with these scars?
What are they thinking?
Kyūshū representatives, my foot.
Do they really think us girls are not good enough for them?
What a joke!
They're just afraid of losing to us.
I wonder if that's all there is to it…
Captain!
Did the All-Japan girls go back already?
All-Japan or not, they're pretty stuck-up thinking that middle school girls can take us on.
Oh…?
Captain…!
Where are you going? Hey, Captain!
What were those scars on her wrists?
What kind of training did she go through?
All-Japan Women's Middle School Camp
Huh…!?
Nichinan High School
We won't go easy on you.
We'll play with all we've got.
I understand.
All-Japan team vs. Nichinan High School, 3-set match, begin!
Keep the serve!
Give it your all!
Center!
Got it!
All right, let's do this!
– Yeah!
Nichinan High School · All-Japan team
Left!
Center!
Yeah!
Here goes!
Don't mind it, don't mind it!
Keep the serve!
Got it!
Nichinan High School · All-Japan team
Center!
Yeah!
Attack!
Good job!
– Yeah!
Here I go!
Nichinan High School · All-Japan team
Time!
Don't think of them as middle school girls.
Go at it with all you've got.
Got it?
Understood?
– Yes sir!
Don't think of them as middle school girls.
In volleyball, there's no distinction between girls and boys, or middle schools and high schools.
When facing each other on the court, we're all playing the same volleyball.
So play with your full power.
– Yeah!
Fight!
Nichinan High School · All-Japan team
All right, it's the set point.
Hey, let's go easy on them.
The match is already ours.
Those Kyūshū boys stand no chance against us girls.
What a disappointment, hehe.
– Arai-s—
– Arai-san!
Don't fool around on the court.
This game's still on.
Ah…
I-I'm sorry.
Sanjou-san.
It hurts…
Arai-san, fight!
Fight…!
Fight!
Nichinan High School · All-Japan team
That was a harsh battle of raw power…
But right now, they're walking with a smile.
They're finally united.
Supporter.
Here you go.
Here, use this.
Red blood, huh?
It shouldn't be just a bunch of players.
A true team needs that red blood.
Warm, red blood circulating in the human body.
That Hongou.
It's just like he said.
Heh.
Nichinan High School · All-Japan team
Girls.
Let's go together.
To the world championships, where excellent teams from all around the world are gathered.
Let's fight with all we've got…!
The day to challenge the world has finally come.
Ten players who have kept up
with the special training…
…are headed to the Central Gymnasium
in New York together with Coach Inokuma.
For Kozue, her sole enemy is the Soviet Union.
Shellenina's cross toss…
And Borchinskaya's spike…
She keeps Shellenina's words: "I'll be waiting for your challenge" deep inside her heart.
Please look forward
to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.