苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 035—
Facing the world
Excuse me.
Please answer some questions.
Inokuma-san.
There were various problems in the training camp at Miyazaki, but how is All-Japan team doing now?
How far do you think you can go at the world championships?
It will be a success if we could reach the quarterfinals.
What are your expectations, coach?
We can't think you're aiming for the first place, can we?
How about that?
We're aiming for it.
Huh?
Then do you have a secret strategy to win with the Soviet Union?
What kind of strategy is it?
My strategy…
…lies in the individual players' results from the training camp.
It's the ten people over there.
Hey, Kozue—
It'll be all right, mom.
I'll be fine. You don't worry about me, mom.
Exactly.
My dad's all like…
…"don't each too much" and "be sure to wake up early".
He treats me like preschooler.
– But Midori…
– A bird must leave its nest some day.
Right, mama?
It's for the best.
Exactly.
Please have a bit more faith in us.
I see you're both pretty confident.
But the world is vast.
Don't get lost in that world.
Don't say weird things.
This time is different.
Right, Kozue?
Yep. We've trained so hard.
I'm sure we'll put up a good fight.
Yep. That's the spirit.
Yep.
The nicest thing about this trip is that
I won't see you Kyūshū boys for a while.
Eh? Ah, heh.
That's tough.
I'm so happy that I can play. I'll do my best.
Meihou Academy will root for you.
Thanks.
You made it, Noda! Hooray!
– Hooray!
Leave it to me.
Foreigners don't stand a chance against us.
There will be only Americans here.
I wonder if I'll be able to talk with them?
Professor, I'm anxious.
I've practiced with all I've got, but I feel like it wasn't enough.
That's no good.
Stop thinking like that. Don't forget that you were chosen as part of the All Japan team.
You need to work hard.
Yes.
Oh?
Professor, excuse me for a moment.
Shirakawa-san.
Kitami-san.
Thank you.
You came here to see me off?
Everyone will be thrilled to see you. I'll go let them know.
You girls…
We wanted to see you off here for a long time.
We're weak.
No matter how much we regret it, nothing changes that we've dropped out.
Mishima-san, do your best in our place.
I will.
You can count on me.
I'll do my best.
– Mishima-san!
Ah, it's professor Hongou.
Professor.
Hey.
Ayuhara, Hayakawa.
– Sir.
I don't have anything particular to say to you.
I believe in you.
Ah, what's this?
It's the ball we used during the All-Japan championships.
Take it. It holds memories and dreams of the whole Fujimi Academy volleyball team.
What's that? Pay attention!
Get a grip!
Forgive me.
Professor!
It bears the hope of the ones left behind.
Hold onto this ball.
Yes sir.
We'll make it our mascot and do our best.
Good.
I expect a lot from you.
Hongou!
Hm?
Oh, it's you, Inokuma.
Take care of Ayuhara and the team.
Got it.
I pray from the bottom of my heart for your success.
Thank you.
Ah, it's your coach, isn't it?
I'll go say hello to him.
– L-Let him be.
– Eh?
What's wrong?
Everything's fine.
Michiru isn't alone.
Beyond that, I have something to tell you when I come back from America.
What do you want to tell us?
I think it'll surprise you.
Coach Inokuma is full of confidence.
What about you?
Think you can win?
– How is it?
– Ah.
I do.
Can you win with the Soviet Union?
What about United States?
Yes. We will do our utmost.
Can you really win?
Your opponents are strong.
We're well aware of it.
We'll simply do our best.
Aw, that's rather weak statement.
We'll win.
We'll win for sure!
Now we're talking.
Can you promise me victory?
We can.
I swear by that red sun.
Ayuhara-san, what about you?
Very well. We promise you.
The 14 o'clock flight to the New York via Honolulu will be departing soon.
– Good luck!
– Do your best, Ayuhara-san!
Hey, check it out. It's speeding up.
Mishima, good luck!
– Do your best.
– Take it easy.
I'm counting on you, girls.
You better show them, Kyūshū's princess!
Good luck.
Next time you'll visit Haneda…
…will we be rejoicing, or will we be struck with sadness?
Everything depends on the games to come.
Can you win with the Soviet Union?
What about United States?
We'll do our utmost.
Can you really win?
– Your opponents are strong.
– We're well aware of it.
We'll simply do our best.
Ayuhara-san.
I'll be training my and Borchinskaya's cross toss to its limits.
I'll be waiting for your letter of challenge.
Borchinskaya's killer spike.
Ah, it's New York!
– Wah!
– Eh!?
Ah.
We're in America!
– I'll take lots of pictures.
– My heart's racing!
I wonder if the Soviet team is already here.
Hm?
Did you say something?
Nothing.
Here is the Central Gym.
Here the fierce battle is going to start the day after tomorrow and last for one week.
Amazing. We'll be playing here.
It'll host matches between teams from 16 countries.
How far can we go?
The time to challenge the world has finally come.
I'm all itching to play.
Ayuhara.
Ah, Kozue.
Ah? S-Sir.
Gather everyone.
We're going to the hotel.
Yes sir.
Wow, so nice.
It's pretty luxurious.
It's completely different from the Miyazaki training camp.
Wow, it's first time I have such a big bed.
I feel like a princess in a castle.
Kozue, you seem off.
What's wrong?
Do you feel unwell?
No, I'm fine.
It feels a bit unreal that I'm here in America.
I see.
Hey, hey! There are hippies in front of our hotel now!
Real hippies! Wanna go see them?
Kozue, let's go check them out.
Nah, I'll pass. I'm a little tired.
All right. I'll go though.
Hurry up!
Nobody, not even coach Inokuma, knows what's ahead.
What should I do?
Shellenina's cross toss. Borchinskaya's killer spike.
How do we defeat it?
Wait here.
– They're Czechoslovakia's team.
– Wow, they're so tall.
They must be powerful.
Oh?
It's been a long time, Ayuhara-san.
Yep.
Shellenina.
I'm glad we got to meet again.
I was sure that I'd bump into you here.
Who is she?
It's the captain of the Soviet team we played against before.
She has intimidating aura around her.
Last time we played with them,
we felt like children in the dark.
I am really excited to see how far you progressed by now.
Shellenina!
Ah, Cassie!
Ayuhara, let me introduce you.
She's American team's captain, Cassie.
Ah, All-Japan's team.
I'm Ayuhara Kozue.
Pleased to meet you.
How do you do?
– I'm Tom. Nice to meet you.
– Hello.
I have been to Japan once.
Japan is a wonderful country.
I played with both Ayuhara and Cassie before.
I think that your attack and Cassie's attack are both very remarkable.
Then the strength between you two could be said to be fifty-fifty.
Ayuhara.
United States were second in last year's world championship.
We had a hard time playing against Cassie's team's fast and unpredictable attacks.
The Soviet Union who led us by our noses had a hard time?
Yes. Don't you think so, Tom?
Ah, haha.
We're short of time regarding the gym usage, so we decided on the order of practice.
Kenya, Korea.
After them it's our turn.
Make sure to closely observe the other teams while waiting for our turn.
Ah, that's…
Awesome power.
They must weight very little.
We didn't think anything about the other teams.
We dropped the ball in that regard.
And now we're facing teams from all over the world.
I am a little worried what kind of teams we'll bump into.
They're rather unrefined in their technique.
It's changing.
Next is Korea if I recall.
She throws them pretty hard, don't you think?
She must be their captain.
She's like a machine gun.
I'm impressed.
Perfect receiving.
They don't drop a single ball.
It's not just receiving.
It's serving, too.
Tosses, too.
And also spikes.
Everyone is at the same level and plays flawlessly.
But in exchange, they don't seem to possess any special techniques.
They don't have revolving receive nor falling leaf.
They've only focused on polishing standard techniques.
But it seems to have motivated the girls.
Heh.
It is a good lesson.
I've been only thinking about
the Soviet Union until now.
But will we stand up against the other teams until we get to play with the Russians?
Then there are United States who won second place last year.
– Ah, they're here.
– How nice.
I wonder what kind of attack do they have under their disposal.
Ah.
I feel less and less sure.
That's no good.
As their captain, I should encourage them somehow.
But…
But…!
Alright, it's our turn.
– Yes sir.
I'm sure you're thinking about a lot of things after coming here to New York.
The Soviets aren't our only enemies.
There are lots of other formidable enemies.
Focus fully on the enemy that stands before you.
– Yes sir.
Okay, time to practice.
Finally it is Japan team. Take a good look.
Here we go, Ayuhara!
Ah, damn!
What's wrong?
It's no good.
What's that?
What's with your form?
I can't believe it!
Oh!
What's the matter?
Shellenina, what's this? Surely that's not the extent of Japanese skill?
Strange.
I'm puzzled.
Spike! Kakinouchi, you first!
Sanjou, your turn!
Not good! Everyone's nervous!
If things continue like this and we end up losing the first round…
…I can't return to Japan.
I didn't see that coming.
Things went down surprisingly, but I still think it'll be all right.
We'll overcome it somehow.
Yep. I didn't feel very well today. There's nothing to worry about.
We'll regain our form in no time.
Ah, finally at hotel.
– I'm hungry.
– Let's check out the city after we eat.
Yeah.
Ayuhara-san.
Do you need anything?
Ayuhara-san, Cassie wants to invite you and the Japanese team to a party.
Huh?
Party?
That's right.
Please come by all means.
Thanks for the invitation. However, I have to consult it with our coach before I can reply.
Hi!
Ah, Cassie said she'd be really thrilled to see you come over.
Cassie.
Come on, Ayuhara-san.
Kozue, we can't refuse her after
she went through the trouble to invite us.
A real party! That's great!
But we have a game tomorrow.
I don't think it's best time to be partying.
That's right. We didn't fly here to party.
I oppose to it too. We should do it when we have more free time.
But it's our chance to know the life of an American middle school student.
Yeah.
– Ayuhara.
– Sir.
I'm going to a preparatory meeting
for tomorrow's game.
Yes sir.
Ah, uhm, coach…
What is it?
Actually, we were invited to a party from the American team.
Decisions about such matters are up to you, the captain.
Lovely, professor Inokuma's understanding.
Come on, let's go.
Welcome. We've been waiting for you eagerly.
Thank you for the invitation.
Ah, you came after all! I'm really glad.
Americans are pretty open, aren't they?
Hey, let's welcome them!
They're the Japanese wonder girls!
Hi!
They're the All-America team members.
Make yourself at home. Take a seat.
Ayuhara-san, let me have this dance.
Ah, no, I'm bad at da—
Come on, dance with him, captain.
Yeah. Don't be party pooper.
Let's dance too.
Yep.
Ah, I'm hungry.
I have to eat something first.
Ah, delicious.
– Come on.
– No no, I can't dance.
How is it, Kozue? It was a good call, don't you think?
Yep.
What cheerful people.
I know.
Maybe that's how it should be.
We might have the game tomorrow, but nothing good will come of it if we overthink it.
Coach Inokuma didn't really oppose to this party.
He must have known we're nervous and wanted us to relax a bit.
Ayuhara-san.
I got a call just now.
The first game is United States vs. Japan.
All right, everyone. Let's make a toast for the match between Japan and America tomorrow.
Everyone together.
– Cheers.
Ayuhara.
Last year, United States' team was second in the world.
We had a hard time playing against Cassie's team's fast and unpredictable attacks.
Let's do our best.
– Yeah!
If I show a sign of weakness, it's our defeat.
We've came to the America on behalf of the Japanese nation.
– Can you really win?
– Your opponents are strong.
We will win.
We will definitely win.
I swear by the red sun like Midori in the Haneda airport that we will win.
We'll show them what we're made of and demonstrate a splendid victory.
Both with USA and USSR.
At last, the curtain of the World Junior Volleyball Championship is unveiled.
The long and hard training of All-Japan's team…
…was all for today's sake.
Starting from Midori's serve, the battle they have bet their youth on…
…aiming for victory and glory, is on.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.