苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 036—
The Black Whirlwind
We've arrived.
To America. To New York.
And at the World Junior Volleyball Championship.
The long and painful training camp was all for this week.
That's right.
Midori's serve starts the battle we bet our youth on.
Ah?
Cassie's smiling.
Is that self-esteem of a team placed second last year?
Protect me, Dad.
She did it!
I did it.
Somehow.
Good!
Easy-peasy.
Hayakawa-san alone is going to win for us.
I can't believe it.
It that the runner-up team?
Where's your energy from yesterday's party, Cassie?
Good! Show them your Japanese fighting spirit!
That's great support.
We must not let them down.
Okay, stay focused!
Yeah!
Ready or not, here I go!
Let's keep this up in the second set.
Piece of cake. Volleyball
is way easier than boy hunting.
We'll land straight victory.
Something's up. It's going too well.
Here it is, my chance ball!
They're good.
An ordinary team would break under such score difference in the first set.
But they continue to play at their pace.
They're calm like the Hudson River.
Hudson River - a river flowing through New York City.
It's just as I feared.
Now they're going to show what they really can.
It was just a fluke.
Let's give as good as we get.
Damn. Dribble.
Midori must be tired bad that she commenced foul play.
Not just Midori. Everyone's tired.
No good. They tired us out.
Cassie's still smiling.
Even though we are doing our best…
…she is still so composed.
Even a preschooler could accept that.
Is that all you've got, Japanese team?
We're doing what we can.
Don't make it more miserable.
Time to get serious. If the enemy plays at their pace, so will we.
Kozue!
Attack!
Beaten again.
As long as Cassie's smiling we have no chance to win.
One more point. We need to get that point.
If we lose here, it's game over.
Great, Japanese team!
It was splendid, Kozue.
We were very lucky.
We won thanks to that last point.
It's great that we beat the favorites at the first match.
But I don't understand Cassie's team.
They were smiling until the very end.
Ah?
Hi.
Congratulations, Ayuhara-san.
Eh? Ah, err…
Thank you.
We lost but it was a lot of fun.
Eh? Fun?
Yes. Volleyball is wonderful.
We are very happy to have played such a fun game with you all.
They're much more easy-going than us.
Now that I think of it,
volleyball ought to be fun, right?
I feel like an idiot for noticing it just now.
It's no surprise. We forgot it in the middle of our special training.
But if we continue like this, we will end up in the finals without any problems.
Let's see… our next match is with Korea, huh.
Hey, the coach called us over. The Soviet team is playing now.
We're to study their style.
The Soviets?
What for? They're playing against some debuting team from Kenya.
Ah, that team without any substitute players?
Which means Shellenina's going to go easy on them, for sure.
Actually, it's on the contrary.
Eh?
Looks like Kenyan team puts them under pressure.
What?
Anyway, Manumba, one of their players, is particularly outstanding.
Awesome jump.
Her arm power is great too.
I'd say even Olympic players can't do such a drive serve.
But she plays so inaccurately.
One should aim more precisely during serving.
Shellenina's still retains her cross toss.
She's saving it until the end.
I'd like to see your famous killer spike soon, Borchinskaya-san.
She aimed at the edge.
– She's fast!
– Like a raging bull.
She has no technique, but she sure has power.
It's not just power. It's her spirit. The fight.
Ah!
Wow, not even Shellenina could receive that.
I heard people call her "The Black Whirlwind".
"The Black Whirlwind"?
We won the first game and eased up. But we still don't know what opponents we've yet to face.
They might actually win.
She strikes well. It is reckless though.
Ah, Kozue, look at that.
It's the cross toss!
The cross toss.
The killer spike comes right after.
That's it. That's her killer spike!
Sh-She received it!
But something's wrong with Manumba-san.
She's hurt.
She received that spike, but it fell so bad that she injured her leg.
So what are they going to do?
The Kenyan team has no substitutes.
She's right.
Their country is poor and they could afford bringing only six players.
No, no!
No! Oh, no!
She doesn't want to leave the court.
No!
She wants to keep playing like this…?
Ah…
Nchi yangu Kenya!
I wonder what did she just shout?
"Nchi yangu Kenya".
It means "my Kenya".
Nchi yangu Kenya.
Kenya, our fatherland,
won independence not long ago.
For these girls, this means everything.
Nchi yangu Kenya.
My fatherland Kenya.
It's only natural they want to call out for their country.
"My Kenya".
"Nchi yangu Kenya"…
Nchi yangu Kenya!
Oh?
You all saw the game, didn't you?
We did.
Even though Kenya lost to the Soviets, they received warm applause.
How did you view Manumba crawling on the court?
Did you think it was ugly?
Or…?
I thought it was beautiful.
I see. Why?
Well, that is because she tried to do her best despite being in such sorry situation.
Very well.
No matter the situation, one needs to do their utmost.
That posture in itself is beautiful.
Let me ask another question.
Can you say your first match was beautiful?
First you were too tense.
Then you gave in to the crowd's taunts.
That posture cannot be called beautiful!
That's all.
Seeing Manumba's fight was worth more than a hundred of my lectures.
The next match is Korea.
This time you better do your best.
– Yes sir.
That's bad.
If we keep playing like this, we won't win.
We have to come up with something.
Midori!
Machine gun-like attack.
Having Sanjou-san switch attack with Kakinouchi-san should earn us some points.
But Captain Sai doesn't seem to be concerned.
We can't let our guard down.
Captain Sai looks like she's up to something.
Looks like we're in tough spot.
We need to destroy their balance somehow.
That was Sai's bullet spike.
She accepts the tossed ball with impetus and slams it just above the net.
It's unlike Borchinskaya-san's cannon-like and Sanjou-san's machine gun-like attack.
It's like a rapid-fire gun.
Ah!
She did it!
They're no easy opponents.
The first set is a complete defeat.
Sai is the central figure in the Korean team.
We have to set her off somehow.
Ah, aim for their captain.
Got it.
"Aim for their captain"…
I'll do my best.
Look at me, Coach Inokuma.
Excellent, Midori!
Your curve ball has surprised Sai-san.
Good. The second set is ours.
It's just like I thought.
Sai-san is tired and started to lose control.
– Kozue!
– Got it!
Attack!
Seems they got used to
the atmosphere on the court.
That's good.
I just do my best.
I can't hear the audience any more.
Attack!
I no longer think I'm in America. I just fight with all I've got.
That's the current me.
Attack!
– Ah! Kozue!
– Midori!
No matter how much I sign, there's no end.
Really. We should've do some sign practices.
Don't pull me too hard.
We only win two matches so far
but we've already got plenty fans.
– Sign, sign please.
– Okay.
E-Excuse me for a moment.
It's my mascot that's very important to me.
Kozue! Kozue…
Oh, no!
Give it back! Please, give it back!
That ball is my treasure!
Please, wait! Wait!
Wait!
Give it back!
I've completely lost track of him.
But what is this place?
Hello, baby.
Johnny stole the mascot ball.
Kozue goes after the boy and winds up in front of the slums.
There, Kozue finds Johnny practice football using volleyball.
The violent act burns in Kozue's eyes.
Meetings or practices, the vision of it comes back again and again.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.