苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 037—
The two-stage reception
Wait!
Give that ball back!
I told you to wait!
I've completely lost track of him.
That was our mascot ball…
Ah?
Ah…!
W-What do you want?
W-What are you going to do to me!?
S-Somebody help me!
Stop it!
I said stop it!
Ah, you're…
What are you doing to my friend!?
Scram!
Sorry to surprise you, Miss Ayuhara.
Virginia. You were on American team in yesterday's match.
Yeah, but I was benched the whole time.
But what are you doing here, Captain Ayuhara?
I was chasing a boy who ran away with my important mascot ball.
He stole your ball, huh?
Was he about this tall?
Yes! Do you have any idea who he is?
It must be Johnny.
He's always wanted a ball for himself.
Let's visit him.
He lives upstairs.
– Hello.
– Hi.
How are you feeling, ma'am?
Oh, it's you, Virginia.
You should stay still, ma'am.
Take it easy. We came here to see Johnny.
Did he get into trouble again?
No, don't worry.
I just need his help.
Oh, I see.
He's probably playing in the back street.
Thank you, ma'am.
Don't worry about anything.
Well, we're off. Bye!
Poor woman. It's terrible, being bedridden all day long.
This way.
Huh?
He's practicing soccer all by himself…?
And doing pretty well.
What amazing reflexes.
That power is unthinkable for a child.
– Johnny!
– Oh?
Ah!
Johnny…
Give back that ball.
Hmph.
So you two are friends now, Virginia?
What on earth are you talking about?
That doesn't matter. What matters is that God Himself won't forgive stealing.
But those players have plenty of white balls.
One less shouldn't matter.
But Johnny, that ball is an important mascot for the All-Japan team.
Hmph. I don't care.
This ball is mine now.
Johnny!
Stick it!
Wait! Listen to me!
Virginia!
I can't blame Johnny after seeing this place.
But of all the volleyballs he could've taken…
This is the ball you won the last All-Japan championships with.
Hold on to this and make it your mascot.
That ball holds the courage and memories
of Fujimi Academy's volleyball team.
Miss Ayuhara!
I'm sorry.
I lost Johnny.
Thank you for going out of your way to help me.
No problem. It is something very important to you, after all.
I will surely get it back later.
But for now I'll walk you back. Everyone must be worried.
Thanks.
Tsk.
But I'm really surprised.
If Johnny wants a ball so much,
I can give him any other volleyball.
Ayuhara! You'd just give him another volleyball?
Yes.
But the ball he took is our lucky charm.
That's why—
Stop right there, Miss Ayuhara.
Virginia!?
He steals your ball and yet
you'd just give him "another one"?
It's like you're running a charity.
Boy, that must feel good.
That's not it! I was only thinking of Johnny—
Save it.
Even if you really feel that way,
we refuse to be pitied.
I don't understand, Virginia!
It's just… when a rich person gives something to the poor for no reason…
…it can't be called anything but pity.
I will bring the ball Johnny stole to your hotel tomorrow morning.
Virginia! Virginia!
"Like running a charity"…?
But I just thought Johnny would be happy
if he could have another ball.
I suppose my selfish excuse for kindness hurt her pride.
I'm sorry, Virginia.
I guess even the poor have their pride as human beings.
How could I forget something so important?
I have to apologize to her tomorrow.
This is America, the world's most civilized country.
What's wrong, Kozue?
You look like country bumpkin, gawking outside window like that.
I can't believe it.
Behind such a wonderful illumination…
…live people like Virginia.
Oh, this is about you getting lost downtown again?
That was just a slum's area. Japan has those too.
Heh. What's so surprising about—
Midori!
Huh?
Of course I know we have those too.
But I've never seen one in person.
Oh.
I see.
I saw it for the first time when I met Virginia.
I've only been thinking about volleyball up until now.
We won against the U.S. team
and now South Korea.
And we'll play against Romania tomorrow.
Which is going to be easy.
We're the superior team,
in both power and technique.
However, the problem is how we plan to achieve our victory.
How we win?
Let me say it clearly. Our goal is the Soviet Union.
Borchinskaya's killer spike and iron curtain-like blocking.
We have no one that can defend against it.
Exactly.
I'll think of a strategy.
But tomorrow, I want all of you to show how accurately you can play against Romania.
How accurate we can play?
The Romanian team is said to use their power first and foremost.
But we're going to stir that up.
And at the same time, this can serve as rehearsal for your match against the Soviet team.
Alright. That's all for today.
Have a good sleep.
We should be friendly with the other team at
the World Championships, but I still want to win.
The Soviet team is our overall goal, after all.
But we still need to come up with something.
Killer spike.
We don't have much time.
If you try to take on a killer spike directly,
it'll only knock you down.
How…!? How can we defend against it!?
Ah.
I can't think of anything.
Oh?
That speed… but more importantly, that force…
Sharp like the killer spike.
But when Virginia called him out…
Johnny!
When he got hit on the head…
The ball lost its force like a balloon as it fell.
If you manage to defend against that forceful spike once, its power will drop by half.
So rather than trying to accept it, we should focus on defusing it.
We'll fail if we try to receive it directly.
But if one of us was able to relay it
and flip it behind themselves…
The killer spike's force would be cut in half.
In other words, two-stage reception that adds another receptive player.
It's pretty far off from volleyball's common practices.
But there is hope.
I have to think this through and consult it with the coach.
Two-stage reception.
This ray of hope was possible thanks to our mascot ball and Johnny.
Thank you.
Looks like we'll get through this somehow, thanks to you.
– Now we have plenty of practice time.
– Ayuhara!
Virginia!
Everyone, wait a moment.
We came to return the ball.
Thank you. I really am sorry for yesterday.
Don't worry, Ayuhara.
Now, Johnny, give the girl her ball back.
Johnny. Apologize to her already.
And swear you will never steal again.
I'm giving it back.
Go to hell!
Johnny!
Virginia!
I'm sorry he made a scene.
It's alright.
Johnny can keep the ball. Consider it a gift.
Ayuhara! You don't understand anything.
No, this time I have a good reason.
I wanted to give you my thanks for—
No matter what the reason is,
you're not doing this for Johnny's sake.
But Johnny wanted this ball…
I wanted to talk to you about why Johnny stole your ball in the first place.
This is hardly an excuse for Johnny's theft.
But Johnny's mom is sick and his dad was killed in action three years ago.
His mother lives a life where she can't even afford to see a doctor.
So Johnny is trying to become a professional soccer player, to break free from his poverty.
A professional soccer player?
To have any chance of experiencing
even a little bit of the high life…
…there is no choice for him but to become a musician or a professional sportsman.
I understand Johnny's feelings.
But I don't approve of him thinking that sports is just a way to make a lot of money.
Johnny saw in that white ball
his only hope for a happy future.
A princess like you who only plays volleyball for fun
can't possibly understand his desperation.
Wait. I don't just play volleyball for fun.
Then why are you playing volleyball?
I'm playing…
…to win.
Is that so? So it's for the glory of victory?
How showy, for celebrations and people's praise.
Hahaha.
What's so funny?
Sports are there for money.
But for the glory of victory…?
Glory won't pay for a single piece of bread!
Virginia!
People are waiting for you.
See you.
Captain, hurry up!
– What are you doing?
– What's taking you so long?
Come on!
Ayuhara-san, you're great today!
We haven't even started yet.
A princess only playing for fun.
Princess only playing for fun.
Victory.
Glory.
Showy celebrations.
People's praise.
Hahaha.
I can't believe it.
The glory of victory isn't worth a single piece of bread…
Ah!
It hurts.
What amazing power.
Kakinouchi-san.
Oh, Captain. Wanna play?
What are we going to do?
Practice receiving killer spikes.
Killer spikes?
But…
Killer spike is all about grazing the net and hitting the receiver's chest with great power.
That's why we'll start with spikes from only three meters away.
Once we receive that,
we'll gradually shorten the distance.
That way we can produce power and speed similar to the killer spike.
I see.
The two-stage reception…
Let's try it out right now.
All of this for the glory of victory?
How worthless.
T-That's not true. That's not it!
Captain, what are you thinking about?
Huh?
Ah, no, it's nothing.
I'll try receiving. Kakinouchi-san, please.
Okay.
I'm ready.
Got it.
Okay?
Captain…!
It's all right! Let's continue!
Kozue's acting strange.
It's like she's losing the ball on purpose.
What's up with you, Captain?
You're acting different than usual.
It's nothing, don't worry about it.
"Don't worry", she says…
Looks like we can pull it off.
– We might stand a chance against the S—
– Hahaha!
You win and then what?
Sports are there for money.
The glory of victory won't buy you a single piece of bread.
Nice social status, you little princess playing for fun.
For fun!
Is that who I am?
I don't understand anything anymore.
Huh?
No.
This holds a different value than bread.
Putting up such a fight
was all for the glory of victory.
It's what I worked hard for and spilled blood for.
I've overcome one grueling obstacle after another.
That's just my way of living,
loving volleyball from the bottom of my heart.
And I want Virginia to acknowledge that.
This isn't the whim of some princess.
It's a serious battle I've invested my life in.
Sports aren't just for making money.
It's a serious fight.
Even though we have different circumstances,
I need her to understand this.
She needs to see what volleyball means to us.
This place…
It's my last chance to connect with Virginia.
What do you need?
Please pass this onto Virginia and Johnny.
Huh?
Okay.
This is for the best. Virginia will come for sure.
To watch our volleyball.
Alright, keep it up.
Keep them confused.
– Yes sir.
She'll come. I'm sure of it.
Alright, let's go!
– Yeah!
Yay, we won!
So she didn't came after all…
Ayuhara!
Huh?
Congratulations.
I had to work at my part-time job,
so I couldn't make it.
So that's how it was?
I wanted you to see it.
But it didn't fully go to waste.
I get to keep these tickets
as a token to remember you by.
Goodbye.
I won't shake hands with you just yet.
Huh?
Before we do…
You are a volleyball player, too.
Please accept one serve from me.
Okay.
Come on!
Falling leaf!
Ah!
Ah…!
Attack!
I won?
Ah!?
Ayuhara…?
That ball won today's game.
See you!
Ayuhara, you won.
It was a wonderful victory.
Thank you.
Thank you…
Alright. I'll definitely complete the two-stage reception…
…thanks to the wonderful hint Johnny gave me.
Just as expected, the USSR
easily beats Czechoslovakia.
Now they're going to face the All-Japan team.
In order to defuse Borchinskaya's killer spike…
…Kozue secretly carries out
her training of the two-stage reception.
But, for some reason, Inokuma's expression is grim.
What secret does the two-stage reception hold?
Please look forward
to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.