苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 038—
Secret operation with friends
Coach, please listen.
I've thought of a way to receive Borchinskaya's killer spike.
Hm?
Let's hear it.
It's still rough around the edges, sir.
But I figured it out after our game with South Korea was over…
…and a boy named Johnny stole our mascot ball.
What a beautiful nighttime view.
You just don't get these in Tōkyō.
We should go down there some time and see it all.
When the games are over, we'll ask Coach to take us.
Dear Papa. Today we defeated Romania in the semifinals.
The day after tomorrow we'll play our final game.
We'll probably play against the USSR.
Hey, why don't we play cards?
Good idea!
Hayakawa-san, come play with us, too.
Okay.
Ah, what about Captain?
I just saw her in the hallway going to Coach's room.
I see.
She's probably discussing strategies with him.
Let's start already. Come on.
– Yeah.
– Okay.
Keep going.
Sir.
I saw Johnny practicing soccer very hard
with the ball he'd stolen.
His speed…
But especially his forcefulness…
It was sharp like Borchinskaya's killer spike.
But when Virginia called him out…
The ball hit him in head…
And it lost its force and fell behind him like a deflated balloon.
So, then I thought to myself…
Would it be possible to cut the power
of the strike in half by relaying it once?
In other words—
You can receive Borchinskaya's killer spike
if you divide the reception in two.
Precisely. A two-stage reception.
To accomplish it, rather than bumping it
to the front, you'd send it back.
E-Exactly!
Perhaps Coach noticed me during our training?
Hm.
You've got us a good strategy.
Ayuhara.
You did well, coming up with this.
Coach, what do you think?
Don't rush it.
As you know, Borchinskaya's spike is…
Even Manumba, who was such a prominent and fit player…
…collapsed on the floor from receiving it.
It really is a killer spike.
Also, in practice, it's very hard
to play a ball backwards.
If you make one mistake, you'll only cause great chaos on your side of the court.
But even if you hypothetically succeed with the two-stage reception…
…the problem is how you launch an attack afterwards.
Just succeeding at receiving it
won't earn us any points.
Then there's the most important problem:
Coming up with new exercises at this point.
Huh?
If you can master it, fine. But if you can't…
…you'll just unnecessarily confuse the rest of the team.
Furthermore, you'll just make them fear killer spikes even more.
He's right.
And yet I practiced backwards receptions in front of everyone.
I'm glad I didn't announce anything yet.
So before we start training the two-stage reception, we need to be sure that it even works.
That way we can take a look
at your suggestion from all angles.
Yes sir.
Tomorrow the Soviets play against Czechoslovakia, which is to our favor.
It's a good opportunity for us
to study on the real thing.
Speaking of Czechoslovakia,
I remembered their match against Mexico.
I can't forget the wonderful revolving receive that Češka did.
Češka is a cousin of Čáslavská. It seems she learned a lot about gymnastics from her.
Věra Čáslavská – a Czechoslovakian artistic gymnast and Czech sports official
Čáslavská, who has been called the queen of gymnastics, is Češka's cousin?
Borchinskaya's killer spike vs. Češka's revolving receive.
Ayuhara. Watch them closely.
Yes sir.
Czechoslovakia is doing better than expected.
Every time the Soviets serve, Češka instructs the receiver where the ball will land.
She really has a handle on her team.
Yes, but the Soviets haven't shown their true power yet.
Huh?
The proofs right in Borchinskaya's still being on the bench.
But I know what's going on in their coach's head.
He doesn't want to use Borchinskaya in today's game.
He's saving her for tomorrow's finals.
But he'll need to have her come out sooner or later.
Wow, she tied the score!
One method to break the Soviets' iron block is to aim at the line.
It's not a real method. It's a sink-or-swim gamble.
The risk was too high.
Češka took that bet and won, but it's not going to last long.
That's just how bets are.
Ah, Borchinskaya!
Ah.
Borcha!
It's over!
Revolving receive!
Ah.
Saw that, Ayuhara?
Yes sir.
Češka's revolving receive
is superior in every way to mine.
And yet, she let it slam the court.
Now I understand what Coach meant in the training camp in Miyazaki.
The last set was pretty close,
but this set is completely different.
After Češka failed to receive Borchinskaya's spike…
…Czechoslovakia started to collapse
like a house of cards.
Who knows if we're going to be just as powerless tomorrow as Czechoslovakia is today?
We've got to think of a way to receive that killer spike.
Ayuhara.
Sir!?
When the second set is over, bring everyone back to the hotel.
Huh?
In the meantime, I'll try to secure us a place where we can secretly practice the two-stage reception.
Coach…?
I analyzed it all night long.
But seeing Borchinskaya's spike today has finally convinced me.
To counter Borchinskaya's killer spike,
we're going to need that two-stage reception.
Coach…
Listen, Ayuhara.
Borchinskaya's killer spike is like South Korean team's Sai's bullet spike.
Its power and speed are almost the same.
Oh, Sai-san's spike?
Ops.
Borchinskaya and Sai are roughly the same height.
It would be very convenient if we could practice with someone with a spike such as hers.
Well, talking won't get things done.
Don't forget what I've just said, Ayuhara.
Yes sir.
Huh? We'll practice a two-stage reception?
Yep.
Coach went to find us a court where we could practice in secret.
With the two-stage reception
we'll have nothing to be afraid of, right?
But can we really learn
the two-stage reception in just one day?
Oh, that must be Coach.
Hai? Oh, I mean…
Yes?
It's not our coach…?
What?
Sai?
I must have surprised you,
paying you a sudden visit like this.
Huh? Oh, no.
Heh. Well, I guess you're right.
Actually, I overheard you and your coach talking about me at the Central Gymnasium.
Huh?
Then you heard about
the two-stage reception as well?
Yes. That too.
So by "Sai" she meant
South Korean's captain, Sai-san?
We've struggled a lot with her bullet spike.
What does Sai-san need with our captain?
Huh?
You'll really come play with us at our practice?
The pleasure is all mine.
I hope I can be of use to you.
Thank you, Sai-san!
Mister Daigo Inokuma?
I'm sorry, but this is the weekday, after all.
Every school's gym is in use.
Is that so?
Sorry for the trouble.
Just a moment.
Why don't you practice at the Central Gymnasium?
You see…
I'm in a hurry, so I'll need to excuse myself.
We need to do this training in secret.
If we do it at the Central Gymnasium and let the reporters near us…
…all of our effort will go to waste.
However, to think that there's
no other place where we could practice…
Hey!
Hippie coach!
Wait, you're from the American team, aren't you?
Yes, I'm their captain, Cassie.
Hippie coach.
Um, "hippie coach" is rather embarrassing.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Hippie coach is your nickname.
That's what we called you within our team.
I see. Haha.
I wonder what Coach is doing?
He probably can't find an empty court.
If we can't practice the two-stage reception…
If we can't master it…!
I'll end up on the court just like Češka…
no, even worse than that.
It's not just me. Everyone in here—
Oh, Coach!?
Really?
Yeah.
Cassie from the American team got her father to put in a request.
The Rotary Club will let us borrow us a gym.
Actually, Coach, we have great news, too.
What?
The South Korean team's captain, Sai, is here?
Sai-kun. We really appreciate this.
I was free anyway.
And I'm very happy that I get to play with the All-Japan team once more.
Cassie not only went through
a lot of effort to let us borrow this court…
…but she also gathered members of her team
to accommodate us with a proper practice session.
Cassie!
Thank you very much.
We don't have to go to school until the end
of the World Championships anyway.
So we're all free.
Most of us are not as strong as the Soviet team, though.
Ladies. Czechoslovakia lost 3 to 0 to the Soviet Union.
Therefore, as expected, our opponent in the final match tomorrow will be the Soviet Union.
Listen up.
We'll now commence the two-stage reception training to counter Borchinskaya's killer spike in tomorrow's finals.
Yes sir!
The basis of the two-stage reception is this…
Oh, he's using chess?
Let's say Borchinskaya performs her spike from here.
The receiver repels her spike backwards.
At the same time the player here runs out of the court and sends it back.
They'll need to be much faster than the ball.
Huh?
Runs o—
Err, runs out of the court?
Next is this player.
Huh? Professor.
Professor!
Professor Hongou!
Oh, it's you, Ichinose?
Good morning, Professor.
Morning. Starting the day with a stroll?
Yes. You too, Professor?
Heh. You could say that.
I just heard in the news that
the Soviet team got into the finals, after all.
I wonder what Ayuhara-kun and her team are doing now?
I was just thinking the same thing.
I guess they're taking a good rest
to prepare for the final game tomorrow.
No, that's not Inokuma's style.
I bet he's giving everyone one last drill.
Who do you think is going to win, Professor?
Hm.
Well, it's obvious that the All-Japan team
is very strong, just like Inokuma's pride.
But the Soviets have become stronger, too.
That iron block and Borchinskaya's spike.
I wonder how Inokuma plans to counter these?
Run faster!
Y-Yes sir!
– Next!
– Yes sir!
One more minute. Hurry up!
Y-Yes sir.
When I think about it, it is kind of weird to hold races in reception training.
Hahaha.
– Hey! Quit running your mouth!
– Yes sir.
Next!
The All-Japan team isn't here yet.
They haven't returned to the hotel yet.
Really?
The Russians returned from their training long ago
and are holding a team meeting in their hotel.
I really don't have the slightest idea where our volleyball girls could have gone.
You don't think they'd go sightseeing before such an important game, do you?
Well, Coach Inokuma surely doesn't make reporting any easier for us, either way.
Next!
Use your lower body more! Make sure
to stay calm at the moment of receiving.
Yes sir.
– Next!
– Yes sir!
How many times do I need to repeat myself!?
That ribbon isn't there just for elegance!
Don't try to return it to an attacker right away and aim it at that ribbon!
Okay.
No good.
Ayuhara, what were you doing at the camp in Miyazaki?
What are we going to do
if you can't even do this much?
I'm sorry, sir.
The remaining problem is the Soviets' iron block.
But I don't think there's that much to be afraid of.
When Captain Shellenina turns
to Borchinskaya, she can no longer block you.
We can earn points by targeting that opening.
This is the end of the meeting tonight,
but one last word.
Thanks to everyone's efforts we managed to figure out the two-stage reception.
Ayuhara.
Kakinouchi.
Yes.
Sanjou.
Hayakawa.
Yoshimura.
Arai.
Noda.
Ootsuki.
Miyatsu.
Mishima.
Everyone of you held out well so far.
You have my gratitude.
Give everything you have in tomorrow's finals and play without regrets.
That's all I want from you right now.
Yes sir.
It's open.
Sai-san!?
Oh, it's you, Sai-san.
Coach Inokuma.
Everyone.
I came here to say good-bye.
Our team is flying home tonight.
Huh?
I really wanted to see tomorrow's finals.
But unfortunately we lost twice in a row,
so we have to go home.
So, Sai-san, you used up all of your remaining time here to practice with us…?
Well, I didn't come to America to play around.
I came here to play volleyball.
Captain Ayuhara.
Good luck tomorrow.
Thank you.
We're fellow Asians, after all.
Everyone of All-Japan.
Please do your best in our stead.
Thank you, Sai-san.
Please give my regards to the Korean team.
Alright, let's go.
– Okay.
– Sure.
First Cassie and her American team.
And now Sai-kun's sincerity.
There are some things I've long forgotten during the last decade.
Now it feels like they're all slowly coming back to me.
The beauty of dreams and the human heart.
Well, girls.
We have last mission.
Tomorrow's finals!
We'll do it.
We will do our best.
We will play to the best of our ability
as her Asian sisters!
The curtain of the final match is finally pulled back.
To counter Shellenina and Borchinskaya's killer spike, the core of Soviets' offense…
…the Japanese team underwent a secret training of the two-stage reception.
They unleash falling leaf and quick play attacks.
Fierce sparks scatter between both teams,
aiming for the world's best.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.