苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 039—
The World Championship Finals
Good going!
Keep it up!
Here goes!
Now, now!
Shoot!
Come on, come on!
Damn, he got me!
Nice one, Johnny!
Geez, it's already that late?
Hey, Johnny! Where are you going?
Ah!
Damn…! Alright then!
Gotta hurry, gotta hurry!
Ow!
You idiot!
What if I'm late!?
Johnny!
Huh?
It's late so we came to pick you up.
Come on, get in.
But…
So you're Johnny?
– You're one lively fellow.
– Hehe.
This is my captain, Cassie.
I'm Tom. Hop on in.
But… I'm all covered in dirt.
So you'll be okay with being late to Ayuhara's game?
Isn't that the ball you got from Ayuhara?
Looks like you patched things up.
Johnny, we're gonna be late.
Come on, now, hurry up.
Okay!
I'm going to work this baby, I hope you can handle it.
Tsk.
Don't insult me.
Go at it full speed!
Oh, the Japanese flag?
Ayuhara! Japan!
Ayuhara!
The final match of Japan vs.
the Soviet Union is about to begin.
Here at the New York Central Gymnasium, both teams will fight for the world's crown.
Will the victory go to the Soviet Union,
or to the debuting Japanese team?
The Japanese team has been playing brilliantly so far, really shaking things up in this tournament.
But the Soviet team still holds the title
of world's best from last year championship.
The expectations for them are very heavy.
On the right we now see the warming up
of Ayuhara Kozue, the Japanese team's captain.
Kozue-kun.
The Japanese team is known
as the "oriental wonder girls" overseas.
Will they show us a wonder today as well?
So that was the kickoff.
We look forward to an exciting game.
Chance ball!
The Soviets' show their renowned block.
We need to penetrate their block.
We got the first point!
We need to break through their block!
Stay calm! We panic, we lose!
We haven't even started!
Yeah!
Coach gave us the sign.
Okay.
Let's get them!
– Yeah!
We did it!
Nice one!
Great! Keep it up!
Midori.
The Japanese team feints!
Their strategy smuggled the ball right behind the Soviets' block.
Good luck, Ayuhara!
Good luck, Japan!
Do your best!
Good going, Japan!
Ah!?
We're leading, but…
I wonder what's wrong?
They're only focusing on their defense now.
What happened to going at us with their full power?
And Borchinskaya hasn't come out either.
What a strong drive serve!
The Soviets claim the ball!
They send it back at Japan.
Japan comes in contact!
One! Two! Three!
Japan scores a point!
The All-Japan team's excellent teamwork.
Japan has a set point!
What's wrong?
When I think of how there's only one point left,
my heart won't stop pounding.
This is only the first set.
It's too early to get all worked up.
The Japanese team's spike slams the Soviet team's court, making them the first to reach set point.
Good going, Japan!
The Japanese team wins the first set.
The All-Japan team is now one step closer to the title of world's best.
Honey! Kozue won the first set!
It's too early to celebrate.
Let's just hope they win
the second or third set as well.
There's nothing to be afraid of. It's Kozue-kun we're talking about.
So far, the Russians have concentrated on their defense to see how they attack.
They're a very careful team.
What are you going to do about it, Inokuma?
They'll start with the attack in the second set.
This is where the real game starts.
They lost the first set, but they don't seem to be upset at all.
On the contrary, they're very calm.
You've been carefully analyzing our power.
When will you show the cross toss, Shellenina?
Keep going!
Japan!
Ayuhara, keep going!
Keep it up!
Got it!
Ah!
Oh!
This is bad.
They're rushing it.
We're losing our concentration.
Time!
Borchinskaya!
Ayuhara! Hang in there!
Borcha.
Shellenina.
Hey! There's nothing to be afraid of!
It's coming!
The cross toss!
Receive!
You did it!
Great job!
An excellent play from Japan!
They succeed at a two-stage reception
suitable for world's best!
You did it!
The match isn't over yet!
Accept it!
Ah!
– She got her!?
– Yoshimura-san, are you okay?
It hurts…!
Yoshimura-san!
Sorry…
Her spike… got my fingers.
She hurt her fingers?
The ball's force must be different from our practice with Sai.
It's exactly as I feared.
Ootsuki! Switch with her!
Yes sir!
Time!
Good job.
Thanks. Good luck.
You did well.
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm sorry.
What to do, now?
How can I make the two-stage reception more reliable?
Good!
As expected from the Soviet team, the holder of the world's best title.
Their tenacity has turned the tables and won them the second set.
Ah.
Alright.
Huh?
The force behind that
cross toss spike is something else.
If anybody was able to receive it and overcome that block, they'd really deserve the title of world's best.
I know, right?
I wonder what's next?
Good luck in the third set.
Hang in there, girls.
Good luck, All-Japan!
If they keep it up, they'll be fine.
They'll be fine!
Understand? We have to try it.
With this you should be able to receive
and pass it to the back reliably.
But, Coach…
I mean, it sounds good in theory…
But we didn't practice it at all.
You can do it! It's not that hard.
It's volleyball basics.
That's true, but still…
The important thing is to try first.
You won't know if you can until you try.
Admit it.
Isn't this the reason everyone started playing volleyball in the first place?
Okay, go!
– Yes sir!
Ayuhara!
– Japan! – Good luck!
– Ayuhara!
Aihala!
It's coming!
You can do it!
Inokuma.
A bold play like that is just like you.
If you can get the timing right,
you can pass it easily from behind.
It's a bold move, going back to volleyball basics, but it's a wonderful technique.
Keep it up!
Good work, Ayuhara!
Ayuhara!
As this fierce competition between two teams continues on…
…the Central Gymnasium here in New York…
…is filled with excitement and cheers from the audience.
13 to 13.
The World Junior Volleyball Championship
is nearing its final phase.
Japan or the Soviet Union.
Which one will receive the victor's laurels?
I can't even begin to guess.
Will it be the iron block and great force of the Soviet Union?
Or will it be Japan's two-stage reception, capable of defusing killer spikes?
Will the title of world's best go to Japan or to the Soviet Union?
One last push.
Fight, fight!
Fight.
Good luck.
Show the world the results of our practice.
Do your best until the very end!
Ayuhara! You can do it!
You can do it, Japan!
The final match between the Soviet Union
and Japan is coming to an end.
The Central Gymnasium is filled
with enthusiasm and heavy expectations.
Is it really the Soviet Union's power that will conquer the world?
Or is it Japan's technique and speed?
The passion of Kozue's team brings the game to its exciting climax.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.