苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 040—
Rally to glory
Japan wins the first set.
All-Japan team is now one step closer to the name of world's best.
We did it. Two-stage reception succeeded.
Yoshimura-san!
Her spike… got me.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
I'm sorry.
Don't be, Yoshimura. You did all you could.
Thank you, sir.
Believe in your friends and leave it to them.
Yes sir.
Coach…
Coach!
Thought I'd tell you something?
Sorry, I forgot what it was.
Captain, you too?
Coach…
Captain!
Huh?
Did the Japanese team go mad?
Far from it.
It was to let you do your best here.
There's nothing else to say.
I'm counting on you, girls.
– Yes sir.
Ayuhara, you're an excellent captain.
You quickly joined in with me, relieving everyone's tension.
We may win this game.
Or rather, I want to make then win.
We will win!
The Soviet Union vs. Japan's final game
has entered its final stage.
Will it be the Soviet team, or the All-Japan team that seizes the glory of the world's best?
Damn.
Very nice, Ayuhara!
Soviets reach the match point!
Yahoo!
Attack!
All-Japan attacks fiercely.
Can the debuting Japanese team win against the current champion, the Soviets' team?
Japan escapes its pinch.
Soviets cannot gain the last point.
Japan right to serve. And a serve!
Soviets receive!
How will it go? Toss!
Spike! And it's a hit.
Next serve.
Japan gets the ball.
Ayuhara jumps! Soviets block.
Japan seizes the ball!
What a fierce exchange.
It lasted half a minute already.
Borchinskaya tosses the ball.
Shellenina hits!
Japan sends it back!
Soviets counter it. Ball goes back to Japan.
They pick up Soviets' intense spike.
This exchange lasts fifty seconds already.
What an excellent example of women's volleyball!
The play is truly furious.
Are Soviets able to beat Japan?
Or will Japan hold out?
Ayuhara.
Shellenina's spike beautifully finds its way through!
Finally, it's Japan's defeat.
Rally to glory has ended with that single serve.
The Soviet Union's power won with
Japan's technique and speed.
The Soviet team continues its streak from the last year and emerges victorious again.
Arai-san.
Oh…
You did well, Japanese team.
Captain Shellenina of the Soviet team reaches out her hand to the Japanese team.
Ayuhara, thank you. It was a wonderful match.
Although defeated, each one of the middle school girls…
…fought with all they had.
Well done, Japan.
We must applaud them for their hard work.
The World Women's Junior Volleyball Championship that lasted the entire last week draws its curtain.
Painful expression of Japanese team's captain,
Kozue Ayuhara, struggling not to cry…
…can be clearly seen here in the lights
of the Central Gymnasium.
All the sweat that sprinkled this court.
All the force that hit it.
I won't forgive them.
I won't.
Not ever!
Oh?
Cassie.
Virginia.
Ayuhara!
Cassie!
You taught us something important.
That volleyball isn't just game played for fun.
And it's not just for money.
You taught me that.
Thank you, Ayuhara.
It never occurred to me until today how good it is that we have volleyball.
Thank you, Cassie.
Ayuhara?
Next time we meet…
…is at Olympics, right?
"Next time we meet is at Olympics"?
Olympics.
Yes.
We have next chance.
Hey.
We're going to Olympics next and aim for the Grand Prix.
They already forgot their victory and aim for the next prize.
Cassie too?
I won't lose to them!
Ah, it's Manumba from the Kenyan team.
Manumba?
I admire how you came here after all.
I remember vividly how you fought calling for your homeland Kenya.
The opponents we faced before, sometimes with burning hatred, are standing before us again.
But this time the players are just shaking hands.
That's right.
When the fight is over, everyone feels
the same way and shakes hands with each other.
This is the essence of true sportsmanship.
Ah?
He's late…
Hm?
I mean our coach. I wonder what's up?
After he said it's our last tea party here in America…
Indeed.
Ayuhara!
Ayuhara.
Ah?
By the way, I saw our coach talk to somebody in the lobby.
They seemed to be asking him for something. The coach had a very perplexed look on his face.
Is it true, Kakinouchi-san?
It's what I saw.
Why do you ask, Captain?
Ah, it's nothing.
Never mind.
Hey, what did they ask coach for?
I don't really know.
It'd be pretty disgraceful if I had eavesdropped on them, don't you think?
Y-You're right.
Ah.
Sorry I kept you waiting.
Hm?
What is it, girls? Come on, take a seat.
– Okay.
– Sure.
I have a news, girls.
I won't be able to return to Japan with you.
– Eh?
– Really?
What do you mean, Coach?
During the championships there have been held certain discussions.
I was asked to coach volleyball in a certain country.
I agreed just now.
I'm flying to that country tomorrow.
– Y-You're not serious…
– Eh.
W-Where are you headed?
It's a small country that has just started its adventure with volleyball.
B-But…
I thought we'll appear with the current squad
at the Olympic Games, and you'll couch us for it.
Oh, I'll return by then.
Then I'll ask you personally to let me coach you.
He's just like me, a madman who doesn't know a thing apart from volleyball.
Not a thing…
At any rate, I have to make sure that you always get capable competition.
Idiot!
And here I was thinking we could finally start living together in Japan.
Michiru.
Volleyball is all I can do.
I need to go wherever my only skill is needed.
You'll be fine now.
You have good friends.
Friends who can encourage each other.
You're ready to stay on your own, don't you think?
B-But…
You're an adult now.
Right? Tell me I'm not right.
You're mean, Bro.
Hmm?
Heh.
It must be nice to have an older brother.
I'm kind of jealous…
I planned to retire from volleyball, should we lose these championships.
But that fixation on glory was just my own vanity.
Your hard work is the reason why I ended up lending a hand to an unknown country again.
I owe it to the great fighting spirit
you have for volleyball.
You've reignited my passion.
Ayuhara.
Let's meet again someday, on another court.
Alright, there's spike.
Oh, wrong, you got it completely wrong.
Listen. Ayuhara's spike isn't anything like that.
She aims the ball at about this point.
Your receive isn't good either.
Ayuhara's revolving receive
is way more amazing than you even think.
Look at this.
Damn, it's nothing like Ayuhara's.
Virginia.
Good luck, Johnny.
Bye bye.
Tsk.
Okay, the game's on!
– Yeah!
Guess I can confess to you now.
Hm?
That last rally was really painful.
I thought to myself that it might not be possible for me to play volleyball again after that.
I was the same.
But when we finished, I didn't feel any sense of accomplishment.
"I won't lose next time."
"I want another chance, right now."
That's what I thought.
I see.
I thought the same after the match has ended.
When I used up my power.
That it's not over yet.
That if it isn't just a beginning of another chapter in my life.
That's what I thought to myself back then.
Exactly.
– Huh?
– Exactly what?
We should play volleyball forever together.
What, that's all?
I thought it'd be plenty obvious by now.
But I see that some people in here are pretty slow.
Next time we'll wipe the court with you at the Interhigh.
Make sure you show up.
And you make sure you don't trip over your own feet.
That's right. I'll come and find you if you don't show up at Interhigh.
And then, we'll come together once more…
…and play at the Olympic Games.
Olympics?
That's right.
Our next stop is at the Olympic Games.
Olympics.
Wow, Olympics!
Exactly. Everyone has to be there. We can't lose a single person.
It's not going to be easy.
There will be lots of formidable enemies.
But I want us to work our way through and win!
This rally was for this sake after all.
I know we can do it.
I'll do my best too.
I'm with you.
Let's make a promise.
I'm in.
Me too.
Let's do it.
Yeah.
Count me in.
Kozue and Midori return to Japan and begin studying for high school entry exams right away.
This includes…
Tsutomu.
Mitamura.
Team mate, Ozawa.
Naka.
Okei and her friends.
They pledge together to make it
to the Fujimi High School.
However, with graduation just around the corner,
Tsutomu stops going to school.
For some reason, Kozue starts to feel her anxiety build up.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.