苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 041—
Headhunters
Fujimi Academy
Welcome, everyone.
Although it was their first time participating…
…these two young ladies stood up against
the strong Soviet Union and won us a silver medal.
Ayuhara Kozue's and Hayakawa Midori's hard work…
…brings pride to not only the volleyball club,
but everyone here at our beloved Fujimi Academy.
Now, a few words from Ayuhara-kun.
It's been a week since I came back from America.
We've been treated warmly everywhere.
But to be honest, I'll tell you that I was most pleased about your applause here, today.
The most impressive thing
at this World Championship was…
…the warm friendship between people from different countries and sporting attitude of all the teams.
We lost to the Soviet Union's team in the final game.
But when the game ended, rather than regret…
…I thought to myself:
"Alright, let's do better next time!"
Hayakawa-san said this to me:
"If you lost a game even though you did your best…
…it doesn't mark the end, but rather
the beginning of your further development."
Under this motto, we want
to continue our efforts for the team.
What function do we get when we translate the graph of y=3x+2 by +3 along the x axis?
Do you know the answer, Yamada?
Nakanishi?
Is there anyone in this classroom who knows the answer?
How about you, Ayuhara?
Sir! U-Uhm…
Let me see…
Ayuhara, you too…?
What about you, Ozawa?
Sir.
The result is y=3x-7.
Exactly.
What use is volleyball if you can't even do simple math…?
Hahaha.
You sweat even though it's chilly.
It is truly a cold sweat.
Hahaha.
It's no laughing matter.
It's the first time I couldn't answer in a class.
I felt so ashamed.
It happens, it happens.
Same goes for my English.
I can't remember all these new words at all.
I guess it's only natural.
I mean, you did just return from the United States.
But then I wonder what you did in the United States
if you now make mistakes in English?
Haha.
You got that right.
Don't make fun of us.
We're trying to be serious, here.
Don't worry. If you study a bit,
you'll catch up in no time.
I can only hope it goes that easy.
Everyone seems to study for the exams
a lot harder than I expected.
Especially you, Ozawa-san. You were great today.
Nah, that was just a fluke.
Naka and Oyoshi are way more amazing.
Eh?
We can't lose to them.
Yeah.
Ayuhara, Hayakawa.
You should start studying for the exams soon.
We know. I was talking about that
with Midori just now.
The entrance exams for Fujimi High School are getting more difficult every year.
Take it seriously, okay?
– Yes sir.
Um, what is going on now in the volleyball club?
Hmm.
The newcomers will be participating in
a regional tournament on January 15th next year.
January 15th? That's only two months from now.
Yes, you're right.
To tell you the truth, I'm busy arranging future plans for each student.
I don't have much time to appear on the court.
I've asked Kashiwagi to take care of the club for now.
Oh…
Professor, I'll show up on the court as much as I can.
Me too.
But you have your studies.
We'll be fine.
I was planning to practice a little everyday anyway.
Besides, if I don't play even for a day,
my condition goes down and it affects my studies.
I see. Thank you.
That'll be really helpful.
But make sure you don't overdo it.
– Yes sir.
When we graduate, the Fujimi Academy's volleyball club will be in your hands.
Work hard for your first tournament!
– Yeah!
– Alright!
We have to study for the entrance exams,
so we might not have much time.
But we'll practice with you as much as possible.
We're looking forward to it.
– Thank you.
I think entrance exams are a pain in the butt,
so I don't plan to go to high school.
That's why…
Haha.
…I'll take care of you full-time until graduation.
With Captain and Midori,
the tournament should be a breeze.
I want you to work hard and aim for All-Japan.
Do you hear?
– Yes!
– Yes ma'am!
Then let's get started.
Assume positions!
– Okay!
– Yeah!
Here goes!
Attack!
Next!
Come on!
One more!
Today I have to start studying for entrance exams.
Okay. Now that it came down to it, let's do this!
I'm home.
Oh?
Huh…
Who could it be?
Oh, welcome back.
Who's here?
Kozue-chan, you have guests.
Huh? I do?
Kozue-san, we've been waiting for you.
I'm a manager of the volleyball club for Mt. Tateyama Manufacturing.
I'm from Black Pine Ironworks.
I represent Marunichi Textiles.
Kozue, these people came to recruit you for their company teams.
Recruit?
Please come to Marunichi Textiles volleyball club.
No, please come to Shimizu Yamato.
Joining our Tateyama Manufacturing would be a tremendous leap forward.
Besides, we're in the area.
We can satisfy whatever needs you have regarding the contract money.
So it's best for you to join Shimizu Yamato.
No, as far as the contract money goes, our company—
Our club offers not only good money, but you also get to train under the famous coach Ōshima.
We'll quite literally make you into Japan's best player.
Please join our Black Pine Ironworks.
If you play for our team, you will certainly participate in the next Olympic Games.
Papa.
Okay, okay.
Gentlemen, I'd like to ask you not to speak all at the same time.
I don't think I should interfere with my daughter's affairs as she's no longer a child.
I respect her will.
So, I'll let you meet with Kozue personally and discuss matter directly with her.
We really appreciate it.
However, it seems all of this was
a bit too surprising for my daughter.
You're perfectly right.
Let's present our offers to her one by one then.
Gentlemen, I know it's sudden, but could
I kindly ask you to just withdraw for today?
– Huh?
– Eh?
This is my request to you as Kozue's parent.
It's a selfish request, but please withdraw for today.
Such a pity…
I was really surprised.
I know you're the world's second, but to scout out such a small child…
A small child? I'll be a high school student soon.
– Hahaha.
– Oops.
You see, no matter how much a child grows up,
parents will always view them as little.
But who would've thought I'd get contacted by the famous Black Pine Ironworks or Shimizu Yamato…
They must think a lot of me.
They offered contract money and everything.
Hm?
– You urchin.
– Hehe.
But I think Kozue's success in the United States
does justify her confidence.
– You too, Honey?
– Hahaha.
It was just a joke.
Maybe I will let them recruit me?
Hm?
Kozue?
Tee-hee.
Kozue, where are you going?
To study.
Is Kozue still up?
Yes. I brought her tea a while ago.
She was bent over the desk and didn't reply.
I pity her for having to study as soon as she's back in Japan.
However…
I guess she has no choice.
Do you really think Kozue will be okay, Honey?
You're worried?
She seemed to joke about the recruitment, but I don't think that's all there was to it…
What if she really drops out of high school and enters some company's volleyball club?
I don't think we have anything worry about.
I wonder about that.
Otherwise, I wouldn't let these headhunters meet Kozue.
But it was always her dream to enter
Fujimi High School and play volleyball there.
I know.
Contracts will come after high school.
You don't have anything to worry about, Dear.
I guess you're right.
But it still seems like Kozue's getting further from us each step of the way.
Here I go!
Make sure to hit hard.
– Nakazuka.
– Present.
– Akiyama.
– Here.
– Ayuhara.
– Present.
Ichinose.
Ichinose?
He's not here.
Ichinose has been absent for three days already.
He must have caught a cold.
But what if it's something worse?
For some reason I have a bad feeling about this…
Flower Shop
I hope it's just a normal cold.
There's no way Tsutomu-kun could be seriously ill.
Just a cold, serious sickness…
Just a cold, serious sickness.
Serious sickness.
Here are your apples.
I really recommend them.
Thank you for shopping with us.
Are these oranges sweet?
Sweet doesn't cut it.
They're literally little drops of heaven.
– Then two kilograms, please.
– Sure thing.
Good day.
Welcome, welcom—
Oh, Kozue-kun.
Don't you  "oh, Kozue-kun"  me here.
Here I was thinking you were ill.
I wasted my time worrying about you.
What are you doing here?
Actually my pops got real sick and can't tend to the shop.
Whoa, what about your dad?
That's why I have to leave school
for a bit and keep the business running.
I see. That must be tough.
Yeah. It's the busiest time
of the year for greengrocers.
But don't tell your parents about my pops' illness.
By the way, Kozue-kun, I'd like to ask for a favor.
What is it?
If possible, I'd like yo—
Could you hurry up?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'll drop by your house after I close the store.
Let's see… two kilos of oranges, was it?
It's 200 yen. Sorry for making you wait.
What did you want to ask me for?
I'd like to see your notes while I'm absent from school.
What do you think?
Oh, that's such a simple request.
You really are great, Tsutomu-kun.
I don't know what you think is so great.
I just do what I need to.
Plus, Pops should get better by next year.
Anyway, Kozue-kun, you've got things pretty tough yourself, don't you?
Tough how?
Well, you need to balance the volleyball practices
and studying for the entrance exams.
Hmm.
To be honest, sometimes it is just as tough as you said.
But I don't want to abandon the rookies until their tournament no matter what.
You see, I feel I owe at least that much
to the club that has raised me.
I'd feel bad if I was the only one who got good.
I want to be a responsible person.
Well, I guess it is like a tradition to pass your knowledge onto the younger generation.
Speaking of tradition, Fujimi High School
is a pretty prestigious school.
Kozue-kun. How about you and I aim for the stars and enter the Fujimi High School together?
Of course.
I'll work hard so that I can enter Fujimi High School and continue studying and playing volleyball.
We'll crush any obstacles with our will power.
Crush any obstacles.
Alright! Let's do our best!
Even though Tsutomu-kun can no longer go to school,
he still has a burning passion to pass the exams.
Looking at him, I don't think it's impossible to balance volleyball and studies.
I won't lose to Tsutomu-kun.
You can't do that, that's a foul play.
Oh, no. I fell asleep before I knew it.
Everyone's working hard now…
But Tsutomu-kun didn't come to see my notes today. I wonder what's wrong?
Maybe his father's condition got worse?
Or maybe he doesn't need notes anymore?
Tsutomu-kun is super-smart, after all.
Ah, I'll go wash my face.
Fight, fight!
Kozue, you're still up?
I can't?
Of course you can, but…
It's midnight already.
What if your heart gets worse again?
I keep playing volleyball, so it's all right.
Anyway, I'm going to wash my face and have another round at studying!
But, Kozue!
Let her be, Dear.
But Honey, she's—
You saw her eyes, didn't you?
Huh?
They were sparkling.
Those are the eyes of someone who is set on achieving their goal.
You're feeling lonely because Kozue gets further and further away from us.
But in reality, Kozue is just growing up into a woman.
We should be happy for her, don't you think?
Kozue's no longer a child.
Let's warmly watch over her
and let her live her life.
Alright?
Okay.
Alright, here goes "falling leaf"!
They have strong grasp of the basics.
But I wonder how they'd be in a real match.
I wish we could hold a practice match
with some strong team.
Their tournament is in 3 days…
Normally, we'd hold practice matches about now.
I know, right?
Everyone is so keen on it.
But we can't prepare them properly
due to our circumstances.
I really feel responsible for them.
That said, we can't really ask Oyoshi and the girls for help, when they're so focused on studying.
That's right.
Anyway, let's consult it
with Professor Hongou tomorrow.
Yeah, good call.
A practice match, huh…?
Hmm.
It is certainly necessary.
But I think most of the schools will refuse. They're busy with their own tournament preparations.
Actually, if we had at least Nakazawa-san and Katori-san…
…it'd be a great help already.
But they're studying hard right now…
It's fine. I understand.
We'll give up on the practice match.
Alright.
By the way, Ayuhara, Hayakawa.
You've worked hard until now.
Thank you.
I'm thanking you on behalf of everyone.
– I-It's nothing. Right?
– Yup.
I can't show up on the court so your presence is a huge help for the juniors.
Please don't worry from now on
and focus on your studies.
But the tournament is still in 3 days.
We could still teach them a few tricks that might prove useful in a real game.
I'm really thankful for your offer.
But as your teacher, I can't keep let you
keep overburdening yourselves.
That's my order as your coach.
Then please let us play with them at least for today.
Please. I still want to teach them
at least the gist of playing in a match.
Okay, but really, it's just for today.
– Thank you.
– Yes sir.
Hey, Kozue.
Hasn't Tsutomu-san's father gotten better by now?
I guess not, seeing as how he still doesn't come to school.
This is Tsutomu-san we're talking about.
He'll do fine at exams even without going to school.
I guess I'll go visit him tomorrow and see how are things.
Let me go with you.
But maybe I shouldn't.
I don't want to be a nuisance.
Huh?
You crazy, Midori?
Midori!
Take this!
Oopsie.
You're all flushed!
Grr!
I can't believe you, Midori!
Wait!
Catch me, catch me!
You're late.
Ahem.
Naka, Oyoshi! What are you all doing here?
It's just as you see.
Sometimes I think that our captain is a bit overwhelmed.
If we keep studying all the time, our bodies will get all stiff.
– Captain, we're under your care.
– Hehehe.
We can hold a practice match!
Yeah. I'm so glad.
Well, let's go!
– Alright!
Look, that kind of spike should be accepted a little bit lower. Like this.
I understand.
Here goes a curve ball serve!
Ready!
Receive, receive!
Good, good!
Oh?
They're all keen on continuing with volleyball.
They all want to go to high school
and to play volleyball.
They're working for this sake.
Naka.
Oyoshi.
Ozawa-san.
Kakko.
Midori.
Let's all work hard to achieve our dream!
Attack!
Closed today
Why didn't you come to school even though the shop's closed?
I wanted to tell you about it later.
Did your father's illness get worse?
Yes. I'm thinking of quitting school.
Huh!?
What… what did you say?!
Due to my father's illness and poor business…
…Tsutomu abandons entering high school.
Full of pity for Tsutomu's circumstances
Kozue responds to the headhunters.
She agrees to enter the club of a company that offers the most contract money.
Her parents are at loss of words.
They try to persuade Kozue to change her mind.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.