苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 042—
Crossroads
Ichinose fruits and vegetables
I'm quitting school.
Huh?
Quitting…?
What on earth?
Why are you quitting?
Why are you giving up on high school?
Is your dad's condition that bad?
Yeah.
He feels a lot better.
But I think being a shop keeper could be pretty nice.
Pretty nice?
Our business is no match for the supermarket
that recently opened nearby.
So we're still in quite a pinch.
I'm guessing that's probably the real reason my dad is ill.
So that's why?
If I don't quit school and help keep the business
going, things will only get worse for us.
But it's such a risk, Tsutomu-kun.
And a waste of your talent.
I think the society and your future would greatly benefit if you entered high school, unlike me.
You know, right now my future isn't as important to me as my family.
Here you go.
Thank you for coming all this way.
Don't mention it.
I'll walk you back.
It's okay.
You're so busy, I can go by myself.
Alright then, see you.
Oops, I almost forgot.
Don't tell my dad anything about what I said today.
See you.
Bye.
Tsutomu-kun looks so sad.
Poor Tsutomu-kun.
The more he laughs,
the more lonely he probably is.
Ayuhara family
Tsutomu-kun wanted to go to Tōkyō Business High School…
Welcome.
What would you like, madam?
Please give me some cabbage.
Sure thing.
Tsutomu, come here for a bit.
We've got a customer now, though.
No matter how I count, it simply doesn't sum up.
Can you please take a look at it?
You're impossible.
Please take care of this then.
Hehe.
Tsutomu was good at arithmetic since he was a little kid.
Even us plain parents can be sometimes blessed with brilliant children.
Your son is aiming for
Tōkyō Business High School, right?
Yes. Thanks. Recently he seems to be skipping classes, though.
A child never really knows how dear they are to their parents.
Here you go. That'll be 90 yen.
Ah, wasn't it 100 yen?
Oh, I'm sorry. Thank you.
Things are a bit hectic here.
Thanks again.
– I'd like some nuts.
– Of course.
But it's such a risk, Tsutomu-kun.
Kozue-chan.
Kozue!
I-I'm here!
I'm studying properly.
You have guests.
They're the same talent scouts.
I'm not sure what to say to them…
should we wait until your father gets back?
I'm not interested in their offer.
Tell them not to bother us.
Where are your manners?
But, if that's what you want…
Now that I told them off, let's get back to studying.
Tsutomu-kun said his future isn't as important to him as his family.
I suspect poor business might be
the real reason my dad is ill.
If only his family's debts were paid,
Tsutomu-kun could go to high school…
That's it!
Huh?
Hey, Mama, where did the scouts go?
Hm?
What are you talking about now?
They already went away.
I was late…
Maybe I can still catch them!
Kozue! Kozue?
Why are you in such a hurry, Kozue?
I'll talk to you about it later.
Ah.
Wait!
Kozue!
Scouts, please hold on!
Wait a bit!
Ah, I can't breathe.
Ah… how much contract money do you offer?
– Eh?
As soon as I sign a contract, I get money.
Did I understand it right?
So you decided not to enter a high school after all?
Let's find a coffee shop
and discuss the details there.
No, no, no. Let's go to my favorite restaurant.
Hold on. I ran from home without saying anything to my parents.
Let's make it short and discuss it here.
– Awesome!
– Hey, come here!
As if.
But it'll be great.
Knock it off.
Come on…
How about here?
You want to discuss it here?
It'll be the same anywhere.
More importantly, gentlemen, your companies' names were…
Tateyama Manufacturing.
Black Pine Ironworks.
Please come over to Marunichi Textiles.
I'm so happy.
Each one is a top company.
Thank you for your kind words.
So, how much?
You should be able to muster up
a lot of contract money.
Huh?
In any case I'd like to enter the richest company.
You leave us in a tough spot…
So, how much?
Please don't hold back.
Make it as high as possible.
Hmm.
Hey, check them out.
That girl is amazing.
Please.
Thank you.
Here.
Fufu.
I've decided. I'll join Marunichi Textiles.
Really? Thank you very much!
Huh…
What a snotty brat.
I couldn't handle her anymore. How absurd.
So cool!
Hahaha.
– Let's play!
– Yeah!
Ah, hello. Hello?
It's a success. It's a success!
I got Ayuhara Kozue to enter our Marunichi Textiles.
Please send the car right away.
Ayuhara family
Please wait a bit.
My husband will return soon. We'll have to discuss it with him.
Oh, madam, that won't be necessary.
Your husband said himself the other day that he respects his daughter's will, did he not?
I'm sure he'll agree to it.
That was—
Oh, miss?
Are you ready yet?
I'm sorry, Papa, Mama.
Miss!?
Coming!
I hope you sign the contract before you change your mind.
Please come in.
Make yourself comfortable.
Kozue, what should I tell Papa?
I'll apologize to him once I get back.
I'm sure he'll understand.
But…
Kozue!
That girl…
Oh?
Tsu… Tsutomu-kun.
Huh? Kozue-kun!?
What are you doing here?
That car… had Marunichi Textiles' flags.
They're famous for their volleyball club.
Something's up.
What did you say?
Marunichi Textiles?
Are you sure?
Yes.
She decided it in a flash.
I couldn't believe it.
Kozue's going to Marunichi Textiles right now.
That's nonsense.
She just went to the company that offered the most money?
I can't accept this at all.
What in the world is she thinking?
Marunichi Textiles
Marunichi Textiles.
This is where a new chapter in my life begins.
Ah!
Stop, stop the car!
Huh? Then Kozue-kun is—
Yes. She's with one of the scouts and is going to Marunichi Textiles headquarters right now.
I don't know what's going on in her head anymore.
Marunichi Textiles, huh…?
Why? Why are you giving up on high school?
We're facing quite a pinch.
All right then, see you.
Bye.
I didn't have to look back to know.
There is no doubt she murmured it while looking at my back.
Poor Tsutomu-kun.
Kozue-kun is doing this for my sake.
If that's not it, what else could it be?!
That must be it!
Excuse me, ma'am!
Tsutomu-san!?
Kozue-kun, you idiot!
Why would you do such thing?
Why? You're better than that.
Just wait.
I will never let you make that kind of sacrifice for me.
If she signs the contract, it's all over.
I have to make it there in time no matter what.
Let's go.
– Yeah!
They're great. Really impressive.
That should be enough, right?
Mr. President is waiting for us.
Damn. The bike's acting up again.
Dammit!
Why does it have to break when I'm almost there?
How was it?
Do you like our volleyball club?
Yes. They're great.
Contracted players are truly something else.
No, no. I'm sure you'll become our company's ace in no time, Ayuhara-san.
Mr. President will surely be delighted.
President's office
Step inside.
After you, Ayuhara-san.
Oh?
Mr. President, I brought Ayuhara-san.
Good day, Mr. President.
No need to be so stiff. Please, sit down.
Okay.
I know a lot about you.
To cut things short, I'd be thrilled to see you
use your great talent for my company.
Thank you, Mr. President.
Your only job will be volleyball.
We'll arrange it so that you have enough freedom.
Oh, please don't. I don't want that.
Huh?
I don't want to be treated specially just because I play volleyball.
Even at school, I still managed to take all my exams.
I love training, but I still need to study.
I guess you have a point there…
Of course, I want to be paid for my work.
But I'd rather have a regular job like everyone else.
Very well.
Your amateur sportsman attitude is charming.
Thank you.
You made a really good catch,
finding such a strong-willed young lady.
Thank you very much, Mr. President.
Did I say something conceited?
No, no, quite the contrary.
I see. That's a relief.
Mr. President, you're really friendly.
Thanks, haha.
I wouldn't have guessed from your face— Oh.
Huh?
Hahaha.
At any rate, Ayuhara-kun,
you're still underage, aren't you?
Yes. That's correct…
Then we'll need the consent of your parents before signing the contract.
Hm?
Ah, don't worry.
I'll talk to your parents personally. I'm sure I'll get them to agree.
I hope so.
Taxi
Kozue?
Well then, leave the discussion with your father to me.
Kozue!
Ah?
Good day. I presume you're Ayuhara-kun's father?
T-That's correct.
You came at the right moment.
I wanted to talk to you regarding your daughter's contract.
Please, come with me to my office.
Don't worry. It'll be fine.
I'm sure Mr. President will successfully persuade your dad.
Oh, where are you going?
To see the volleyball club's practice.
First of all, I'm glad that you're here…
Mr. President, what was it
you wanted to talk to me about?
Please, let's not rush the subject.
First of all, I wanted to tell you
that I'm a big fan of volleyball and Ayuhara-san.
For some reason I hope Papa denies Mr. President his consent.
Then maybe I could go to high school.
Did I make wrong choice?
Is that it, Ayuhara Kozue?
Sorry!
Please throw us the ball.
Huh?
Throw us the ball!
No. I didn't go wrong.
Wow, wonderful serve.
It curved mid-air and fell perpendicularly.
I had a hunch that I knew her face from somewhere.
Oh, Captain, you know her?
Ayuhara Kozue.
She's the junior Japan's volleyball representative.
So she's the captain of
Fujimi Middle School's volleyball club?
Whoa.
So that serve must have been the "falling leaf".
I thought she was going to high school, though?
Maybe she's here to join our club?
Let's try calling her.
Ayuhara-san!
Yes?
You're Ayuhara Kozue from Fujimi Middle School, right?
I am. Nice to meet you.
I knew it!
You're joining our club, aren't you?
I am.
Your daughter has made her decision very carefully. It's not on a whim.
She'd like to test her skills at our prestigious Marunichi Textiles' volleyball club.
And she wants to work, too.
Her resolve is incredible.
What do you think of it as her father?
Hmm…
But what's her motivation for all of this?
That matter is quite clear to me.
Your daughter just wants to play volleyball to her heart's content, don't you think?
I see…
Amazing!
So cool!
Kozue-kun!
Tsutomu-kun, what are you doing here?
Who is he?
He must be her boyfriend.
That's my line. What did you come here for?
What are you doing at this company?
What am I doing, you ask…
I'm going to get a job here once I graduate from middle school.
Idiot!
Ah!
What a scumbag!
Who'd hit a girl? Let's stop him!
Stop.
We're in the middle of practice.
Think only about volleyball during practice.
People are watching,
so let's talk somewhere in private.
What are you doing?
Slapping and pulling me out of the blue?
Tsutomu-kun, you're way out of your bounds!
If I don't do this, you won't open your eyes.
What I do is none of your business.
I live my life how I want to, so don't you get in my way.
You're such a liar!
You told me you wanted to go to high school and play volleyball there.
Where did that passion go?
I changed my mind.
Changed your mind?
I know exactly what made you do it.
You're going to use your contract money to let me go to high school. Am I right?!
Huh?
Are you really trying to push your self-important compassion down my throat, Kozue-kun?
That's a terrible thing to say!
"Push down your throat"?!
I'm sorry, Kozue-kun.
I just don't want that kind of sympathy.
Now that's problematic…
I'll make myself clear.
I don't want that money.
Hmm.
How am I supposed to go to high school when I know that you sacrificed yourself for it?
Sacrificed?
Don't be absurd.
If I work here, I can play volleyball all I want.
Then what about the school?
I don't care about it anymore.
What?!
Cut it out already!
Ah!
They've been gone a long time…
He's quite the delinquent, don't you think?
Hey.
How long are you going to think about her?
Sorry.
But it's only natural to think about her.
We'll become even stronger with her around.
No, we won't.
Huh?
What makes you say that?
She has as much talent as you, no more and no less.
When she entered our court,
her thoughts were somewhere else.
Her technique was good but her soul was missing.
Kozue-kun.
You were wrong.
You won't earn points with people
with this kind of such selfish, pushy behavior.
But I couldn't just stand there doing nothing.
You always took the school seriously, Tsutomu-kun.
Come on, don't pity me.
Do you really think feeling sorry for me will have made me happy?
Shocking, isn't it?
I don't need anyone's help.
Not a single yen.
I'm sorry.
I knew you'd shout at me, Tsutomu-kun.
And yet, I still wanted to do something for you.
Even if it you didn't want anything.
I understand.
I understand it very well.
Thank you, Kozue-kun.
Hmm.
Okay then, let's proceed with the contract.
Wait a moment.
I gave up on getting her to come to my team.
Eh?
I am truly sorry for it, but it can't be helped.
She's truly a great girl.
I decided to withdraw the contract
and ask again three years from now on.
Eh…
That's how things are, Ayuhara-kun.
So please proceed as you initially planned
and play in a high school club.
It's regrettable. I hope we meet again some day.
I'm sorry, Mr. President.
Oh, no, you really don't need to apologize to me.
But be careful. If you're still free three years from now,
I will personally go scouting to your house.
Ah… If I actually do that,
that boy might lose his means of livelihood…
– Hahaha.
– Mr. President…
Mr. President knows everything.
Oh, it's Ayuhara-san.
She's with the boy from before.
They've patched things up?
To you, who for a single day were my team mates…
Goodbye!
"Falling leaf" again.
A one-trick pony!
Ah!?
Her soul… is right here.
Let's go home.
That was "falling leaf", huh…?
What a pity.
What a real pity…
Well then, I'm in a hurry.
I see.
Sorry for making you worry.
No worries. Well, see you.
Tsutomu-kun and you seem to be walking different paths now.
But, each person has their own way.
Today, you learned something important.
Would you like to come back by taxi?
I want to walk with you for a bit longer, Papa.
Can we?
Hm? Heh.
Of course.
Kozue enters Fujimi High School as planned.
She immediately joins the volleyball club.
There, she meets Miyuki Oonuma, who is treated like a queen.
A group of third-year zealots…
…make the newcomers work hard and even harasses popular Kozue to drive her out.
However, Kozue boldly faces Miyuki's challenge.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.