苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 043—
The queen's challenge
World Championships at New York
Junior Women's Volleyball Japanese team wins second place
We couldn't defeat only the Soviet Union.
Memories of middle school life
Middle school life, huh?
Well, I'm not going to look back on the past.
My new life begins today.
Life in high school.
It'll be different in so many ways.
Tsutomu-kun.
Yo.
Good morning.
What's wrong?
You don't look very happy.
Nope.
I feel full of energy today.
I have something for you. Catch.
Thanks.
See you!
That was nice of him.
Ah, spring's here.
– Shh!
– She's here!
I am Shimizu Haruko and
I am in charge of group C for this year.
My subject is Japanese. Nice to meet you.
– Whoa!
– A true lady!
A perfect wife!
Silence.
All right, let's start with attendance check.
Aida Michio-kun.
Present.
Just as I thought, a lot of people came from other schools.
Ayuhara Kozue-san.
Ah? P-Present!
– That's quite a debut.
– Are you okay?
Ayuhara-san, you…
Ma'am?
You were junior volleyball team's captain, weren't you?
Yes, that's correct.
Your match with the Soviet Union was fantastic.
Thank you very much.
But ultimately, we weren't strong enough.
So, from today on…
From today on?
What is she gonna do?
I am planning to enter
the volleyball club and start over again.
I-I see.
I wish you best of luck.
Kozue-san, the best in Japan!
C-Continuing.
Ishida Naomi-san.
I'm here.
Professor Shimizu…
Why did she get so uneasy all of the sudden?
Table tennis club members wanted
Please join our drama club!
Try our baseball club.
Maybe I should enter baseball club?
So that's the first day at high school.
Everyone's looking for new club members.
Why don't we check them out?
The volleyball team will beg for us.
As if, Miss Hubris.
Tee-hee!
First of all… I don't see volleyball club posters anywhere.
Huh?
Become a karate master!
Have fun in our badminton club!
There are so many sports clubs…
Badminton!
Make your high school life meaningful in the basketball club.
Katsuragi-san.
Our basketball team is looking for promising newcomers.
Katsuragi-san!
Ah, Ayuhara-san!
Katsuragi-san, what are you doing at the basketball club?
You made it here, Ayuhara-san!
What happened to volleyball, Senpai?
Did you quit?
Hmm. Things changed about six months ago.
Changed how?
The volleyball club is dominated by the captain,
Oonuma Miyuki, and her followers.
In order to keep their captain popular…
…her followers are trying to get any popular or skillful newcomers to quit.
They really do that?
And the club's advisor just turns a blind eye to it?
Professor Shimizu just has no control over her.
Professor Shimizu?
That woman teacher?
Yes.
I think a woman teacher is no good for a girls' team.
She's too lenient.
You should really consider entering the basketball club.
It'll be easy to adapt for someone who come from a volleyball club.
I'm sorry, but I can't see myself doing anything but volleyball.
What about you?
I feel the same way.
I guess that's to be expected.
Well, I'll go check out the volleyball club now.
I'll go with her. See you later.
Uhm, what should we do, Senpai?
I guess you could stick around for a bit and see things for yourself.
Isn't that the volleyball club's room?
– …right?
– Hahaha.
Uhm…
Uhm, we'd like to enter your club…
Captain's not here.
We'll talk to you in her stead. What do you want?
What are your names and classes?
I'm a first year, Ayuhara Kozue from group C.
I'm Hayakawa Midori from group A.
Hm? And your experience with volleyball?
We both were Japanese representatives at Junior Volleyball World Championship.
We asked you about your experience with volleyball!
Midori.
But you can see…!
We've played volleyball for three years at middle school.
I see.
That's neat.
But you see…
High school is different from children's games.
Children's games?
Yeah, and it's definitely not the place to brag about your children's games either.
W-What…?
We just want to play volleyball.
Really, now?
I think you want to be treated as a star,
like you used to be during middle school, right?
That's not true!
Kozue.
Let's talk directly with the captain
or Professor Shimizu.
Hold on.
We never said that we wouldn't let you join us.
Then what's with that talk?
There are conditions, though.
You could say it's our club's tradition.
Tradition?
What kind?
Rule #1.
Captain's orders are absolute.
Rule #2.
Same goes to the seniors.
And the final rule…
You need to be polite at all times when you face your seniors. Got it?
Yes.
Then clean the court right away.
Yes ma'am!
Midori.
What do you think?
I guess these two are a bit different from the other freshmen.
This is bad.
If we let them loose, they'll outshine us.
Actually, it'll be easy. We just need to make it
so that they quit of their own accord.
That way, they can't hold us responsible for anything.
How long do you think they'll stay with us?
I don't think it'll be too long before they leave.
Then we'll get bullied all over again…
Ah, finally we're done.
Just look at those second-years.
It wouldn't kill them to help us.
Why are you standing there doing nothing?
Eh?
You think you're done? The floor still needs to be polished to a shine with a dry rag.
Get started already!
Polished to a shine?
It's our tradition decided by Captain Oonuma.
Now get moving!
Y-Yes ma'am.
On it.
Get started with your gymnastics!
– Yes ma'am!
I won't give up.
Dammit.
Ah, we made it.
This is too much. I feel like Cinderella.
Shh!
Midori, the seniors are here.
Patch these up.
T-These…?
Captain Oonuma teaches us to respect the equipment.
Catch.
There's no way we can use that ball anymore.
Oopsie, I'm sorry for bumping into you.
Are you hurt?
Oh, you look fine to me.
Glad you're not hurt or something.
Alright then.
No. Not yet.
But—
If we snap now, we'll play right into their hand.
They're just waiting for us to quit.
That's what this is all about.
We can't play along.
Please, be patient for now.
You've still got three more laps to go!
Our orders are absolute.
It's our club's tradition.
Come on, come on. Jump higher.
We'll do it every day from now on.
We'll drill a solid foundation into your bodies!
Jump higher.
I said higher!
Good.
What's wrong?
Be grateful to your seniors for helping you out.
What's wrong, what's wrong?
Hey!
How long are you going to just lay there?!
Time to stand up, Miss Captain.
Next is a hundred push-ups!
What's with that look? I said a hundred push-ups.
I refuse.
Are you for real?
We're good with normal exercises.
But I… we refuse to participate in this nonsense!
I won't let you calling our training "nonsense" slide.
You've insulted not only us, but Captain Oonuma.
You won't get away with it!
That's my line, you bully!
Whoa, we got a badass over here!
Hold it.
Captain.
Captain…?
Captain Oonuma.
I'm Oonuma.
This is the way I run things around here.
Do not reject one who comes.
Do not chase one who leaves.
However, I will not forgive insulting our club or our members.
But—
I'm not finished.
Whatever your middle school achievements are, that's all history.
So don't bother bragging, it's out of place.
That said, let's see what you're made of.
Swap!
Captain!
Shut your mouth!
Do it properly!
Captain…
They have a lot of potential.
But can they endure it to the end?
Captain's become serious.
I won't give up!
Midori!
Kozue!?
Kozue.
Practice is over.
Clean this up later.
Kozue.
So that's how far middle school world championships runner-ups can go.
Well, I can't say I expected anything more.
Hahaha.
Kozue.
Everything's fine?
Y-Yeah.
Kozue.
I'm sorry.
I'm not giving up.
They think that's all it takes to break me?
That's the spirit.
We'll play volleyball here.
No matter what.
Captain sure knows how to give people a lesson.
– They'll just run away.
– That'll teach them.
Hahaha.
Don't get me wrong.
– Eh?
– Huh?
I just put those girls' skill to the test.
W-We know that, naturally.
Alright.
I'll go ahead, Captain.
Ah!
Professor Shimizu.
Oonuma-san.
You have a guest.
A guest…?
Yes. She's a captain at
Misawa Academy's volleyball club.
I am Mihara Yumiko.
Nice to meet you.
I am Captain Oonuma Miyuki.
Likewise.
She wants to hold a practice match with you.
Our volleyball club was just formed,
so we have no formal match experience.
I guess you can say we can't estimate our ability too well. So, if possible…
Very well.
Let's do it.
How does Saturday after school sound to you?
Isn't that a bit too soon?
It sounds great.
Then meet us at our court.
Thank you very much.
Hey, Midori. I guess there's nothing left but to get this club to change somehow.
Agreed.
The biggest problem is
the captain and her followers.
Yeah…
Even if it's just a friendly game,
it's a bit too early, don't you think?
It's just some new club at Misawa Academy.
We don't need to prepare.
Plus it's them who wanted that match.
By the way, did Ayuhara Kozue-san join the club?
Why?
I need the list of members by tomorrow.
I understand.
Captain.
Professor Shimizu's attitude has changed.
Even though she was so indifferent before.
She's motivated since we now have such a talent on the team.
We won't get so much freedom anymore.
It'll be okay.
We have nothing to worry about.
Takeichi-san.
If Captain finds out…
Takeichi-san!
Se-Senpai!?
Relax. It's our court, too, after all.
Alright!
Huh, a respectable senior for once.
Oh?
Her too?
Let's clean up quickly so we can practice.
That's what I'm talking about. I have to work hard!
Looks like we've brought some changes.
Yeah.
That's how it should be.
Let's not disappoint them.
Yeah.
Oh?
I'll help you out.
Naka!
In the end, I couldn't leave you, Chief.
How could I quit volleyball?
But this is all we do in this club.
When I asked the third-years to let me enter,
they practically dropped their jaws.
Hahaha.
Yeah. "Why would they want to play with us?!"
But we can't let our guard down.
The captain's followers are gonna be here soon.
So, what do you think about it?
They invited even more of their friends, which means…
The future of our team doesn't look too bright.
It was the same story with second-years.
We need to get them under our control.
I understand.
That's what leadership is about.
Okay, pull!
Got it!
Is that high enough?
It's okay.
Captain…?
What is this?!
Ayuhara-san.
You're a newcomer.
Why are you making your seniors help you?
Don't be so full of yourself!
This is the only language…
…you'll understand!
So that's how you run your club, Captain?
Submission is necessary to make the team work.
We're not your slaves.
Did you just call us slave traders?
Cap— We… volunteered our help by ourselves.
What?!
And just what, exactly, do you think of our team's integrity?
That so-called integrity is built through violence and harassment.
True unity lies in teamwork.
Are you questioning my authority?
If that's how you choose to see it.
Very well.
Let's put you in the practice match
with Misawa Academy.
We will use all three of you.
Fine.
If you don't show your worth during that match… if you don't…!
I understand.
It's here!
Midori!
Offense! Get a grip!
W-What?!
Calm down, Suga.
– Midori!
– Kozue!
Kanda.
But…
– Nice!
– It's just luck.
Misawa · Fujimi
I got this!
They're great!
She'll hear you, Takeichi-san!
Captain Oonuma is in trouble.
We have to do something.
We have to do something…
Ayuhara
I know.
Misawa · Fujimi
We got the first set.
Now for the second.
Let's keep it up.
I swear I won't pass a single ball to our third-years.
I'm sorry for them a bit.
Captain, are you okay?
We won't let them touch the ball.
That way Misawa's reception will be enough to destroy them.
I-I see.
It's itchy…
What's wrong?
Kozue.
You seem off.
Nah, it's nothing. I only got some sweat in my eye.
It's the second set.
Naka, Midori, I'm counting on you.
Leave it to us.
Good luck, Kozue.
Something's wrong.
My eyes hurt.
Kozue!?
What's wrong?!
I-I-It hurts…!
It hurts!
Everything's pitch black!
Hey, what's wrong?
Kozue!
Make it stop…!
In the middle of a practice game with Misawa Academy…
…Kozue's suddenly experiences an excruciating pain in her eyes and falls on the court.
Consequently, Fujimi High School loses the game.
Kozue and her friends' future in the club becomes unclear.
Filled with grief, Midori investigates the cause of Kozue's collapse.
Something unexpected gets revealed in the process.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.