苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 044—
Spike machine
I-I-It hurts.
I… I can't see!
Kozue! What's wrong?
You're down already?
Get a grip!
You're completely useless!
Like I told before, we're not playing children's games in here!
If we lose this game, it'll be all your fault.
Kozue, are you okay?
Yeah… Yeah.
Come on, come on!
Kozue!
It's no use.
It's no use!
I can't see anything.
Midori, help me!
Mama!
Where…
Where's the ball…?
Ayuhara-san, hang in there.
Kozue?
Chief.
I just gave her a sedative. Don't worry.
Now, let's examine her eyes.
What's so funny?
That's right! It's despicable to laugh at human suffering.
Today, thanks to you…
…we lost.
Now, take responsibility like you promised to.
We're waiting for your resignation.
I'm guessing you finally understand the difference between middle and high school volleyball?
They're all so cruel!
Naka. I know it's frustrating, but a promise is still a promise.
Time to bid farewell to volleyball.
Ah, Professor.
How is Kozue?
How are her eyes?
Relax.
She was treated quickly so it'll heal well.
But…
But?
The doctor said that he found lime in her eyes.
Lime?
But why, how?
Hayakawa-san,
Nakazawa-san.
Please take care of Ayuhara-san for me.
I have something I want to investigate.
Kozue?
Let her be. She just managed to fall asleep.
Doctor, is it true that there was lime in her eyes?
There was.
But it's already been thoroughly cleansed out.
There's no need to worry.
I'm so glad.
It looks like she'll be fine.
Oh, by the way, I just remembered the track and field club was exercising on the schoolyard then.
I bet the lime could've been blown by the wind.
Huh?
If that was the case, we would've all been affected, not just Kozue.
Ah!
What is it, Midori?
Perhaps it was back then…
Oh? Weird.
What's wrong, Kozue?
Ah, it's nothing.
Maybe I got some sweat into my eye?
Kozue lost her vision and collapsed right after.
I'm sure someone put lime on that towel.
N-No way.
Even they have their boundaries.
No.
Listen. I'm sure this is it.
They're jealous of our skill and popularity.
And that's why they're trying to get rid of us by all means.
I can't take it anymore.
What's with the racket?
Would it kill you to enter in a more civilized way?
Captain.
Kozue was blinded with lime!
Huh?
How far are you willing to go to drive us out?
You were the ones who put lime on Kozue's towel!
Hayakawa-san.
Do you understand what you're saying?
I have no idea about any lime.
Don't throw ridiculous accusations at us.
Don't screw with me!
Do you think I'm going to keep my mouth shut
after what you've done to my friend?!
Oh, this just got interesting.
But we won't forgive you talking smack about us either.
Do you even have any proof that we did it?
Right.
How about you show us evidence right here, right now?
Fine.
I'll show it now.
The towel's gone!
Where's your evidence?
Maybe there wasn't one from the beginning.
Yeah.
You talk so big, but you've got nothing to back it up.
– Yeah.
– What's with her?
Volleyball club's room
I'm sorry, Hayakawa-san.
Kozue. Can you recognize my face?
You can see it, right?
Mama. What happened?
It's over. Everything's okay now.
Naka. Midori, you too?
Kozue.
You lost your sight and collapsed in the middle of the game.
Ah, now I remember.
Midori, what about the game?
How did it end?
It was a complete defeat for Fujimi High School.
Huh?
Then we're gonna have to…
Yeah.
We've already dropped out of the club.
Huh?!
If you don't show your worth during that match… if you don't…!
I understand.
Kozue.
I have no proof, but bear with me.
When the first set was over,
you wiped your face with a towel, didn't you?
Do you remember?
Someone put lime on that towel.
Huh!?
Who could have done that!?
I hope they don't think
I'll just let them get away with this!
Kozue.
Midori-san has told me the whole story.
But you shouldn't do anything rash without any proof,
otherwise you might harm innocent people.
But…
But this is too much!
I bet my future in volleyball on this one game.
To lose it like that…
I can't stand this!
I understand you, Chief.
Kozue.
Fujimi High School
It's A-Ayuhara-san.
Ayuhara-san.
Oh, it's you, Katsuragi-san.
I heard it all.
You were driven out of the club like I told you.
Why don't you play basketball with us instead?
Thank you.
But right now I feel really tired.
I'm sorry.
Ayuhara-san, a person like you…
…no matter what she's put through, will not give up.
I respect that about you.
Hey, hey! Listen, listen!
Have you heard the news about the volleyball club?
Eh?
Well, they say the one who burned Ayuhara Kozue's eyes with lime was one of Oonuma Miyuki's followers.
You don't say!
Hey, hey!
Oonuma Miyuki burned Ayuhara Kozue's eyes!
Really?!
That's terrible.
Alright. Let's make sure the Student Council punishes the captain of the volleyball team.
Kozue, trouble.
What's wrong?
The thing from yesterday became the hottest topic at school.
Eh?
Who spread gossip about it?
No idea.
I didn't tell about it to anyone.
Me neither.
I see.
Well, it has nothing to do with us either way.
We're better off staying away from it.
Right?
Eh…?
Every afternoon, as they were coming from school…
…the children went to play in the Giant's garden.
It was a large, lovely garden,
with soft, green grass and beautiful flo—
Ayuhara-san!
Y-Yes ma'am!
Ayuhara-san?
Ma'am?
Ayuhara-san.
Please read the current passage.
Yes ma'am.
Every afternoon…
Ahh.
When I can't play volleyball, everything starts to remind me of it.
This is no good.
I need to forget about it soon.
Thanks for waiting, Kozue.
Oh. Going home?
Yeah.
Doesn't it feel strange going home this early?
I honestly don't know what to do with myself at home.
I'm hoping you have some ideas?
I start new school term by reading a book.
A book.
And also—
Eh?
Oh, so Miss Volleyball wants to turn into a book worm?
What's with the sarcasm, Mitamura-kun?
It just doesn't feel like you.
I see you know what suits us
better than we do, huh?
Yeah, maybe I do know.
I heard some gossip about you.
Really, now? Is that seriously all it takes to bring you down?
Where's your usual enthusiasm?
Right.
He's right, you know.
It's just like Mitamura-kun says.
No matter how much I try to forget about volleyball, my mind keeps going back to it.
I'm the same.
That's why I don't know what to do anymore. It's like between a rock and a hard place.
Do you feel the same, Ayuhara-kun?
Yeah.
Well, either way, the current girls volleyball club is no good.
In my opinion, it's clearly its advisor,
Professor Shimizu's, fault.
I wonder if a woman is fit for such position…
See, she feels like she's just a puppet for show.
Why would she even become an advisor?
Anyway, that's exactly why you've gotta patch things up by yourselves.
Keep fighting!
And cheer up!
Alright, gotta run.
I've got soccer practice now.
Ayuhara-san!
Ah?
Uhm, our captain called for you.
She wants you to come to the club room.
– Eh?
Don't you think she did it on purpose?
She's here.
What did you call us for?
I bet you already know, don't you?
No, I don't.
Wow, playing innocent.
You're the ones who spread all those rumors!
What? I have no idea what you're talking about.
What a liar.
Thanks to the rumors you spread, our club's prestige went downhill.
Why did you do it?
Why…? But we didn't do any—
You're pretty bold, you know that?
I guess we've misjudged you.
Backstabbing like that
is completely unsportsmanlike.
B-But we didn't do anything!
Stop pretending.
We're not pretending.
You were the ones who backstabbed us.
W-What?!
What are you doing to our Captain?!
Know your place!
Captain!?
Captain. These rumors are not unfounded.
There can't be so much smoke without a fire.
I agree.
We all found this thing that happened with Ayuhara-san strange, and we discussed it together.
Ayuhara-san didn't spread that gossip.
It was all of us!
What… what are you saying?!
– That's right.
– I talked about it too.
We didn't have the courage until today
and so we did as you pleased…
But we can't take it anymore!
Yeah!
I've had enough of your messed up "traditions"
and being under your thumb!
Right!
What's with these "traditions"?
– Exactly!
– Whoa, whoa!
Rebelling against your seniors?
Talk about a bad attitude!
Yeah! You're way out of line!
Impudent lasses!
I won't forgive a rebellion!
Who's the ringleader?! Step forward!
There isn't one! We're all in this together!
Yeah!
Wait.
Girls, that's no good.
Ayuhara-san, why are you stopping us?
You had it worst.
Exactly…
You've got the most reasons to resist her!
Wait.
I don't think we're going to solve anything like this.
But…
But if we don't do it this way, it won't get to them!
We stood up thanks to Ayuhara-san's group's courage!
I can't hold back anymore!
– Yeah!
– What's so special about you!
Wait! Stop it!
If you're not helping, don't stop us!
I've been waiting for this!
Don't stop!
Finally, it's payback time!
Payback time…!
S-Stop it! Cut it out!
What was that?
If you hate each other so much, it's all over.
All of you loved volleyball… and it was
the reason you joined the volleyball club.
And yet…
And yet…!
Oh, Kozue.
Kozue?
Oh, Midori.
I'm not surprised seeing you here.
Yeah…
I always end up taking a walk here
whenever I have breaks.
Same here.
That brawl yesterday was really intense.
The whole school's talking about it.
Oh…
Things are getting more and more messed up…
Trouble, trouble!
Trouble.
Serious trouble.
What is it, Naka?
Wait… till you hear…
Takeichi-san's group has gathered…
…and are talking about how to reform the club.
Huh?
First of all, they decided that Captain Oonuma…
…should give up her position of captain.
So they're reshuffling the team?
Yeah.
And that's why everyone says they'd like you two back in the club.
Kozue.
What do we do?
Hey.
I refuse.
Huh?! But why?
It's a perfect opportunity to get back at Captain Oonuma for what she put us through.
I understand all that.
But remember what I said yesterday?
Deepening the conflict won't solve anything.
Besides…
Even if Captain Oonuma forfeits her captain title now…
…nothing will really change.
Nothing will truly change…
Principal's room
What? Disband the volleyball club?
Precisely.
I am very sorry to have to disband our volleyball club that has such a long winning tradition.
But it seems the club is undergoing a variety of problems.
I can't just continue to overlook its recent bad reputation.
B-But…
No, no.
I understand your feelings
as the volleyball club's advisor very well.
But if there is any budget for the volleyball club…
…the overwhelming opinion is that it is better to put it in more promising clubs.
They've got some nerve.
Making Captain Oonuma forfeit her title…
We can't let them off the hook.
We have to teach them a lesson, one that they won't forget.
But Takeichi-san and her friends are gathering evidence for the lime case…
…and if they do, we're done for.
I still don't understand why you did it.
Do you know how I feel now?
But these first years trashed our club's traditions…
Yeah. Besides, there's no evidence we did it.
We don't have to worry.
– I guess you're right.
– Okay.
The evidence is right here.
Professor Shimizu.
I didn't want to add fuel to the fire,
so I hid Ayuhara-san's towel.
Now I see that was a mistake.
If you want to continue this farce no matter what…
…I'm ready to call a witness who saw you.
Eh?
A witness?
Nakahara-san.
A person from the track and field club saw you putting lime on that towel.
I asked her not to tell anyone about it…
…but I can call her over here any time.
Oonuma-san.
Please gather everyone in the gym after school.
I have something I'd like to talk about.
I understand.
It's all over…
What should I do?
If it gets public, I'll get expelled…
I… I'm dropping out of the volleyball club…
Girls.
I want to apologize to everyone gathered here.
Up until now, rather being the club's advisor…
…I was just a puppet for show.
The reason the volleyball club ended up like this…
…can be directly attributed to my indifference.
I was uneasy about the club traditions
and so I left everything to Captain Oonuma.
Now I am reflecting on that decision.
Professor!
Do you mean I am disqualified as a captain?
Yes.
It was too much of a burden on you.
Not at all! I only wanted to protect the club traditions…!
Silence.
Huh?
Under your captainship the club is at a point
where it can't be saved.
The principal ordered
the dissolution of the volleyball club.
I can't believe it.
Professor, tell us it's not true!
Unfortunately, it is.
But I asked the principal.
I acknowledged I am responsible for this mess,
so I would like one last chance to clean it up.
The principal agreed on one condition.
One condition?
Professor, what was it?
That is… to challenge Misawa Academy
to a match once again.
Huh?
If we win, we can keep the club running like always.
But if we lose, it's disbanded immediately. That's the principal's condition.
So that just leave you girls, will you play the match?
Or will you let the club get disbanded?
Everything depends on you.
Oonuma-san.
What is your opinion as the current captain?
Now that Kanda-san's group are no longer regulars…
I really…
…can't play the match, correct?
Yes.
Therefore I quit the club.
Very well.
Ayuhara-san, you?
Y-Yes…?
Ayuhara-san, it's just like you wanted.
The captain's title is free for you to take.
You must be so happy.
Oonuma-san.
You can do whatever you want now.
But I never said I wanted to be the captain.
Kozue, you don't owe her an explanation.
Oonuma-san tries to make it look like we've driven her out…
But in reality, she doesn't think she can win the game
so she's shifting the responsibility to you.
Am I right?
What a coward.
What…?
Knock it off.
Enough with these fights!
I won't allow anything more.
E-Excuse me!
Professor, I'm in.
Me too.
I'll do it too.
– Let us play as well.
– Please.
Alright then, we'll start practice tomorrow at 7 o'clock after school.
If you don't want to let the club get disbanded…
…show up and give it your best.
I am going to become a proper coach, too.
I won't go easy on you.
Be ready for it.
– Yes ma'am!
Ayuhara-san, thank you.
Huh?
Seeing your enthusiasm for volleyball has finally given me motivation.
Let's work hard, both of us.
Yes ma'am.
Hey, Kozue.
Let's forget about them already.
If we lose with Misawa Academy because we dwelt too much on past, now that'll be trouble.
Yeah.
Hey, watch it!
Oh, it's you lovelies.
Tsutomu-kun?
That was dangerous!
Don't surprise me like that.
Don't walk around all spaced out then.
Oh? Wait, both of you look pretty serious.
I get it.
Unlike middle school, there are a lot difficulties in high school…
Exactly.
I miss middle school.
By the way, about that match with Misawa Academy that decides the survival of your club.
I'd say it'll be pretty difficult.
Huh?!
Hey, don't joke like that.
We'll win for sure.
Right, Kozue?
Yeah.
The club politics might be in bad shape,
but we're fine on the court.
Are you sure about that?
What is it supposed to mean, Tsutomu-san?
Don't doubt our power.
You're going to get burned if you get too confident looking at your past glory.
I want to show you something cool,
so come with me for a bit.
We're here.
Here?
Mihara
Yep. We're at Mihara Yumiko's house, the captain of Misawa Academy.
How do you know where this is, Tsutomu-kun?
I deliver fruits here every day.
Let's go see the backside.
Check that out.
How do you like it? You've never seen anything like that, have you?
Famous attacker, Ayuhara-san.
I'll counter your ball with these hands.
Alright, increase the speed!
But if I raise it any further, the speed will be 80 km/h.
I don't care.
You really are a superhuman, Captain.
Here goes.
Okay.
Speed of 80 km/h…
It's twice as fast as a world's best girls' spike.
What a machine.
Fujimi High School team makes Kozue their new captain.
The match with Misawa Academy is drawing near.
The girls train restlessly every day.
But somehow the team stays in low spirits.
Kozue realizes that it is impossible for her
to replace the former captain.
She asks Oonuma Miyuki to come back to the club and complete the "machine gun attack" with her.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.