苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
Machine gun attack
Increase the speed!
But if I raise it any further, the speed will be 80 km/h.
I don't care.
You really are a superhuman, Captain.
Here goes.
Okay.
Ayuhara-san.
I will become a receiver
that can compete against your spikes.
I've been practicing like hell until today.
I'll counter your ball with these hands.
I've never seen such training before.
That in itself is a bit unsettling.
Unbelievable.
She set that machine at speed of no less than 80 km/h.
Do you realize it?
It's twice as fast as the girls' record spike.
Wow, that's a shock.
So no matter how strong our spike is, she'll receive it like it's nothing.
Don't make such a miserable voice.
It only means that we must practice more and harder.
That's what I'd like to do.
Let's start with it right now.
But it's just Mihara Yumiko, their captain,
who can do such receive, right?
Then I suggest we just aim at other people in her team.
In principle, you're right, but I'd prefer if the new Fujimi High School team would fight honestly.
Right, Kozue?
Sure.
I don't believe that speed alone is decisive.
But how are we going to attack?
Kozue, you, of all people?
Don't forget you were the captain of our national team.
Yeah. We'll follow you anywhere, Captain.
Naka, stop calling me captain.
We're not in middle school anymore.
All right, all right. At any rate, we're counting on you.
Right, girls?
Yeah!
All right, time to practice.
Let's do our best.
It's Fujimi High School team's rebirth!
– Work hard!
– Fight with all you have!
Come on, Captain.
– Yeah.
– Let's go.
Ah, I'm sorry!
Spike machine.
They practice receives by launching a ball twice as fast as world's record.
To counter that receive, we need…
All right, let's wrap it up.
Ayuhara-san, Takeichi-san, Hayakawa-san.
Yes ma'am.
The rest, short break.
What do you think we need to counter Misawa Academy's reception trained with a spike machine?
Uhm…
What is it, Takeichi-san?
Professor, you just told "Misawa Academy's reception"…
But the problem is Captain Mihara alone.
I thought to aim at her teammates instead.
It may not be the most honorable strategy, but I think it's better than forceful pushing.
I agree.
But I'm sure it's not just their captain that practices on that spike machine.
We shouldn't underestimate the other players.
Besides, captain's pace is usually a sign of the whole team's performance.
It's better to assume that all of them are good players.
I see.
Professor, the problem is how to throw their reception out of balance.
How about a very fast game?
Yes, that too is a possible strategy.
That's why I want three of you to master a "machine gun attack".
– Eh?
– "Machine gun attack"?
Yes.
It is an attack that performs reception-toss-spike pattern in a very short time.
It requires three experienced players and good harmony.
First, the recipient passes the ball
to the tosser in a low horizontal line.
Then the tosser quickly twists their body and sends the ball diagonally just above the net.
The spiker jumps with the ball and slams it at the right moment.
– Do you understand?
– Yeah. – More or less.
Hayakawa-san, receive.
Takeichi-san, toss.
Ayuhara-san, spike.
All right, let's get down to it.
– Yes ma'am!
Ready?
All right, begin!
Lower!
– Toss it faster!
– Yes ma'am!
– Steady!
Wrong!
That's just an ordinary toss.
Twist your body with the ball and send it diagonally!
Yes ma'am.
Once more!
Too high! Make it lower!
You raise it too much! You can't send it so high!
Wrong, wrong, wrong!
There is no harmony at all.
Let's do it again.
She's on fire…
All right, once more!
Wrong! Redo!
It looks very tough…
Good luck to all three of you.
Wrong!
Twist your body faster!
Wrong, completely wrong!
You're all out of sync!
It's so difficult…
Am I really able to send it diagonally?
But I have to do it.
Wrong, wrong, wrong!
Takeichi-san.
Takeichi-san looks so beaten.
I feel the same, actually.
But Professor Shimizu is sure strict.
She won't allow even slightest mistake.
Really.
We have to be precise like a clockwork.
But at this rate my clockwork spring will break.
Since when you're so fragile?
Huh?! Hey!
Kozue!
Oh, a nap?
Ah, Katsuragi-san.
I was so sleepy from the training I was sure I'm going to fall asleep in class.
Looks like you have it tough.
I feel tired no matter how much I sleep.
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's all right.
But make sure you don't do that during a game.
A single yawn could make our club gone.
Good luck.
Thanks.
Oh?
It's Oonuma-san.
She looks very different when she's all alone.
Where are Kanda-san and Suga-san?
– They don't hang out with her any longer.
– Why?
Oonuma-san has lost her queen status.
Standing on the court with the ball in her hand, Oonuma-san really looked like a queen.
That image alone was the reason why many girls wanted to enter the volleyball club.
But Kanda-san's group wanted to keep the queen for themselves.
That's why they bullied and driven out anyone who was in their way.
Oonuma-san didn't orchestrate any of it.
I don't think Oonuma-san even knew about the case with lime, Ayuhara-san.
But Oonuma liked to be the queen,
so she tolerated Kanda-san's group's actions.
In a way, Oonuma-san got lonely all by herself.
Oonuma-san, alone and with no ball, isn't queen anymore.
No good, Takeichi-san!
That'll be declared as holding!
Besides if you do it this slow,
the "machine gun attack" loses its meaning.
The whole thing must last no more than five seconds from the reception. Understood?
All right, let's take a rest for a while.
Will we make it in time before the game?
Takeichi-san, that's enough.
You don't have to do it anymore.
Nakazawa-san!
Yes ma'am!
Nakazawa-san.
You'll do reception.
Huh? M-Me?
That's right.
You'll be receiver.
Hayakawa-san – toss.
Ayuhara-san – spike.
All right, let's redo from scratch.
Takeichi-san.
You were good at serves. Practice these.
Professor!
All right, begin!
The match with Misawa Academy is about to come!
Here goes!
Lower!
Yes ma'am.
What's wrong, what's wrong?
Great! That's it!
Now to only make it faster. All right, resume.
Here goes!
Okay, good.
A "machine gun attack" to counter the spike machine.
Misawa Academy doesn't stand a chance against us.
We won't get beaten.
But we're not finished yet.
We still can't do it under 5 seconds like Professor Shimizu told us to.
It's fine as long as we master it before the match.
Everyone's into it.
With us, the Fujimi High School volleyball team was born anew.
Captain, Midori!
Here you again with your "captain"…
Hey, hey. You gotta see it yourself.
Eh?
They're letters of resignation
from Takeichi-san and Ishikawa-san.
Huh!?
What's the reason?
They just left it in the club room and departed without a word.
Maybe because she was removed from the "machine gun" team?
Ah, and Ishikawa-san went along…
Having regular players quit right before the game is pretty troublesome…
Ah, Kozue!
Takeichi-san!
Ayuhara-san—
Why did you quit the club? Why?
We promised to play together in the new volleyball club…
I don't want to anymore.
I'd like to keep the reason to myself.
Takeichi-san…
Do I really have to tell why?
All right, fine.
It's awkward for us second years if you, a first year, become our captain.
But I'm not even your captain.
You have the skill.
You're in the center of the current team.
It's only natural for you to be our captain.
And it's awkward for you to have us around.
And to be perfectly honest, I don't want to play under a freshman.
I never wanted to become the captain…
The current Fujimi High School team needs you to become its captain.
It doesn't need us.
You should think less about me and more about the team.
I see.
It can't be helped.
Professor, what should we do?
Are we going to let them go like that?
There's nothing we can do.
We have to do with the remaining players.
All right.
Captain's pace is usually a sign of the whole team's performance.
Assume all of them are good players.
You should become their captain.
The team no longer needs us second years.
Miyuki told me she's going out for a walk a while ago.
She looks troubled.
Did something happen at school?
No, everything's fine.
I'll look around for her.
This way!
Come on!
Tell us about volleyball, miss!
Please!
Sure.
Let's play, let's play!
Good, good!
You got a whole lot better!
Keep it up, keep it up.
Here goes next one.
Great. Stretch your arms straight out.
Keep your eyes on the ball.
Try to accept the ball sooner.
Oops, I forgot.
Okay, let's go.
Good, keep it up!
You're doing great!
Come on!
Stretch your arms!
Good, good.
Let's wrap it up for today.
It's getting dark, so hurry up home.
Teach us more next time!
Good bye!
Good bye! Till next time!
Be safe on your way home!
Okay!
Aren't you going to her?
Ah, Tsutomu-kun.
What are you doing?
Aren't you going to her?
Huh?
You came to pick Captain Oonuma up, didn't you?
How did you know?
I know the way you think.
Hurry up and tell her what you want to.
Yeah.
Believe in yourself, Kozue-kun.
I'm in the middle of delivery.
I'll be on my way.
Thank you.
Oonuma-san!
Ayuhara-san.
Captain, I'd like to ask you
to return to our volleyball club.
Huh?
Right now the Fujimi High School team
doesn't deserve its name.
Please, get back.
Make us into a proper Fujimi High School team.
The club room is lonely without you.
Everyone misses their captain that showed at the club every day for two years.
I haven't been enrolled for a single month yet.
I've no idea how to comfort them.
I want everyone to be happy.
Please, Captain.
We'll be waiting for you.
Ayuhara-san.
One. Two.
One. Two…
One.
Kozue… she's not coming no matter how long you wait.
The pride of a queen won't let her go back after she quit out of her own will.
Ah!
We'll be waiting for you in the club room.
The club room is lonely without you.
Captain!
The practice has already started!
I'm ready!
Oonuma-san, we didn't have to wait long!
Yeah.
I wonder what Chief's thinking.
Why did she let Oonuma-san become our captain again?
No matter what you say, Oonuma-san looks great.
She has this cool vibe around her.
I hate to say it, but I can feel the queen's dignity after all.
I guess, but I still can't forget how they bullied us before.
Everything was for queen's sake.
Why don't we forget about it already?
With her around, Misawa Academy's doomed.
Yeah.
Receive it firmly!
Great! Don't forget that harmony!
We did it! We completed the "machine gun attack".
One swallow doesn't make a summer.
We can't be sure if we can repeat it.
We need to drill it to perfection!
Hayakawa-san, try passing it a bit lower.
That way, you can toss more diagonally and the spike will be more powerful too.
I understand!
Professor Shimizu!
Takeichi-san.
Ah, Professor.
I hated how I couldn't be of use to our team.
Deep inside, I also hoped that I might become the captain.
I'll redo it from scratch.
Please teach me again.
Please!
Ishikawa-san.
You can help these three with their exercise
It's fine for you, right?
Yes ma'am!
Takeichi-san.
You practice serves.
The match is getting close.
We're counting on you.
Yes ma'am.
Here goes! Get ready!
Twist your wrist more! Make it lower!
Yes ma'am.
Lower. Make it so that it barely grazes the net.
City Gym
Misawa ・ Fujimi
Time!
Our opponents got confident.
Time to make them lose that pace.
Calm down, girls.
Yes ma'am.
Do it just like we practiced.
Got it?
– Yes ma'am!
They're ours!
Hit, hit, hit!
Misawa ・ Fujimi
Ayuhara-san!
Ah, Ayuhara-san!
We did it!
Fujimi jumped back on their feet.
Fujimi… fight!
Yeah!
Fight!
Kozue's team armed with "machine gun attack" challenges Misawa Academy to a rematch…
…and demonstrates its superiority, steadily gaining point after point in the second set.
However, it all changes when Mihara Yumiko's spike slams the Fujimi's court.
It's turnaround for Misawa.
Having bet their club's future on this match, Kozue's team starts feeling pressure.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.