苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 046—
The fearsome invitation letter
Naka, it's yours!
Captain!
Great. Keep it up!
Watch out!
Fujimi · Misawa
It's Ayuhara Kozue's machine gun-like spike again.
We have to counter it somehow.
It goes better than expected.
At this rate the second set is already ours!
But we can't let our guard down.
Let's keep going steadily ahead.
Listen! When Ayuhara Kozue starts her spike, leave its reception to me.
Got it?
– Yeah!
Takeichi-san, give us a good serve.
Okay.
But first, let's take care of that serve.
Attention. I'll receive this serve.
Please don't get in my way.
– Yeah.
– Okay.
Here I go!
I'll disturb your pace a bit.
Alright. I'm going to hit it with all I've got!
What a powerful spike!
Midori!
– Waah!
– She did it!
Girls, now's our chance for a comeback. Got it?
She hit me!
Midori.
Are you okay?
That was an intense spike.
Hayakawa-san!
I'm fine. I'm fine!
That spike seemed to have quite the startling effect on them.
Hey.
Maybe that's the key to winning with Fujimi High?
Move, girls!
Okay. Now.
Let's try it again.
It worked, just like I thought.
I'll just keep on striking, one after another.
Fujimi · Misawa
They caught up to us.
They're amazing.
Where did Mihara-san learn such a powerful bullet spike?
An outstanding spike and equally good reception.
She's almost as good as Češka from the Czechoslovakian team.
Češka could receive Shellenina's spikes like it was nothing.
Mihara-san's reception is just as good as Češka's.
And just like Češka, she can move from defensive to offensive play in a heartbeat.
Mihara-san's spike is just like Češka's.
Fujimi · Misawa
What's wrong, girls?
How can you let Mihara-san disturb your pace?
Mihara-san aims her spikes at our faces on purpose.
I get scared when I see it coming.
I certainly don't know how to deflect it.
You're right, that's something I didn't expect.
But nothing has really changed.
Mihara-san is the only one who worries me.
If we manage to throw her off balance,
it'll be an easy game.
Yes, but how do we do that?
Listen up.
I thought up a strategy.
I hit someone's face one out of two times.
Nobody but Ayuhara can accept my spike.
We've practically won this game already.
But you're my real target, Ayuhara-san.
Do you girls understand?
– Yes ma'am.
Don't forget that the fate of our club
is hanging on the result of the third set.
– Yes ma'am.
"Throw the ball left and right. That'll shake Mihara-san."
Professor Shimizu's strategy seems to be working.
Professor's idea worked great!
She doesn't trust anyone on her team, so she tries to get everything herself.
Alright! Let's score a lot.
Hey, Kozue. When the game's over,
let's go to the City Stadium.
Sure, if we win. But what for?
You'll see when we get there.
Okay, let's wrap this up.
Fujimi · Misawa
Receive!
Do you even know how to play this game?
The club's safe!
I'm so glad.
I'm glad, too.
Ayuhara-san. We lost, but I have no intention of pulling back.
Fujimi High · Tōkai Commercial High
Eh, they're losing…
I didn't know you were a soccer fan.
Mitamura-kun told me to come with you to see his game after we're finished and now he's losing…
Good! Keep it up!
Mitamura-kun! Good luck!
Hey, what's wrong?! Get a grip!
Alright!
Nice, Mitamura-kun!
Great!
Ayuhara-san seems to have gone somewhere ahead of us.
Is that so…
Do you need anything from Ayuhara-san?
I'm from Misawa Academy.
I came here on behalf of Mihara-san, our volleyball club's captain.
She asked me to deliver this.
Mihara-san wanted you to deliver it to Ayuhara-san?
What is it?
"Invitation to a one-on-one volleyball match".
What does she mean by "one-on-one match"?
It's a challenge. No mistake about it.
A challenge?
I'll hold on to this.
Thanks.
"Unfortunately, Misawa Academy lost to you in a six-on-six match."
"However, this is because of the difference in the power of the whole team."
"Personally I don't think I'd lose
to any one of Fujimi High School members."
She's got some nerve.
"Ayuhara-san. Let's hold a match between just the two of us."
"If you're not scared, come see me at Fujimigahama at once."
It is a challenge.
Good going, Fujimi!
Mitamura-kun, you can do it!
Hey, Midori. I think I'll leave early.
I want to let Tsutomu-kun know that we won.
I'll see you later.
Huh? Kozue!
Kozue…!
"Come see me at Fujimigahama at once"…
What a pain.
Where is Ayuhara-san?
If Chief only knew about this letter,
she'd storm in Fujimigahama like a hurricane.
I'd like to know where she went, too…
Hey, let's split and search for her.
Yeah, good call.
Well, we don't have any other option. Let's go.
Yeah.
Wait, girls.
Eh?
We don't have enough time to go search for her now.
Besides, I'm positive that if she arrives even a little late, she'll be flagged as a coward.
I can see Mihara-san saying that.
This means it's not just Ayuhara-san's problem.
It'd be an insult to the whole Fujimi High School volleyball club.
So what's the plan?
The plan is I will go in Ayuhara-san's place.
Huh?
I'll go in her place.
I am the captain of the Fujimi High School volleyball club.
I'm going.
Okay.
But give me an hour, just an hour.
I'll find Chief for sure.
Okay. I'm counting on you.
Sure.
Let's go.
Yeah.
It's already been an hour.
That's why I came in her place.
Are you saying I'm not good enough?
I'm not.
But I invited Ayuhara-san, not you.
I told you already, I don't know where Ayuhara-san is, so I came instead.
I hope she didn't run away?
Just like I thought.
There is no place in our club for weaklings that run away from a challenge.
Ayuhara-san is a part of Fujimi High School volleyball club and I am their captain.
A challenge to the club members is a challenge to the club's captain.
Fine, have it your way.
I can play with you instead.
But don't hold me responsible after it.
What do you mean?
You'll see it when we play.
The rules are as follows. Each of us plays five spikes.
The one who receives the most, wins. Is that okay?
Yeah.
I see. Thanks.
She's not at home.
She's not at Hayakawa-san's either.
Hmm… Where did you wander off to, Chief?
Nakazawa-kun.
Oh, Ichinose-san.
You look upset, what's up?
I don't really have time to explain…
Alright, hop in.
I received three out of three so far.
So you only have two left.
I know.
Yeah.
Captain, last one.
You did it!
Looks like her practice with the machine has paid off.
Nobody can beat our Captain's reception.
Captain.
I'm fine. Leave it to me.
How was that? Don't you want to take
a short break before receiving my spike?
If you need a break, you can take one.
No, let's continue.
Somebody, toss the ball.
I wonder if Tsutomu-kun is at store right now?
Ichinose's greengrocer
Captain, keep it up!
Two left.
Alright. Time to show what I'm made of.
I'll aim for her face.
– Wah!
– She did it!
Captain!
I lost.
But there's still one serve left.
Bring it on!
I'll receive your spike this time, for sure!
Captain!
You've got guts.
But, if you insist, fine. I'll take you on.
I came all this way and he's not even here… how disappointing.
Hey, Kozue-kun!
Oh! That voice!
Tsutomu-kun! We won the game
against Misawa Academy!
Our club is saved!
I know. Congrats!
Oh, you already knew?
Hop on the back.
Huh?
Chief, it's good that you're here. Come on in.
Oh, Naka, what are you doing there?
We don't have time. Hurry up and hop in.
We need to go to Fujimigahama at once!
Fujimigahama?
I won't hold back!
Hey, Ichinose!
Kozue?
– Captain!
– Hang in there!
That's why I told you not to hold me responsible.
I won against Fujimi High's captain who showed in Ayuhara-san's place.
I guess that means I beat Ayuhara-san as well.
Alright, take down the net.
It's too early for that.
Ayuhara-san!?
I'll avenge my Captain.
Huh?
Mihara-san. Before we hold the match,
I want to say one thing.
You're petty and immature.
I'm disappointed in you.
What the heck?
If you hated losing a regular volleyball match so much…
…you should have just asked us for a proper rematch.
But instead, you sought revenge by holding an one-on-one match.
You're a disgrace to sportsmanship.
Are you finished?
Maybe we did lose today's game.
But I was only working hard for and looking forward to your spike.
And yet, I couldn't even receive it properly
thanks to my teammates that held me back.
What am I supposed to do about my regrets?
I couldn't use my true power!
So what do you want me to say here?
Volleyball isn't an one-on-one game.
– It's a team sport.
– I know that all too well.
No, you don't.
You said you can't shine in a regular match.
But that just means your skill isn't good enough.
I don't care about the match!
I only hated the idea of losing to you!
I know I can win!
This is like talking to a brick wall.
Okay, let's play then.
I'll smash that pride of yours.
That's my line.
I've never seen Kozue this furious before.
We'll play 10 serves each.
If I lose more than 3, you win.
If you lose just a single one, I win.
How is it?
Fine by me.
Midori, toss the ball to me.
Okay.
Let's go.
Midori.
Second serve!
Third serve!
Fourth serve!
Fifth serve!
I thought something was off. It's all because of this rock!
Save your excuses.
The conditions are in your favor.
Five serves left.
Midori, let's do this.
Do it in one go.
Alright.
Attack!
That's enough, don't you think?
It's obvious to me you're equally strong.
So what do you really want to prove here?
It's time to cut this out, don't you think?
Who are you?
I'm Yagisawa Kaori, a third year at Ōsaka Jidōin High School.
Yagisawa Shizuka, second year at the same school.
And I'm Yagisawa Katsura, first year.
So you're the three famous Yagisawa sisters?!
From Jidōin High School which has consecutively won the last 3 Interhigh tournaments?
So that was the famous trinity attack of the Jidōin High School's queens?
One of our relatives lives here in Fujimi.
We're here for her wedding tomorrow,
but we arrived a day early.
So we decided to see the game between Fujimi and Misawa. It was even better than expected.
We heard a lot about Ayuhara-san and Hayakawa-san, so we watched you two closely.
Very closely.
But I'm surprised with no-name Misawa Academy's captain.
I've never seen a receiver like you, Mihara-san.
Also aiming spikes at your opponent's face.
It seems incomplete for now, but if you polish it,
you can make it into a killer technique.
How about we play at the next Interhigh?
Interhigh?
But first you must win the prefectural contest.
We'll wait for you until then.
I feel a menacing aura around these three.
And that trinity attack looked so fearsome.
They're all fearsome players.
My new rival are these three sisters.
Ayuhara-san.
Huh?
Midori-san, you too.
Our Katsura wanted us to ask you for a favor.
A favor?
Katsura really wanted to play
a match with you while we're here.
Huh?
Please.
Kozue, what do we do?
Hmm…
Machine gun spike versus the trinity attack?
It might be a perfect opportunity to learn more about them.
Fujimi High School, who just won against Misawa Academy, decides to participate in the Interhigh.
They hold a practice match with
the three sisters of Jidōin High School.
But they're brought to their kneels before the sisters' powerful attack.
The sisters move like ninjas.
Kozue is stunned by the trinity attack,
not knowing who accepted and who spiked the ball.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.