苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 047—
The three sisters of Jidōin High School
That's enough, don't you think?
It's obvious to me you're equally strong.
What do you really want to prove here?
Time to cut it out, don't you think?
Who are you?
I'm Yagisawa Kaori, a third year at Ōsaka Jidōin High School.
Yagisawa Shizuka, second year at the same school.
Likewise, Yagisawa Katsura, first year.
So you're the three famous Yagisawa sisters?!
Jidōin High School which has consecutively won the last 3 Interhigh tournaments.
So that was the famous trinity attack of Jidōin High School's queens.
One of our relatives lives here in Fujimi.
We're here for her wedding tomorrow, but we arrived a day earlier.
We decided to see the game between Fujimi and Misawa. It was even better than expected.
We heard a lot about Ayuhara-san and Hayakawa-san, so we watched you two closely.
Very closely.
But I'm surprised with no-name Misawa Academy team's captain.
I've never seen a receiver like you, Mihara-san.
Also that spike aiming at opponent's face.
It seems incomplete for now, but if you polish it,
you can make it into a killer technique.
How about we play at the next Interhigh?
Interhigh?
But first you must win the prefectural contest.
We'll wait for you until then.
I feel menacing aura around these three.
That trinity attack looked very fearsome.
Fearsome players.
My new rival is these three sisters.
Ayuhara-san.
Midori-san, you too.
Our Katsura wanted us to ask you for a favor.
A favor?
Katsura really wanted to play a match with you once while we're here.
A match with us?
Yeah.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.