苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 048—
Dash of youth
One more time.
Yes sir.
Nice!
Next!
Hayakawa.
Yes sir.
She expected so much from Professor Hongou.
But so far he hasn't really achieved much, has he?
I still don't see how we can beat the Jidōin Academy's trinity attack.
Professor Hongou…
Why don't you say anything?
Why?
Good, Hayakawa.
Your wrist bone has grown stronger.
Yes sir!
What's wrong, Kozue?
You still want to practice?
I just thought of something.
I feel like I realized a weak point in my spike.
It's no use…
There's a big difference between thinking of something and doing it.
Weak point…?
Did Professor Hongou point something out?
No.
It's just my intuition.
You're thinking too much.
You're too young to develop a neurosis.
Go to bed already.
Come on, Kozue.
Yeah…
Kozue?
You're still up?
Hm? Oh, no, no.
I guess working at home
at your own desk really is the best.
I think life in the dorm is starting to get to me.
But Fujimi High School
doesn't allow a dormitory system.
The Interhigh qualifiers begin soon.
We got a special pardon.
Well, color me surprised.
Why?
Who'd think a princess like you could live in a dorm.
You've gotten pretty sturdy.
Come here, I'll show you something.
You still think I'm fragile?
Very.
Can I go to see your practice today?
I want to see what kind of training you're going through and how much you've grown.
Be my guest. Today we're holding a test
for new club applicants.
Why don't you take it too, Mitamura-kun?
I'll pass.
I wanted to surprise them.
But I guess it wasn't the right moment…
Mitamura-kun and Midori-san, huh…?
I'm jealous.
Attack!
I feel lonely…
What's wrong?
Are you down just after three?
Redo!
Yes sir.
I've had enough!
"Enough"?
Have you given up already?
All right, next!
Yes sir!
Five consecutive receptions, huh…?
This is a pretty strict test.
Second!
Come on, come on!
The only one stricter than the test is Professor Hongou.
What's wrong? Finished already?
A-As if!
Good!
She's pretty good! Ishida-san doesn't exercise restraint during her reception.
She may be rough, but she's got what it takes.
Ishida Matsue.
Nickname "Ishimatsu".
That's pretty fitting for a tomboy.
Damn!
Got it, man!
Still alive!
Keep going, Ishimatsu-san!
Just one left! You can do it!
Ah, damn it!
Are we done here?
Why, are you tired, Professor Hongou?
She's even better than Professor Hongou.
What's wrong?
Too bad!
Professor, once more!
Ah, oops…
I'll get it next time!
Why doesn't she just quit already?
She's pretty obstinate. What's her name? Inomata?
Please, once more, Professor.
I feel sorry for her. She must be exhausted.
Professor Hongou is only throwing difficult balls.
Are you suggesting that the enemy should serve where it's easy to pick up?
Ah, you're right.
– Hey!
– Ah!
Still want to keep this up?
If it's okay to try as many times as I want,
I'd like to keep going until I pass!
What…?
Even if it takes until tomorrow…
I'll do my best!
It can't be helped I guess.
Whatever. You pass.
Yeah! Congrats, Forehead!
Oh, I'm so glad!
– Ah…
– Forehead!
Hang in there!
– Hang in there, Forehead!
– What's wrong? – Are you okay?
Ishimatsu and Forehead, huh…?
With these two around, Hayakawa-kun and Ayuhara-kun can't be careless.
I'm fine, I'm fine!
Don't worry about me.
Alright, the test is over.
Let's hold a practice match.
Split into two teams.
– Yeah!
Here goes!
Stop!
I'm gonna get scolded…
Ayuhara.
Yes sir.
Oonuma, you too.
Such a sloppy block
causes trouble for the back line.
Huh?
Let me hear you say it.
Uhm, it causes trouble.
Exactly.
So, Ayuhara, Oonuma.
Hit Hayakawa and Nakazawa.
– Huh?
– Huh!?
Huh?
I told you to hit them.
What are you waiting for?
Hurry up!
What was that?
I didn't tell you to caress them.
Hitting is done like… this!
You can't be lenient, otherwise Hayakawa and the rest become careless. Continue.
Y-Yes sir.
Where's your enthusiasm?
Let's go!
Fight!
I'm sorry, girls.
Don't sweat it.
I won't cause you any more trouble.
As expected.
I did it!
Good.
I hope you've learned your lesson.
Y-Yes sir.
We did.
Midori, that block just now dissipated the pain on my cheeks.
Let's hurry up!
We don't have much time left.
Professor Hongou truly knows how to lead his students.
That's it, Forehead.
That's Fujimi High's trademark, the machine gun attack.
Hm.
Machine gun attack, huh?
It certainly is a unique technique.
But it won't be of much use.
But why, Professor?!
We learned it specifically
to use against the Yagisawa sisters.
Oh, you did.
But it's only worked once so far.
Huh?
Fine, I'll explain it thoroughly.
The opponent we'll meet at the Interhigh
are nothing like the ones we played with so far.
A technique that worked once
won't work second time against them.
For example, let's take you, Ayuhara.
Sir?
You certainly were an excellent attacker in middle school.
However, it's dubious how far you can go at the Interhigh. It's on whole another level.
The game with the Yagisawa sisters
the other day has proved that very well.
Ayuhara's spike, no matter how you look at it, has no weak points.
But it's just a textbook spike.
Because of that, a professional player will immediately see right through it.
If Ayuhara-san's spike isn't enough…
What about the team?
Forget Jidōin, we might not even be able to beat Misawa.
We can't rely solely on Ayuhara-san.
All of us have shared responsibility
on the match score.
Offense is said to be the greatest defense.
We should focus on that.
Alright, Captain!
I'll practice spikes with all I have.
You should spike with your forehead.
What did you say?!
That's the spirit! If the machine gun attack is no good,
we just need to think of something else!
Well said.
As a reward, I'm inviting you all to dinner today.
All right! Great!
Professor Hongou has changed.
He combines severity and kindness
in just the right proportions.
"If only Professor Hongou was here."
That way of thinking was a mistake.
The problem was me all along.
Me and my limited power…
Thanks for the food.
It was great, almost like Bon Curry.
That was delicious.
But Professor…
What is it, Inomata?
You invited all of us to a dinner, but can you really afford it?
Don't worry.
Professor Shimizu helped me out.
Wow, you look so close!
Hayakawa-san…
Professor Shimizu is blushing!
High school students these days…
Professor Hongou, that's Professor Shimizu's tea.
Ah? Oh, you're right. Sorry.
Let's hurry up and go to sleep.
Yeah, not a word.
I'm gonna sleep like a log.
Where's Ayuhara-san?
She's stayed behind with Professor.
I expected to see you here, Ayuhara.
Please tell me, Professor!
Hm?
I knew without you saying anything.
My spike is not enough for the Interhigh.
But I was afraid to acknowledge it.
I gave my all to obtain my current attack.
But what should I do if we need even more power?
I just don't know what to do anymore.
So you want me to solve that problem for you.
Yes sir.
You're asking too much, Ayuhara.
Huh?
You can destroy this wall
that's blocking you with your own power.
But trying to overcome that wall with a ladder is not the way to go.
I can say only one thing.
Get rid of your pride as attack number one.
Excuse me.
Poor thing.
Ayuhara-san was in such low spirits…
Talking to other people was never my thing.
Besides…
I've known Ayuhara for a long time.
I know all too well how she feels.
She's like a bamboo that grows very slowly.
Sometimes she gets under the snow, but eventually she stands straight again.
Fujimi High School Girls' Dormitory
Ah, hello?
Ayuhara speaking.
Oh, it's you, Kozue-san?
Can I speak with Tsutomu-kun, please?
Too bad. He hasn't returned from work yet.
Really…?
He works this late?
He came up with "Mobile Supermarket".
He sells right off the truck.
Every day, he drives near the apartment houses where the business is better.
He probably still works at this time.
I see…
He says that balls and radishes are handled differently, but he'll do his best not to lose to you.
He works just as hard as you.
You're late. Did he tell you anything?
Not really.
You're sleeping already, right?
I'm turning off the lights.
Kozue.
You're not gonna practice spikes tonight?
Kozue?
Balls and radishes.
They're handled differently,
but I'll do my best not to lose to you.
Kozue?
Did you say something?
Let me guess what you were thinking about.
Huh?
Tsutomu-san.
Did I get it right?
Midori!
Hey, Mister!
Yo.
I'm here again.
We were waiting for you!
I'll go tell everyone you're here!
Grandma!
Grandma.
The greengrocer mister is here!
Today we'll have a festival too!
Yes, ma'am, a daikon. Would you like me to cut it?
Five of these?
Thank you.
Welcome, welcome!
Welcome!
Ichinose's greengrocer Mobile Supermarket is here!
You won't get fresher goods than at our shop.
If you buy here today,
we'll give you a discount next time.
Huh?
You don't want me to appear on the court?
Yes, you heard me well.
I told you yesterday,
we're going to start with the basics.
The basics…?
So what do you want me to do?
For now, just keep silent and follow
the instructions from Professor Shimizu.
Hurry up.
Today we'll hold a practice match again.
– All right!
– Okay!
We'll go first.
Ayuhara-san…
Oonuma.
Sir?
Put Ishimatsu in Ayuhara's place.
We'll be waiting for you.
Professor is making me go through some special training all over again.
Professor Hongou has prepared something for you again.
I'm jealous.
Hayakawa-san, we're going.
Sure!
Your control is too weak!
Oonuma.
You'll be the setter.
Setter?
You'll be creating attack opportunities for the spiker.
It's plain but it's very important.
It'll be your duty, Captain.
Yes sir.
I don't understand.
Why am I the only one
who has to go through this training?
Ayuhara-san.
Ma'am?
You heard about it already, right?
Let's begin.
Y-Yes ma'am.
You'll sprint with all you have.
The most important thing is the start.
Okay. 100 meters, right?
We don't need such a long distance.
Huh?
Goal is just 30 meters away.
After you reach the flag, circle it around.
Then run back here. Got it?
Yes ma'am.
Alright then, let's start.
Not enough.
You have to run faster from the 20th meter.
Otherwise it's not a real race.
Huh?
Professor, who do I race against?
A ball.
Huh?
You're racing against a ball.
I don't understand what she means,
but I don't feel like doing it.
My teacher told me to get rid of my pride as attack number one.
Right on the mark…
I don't want to start over with some new techniques at all.
Ayuhara-san.
Assume position. Don't just stand there.
Y-Yes ma'am.
Come on, we don't have much time.
Alright!
Five minutes break.
– Okay!
– Yes sir.
Ayuhara-san is just sprinting?
What are the teachers thinking of?
That's Professor Hongou's way of doing things.
Way of doing things?
Professor's goal is…
…is to make Kozue into a secret weapon again.
I see.
And here Professor was complaining how Ayuhara-san skills were not enough.
So he plans his strategies sneakily.
Hayakawa.
Ayuhara isn't the only one who's the secret weapon.
You too.
Oonuma too.
No. The entire Fujimi High School team needs to become the secret weapon.
Or else we don't stand a chance against Jidōin.
Is this exercise worth anything?
Even if it is, I still feel like the weakest link.
I wonder what everyone's thinking…?
Ayuhara-san!
Y-Yes ma'am!
I wonder what Kozue-kun's doing now.
It's about time she enters the court.
I'd better work hard, too.
Ayuhara-san, stand up!
Yes ma'am.
Tsutomu-kun!?
Kozue-kun.
I'll do my best not to lose to you.
So, you better not lose too!
Tsutomu-kun.
As if I could lose.
Professor Shimizu, let's keep going!
Go steady.
Yes ma'am!
I won't lose.
I won't lose!
If I'm to race against the ball, so be it!
Tsutomu-kun, I wanted to tell you something.
Good luck!
But that…
…needs to be saved until after I've won against the ball.
Next Sunday are the district qualifiers…
Do we have enough time to finish her training?
Ayuhara.
Hayakawa.
Oonuma.
Everyone. I'm counting on you!
The district qualification matches are drawing near.
Coach Hongou orders Kozue to race with the ball…
…Oonuma to toss from the back…
…and Midori to practice long spikes.
All in service of them learning to strike
the opponent's court in under five seconds.
The "double attack" strategy.
However, the district qualifiers are just three days away.
Impatience and anxiety begin to creep into Kozue's team.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.