苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 049—
The secret double attack
Ayuhara-san.
Y-Yes ma'am!?
Let's try it once more.
Y-Yes ma'am.
Captain, I can't keep quiet any longer.
Hayakawa-san…
Professor.
Aren't you forgetting something?
There are only three days left until the prefectural qualifiers.
What of it?
Why are you making Kozue
race against volleyballs, Professor?
Please tell us.
As their captain, I'm worried about this, too.
Hayakawa.
From now on you'll practice long spikes.
Oonuma, you'll practice tossing with the balls I throw you.
Yes sir.
As for you, Hayakawa, you're to aim at the left and right edges of the net.
Make it graze the net as close as possible.
Got it?
The end of the net at its current height?
It's too reckless!
The ball will just jump behind the line.
Maybe, but I'd be happy if you could get it that far.
Okay, Oonuma, let's practice your toss!
Here I go!
We're not practicing receptions! They're tosses!
– Show me a good toss!
– Yes sir!
What's wrong!?
B-But, Professor, you're throwing it too hard!
All I can do is to receive.
I know you can do better!
Too high, too high!
Aim lower!
What's that? I told you not to aim at the center!
This is too much…
Don't worry! Just focus when you shoot!
Easier said than done!
This feels better…
What are we even doing this stupid training for?
Those serves are way too strong, and he expects me to toss them?
Yeah. My long spike is absurd too.
I don't understand it either.
But I promised Professor Hongou
I'd re-learn everything from the basics.
So you're saying that racing against balls is one of the basics?
I can't help but think this training is only taking us further away from the basics.
Something's wrong with Professor Hongou.
Maybe he went crazy?
Oh!
Ayuhara-san, there's a letter to you.
Thank you.
Your mother gave it to me.
Thank you very much.
I wonder if she heard what I just said?
Huh?
It's from Ōsaka, from Arai Tomoyo.
I hope you're well.
It's been almost half a year since the World Junior Championships.
I enrolled in Yamaha High School and joined its volleyball club.
By the way, the Ōsaka prefecture qualifiers for the Interhigh have already started.
We played against Jidōin High School
in the first round.
Jidōin…!?
Jidōin · Yamaha
We couldn't do anything against the Yagisawa sisters' trinity attack.
Before we knew it, we were beaten 15 to 3 and 15 to 2.
Even Arai-san…?
It's just like in the rumors.
I guess high school volleyball really is at a whole other level.
We have no choice.
We need to trust Professor Hongou.
B-But, Kozue…
We can't turn our backs now.
Do you need something, Professor Shimizu?
I'd like to talk about their training.
I'm all ears.
All three of them seem very anxious.
Can we really get through
the prefectural qualifiers like this?
They've already practiced to make up for their loss against Misawa Academy.
Yes, and?
Are you trying to tell me that
my new method is too much for them?
Yes.
Well, it's clear to me that if we don't do something, we're going to lose to Jidōin High at the Interhigh.
So if we know we'll lose anyway, I'd like to try something new.
That's what I think.
Something new?
Yes. I'm not sure it'll work, though.
So you're making them do something
you don't fully believe in?
If we lose no matter what path we take,
I don't see the harm in trying it.
So that's the reasoning behind your training?
Professor…
What's wrong?
Okay. Let's wrap up for today.
The prefectural qualifiers start tomorrow,
so everyone can go home.
– Yeah!
– Right on!
Ayuhara, Hayakawa, Oonuma, huh…?
How'd it go, Kozue? Did you catch up with the ball already?
Nope.
Not at all. What about you?
Don't be silly.
If I tried, I'd only make a fool of myself.
Is that so?
Hey, Hayakawa-kun.
Mitamura-kun.
Have fun!
Ah, Ayuhara-san!
Let her go. Besides, you came to pick me up, didn't you?
You're right.
Idiot.
Hahaha.
Oh?
It's Tsutomu-kun's house.
Ichinose's greengrocer
I always wind up going here…
I don't like it!
Tsutomu!
But…!
But I'm just thinking about our customers.
That may be true, but if you keep doing this we might go out of business in this town!
That's nonsense!
Please don't yell, Tsutomu.
You'll inherit this shop either way.
You can do whatever you want with it.
But please, everything but that.
Have it your way, Dad!
Tsu-Tsutomu!
Tsutomu-kun.
K-Kozue-kun?
Tsutomu!
Why did you have a fight with your father?
It doesn't matter.
Your face says otherwise.
Sometimes I go to see your training. Racing against a ball is a pretty strange exercise, don't you think?
Tsutomu-kun?
Why do you even have to do that?
I don't really know.
And that…
…makes me really worried.
Wow, Kozue-kun, you're going through this without even knowing why?
What, do you see something I don't?
More or less.
Professor Hongou is trying to come up with a technique no one has ever seen.
Something unfathomable by common sense.
Don't you think?
I guess you might be right,
but our current training still looks crazy.
But that's exactly it. It has to look crazy.
Everything new looks crazy at first.
The same goes for my family's business.
If we buy directly from the production area…
…there's no place for the middleman, so we can sell our vegetables cheaply.
But my dad says that's not possible
and just forbids me.
Why?
Because apparently no one has done it before.
If we were to try it, we'd get resistance from the other stores.
Dad's afraid of the backlash.
But I still want to try it, Kozue-kun.
There never will be any progress unless we can overcome the boundaries set by common sense.
Overcome common sense's boundaries?
You're right. We need to do things
the others won't dare to do.
Maybe that's what Professor Hongou is thinking?
What does he expect from your training?
If you think about it, you'll understand.
Maybe you're right.
Do your best, Kozue-kun.
Yeah.
I'll go cheer you on during the prefectural qualifiers.
Thank you.
Think about what he expects from our training.
Captain Oonuma-san – toss.
She has to precisely pass any ball she's thrown.
Then Midori spikes it with perfect precision.
Their training is a little unusual,
but it's still in line with the basics of volleyball.
What about me, then?
Racing against the ball…
Just to be able to counter a fastball?
Aren't there easier methods to accomplish that?
He can't possibly expect me to actually catch up with every ball!
I'm not a ninja.
But still…
What's the connection between all of our training?
The attack ends with the spike.
Don't tell me that after the spike…!
No, that's too insane.
There's no way I can do that!
But…
But it's just the thing
Professor Hongou might come up with.
Fujimi High School volleyball club
Professor.
About Ayuhara-san…
What's wrong, Kozue?
You've been looking down all day long.
Maybe she doesn't feel well?
I don't think that's it.
Ayuhara!
Yes sir.
We need to talk.
Why don't you come here for a bit?
Yes sir.
What is it, sir?
Take a seat.
What are you worried about?
The main pillar of the team shouldn't show anxiety on the way to the match.
I'm not anxious.
I just feel uneasy.
Hm?
About what?
What is the new strategy
you're thinking about, Professor?
My strategy?
Yes sir.
I understand the cooperation between Captain Oonuma and Hayakawa-san.
But, what I don't get is my role in all this.
If you figured out that much,
can't you see the big picture already, Ayuhara?
What you need to do.
I do but I can't believe it!
Well, I'd like you to believe in us more.
New strategy?
I haven't heard anything about this either.
Ayuhara-san's special training is connected with Oonuma-san and Hayakawa-san's practice, right?
Yes. It's deeply connected.
Oonuma will give us a chance.
For that reason, I gave complete control of both reception and toss to Oonuma.
Sir.
Then Hayakawa relays that toss with her long spike to the right or left end of the net.
Yes sir.
The enemy will naturally think the ball will be an out.
Then at the last moment Ayuhara slams Hayakawa's spike to the corner of the enemy's court.
Just like I thought!
Yes. Spiked balls are flying at 30 to 40 km/h.
You need to catch up with that ball, jump and spike rather than cutting it.
I named this technique a "double attack".
Double attack?
Yes, double attack.
Unless we go with such a crazy strategy, we have no chance of breaking the Yagisawa sisters' attack.
Everything depends on you now.
I'd like us to master this technique
in the prefectural qualifiers, before the Interhigh.
Professor Hongou's amazing strategy.
The double attack.
Double attack…!
Tōkai District Volleyball Interhigh qualifying venue
City gymnasium
Mishima · Fujimi
The first set finished with 15 to 0.
The second set is already at 8 to 0.
They have a chance to break Mishima with a perfect score, Ichinose.
It's the revival of Fujimi Academy's duo.
Kozue, don't get too excited that Tsutomu-san came to see your game.
Mishima · Fujimi
They're one step away from a perfect score victory.
Mishima team will be celebrating
if they manage to land at least one point.
Everyone is in great form.
So far I don't like it all.
Huh?
They did it!
They got perfect score!
Great, Fujimi!
Hayakawa-kun!
Ayuhara-kun!
Tōkai District Volleyball Interhigh qualifying venue
City gymnasium
Thanks for coming.
Is your work okay?
Yeah. You were awesome with that perfect score.
Thanks.
But, don't let yourself go out of breath by working too hard in the beginning.
The road ahead is long.
Wow, you're saying the same things
as Professor Hongou.
"You won with perfect score?
Great, now think about the future matches."
"Complete the double attack."
"Double attack"?
Yes, it's our new attack method.
Oh?
Racing against the ball, right?
Yep, you got that right.
Ayuhara-san.
Misawa Academy's match is about to begin.
Coming!
See you.
I'll come to see your game every day!
Good luck, Kozue-kun!
Thank you! I'll be waiting!
Yokota · Misawa
How's the game, Midori?
Misawa is completely controlling the match.
They're on a whole other level.
What an amazing spike!
And reception, too.
They're picking up the ball like it's nothing.
I don't care about the match!
I only hated the idea of losing to you!
I'll win. I'll make you lose!
I know I can do it!
This is overwhelming.
Yeah. They're a lot more formidable
than I had imagined.
Exactly.
If we keep winning like this, four days from now on…
…we'll meet them in the semifinals.
So far we won once and lost once.
I hope the third time's the charm.
But can we really win?
It'll be fine.
We have Professor Hongou with us.
Girls!
Once we get back, we practice at once. Got it?
– Yes sir!
See?
Huh?
Mihara-san can stay calm even though she knows we're observing her.
She's so confident.
That's not good enough yet.
Don't worry too much.
But we do need to complete
the double attack as soon as possible.
Murasawa · Kōga
Ota · Yokohama
Tenryū
Misawa · Futaba
Tenryū · Tōkai
Tenryū is pretty good.
They're a dark horse.
They have no distinct technique,
but they have an outstanding team work.
I think they might get to the semifinals.
So they'll play against…
Either Misawa… or us.
Maybe we'll have to play with Misawa first, then Tenryū?
We should be thinking about how to play against Tenryū, too.
Kozue!
Ah, huh?
What are you doing?
We were talking to you, you know.
I'm sorry.
It's just I can't see Tsutomu-kun anywhere.
Don't worry, he must be busy.
Midori…
Prepare yourselves.
We're playing against Matsubara High next.
– Yes sir.
Kozue.
Ah, yeah…
Fujimi · Matsubara
He's still not here…?
Maybe something's wrong?
Did something happen?
Kozue, chance ball!
The power of Fujimi High School is improving.
But Ayuhara-san's spike hasn't changed a bit.
In fact, it's gotten worse.
What are you doing?
What are you doing…?
What are you doing!?
Double attack!
Fujimi · Matsubara
Ah, what a close call.
Who'd think Matsubara—
Kozue!
What was with you today?
We might've won, but you've played like a novice!
I'm sorry.
Tomorrow we're playing against Misawa.
Get a grip!
Hayakawa-san, that's enough.
But Captain!
Good luck tomorrow, Ayuhara-san.
I'm sure Tsutomu-kun will come see you tomorrow.
Yeah…
Fujimi High School volleyball club
Professor.
Did you notice Ayuhara-san's behavior today?
Yeah. What of it?
She'll be fine.
She'll train for an hour and she'll get better.
I wonder about that…
What do you mean?
High school students are different from junior high school students.
They have become older
and their problems have changed as well.
I understand.
She's going through something
that has nothing to do with volleyball?
Yes.
I don't think I'm the best person to handle that.
Ayuhara-san.
Please help me out with some shopping.
Ah… yes ma'am.
Oh?
What did you want to buy?
Ayuhara-san. You can't play a satisfying match if you're worried about something even a little.
Y-Yes ma'am.
Go and sort out your concerns quickly.
Give me a match without regrets tomorrow.
Professor…
But come back by dinner.
Professor!
Thank you!
Ah!
Business suspended until further notice
Ichinose
Huh!?
Tsutomu-kun!
Sir, it's Kozue!
Please open the door!
Tsutomu-kun!
Sir!
Fujimi team plays in the Interhigh qualifiers without completing the double attack.
Numazu attacks without mercy.
But Hongou still doesn't give up
on the double attack.
The second set. Score is 14 to 14.
Kozue is growing impatient.
What is Hongou's plan?
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.