苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 050—
Tough love
Ichinose's greengrocer
Tsutomu-kun! Are you there?
Tsutomu-kun!
Knock all you want, no one's gonna come out.
Huh?
Uhm, did something happen?
The owner's condition suddenly got worse. Tsutomu-san took him to the hospital.
Oh dear, they went to hospital?
Excuse me.
Kozue-chan.
I saw the sign on the store and got scared.
How are you feeling, sir?
Thanks for asking.
There really was no need for all of this.
Huh?
The doctor said it's just overwork.
But Tsutomu exaggerated as usual and took me to hospital.
So where is Tsutomu now? The store was closed.
– Lie still, Dear…
– Yeah, yeah.
You see, he left to sell more.
He's very enthusiastic about it.
Left to sell more?
It's the greengrocer man!
Cheap fruits! Very cheap!
Fresh fruits, very cheap!
Ah, Toko-chan?
Is their offer really so special?
It is! You can get radish for 30 yen!
Are you playing house?
Nope! The store is real!
Hurry up or all will get sold out!
Oh dear.
Welcome, welcome!
Ichinose's mobile supermarket!
We got great discounts! Welcome!
I'd like these.
And one cabbage.
Sure thing.
Let's see… it'll be 350 yen total.
Thank you.
I'd like some potatoes.
Coming.
Well, that'll be 150 yen.
Wow, it is really cheap!
Tsutomu-kun.
Oh, what's up?
I heard about it from your dad. I'll help you out.
You don't need to.
Hey, hey, I'd like to buy these tomatoes.
Of course. One kilogram, right?
It'll be 100 yen.
How much for these?
Ah, let's see…
Please serve me too.
Naturally. Just a second.
Aren't you glad miss came to help us out?
Ah, Toko-chan.
You won't cut any profit with such prices, will you?
I can sell them fresh and so cheap because I contracted the producers directly.
Good luck with your business.
Oh, is that your girlfriend?
N-No, you're wrong.
Ah!
Well, well?
You're both flushed!
Hey!
But I just spoke the truth.
Sorry I didn't come to cheer for you today.
Nah, don't sweat it.
Your dad got sick.
You have it tough, running everything all by yourself.
Haha. As if.
On the contrary, I feel very excited.
You saw the direct contracts' results yourself, didn't you?
It was a bold decision, but it ended up great.
Yeah, you got a lot of customers. I didn't expect it.
Right?
Even my dad, who opposed it so much, had to give in.
But Tsutomu-kun, can you do it all alone?
The customers made a real siege today.
Tsk. I'm not that frail.
If you have time to worry about me,
think about your volleyball.
That reminds me of
Professor Hongou's double attack.
I'd love to see it once.
After all, it's what motivated me to try out this direct selling method.
How is it going?
It's still incomplete.
Incomplete? Seriously?
You're not slacking, are you?
No…
My direct sales have been successful.
I'm sure your double attack will succeed, too.
Listen. No matter what happens, I'll go cheer you on during the final game.
Show me your double attack then.
Believe in yourself.
I know for sure Ayuhara Kozue can do it.
Tsutomu-kun…
It's a promise.
Come on.
If I lie, I'll eat a thousand needles.
Go! Go! Ayuhara!
City Gym
Tōkai district volleyball Interhigh qualification venue
Tenryū · Hamana
Misawa · Izu
Just like we thought.
Tenryū and Misawa are very strong.
If we win today, we'll face Misawa tomorrow in the semifinals.
We can do this.
We're gonna show them!
Today's opponent is Numazu. Easy-peasy.
We can't let our guard down.
– Are you ready?
– Yeah! – Okay.
Professor! Uhm…
What is it?
I'd like to try double attack in today's game.
Hmm.
Kozue, you made beginner mistakes yesterday.
There's no way you can do double attack today.
Professor!
Okay. Let's try it out.
I don't feel confident, though.
Confident?
Don't be afraid to fail at the beginning.
When you fail, you just have to retry.
This gesture will be our sign.
Numazu · Fujimi
Kozue!
Good going!
It's the sign!
Yeah.
Here I go!
Good luck.
Captain!
It seems it's still out of their reach.
She's way too reckless. There's no way that long spike would do anything.
But I feel she's going to try it again.
Numazu · Fujimi
Five points left.
Hold out, girls!
– Yeah!
It's the sign for double attack again.
Professor! They've just recovered from the previous mistake.
We shouldn't press them so hard in such important game.
I press them because it's important game.
But if they fail this time,
we might be unable to recover.
They'll lose confidence and it'll be all for nothing.
If we were to lose now, we might as well give up. We'd have no chance with Misawa nor Tenryū anyway.
This time…!
Numazu · Fujimi
Something's up.
Don't lose your spirit. Fight! Fight!
Yeah!
Numazu · Fujimi
Professor!
Not again! I can't do it!
At last minute? It's reckless!
My direct sales have been successful.
I'm sure your double attack will succeed, too.
Let's do it! A sign is absolute!
Huh?
Numazu · Fujimi
Damn it!
Believe in yourself.
I know for sure Ayuhara Kozue can do it!
If we lose heart here, it's all over.
Believe in yourself and win this through!
Numazu · Fujimi
It was way too reckless.
We barely made it.
Yeah. He kept signing the double attack.
It was insane. Ayuhara-san, don't you agree?
I…
Good job!
You did well, girls.
I'm happy that we've finally tried it in a real game.
Now I'm confident we can succeed with the double attack.
But, Professor, we failed in all our attempts!
So what?
Being afraid of failure won't get you anywhere.
If you fail, do it again.
If you fail again, do it yet again.
If you keep at it, you'll eventually reach your goal!
I think so, too, Professor!
Please let us try the double attack in tomorrow's game, too!
Kozue! What are you talking about?
It's the semifinal tomorrow. Our opponent is Misawa!
I know.
That's why I want us to do it.
We have to do it!
All right. Let's go back to school and hold a practice at once!
Professor Hongou really is crazy and now
he has infected you, too. It can't go well.
– Kozue.
– Ah, what?
Ah, never mind.
You don't listen at all to what I'm saying.
Have it your way.
Tsutomu-kun. I will definitely show you double attack in the finals.
Definitely…
Everything sold out!
Yeah. It's thanks to your advertising.
Thank you.
All right, I'm going for another round.
This time, it's the other side of the river.
Okay! Come see us again!
Hey you, clown.
Huh?
You do some flashy stuff.
Your crazy low prices cause trouble for our business.
Why do you want to destroy us?
Do you have something against us?!
Destroy?
I just…
Keep your mouth shut.
Why are you doing this?
Let's have compensation for our damage.
Let me go.
I'm only selling cheap and fresh vegetables to my customers.
What…?
You're asking for it!
Please don't use violence.
Screw you.
Give us half of the sales!
If you do, we'll let you off the hook for today.
I refuse.
I have no reason to give money to you!
What…?
Come here, Mr. Policeman!
Here they are, Mr. Policeman!
Mr. Policeman!
– Please save him!
– Crap! Let's run!
– Damn it!
– Mr. Policeman!
Are you okay, mister?
I'm fine. Where's that policeman?
There is none.
I tried to save you. I just came up with it.
Thank you.
You saved me, Toko-chan.
Ah.
What was that!? Once again!
Again!
What's that?
It's nothing like during the match!
Do it like it was the actual thing!
I disregarded tactics for the most part
and let you do the double attack…
…because I believed your willpower was more important than technique.
The double attack will succeed for the first time
when all three of you work in perfect sync.
But now, Ayuhara's the only one
who's taking this seriously.
Oonuma. Hayakawa.
Do you have anything to say?
I'm sorry.
– Professor Hongou.
– Yes?
We can do this, Midori!
We have to do this!
Don't you think that Ayuhara-san's obsession regarding double attack is a bit abnormal?
Huh?
You said yourself that rather than technique, the double attack requires willpower.
Don't you think Ayuhara-san's obsession with double attack…
…is a bit different from the pure obsession about volleyball?
Girls at her age are very delicate.
Her heart is vulnerable to every little thing.
Sis!
Toko-chan, what's wrong?
Sis, big trouble!
Greengrocer mister was badly hurt!
Huh?!
Tsutomu-kun?!
What's wrong, Toko-chan?
Ayuhara-san for the first time fell in love with someone.
Tsutomu-kun… Tsutomu-kun!
Professor Shimizu.
I'm leaving it to you.
Hey, hey, Sis! Let's hurry up and go!
Ayuhara-san?
Hurry up and go.
You can't leave him hurt, can you?
But…
Are you worried about double attack?
Yeah.
Ayuhara-san, do you really think you can do it like this?
Like Professor Hongou said, double attack
requires willpower rather than technique.
There is no way you can do it with your mind like now.
Now…
Y-Yes ma'am.
Ayuhara-san!
Please promise me one thing.
That no matter what, you won't forget about volleyball.
I won't.
– Let's go.
– Okay.
Ichinose's greengrocer
Tsutomu-kun!
Ah, Kozue-kun.
How's your injury? Does it hurt?
Oh, this?
It's nothing serious.
Are you really okay?
I am.
See?
I'm fine, really.
The doctor said it's going to hurt for today,
but I can go to work tomorrow.
Tsutomu-kun, I'm begging you to stop this dangerous work.
Huh?
I'll talk to my dad about you.
He'll definitely come up with a way to help you.
Kozue-kun, that's the last thing I want.
I've bothered your dad too much already.
I don't want him to help me again.
But…
Please understand, I have my pride as a man.
I'm confident I can go through my problem alone.
So please let me.
Tsutomu-kun…
I understand, but I'm so worried about you…
Kozue-kun, you're of surprisingly weak heart.
I'm not going to stop with my direct sales, no matter what.
Kozue-kun, you see…
I am not doing this just for money.
Have you seen how happy those housewives were when taking cheap and fresh vegetables?
Kozue-kun.
I intend to put all I have into this work.
That kind of trifle won't stop me.
I won't lose to you.
Tsutomu-kun, you've changed.
You've grown up so much more than me.
I have an idea. Let me help you around the store.
Huh? You?
No way. You have your volleyball.
Volleyball this, volleyball that.
Even if you won't let me, I'll do it anyway.
I've decided already.
B-But you have an important match in front of you…
Promise me. Promise me, okay?
Professor Hongou. Professor Shimizu.
I'm sorry.
Ayuhara-kun!
Oh, Mitamura-kun.
If you're looking for Midori, she's inside.
No, I was looking for you.
Huh?
I got this from Ichinose.
He asked me to deliver it to you.
Tsutomu-kun did?
Dear Kozue-kun.
Promise me you don't get angry about what you're going to read.
I thought about it a lot last night after our conversation.
I decided that I'll run my business alone.
This means that I want to put all my energy into my work.
I thank you with all my heart for your friendship.
But I'm not the man who ever gives up.
I believe that you know it the best.
Please keep going on with volleyball
with all you have.
Rather than pitying me, think of your own life.
Of your volleyball!
I find the way you are very beautiful.
And I love you very much.
I can't go cheer you on because of my work,
but in my thoughts I will always be with you.
Please make sure the double attack is a success.
Go! Go! Ayuhara!
Oh, Mitamura-kun.
K-Kozue, what's wrong?
So Tsutomu-kun… where's Tsutomu-kun now?
Ichinose went to work.
Huh? He left to sell again? That can not go well.
There's no telling what will happen to him this time.
Hold on, Ayuhara-kun!
Ah!
Where are you going?
Let me go! Let go of me!
Kozue, are you going to skip the match with Misawa?
Tsutomu-kun is in big trouble.
You have to play without me!
Ayuhara-kun.
Don't you understand Ichinose's feelings?
Ichinose really wishes that you focus on volleyball.
That's precisely why he refused your love.
No, it's not just you. I was left behind too!
Tsutomu-kun.
Kozue-kun.
And Mitamura.
Let's spend our youth so that we have nothing to regret.
To accomplish it, let's use all our strength sensibly.
I'll work hard not to stand behind you.
Tsutomu-kun!
Kozue, don't cry.
But… But Tsutomu-kun…!
Tsutomu-kun…!
Ayuhara-kun!
It isn't me who hit you just now.
It was Ichinose!
Huh?
Are you… Are you going to trample on Ichinose's feelings and throw volleyball away?
Kozue…
Ayuhara-san.
People are always experiencing the difficulties and suffering in life.
You have to first-hand experience those worries and sorrows, too.
Everything will only make sense in the near future.
Here you go.
Thanks for waiting.
Here you go!
City Gym
Fujimi · Misawa
Kozue, are you ready?
Yep.
Let's do our best!
– Yeah!
In my thoughts I will always be with you.
Please make sure the double attack is a success.
Go! Go! Ayuhara!
Tsutomu-kun. For your sake, and for the sake
of my youth, I'll fight with all I have.
Finally, the semifinals.
"Today we'll definitely succeed with the double attack."
In the middle of a balanced game and growing agitation, the sign for double attack comes out.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.