苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 051—
The pledge under Mt. Fuji
Professor Hongou. Professor Shimizu.
I'm sorry.
Ayuhara-kun!
Oh, Mitamura-kun.
If you're looking for Midori, she's inside.
No, I was looking for you.
Huh?
I got this from Ichinose.
He asked me to deliver it to you.
Tsutomu-kun did?
Dear Kozue-kun.
Promise me you don't get angry about what you're going to read.
I thought about it a lot last night after our conversation.
I decided that I'll run my business alone.
This means that I want to put all my energy into my work.
I thank you with all my heart for your friendship.
But I'm not the man who ever gives up.
I believe that you know it the best.
Please keep going on with volleyball
with all you have.
Rather than pitying me, think of your own life.
Of your volleyball!
I find the way you are very beautiful.
And I love you very much.
I can't go cheer you on because of my work,
but in my thoughts I will always be with you.
Please make sure the double attack is a success.
Go! Go! Ayuhara!
Oh, Mitamura-kun.
K-Kozue, what's wrong?
So Tsutomu-kun… where's Tsutomu-kun now?
Ichinose went to work.
Huh? He left to sell again? That can not go well.
There's no telling what will happen to him this time.
Hold on, Ayuhara-kun!
Ah!
Where are you going?
Let me go! Let go of me!
Kozue, are you going to skip the match with Misawa?
Tsutomu-kun is in big trouble.
You have to play without me!
Ayuhara-kun.
Don't you understand Ichinose's feelings?
Ichinose really wishes that you focus on volleyball.
That's precisely why he refused your love.
No, it's not just you. I was left behind too!
Tsutomu-kun.
Kozue-kun.
And Mitamura.
Let's spend our youth so that we have nothing to regret.
To accomplish it, let's use all our strength sensibly.
I'll work hard not to stand behind you.
Tsutomu-kun!
Kozue, don't cry.
But… But Tsutomu-kun…!
Tsutomu-kun…!
Ayuhara-kun!
It isn't me who hit you just now.
It was Ichinose!
Huh?
Are you… Are you going to trample on Ichinose's feelings and throw volleyball away?
Kozue…
Tsutomu-kun.
I understood.
I'll do my best for today's game.
And…
Let's go!
Kozue!
It's a race with that sun!
Okay, let's go!
Double attack!
– Yes sir!
Kozue!
Too slow!
Redo!
Yes sir.
Our weapon against Misawa is this double attack!
Do it again!
Yes sir!
No matter what happens,
I'll go cheer you on during the final game.
Show me your double attack then.
Okay! Once more!
Believe in yourself.
I know for sure Ayuhara Kozue can do it!
Aw, shoot! It almost went in!
Go for it, Ayuhara!
Kozue!
She did it!
So cool!
All right!
Don't forget that timing.
– Yes sir!
City Gym
A high school girls' volleyball tournament semi-finals three-set match…
…between Fujimi High School
and Misawa Academy is about to begin.
Here they go!
Best of luck!
Fight!
– Yeah!
– Fight!
– Good luck.
Good luck, Ayuhara-kun.
I'll watch your game on Ichinose's behalf.
It's the falling leaf!
Leave it to me!
Misawa · Fujimi
– You can do it!
– Hang in there!
Attack!
Machine gun attack!
Misawa · Fujimi
I'll receive the next one no matter what!
Here goes another.
That was the last one.
Thanks.
You have it rough, too.
You have a long way to my farm.
I decided to purchase goods without the middleman.
This way of operating is tough,
but still, I want to keep at it.
So you'll come tomorrow, too?
Yeah. I decided for myself…
…that I'll try as far as I can.
Anyway, it's a pleasure to do business with you.
Ah. Sure thing.
I do what I can.
Well then.
Yeah!
See you. Be careful on your way home.
Misawa · Fujimi
– Great! Keep it up!
– You're almost there!
Are you okay?
Ah, ow…
Damn!
But my nose's still there!
It won't happen again!
My nose mustn't be pressed any further!
Or else I'll have to play like this!
All right!
Fight!
Chance!
Machine gun attack!
Attack!
Don't sweat it!
Misawa · Fujimi
They're neck and neck.
They just can't shake them off.
All right.
Are you making them do that?
Finally, it's there.
The sign for the double attack.
An out!
Don't be afraid to fail at the beginning.
When you fail, you just have to retry.
All right, gotta hurry.
The apartment families are waiting for me.
Damn.
All right, we got the right to serve.
Let's try it once more! Good luck!
Don't get disheartened by failing once or twice.
Mental power is everything.
When you reach a good harmony,
you'll succeed with the double attack.
Damn!
Kozue-kun is giving her best right now.
And here I am losing time!
Fight!
Yeah!
Hit it!
Now's our chance!
Kozue!
Believe in yourself.
Attack!
They did it!
– Great, Fujimi Academy!
– Ayuhara-kun!
Good.
Ayuhara-san.
Keep it up in the second set.
We'll do what we can.
Alright, finally it got out.
Gotta hurry.
One last push.
Fight!
– Yeah!
– Fight!
You can do it, Fujimi!
Misawa · Fujimi
Captain, it's all yours!
Midori!
Attack!
Fujimi
She did it!
Easy victory!
Misawa · Fujimi
Fujimi High School wins in the semi-finals of high school women's volleyball prefecture tournament.
They advance to the final game.
Tomorrow is the final match with Tenryū High School.
Yeah.
I want us to become the prefecture representatives and go to Interhigh.
We just won Misawa Academy which we thought was the most powerful enemy.
Who knows? Maybe we'll even win through
the whole Interhigh and become the champions?
Here you go again, Midori. It won't be so easy.
I guess.
Our goal is still miles away.
Let's do our best!
Fight!
– Yeah!
It's the Tenryū High School's director, Oowada.
Everyone's relieved now that we won with the mighty Misawa Academy.
I can't say I am not, too.
Everyone's in such high spirits.
I wish it stayed that way.
No…
It's possible that our real enemy has been hiding behind Misawa's back all this time.
Huh?
Tenryū High School.
I'm afraid…
No, I'm sure…
…that they will turn out to be a terrible opponent.
Fresh vegetables straight from the farm
Welcome! Fresh vegetables straight from the farm!
Welcome, welcome!
Here's your radish. Also a tomato, right?
Okay. Thanks for shopping with us.
Ah, ma'am, can I be of any help?
Welcome, welcome!
– Right away.
– Here you go, ma'am.
Here. Onions, potatoes and a radish.
Hey, buddy.
What are you gawking at?
Hehe.
We got ahead with your idea.
We have many friends.
We've got good trucks, too.
We've already formed contracts with various farms.
No matter how much you struggle, you stand no chance against us.
Resources and willpower are different.
But don't mind us.
Just keep doing your business.
But unless you make it much cheaper,
I don't think anyone will buy anything from you.
Hahaha.
Going home already?
Don't quit your job too soon.
I won't give up! Damn!
One-two! One-two! One-two! One-two!
Keep up that pace!
Fresh vegetables!
Very cheap!
Fresh vege…
Nobody's gonna buy anything here either, huh?
One-two! One-two! One-two! One-two!
Fresh vegetables!
One tomato for a hundred yen!
Straight from the farm!
Come on, come on! We got very low prices!
Welcome, welcome, welcome!
We got everything!
Welcome, welcome!
Come on take a look!
Very cheap!
One-two! One-two! One-two! One-two!
Here you go. Two spinaches, right?
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
I'll be here tomorrow, too.
Thank you, thank you.
Next customer, please come in.
Tomato, right? We got plenty. Ah, please wait a moment.
Tomorrow is the final game, right?
Yeah.
What's with that voice?
You don't sound enthusiastic.
Don't you believe you'll win?
No, that's not it.
I just feel this way the day before an important match.
That's not like you, Kozue-kun.
Get a grip!
Where's your usual fighting spirit?
I'll be fine.
On the other hand, Tsutomu-kun, you look somewhat tired yourself.
How's your work?
Actually, it's pretty tough.
There are some painful things I need to deal with.
But I'll work hard.
I'll do so too.
I won't lose to you, Tsutomu-kun.
Hey, Kozue-kun.
Wanna climb Mt. Fuji with me?
Huh?
Yeah.
Hmm…
Of course, after you're done with tomorrow's finals.
But Tsutomu-kun, what about your job?
Don't sweat it. One day won't make a difference.
Let's climb together.
Yeah. I have to win tomorrow's finals by all means.
That'll be the first time I'll climb Mt. Fuji.
I wanted to climb it at least once
ever since I was a little girl.
I climbed it once with my pops when I was in elementary school.
Recently they built an awesome highway all the way till the 5th Station, so we can drive with a car.
Let's go with my truck.
Oh? Are you okay with it?
It'll be okay.
Daradadan!
Climbing a mountain or two
will be piece of cake.
You sure about that?
Remember how you always call it a piece of junk, Tsutomu-kun?
Haha.
I do?
Well, if I treat it well, I guess it'll let me drive itself far enough.
So what after we reach the 5th Station?
We walk up and climb, of course.
It's going pretty steep right from the beginning.
Here.
Ayuhara
Do your best tomorrow, Kozue-kun.
I'll definitely go cheer for you this time.
Yup! I'll win for sure.
Tsutomu-kun, good luck with your work, too.
Well then, goodbye.
Goodbye!
The final game, Fujimi High School vs. Tenryū High School, is about to begin.
Ayuhara-kun!
Do your best, Fujimi!
Captain Ayuhara!
If they see through our double attack,
they'll be able to receive it.
Tenryū High School will then pick up any serve we throw at them.
What to do if they catch up with our double attack?
We'll have to deal with that problem at the right time.
Okay, go!
– Yes sir!
Finally, it's the prefectural qualifying round final match.
The time of confrontation between Fujimi and Tenryū has come.
With Miyuki-Midori-Kozue's exquisite double attack…
…Fujimi unilaterally leads the game.
However, the shadow of anxiety starts to creep into Kozue's heart.
Tsutomu, who should've been here to cheer for her, hasn't come yet.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.