苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 052—
An extraordinary game resumption
On that sunny day, Tsutomu-kun was much brighter,
much more lighthearted than usual.
City Gym
The final qualifying match for high school women's volleyball tournament is about to begin.
The match is between Fujimi High School, who brilliantly defeated Misawa Academy…
…and the dark horse, Tenryū High School.
Ah! It's a chance for Fujimi!
Will we get to see the double attack?
Go!
They did it! It went in!
Fujimi Academy shows
its brilliant double attack strategy.
But Fujimi's double attack
is sure hard to counter against.
It must be thanks to
Coach Hongou's special training.
If they continue to play, they'll seize the first set completely one-sided.
Is there no way for Tenryū
to change the course of the match?
That's difficult to answer.
It all depends on how the Tenryū team's
coach prepared for the game.
Ah! Fujimi strikes again!
Fujimi's explosive double attack gains them another point!
It truly seems nothing can be done
to break their offense.
Fujimi · Tenryū
8 to 2.
It's the first set and Fujimi has already gained tremendous advantage.
Go forth, go forth, Fujimi! Come on!
Go forth, go forth, Fujimi!
That Mitamura-kun, acting like a cheerleader.
Kozue-kun.
Let's go hiking after the tomorrow's finals,
with just the two of us.
Thank you. I'm so happy.
We'll go by car until the 5th Station.
After that, we walk by foot, step by step.
If we manage to climb to the summit…
…then we can do it in life, too.
You at volleyball.
I at work.
We both can do it, I know that.
I'll have to work hard tomorrow, then.
I'll come to cheer you on, this time for sure.
Thank you, Tsutomu-kun.
I'll be waiting for you.
I'll come to cheer you on, this time for sure.
Tsutomu-kun… why aren't you here?
Alright, that's the last one. You ready?
Here you go!
Will you be okay with your truck
being loaded so heavily?
It'll be fine.
More importantly, I'll come back tomorrow.
Sure, I don't mind.
But isn't it too much effort to make such a long trip
from Fujimi to buy a bunch of vegetables?
I'll travel anywhere if it lets me
to cut my costs and sell them cheaper.
I see… You have it rough, youngster.
Not at all.
All right then, thank you very much.
Sure. See you tomorrow.
The road is dangerous.
Be careful on your way home.
I will. Good bye!
You'll show up in my game tomorrow, right?
Yes.
I'll come to cheer you on, this time for sure.
Thank you, Tsutomu-kun.
I'll be waiting for you.
I wonder where I can sell them…
Ah, it's so late already.
I have to hurry.
Fujimi · Tenryū
Here I go!
Nice, Fujimi!
Fujimi · Tenryū
The double attack strikes again!
It earns Fujimi another point.
Not even Tenryū can do anything
about this technique.
Still, Tenryū gets the ball
from time to time, which is good enough.
Not even the great receiver Mihara from Misawa, who confronted Fujimi in the semi-finals…
…could do anything against their double attack.
Ah! Tenryū's spike!
Great, Fujimi!
Good going!
Ayuhara's feint does its job and gets a point for her team.
Fujimi · Tenryū
At the score of 14 to 4, Fujimi now has the set ball!
Here I go!
We just need one more point!
We have to make it!
– Yeah!
No problem.
We just have to stay with the double attack.
But we can't let our guard down.
Kozue!
Midori!
Tenryū's captain Suga for the first time
succeeds at receiving the double attack!
All right!
It's coming, it's coming!
Tenryū finally puts up resistance.
They started to fight back against
Fujimi's double attack.
Attack!
Fujimi finally wins the first set.
Oh, but Tenryū's perseverance was really wonderful.
If they had started biting back earlier, it'd have been a lot more interesting.
But in any case, the second set will be very exciting.
It's so late already…
I hope I can make it in time.
Kozue-kun.
Hang in there!
Fujimi · Tenryū
The Tenryū team earned another point.
In the first set, we thought Fujimi's double attack was invincible.
But now they receive it flawlessly.
They pick up every serve.
Their opponents' impatience
in the second set surely plays a role, too.
A sudden turnaround in the game comes as a surprise to the Fujimi team.
It truly does.
Fujimi's side should change their tactics
if they want to continue to dominate the game.
Normally at this point
Fujimi would have asked for a timeout…
But for some reason, Coach Hongou stands completely unshaken.
Our double attack ceased to work.
Coach…
What should we do?
Right. Tsutomu-kun would laugh at me had he seen me like this.
I have to work hard so that
we can climb Mt. Fuji together!
All right!
Kozue-kun!
Apparently, Fujimi team's
Ayuhara Kozue's shoelace snapped.
This doesn't happen very often.
Coach Hongou asked for a timeout for the first time.
What kind of strategy can we expect?
Fujimi · Tenryū
Tsutomu-kun isn't here yet…
Even though he promised… maybe he forgot?
Ayuhara. Are you okay?
Ah?
Yes sir.
Good. Girls. Listen well.
Our double attack worked so well in the first set.
But now you are unsettled since
it seems to have stopped working.
Am I right?
– Yeah.
– Yes…
But you must not give up now.
Actually, Tenryū had given up on the first set to begin with.
– Huh?
They wanted to use it solely to learn the double attack.
Unbelievable in how short time they managed to do so.
And that's why we have problems now in the second set.
But Coach, what should we do now?
Heh.
We need to keep going.
No. We'll use the double attack even more often.
– Huh?
But you just said…
Trust me and listen to what I have to say.
Listen. Even if they manage to receive it
once or twice, it's still our honed trump tactic.
Will Tenryū's tenacity prevail?
Or will it be Fujimi's continuous attacks that win?
Believe in yourselves and make me proud.
– Yes sir!
What kind of offense can we expect from Fujimi now?
Hayakawa!
Show them!
Kozue-kun!
My shoelace snapped like a stick. It's too unnatural.
What if something happened to Tsutomu-kun?
Serve goes to Tenryū's captain, Suga.
Height: 165 cm. Weight: 60 kg.
A very impressive physique.
Everyone in Tenryū's team has masculine body.
With their tremendous power and stamina they can instantly turn a normal action into a counterattack.
Here goes!
Kozue, jump!
Got it!
You did it!
I'm counting on you!
Leave it to me!
Tenryū!
Fujimi · Tenryū
Tenryū gains set point!
Finally, Tenryū wins the second set.
What a great determination.
They showed a lot of strength and tenacity.
On the side of Fujimi one sees disappointed faces…
…that their double attack has become ineffective.
The Fujimi team will have
a tough time in the third set.
Hayakawa. I know you can play better.
I'm sorry, sir.
But no matter how much we try, they just receive our double attack.
But there's nothing to be afraid of anymore.
– Huh?
– Coach?
To tell the truth, this time it's us who gave up
on the second set from the beginning.
– Huh?!
– Huh?
In order to learn Tenryū's defense against our double attack.
You should have told us so from the beginning.
if I had done that,
then you'd feel too much pressure.
Do you understand?
Thanks to their countless receives…
…you've learned Tenryū's movements naturally.
Exactly.
One more thing.
Thanks to repeating the double attack,
we locked the enemy's defense in one pattern.
As expected from Professor Shimizu.
She saw right through it.
Listen up, girls.
In the third set feel free to use any attack,
not limited to the double attack!
– Yes sir!
And when using the double attack, aim not only at the edges, but also at the center.
At the center, too?
To that end, Hayakawa is make her long pass
at the net from a greater distance.
Yes sir.
We're bound to defeat them.
We will win for sure.
– Yes sir!
Fujimi · Tenryū
Finally the third set is about to begin.
The serve goes to Ayuhara Kozue,
captain of the All-Japan middle school team.
She's a wonderful player despite being a first year student.
We're counting on you, Ayuhara!
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Go! Go! Ayuhara!
Tsutomu-kun!
I'm such a fool.
I bet that shoelace was hit by a spike.
What am I thinking?
Tsutomu-kun didn't come because he's just busy with work.
Which means it must be going great for him.
Right? Right, Tsutomu-kun?
Alright!
I won't lose to you!
Watch me, Tsutomu-kun!
Move, move!
Captain!
Attack!
Surgery
Fujimi · Tenryū
After double attack from left and right…
…another of Fujimi trademark attacks,
the machine gun attack, firmly hits the court.
Captain!
I'll aim at the center!
Got it!
That's unexpected.
A double attack from the center!
Fujimi gains another point!
Ah? A timeout!
Tenryū Coach asks for time!
Alright!
Keep this pace!
– Yes sir!
Fujimi · Tenryū
Tenryū lost their resolve in the third set.
They are desperately trying to catch up.
Again, they demonstrate
an incredible stamina and perseverance.
That's Tenryū for you.
They saw through our tactics right away.
Yeah. Ever since that double attack
from the middle.
If we improve it a little bit, we could win…
Is there anything we can do, Professor?
I've been thinking about it before…
…but I still can't quite figure it out.
Fujimi · Tenryū
Tenryū catches up, point by point!
Fujimi desperately tries to stop them!
Another point for Tenryū!
A tie!
Tenryū finally caught up and finally achieved a draw.
It's truly a match at level worth of Interhigh.
Both teams go head to head.
At this rate, it's a battle of sheer willpower.
If we lose here, I won't be able to face Tsutomu-kun.
I have to think of something!
Surgery
Fujimi · Tenryū
A tie!
It's a tie, again!
You can do it, Fujimi!
Do your best!
Kozue. I'm scared.
What the heck, Midori? It's so not like you.
If this isn't time to give it our best,
then I don't know when is.
Fight!
– Yeah!
Captain!
Sis!
Tsutomu's in trouble!
Time!
A little girl appeared on a court.
Coach Hongou asked for a timeout.
What can we think of it?
Perhaps she was worried that Fujimi'd lose
and dashed out to cheer them on?
Sis! We have to hurry!
Wh-What did happen to Tsutomu-kun?
Go to the hospital immediately.
He's fatally injured…?
Tsutomu-kun…!
This is emergency.
Go see him at once!
– Ayuhara-san.
– Kozue.
I can't go until this important game is over.
Kozue…
That's right.
Let's resume the game as soon as possible!
Then let's win it as soon as possible!
To get Kozue…
To get Kozue to the hospital as soon as possible!
Thank you, Midori.
B-But…
Tsutomu-kun. You can't die, no matter what.
A-Ayuhara!
Sis, you're an idiot!
Sis, you idiot!
Sis, you idiot…
Don't be sorry if Tsutomu dies!
He can't die.
That's… That's absurd!
There's no way that'd happen!
Right, Tsutomu-kun?
We're going to climb Mt. Fuji together.
Tsutomu-kun… wait for me!
I'll go see you in a moment!
Dear God…
Please, please let me finish the game quickly.
Even if it's just one minute,
one second… please make it over sooner!
She chooses to disregard Hongou's advice to go see fatally injured Tsutomu as soon as possible.
Kozue stays to finish the match.
Her heart burns with conviction that it's absolutely impossible for Tsutomu to die like that.
Just one point more.
With just one point, she can go see Tsutomu.
Kozue's desperate.
Kozue, hang in there.
Hang in there, Kozue!
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.