苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 053—
Tsutomu
Kozue-kun.
Kozue-kun…
Tsutomu! Hang in there!
Tsutomu.
Tsutomu!
That Kozue…
What on earth is she doing?
I almost had it!
Tenryū · Fujimi
16 to 15. This is truly a match where
just one point could decide everything.
Ayuhara-san, just leave it to us
and go to the hospital.
We have to win this match as soon as possible so that Kozue can go.
We'll win for sure.
Tsutomu-kun, I'll be able to fulfill
my promise to you in just a few moments.
Please wait for me.
Please, Tsutomu-kun!
Kozue-kun…
Kozue-kun.
Hang in there, Tsutomu!
Kozue-chan will be here very soon.
Kozue… Kozue didn't go with you?
Why…?
I can't believe her, is that match really more important?
Alright! Let me try calling them again.
Mister, I told her and she said she'll be here soon. So don't die.
Mister…
Kozue-kun… the game…
What about the game?
Syringe, please.
Save him, doctor! Please save him—
It'll be fine, Toko-chan.
Kozue-kun.
Kozue-kun…
Time to finish this.
Now's our chance!
If it scores, Kozue can go!
Ah! Double attack!
Tsutomu-kun!
It disappeared!
She did it!
Damn!
Great, Fujimi!
– Nice!
– Awesome!
We did it. We won!
Turns out the double attack actually worked, Tsutomu-kun!
Kozue.
You fool!
Are you going there or not!?
Hurry up and go!
I ordered a taxi for you. It's already waiting.
Go!
I hope she makes it in time.
She will. I'm sure of it.
Please go faster, mister.
Please!
Tsutomu-kun. I held up my end
of the bargain and won the match.
Now you need to get better as soon as possible…
…and take me to Mt. Fuji like you promised.
Fujimigahama Municipal Hospital
Tsutomu-kun…
Tsutomu… kun…
It happened just a moment ago…
What on earth were you doing?!
Tsutomu-kun kept on calling your name,
struggling to breathe!
Stop! I don't want to hear this!
Kozue, please compose yourself.
Now, go and look at Tsutomu-kun.
Tsutomu…
Kozue-chan's here.
She came here for you.
No! No! No!
What's wrong, Kozue?
No! I don't want to look!
I don't believe it!
Tsutomu-kun's not dead!
I just don't believe it!
Kozue!
Idiot! Idiot! Idiot!
Even though he called your name so much…
Even though I told you…!
If you just came with me right away,
you could've seen him!
Idiot, idiot, idiot!
Miss, you big idiot!
Idiot… idiot…
If you went with me right away,
you could've seen him!
Miss, you idiot!
Idiot…
I'm sorry, Tsutomu-kun.
I…
I just…!
I just never thought you could ever die.
Tsutomu.
Tsutomu…
Tsutomu!
Hey…
Tsutomu…
Tsutomu.
Tsutomu-kun.
I fulfilled my promise to you.
If I won, we'd climb Mt. Fuji together…
That's the reason I fought so hard.
I wanted to climb Mt. Fuji
with Tsutomu-kun, no matter what.
And there, in the highest place in all Japan,
I wanted to confess something to Tsutomu-kun.
Kozue-kun.
What is it that you wanted to tell me?
I'll tell you in a moment.
Just please close your eyes.
Close them?
Like this?
Kozue-kun.
Can I hold your hand?
When I close my eyes,
I feel like you're going to go somewhere.
Alright.
Time to get brave and finally say it…
I've loved you for quite some time, Tsutomu-kun…
Kozue-kun.
Tsutomu-kun.
Tsutomu-kun!
Where are you?
Where did you go, Tsutomu-kun?
How could you leave me alone?
Tsutomu-kun!
Kozue-kun!
Wait, Tsutomu-kun.
I don't care about volleyball anymore.
Just don't leave me!
Tsutomu-kun!
Kozue!
Ayuhara-san!
Ayuhara-san…
Ayuhara!
Kozue!
Ayuhara-san!
Ayuhara!
Kozue!
Ayuhara-san!
Ayuhara!
Oh! Ayuhara!
Tsutomu-kun!
Ayuhara!
Mom…?
Midori…
What…
Kozue.
Everything's okay now. Don't worry.
Huh…?
All right, I'll go make her something warm.
I'm leaving her to you.
Sure.
Tsutomu-kun…
Kozue, hang in there.
I had a nightmare where Tsutomu-kun died.
It was terrible.
Kozue…
It wasn't a dream.
He really died.
Huh?!
You're lying!
That can't be true, Midori!
I guess you weren't lying.
Maybe I thought I'd meet him in my dreams.
Cheer up, Kozue.
I'm sorry.
The person you love has passed away.
It must be heartbreaking.
Please, leave me alone for a while.
Sure thing.
But if you change your mind, give me a call.
I'll rush to you any time.
Even in the middle of the night.
Tsutomu-kun.
Tsutomu-kun!
Kozue!
Tsutomu-kun…
Tsutomu-kun won't be around anymore.
Just like everything else within me.
I feel so empty inside.
When I'm waiting like this, I feel like I'm going to hear Tsutomu-kun's footsteps any second.
But it won't happen…
Tsutomu-kun!?
I'm guessing you didn't get much sleep.
Are you going to quit volleyball?
I wouldn't blame you. I'd understand.
Midori…
I'd probably do the same if I were in your shoes.
So what are you going to do now?
I don't know…
I don't know anything.
There's nothing left for me anymore.
Get a grip already!
What the heck, Midori?
Not accepting reality isn't like you at all, Kozue!
I can understand the shock.
But wallowing in despair all by yourself…
Didn't Tsutomu-kun despise that kind of behavior?
Despise?
I guess you're right. Heh.
Kozue!
Stop hurting yourself!
Tsutomu-kun would hate this.
Spare me that.
You don't understand my feelings.
No, I don't.
However, Tsutomu-san never let any situation stop him, no matter how difficult it was.
In fact, the more difficult it was…
…the more motivated he was
to face it and crush it.
Unlike how you're being!
That's easy for you to say, Midori…
…since you and Mitamura-kun are both alive!
Kozue!
I'm sorry for that.
But…
That was…
You shouldn't have said that.
I might be your best friend, but even I have my limits.
Fine.
Keep serving me all the lectures you want.
But there's no way you'll ever
understand what I'm going through.
Stop acting like a spoiled child!
Oh, so now you'll slap me from the left?
I've had enough!
Hold on!
One more thing.
If you give up on volleyball like this, you'll be hurting Tsutomu-kun the most.
Keep that in mind.
You have to catch up to the ball faster!
Ah, shoot.
Alright! Ten minute break!
Professor Hongou.
Is Ayuhara-san really going to quit volleyball?
Hmm.
I talked with her mother over the phone just a while ago.
It looks like she shut herself in her room.
But I can't believe that Chief could just let go of volleyball.
Ayuhara is serious.
It's just that she can't think about volleyball at the moment.
Either way, this is going to have great influence over Ayuhara's future.
Kozue will definitely come back to this court.
I can't imagine any other future for Kozue.
There's nothing left for me anymore.
Only memories of Tsutomu-kun.
Other than that, there's nothing at all…
Kozue-chan.
Oh, it's you, Auntie.
I'm not going to tell you to try and forget about Tsutomu.
But you're going to get sick
if you don't go outside.
Cheer up a little.
Okay?
Yeah…
Actually, I have some of his belongings with me.
I thought that it'd be better to give it to you.
Tsutomu-kun's diary?
Diary
Thank you, Auntie.
It may awaken some hurting memories…
…but I think you'll also find some happiness in there, even if it's just a little bit.
Thank you.
I'm sure Tsutomu would've liked it this way.
Tsutomu-kun's diary…
I'm pressing to my chest everything he didn't show to anyone until now.
Diary
This book holds all the memories of Tsutomu-kun.
With this, I can meet with Tsutomu-kun one more time.
"New Year's Day, 1970."
"I'm going to confess to myself."
"I'm in love with Ayuhara Kozue."
"In love"!?
But I'm not going to tell it to her…
…until she becomes the best attacker in the world.
The best attacker in the world!
World's Attack no. 1
Tsutomu-kun…!
These pictures and data are all about me!
He went this far?!
Through all of this just for me…?
At first, I was jealous.
Kozue-kun puts so much effort into volleyball
that there is no room for me to enter.
Around that time I hated volleyball from the bottom of my heart.
But I quickly realized that it was selfish and immature.
I have my dreams too, just like Kozue-kun has her volleyball.
I understood that…
…we have to devote ourselves to our talents for the sake of our futures.
What made me realize it was
how important volleyball is to Kozue-kun.
But also the pleasure I take in my work.
Right now, my biggest wish…
…is for Kozue-kun to become the best attacker in the world.
Tsutomu-kun.
I want to become the best
attacker in the world, too.
I want to become what you want me to be.
You supported me with
everything you had for this.
But…
To tell you the truth, Tsutomu-kun,
you overestimate me.
I don't have the talent it takes.
I lack the confidence, too.
Tsutomu-kun…
It's you, Toko-chan!
I went to your school but you weren't there!
You're not playing volleyball anymore, miss?
Huh?
Yeah.
Hey, miss, why don't you teach it to me?
Teach you volleyball?
Okay. If it's you, Toko-chan, I can teach it.
Really?
Thank you, miss!
I'll become the best attack player in the world!
The best attack player in the world…
I'm ready!
Okay, let's start.
Catch!
Are you okay, Toko-chan?
Throw again! Make it strong!
Okay.
I'm sorry, Toko-chan!
I said stronger!
Throw it stronger.
What are you doing? Here goes!
Kozue will come back for sure.
To this court. To our volleyball.
More, miss!
World's best attacker.
World's best attacker!
I'll become the best attacker in the world.
Miss?
This time it's miss's turn.
I'm not going to lose to you, Toko-chan!
Oh, miss!
I'll become the best attacker
in the world for you, Tsutomu-kun.
Watch me, Tsutomu-kun!
After the shock of Tsutomu's death,
Kozue turns away from volleyball at first.
But thanks to a little girl named Toko,
she regains her motivation.
Kozue returns to the court.
But what's waiting for her is a special training of the double attack that's even more intense than before.
Hongou says:
Your double attack had disappeared.
We must make disappear it once again.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.