苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 054—
The blind spot
I'll become the best attacker in the world.
For my Tsutomu-kun.
Watch me, Tsutomu-kun.
Kozue-kun! Do your best!
Tsutomu-kun!
Do your best!
Do your best…!
You can count on me, Tsutomu-kun.
You can count on me.
Kozue.
Where are you?
I can't receive your attack.
It's sad without you.
Hayakawa-san!
Hayakawa-san.
She's trying to replace Ayuhara-san, isn't she?
Yes.
That's a good intention, but it won't work out.
Why?
She's too annoyed.
Look at her.
There's a lot of useless movement, too much power.
As a result, she's tired already.
She must be thinking about Ayuhara-san.
Of course.
She's the one who asked Ayuhara not to stop volleyball and come back to the team.
No, I don't.
However, Tsutomu-san never yielded
to any situation, no matter how difficult it was.
No. The more difficult it was…
…the more motivated he was to face it and crush it.
Unlike you!
That's easy for you to say, Midori…
…since you and Mitamura-kun are both alive!
Kozue!
I'm sorry for this.
That was… way out of line.
Even I, your best friend, have my patience.
Fine.
Keep serving me any lectures you want.
There is no way for you to understand my feelings anyway.
Ayuhara refused Hayakawa's advice and left the club.
The two of them laughed and cried together until today. She's very confused.
Let's keep going, Hayakawa-san.
A player such as her is well aware of her own limits.
No matter how hard she tries,
she'll never be able to replace Ayuhara.
She's well aware of it.
It's no wonder she's so nervous.
Kozue.
Kozue!
I'm here, waiting for you!
However…
I believe in Ayuhara.
I'm confident she'll return to us.
But we have to go to Tōkyō in a few days.
I hope she comes back before we leave.
You make me worry so much.
I feel like slapping you again!
Midori!
Kozue…
She's here?!
Ayuhara-san!
I'm sorry for being late.
I was waiting for you.
I'm sorry, Midori.
I'm so glad, Ayuhara-san.
Yo! Welcome back!
We've been waiting for you!
Come on.
Yeah.
I'm sorry for all the trouble, Professor.
Alright! Save formalities for later.
We don't have much time.
Ayuhara. Hayakawa. Oonuma.
Get down to double attack practice immediately.
Yes sir!
Yes sir.
Y-Yes sir!
Let's start with the center double attack!
Yes sir!
It's the revival of the double attack!
No. The ball didn't disappear!
Huh?
Redo!
Yes sir!
Let's go!
Kozue!
No!
Huh?
That's not it, Ayuhara!
That's not it!
Remember how you scored the last point against Tenryū!
Remember the turmoil in Tenryū team
from when you launched that last double attack.
Last attack…
Last attack?
Time to finish this.
Now's our chance!
If it scores, Kozue can go!
Double attack!
Tsutomu-kun!
It disappeared!
The ball disappeared?
We're playing volleyball,
not doing some illusion tricks.
After the game I spoke with Captain Suga of the Tenryū team. Those were her words.
But it's strange how Ayuhara-san didn't notice it herself.
Tenryū's captain just trembled in fear facing the match point.
– Yeah.
– That's it.
No!
Suga is not the type
that can be intimidated so easily.
You should know it the best, having played against her!
Of course it was just an illusion.
But it must be a pretty good one
if it tricked a player like Suga.
My spike disappeared…?
Coach.
What is it?
Um… the trajectory of the ball in the double attack
is shaped like a triangle, right?
Yes.
Exactly.
Like this.
So?
The opposing team first has the horizontal line in sight.
But when Kozue attacks,
the ball suddenly moves vertically…
…and it seemingly disappears.
But that alone isn't enough
to make the ball vanish.
If that was the case, the ball would disappear every time.
Furthermore, you can see the ball all the better when it changes its direction.
Did you lose track of the chalk?
No. On the contrary, I saw it very well.
Then how did it vanish?
I'll explain it later.
What matters is that your vanishing attack
won us the match with Tenryū.
If you could do it once, you can repeat it.
Listen up.
We'll reproduce that game from the start.
Reproduce?
Ayuhara.
I need you to remember the whole thing.
Every detail.
Y-Yes sir.
Making her go through it again is very cruel…
Tsutomu-kun…
Tsutomu-kun.
Tsutomu-kun!
Right. Now, Oonuma tosses the ball.
Once more!
Do it again, Ayuhara!
Do you know what's lacking?
Your spike isn't nothing like back then.
Look at me!
You can't be emotional.
You're averting your eyes from Ichinose's death!
I'm not!
You are.
You're bringing your emotions onto the court.
I'm not!
Then let's begin again.
Reproduce that spike, this time without fail!
Yes sir.
What's with that attack?
It's nothing like Tenryū's attack.
Ayuhara-san, I know you can do better!
We're up against Tenryū!
Yes!
Vanishing spike.
Ayuhara!
Alright!
Assume position for the double attack!
Alright! We're Tenryū High School!
Let's show them how deadly we are!
We're up against Tenryū.
Tsutomu-kun!
Kozue! Get a grip!
Ayuhara! What on earth are you doing!?
Spike! Spike!
Kozue!
Kozue-kun.
Stop it, Tsutomu-kun!
I'm in the middle of practice.
I'm in the middle of practice!
What was that?!
Even an amateur could receive that spike!
Kozue! Abandon your emotions!
If the ball really did vanish,
it's a miracle brought upon by Tsutomu-kun!
Telling me to reproduce that is insensible.
It's heartless!
Kozue!
Ah, it went in!
All right, it's a tie!
Fujimi and Tenryū both have 16 points.
Continue!
Here, Oonuma-san…
Oonuma-san muttered to me…
"Leave it to us and go to the hospital."
I'll succeed.
Tsutomu-kun, please wait for me.
We won't lose to Fujimi High!
Go back!
Okay!
One!
Two!
Three!
One!
Two!
Three!
Now! Oonuma takes over!
Got it!
Hayakawa – spike!
If it scores, Kozue can go!
And now, the climax of that game!
Tsutomu-kun!
Kozue. You did it. You did it!
You died in that moment.
You passed away during that attack.
Tsutomu-kun…
Let me share what I think.
Vanishing attack is a special case of the double attack.
The fact that we discovered it in the last moment of the final with Tenryū was very favorable.
Ichinose-kun protected you.
The reason why it worked is that we still haven't fully developed the double attack.
Listen well.
At that time, Ayuhara was extremely confused.
But that worked to our favor.
Ayuhara's confusion caused her to change the attack pattern before it settled in for good.
That's how the vanishing attack was born.
Now onto the reason why the ball disappears.
Do you have any idea, Oonuma?
Nothing comes to my mind at all.
Not even a wild guess?
Humans are prone to optical illusions.
You know how our eyes
don't always see what they should.
Are you talking about a blind spot?
Yes.
You didn't sleep in biology classes.
The retina of the human eye has a spot that has no optic nerves at all.
It's called the blind spot.
Biology, now?
I can't follow you anymore.
Our brain works in a way that it complements what we can not see.
We only believe that we see it.
Normally it works out.
But that was not the case in the game against Tenryū.
The ball changed its direction at exactly the point where the blind spot of the entire team was.
That's the reason it looked as if it had disappeared.
But everyone looked at it.
No one said it's easy.
But when the movement changes from horizontal to vertical, the eyeball stops for a moment…
…and the chance that the ball gets into the blind spot is high.
What's next?
The ball vanishes.
Just like it did in our match against Tenryū.
Well, that's how the vanishing attack works.
It also explains why Suga couldn't see it,
while it looked normal to Ayuhara.
Now that we understand the science behind it, we can practice.
What do you think, Ayuhara?
Ah… Yes sir.
Great!
Then let's try to lock the ball in the blind spot.
Got it, girls?!
– Yes sir!
But it sounds tough.
Can we really do it?
Of course we can!
But it's too hard for me.
But with Ayuhara Kozue, who can't miss even a millimeter, we'll be fine. Right?
No.
That vanishing attack was a miracle.
Tsutomu-kun protected me.
It has nothing to do with science.
No way!
I can't do it!
There's no way I can.
It's not science.
I can't do it!
There's no way a ball can disappear.
Everyone's crazy. What are they thinking?!
They expect me to repeat that miracle…
To repeat Tsutomu-kun's gift to me…
"Do it again…"
"Complete it…"
I can't do it!
So stupid!
Everyone's stupid!
They think I'm some volleyball machine.
I'm just a girl!
I can't… I can't do it!
There's no way I make the ball vanish!
It's insane.
Tsutomu-kun…
Tsutomu-kun.
Tsutomu-kun!
The Yagisawa sisters of Jidōin High School. Kakinouchi from Fukuoka. Sanjou from Kanagawa.
Ayuhara-san and Hayakawa-san told me how good they were…
…when they played together in the junior national team.
We don't know what traps, what strategies
lie ahead of us at the Interhigh.
Then there's Aoba High School, which participates in the tournament for the first time.
We only know they have
a lot of outstanding spikers.
We don't lose in terms of outstanding players.
Huh?
Hehe.
What a faint, lonely smile.
Kozue never smiled like that before.
Ayuhara.
Don't look so sad.
I know you're trying to forget Ichinose,
but that's not enough to recover.
Life and death are inseparable.
You have to accept and get over it.
When you do so, you can make a big leap.
Get over it. Overcome death.
It's a painful challenge.
It's unbelievable.
However!
The vanishing attack isn't some romantic miracle.
Believe me.
Then complete it.
That's what's going to make you recover.
The vanishing attack is the way.
Attack.
Attack it!
Victory to Fujimi
Go! Go! Fujimi!
If you win, I'll date you!
Hayakawa-kun! Ayuhara-san! Do your best!
You can count on us, Mitamura-kun.
Great! Good to see you cheered up!
Mitamura-kun, it's all right already.
It's dangerous to run!
I'll be fine!
Hayakawa-kun, don't lose to Kozue-san.
Sure! I'll do my best!
Oops!
I told you!
I'm fine!
– Ah!
– I knew it.
I'm so happy.
About?
You need to ask?
Kozue, you look a lot better.
Seems like Mitamura-kun's energy got to you.
Looks like Tsutomu-san's ghost stopped haunting you, Kozue.
Weeping won't do us any good.
I'll give my best in the matches.
That's the spirit. Keep it up!
Keep your head high, Attack No. 1.
What should I do, Tsutomu-kun?
Vanishing attack… I can't even do double attack flawlessly.
I have to be strong before others, though.
I'm afraid I'll just freeze still on the court.
Kozue, I have no idea how to help you
other than pretending everything's fine.
Please, cheer up soon.
The tournament's just around the corner!
I must do what I have to do.
That's the way, right? Tsutomu-kun!
Kozue, tormented with memories of Tsutomu, is trying to pull herself together after his death.
She meets again with her friends from
the All-Japan team at the Interhigh tournament site.
This time, they stand on the opposite sides of the court.
Kozue's determined to complete Tsutomu's gift to her,
the vanishing attack. The first match begins.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.