苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 055—
Go for it! Interhigh
Tōkyō Shin-Yokohama Station
Tōkyō, huh…?
I feel so excited.
Interhigh…
Huh?
Tsutomu-kun!
Kozue, what's wrong?
No…
It's nothing.
Matsukaze Inn
Tsutomu-kun.
I'm still in pieces.
Now I'm seeing Tsutomu-kun's in strangers…
I bet Kozue is still thinking about Tsutomu-san.
Kozue, I won't tell you to forget him.
But moping forever won't do you any good.
I know. I'm sorry, Midori.
Matsukaze Inn
Fujimi High School Volleyball Club
All right then, Professor Shimizu.
I'm going to the Central Gymnasium for an administrative meeting.
– Okay.
– I'm leaving the rest to you.
Your students are sure full of energy.
Even though they just arrived here in Tōkyō.
They must be worried about the game.
What are you doing?!
There's plenty of lumber around here.
I told them to be a little bit more careful…
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
Here goes!
Captain!
Eh, out, again…
That bad, huh?
Yeah. I could totally see the ball.
Kozue. Don't push yourself too hard.
The training doesn't seem to produce any results.
Wouldn't you be better off if you gave up?
We're going to participate in the Interhigh.
We can't hope for luck alone.
Captain, you too?
Kozue. The vanishing ball was an illusion.
An illusion?
Yes.
It was a miracle.
A miracle?
Tsutomu-kun…
A miracle gift from Tsutomu-kun…
No.
Fine, so it was an illusion or a miracle.
But the ball did disappear once.
If it did so once, we can repeat it!
Welcome back!
Hello.
Listen up, girls.
The lineup for tomorrow has been decided.
– Really?
– Who are we playing against?
– Come on, tell us.
– I hope it's no one too strong.
The first match is Aoba Academy
from Chiba Prefecture.
The school that gathers outstanding attackers?
Oonuma.
Aoba Academy isn't any special in this regard.
Every team is excellent.
We have to be serious with every opponent.
I understand.
Isn't Aoba Academy that popular sports school?
Yes, it is.
It's a school that puts emphasis on sports and where it's fine to have poor grades in academic subjects.
Baseball, swimming, jūdō, finally volleyball.
They're rumored to be strong in any sports one can think of.
Yes. That's because they're recruiting
top players in the country and reinforce their talent.
It's no surprise they're strong.
I see.
But…
We'll be fine.
I'll think of a strategy first thing in the morning.
We have nothing to worry about.
Sorry for saying too much.
Our team is already dreaming of their big win.
Yes…
National High School Women's Volleyball Championship
Waiting room – Fujimi
Where are you going, Ishimatsu?
I'm going to spy on Aoba Academy for a bit.
You're going to get scolded.
Don't sweat it. Just keep it between us.
Ow!
Hey, watch where you're going!
Are you okay?
You looked away yourself.
We're sorry.
No problem, just be more careful next time.
What a tall person.
What happened here?
Wow. Maybe she's a college student?
She must be like 185 cm tall.
Yeah, that must be it.
Yamamoto-san!
Ah!
You're…!
Yes, I'm Shirakawa Teruko.
You were with us in the Japan Junior Volleyball Team.
That's right.
I was chosen for the national team,
and yet I gave in and fled the training camp.
I'm that coward from back then.
Coach!
Wait— Ah!
Coach! Please, stop it!
Please stop!
Stop!
No…!
No, I've had it!
I've had enough!
To hell with volleyball!
I escaped from you.
But I still didn't forget how miserable I felt back then.
I'm not holding a grudge against Coach Inokuma and his cruel training.
On the contrary, I didn't want to stay labeled as a loser for the rest of my life.
That's why I picked up volleyball once again.
Please watch me and see how far that coward went, Ayuhara-san.
Hayakawa-san, you too.
This means you're going to participate
in the tournament, right?
Yes. I'm with Aoba Academy.
Huh?
Aoba Academy?
But, if I remember right, you were from Gifu…
I transferred for the sake of volleyball.
Shirakawa-san.
I'm coming. Just a second.
She's not from college.
She's our captain, Yamamoto Misao-san.
She's their captain…?
See you soon!
So that's their captain.
I've heard she's a very famous attacker.
Yeah…
I heard it too.
We won't lose to them.
I'll go tell everyone!
Aoba Academy.
They're making me worry.
You mustn't think like that.
No, I didn't mean that.
I meant we need to come up with a proper strategy.
There she is!
Hayakawa-san!
Ayuhara-san!
Sanjou-san!
Ah, Kakinouchi-san!
– Long time no see!
– Finally.
– How have you been?
– You got all pretty.
Seeing us like that, I remember of America, the camp at Miyazaki and Coach Inokuma.
Yeah, yeah. But he went off to somewhere
after our matches in America.
He flew to some small country that had just started with volleyball.
That was so cool…
Actually, Coach is my older brother.
Huh…?
Huh!?
Kozue, you knew?
Hm? Yes.
Wow, that's cold. Why didn't you tell me?
It's a letter from my brother.
Let's see…
"Michiru, you're still playing volleyball
like we promised, are you?"
"If you participate in the Interhigh,
you'll meet your teammates from All-Japan."
"But this time, they'll be your opponents."
"Remember, your opponents aren't your enemies."
"The stronger your opponent is, the stronger you have to be."
"When you play against strong opponents…"
"…you can give your best shot and have a memorable sporting event."
"Best regards, from the far side of the ocean."
Yeah… It's like he says.
We won't lose.
Neither will we.
Well, if I were you, I'd wait to talk.
I'll pretend I didn't hear that.
Hehe.
By the way, apart from us,
Shirakawa Teruko from Gifu is also here.
Shirakawa?
Ah…
The one that dropped out
from the Miyazaki training camp.
Yes. But she's nothing like back then.
She's very motivated.
Yeah, she moved to Chiba and enrolled to Aoba Academy.
They're our first opponents today.
Aoba?
That sports school?
What do you mean, "sports school"?
It's a school that focuses on sports and gathers the best players from all over the country.
Exactly.
They invited me, too, but I refused.
A-Are they really that good?
I can't tell for sure, since the school is rather new.
But they do have a team full of first-class players.
What's up, Ayuhara-san?
You seem down.
Hm? No, it's nothing.
Yes. Kozue is a little tired, that's all.
She's in the spotlight all the time.
Ayuhara-san, don't tell me you're afraid of Aoba just because they're a popular sports school.
I'm not.
Then maybe a heartbreak?
Hah, as if.
Then all's good.
Ayuhara-san, Hayakawa-san.
Make sure you don't lose until we play together.
I pray for your success.
Yeah.
We do the same.
Good luck, Captain.
You too.
See you.
We'll watch your game.
Let's meet on the court.
Do your best!
This is going to be a tough tournament.
We cannot afford any mistakes.
We have to do our best.
We have to work hard!
We have to…
But I haven't mastered the vanishing ball yet…
Sports school, Aoba Academy…
Aoba Academy…
The Japan High School Women's Volleyball Tournament starts.
For four days, the best teams in the country
will aim for the title of Japan's best.
Hokkaidō · Fukuoka
Awesome. Kakinouchi-san's spike blooms wonderfully.
Yeah. Fukuoka will walk through this like a breeze.
Hokkaidō · Fukuoka
Kanagawa · Akiō
Sanjou-san's play seems to be on another level, too.
Her teamwork is splendid.
It's unlikely that block can be bypassed easily.
Sanjou! Good luck!
Ayuhara-san.
Ah, Captain.
Captain…
That Ishimatsu…
Running her mouth again about Aoba.
Going crazy now won't do us any good.
It's not like they can help it.
This is bad…
Kozue is nervous and the team can feel it.
We… We have to do something.
Please think of a way to ease her up.
Okay.
Get a grip already!
Is this how a team aiming for the top behaves?
If you get scared just because their captain is a bit tall…
…you're bound to lose even the simplest games!
Besides, Ishimatsu, what the heck are you doing,
undermining everyone's morale?
Kozue, just let it go.
While we're at it, there's something else I want to say about Aoba Academy.
Midori…
It's already the wildest rumors anyway,
so I think it's about time to speak the truth.
Only then we can create a fitting tactic how to play against them, don't you think?
That's right. Strange rumors won't do us any good.
Huh?
A sports school?
What does that even mean?
It's obvious they're strong.
Do Coach Hongou or Professor Shimizu know that?
There's no way they don't.
They're teachers after all.
Then why did they keep us in the dark until now?
Beats me.
Hey, Ayuhara-san.
If what Hayakawa-san says is true…
…then we have to come up with something as soon as possible.
It's too late to change anything.
Yes, it's too late.
We're playing in two hours.
There's nothing to be done.
We have to go along with it.
We just have to win.
Yes. Ayuhara-san nailed it.
We made it that far.
There's no reason to rush anything.
We need to obey Coach Hongou's instructions and fight with full power.
Precisely.
Have faith in Professor Hongou.
Professor Shimizu.
Now, the third match,
Jidōin vs. Shirane Senior High School has begun.
If you really aim for the top, you need to see that game.
You'll find that they aren't called the queens of volleyball in vain.
Shirane · Jidōin
I can't see who spiked the ball.
They move like ninjas.
10 to 0.
They completely control the match.
Unbelievable. They're even stronger than before.
That block…
We have to overcome that block.
I see Jidōin players aren't called queens for nothing.
Yes, just like we expected.
Before we can play with Jidōin, we must face Aoba Academy.
Please watch how far that coward went.
She's not from college.
She's our captain, Yamamoto Misao-san.
Don't tell me you're afraid of them just because they're a popular sports school.
Ayuhara-san, make sure you don't lose
until we play together.
The bond with your rivals is what makes both of you develop further.
Develop further…
I don't want to lose.
Rest in peace, Ichinose Tsutomu
I want Kozue-kun to become the world's best attacker.
What do you think?
Jidōin High School style is really impressive. Right, Ayuhara?
Hm? Ah, yes.
All teams of this tournament have probably set themselves the goal of beating Jidōin.
They're not conscious of it at all.
They're just focused on the match, full of confidence.
It's an attitude truly worth of a champion.
Wouldn't you agree?
Ayuhara
Time's up.
It's our turn.
Captain, I can't get out of my head what Coach Hongou said before…
Ah.
What did he say?
I'd like to ask all of you for a favor.
Please don't think about Aoba Academy.
Forget that they're a sports school.
I just want you to focus on the match
and give your best.
It's what Jidōin High School does.
Nothing more, nothing less.
If we focus on what's right, we can win.
I want you to remember that simple thing.
I want you to become the world's best attacker.
It all boils down to whether we can fight at our full power.
That's all there is to it.
I'm counting on you, girls.
Right.
Let's do our best.
Yeah.
Here they come.
Ah, Ayuhara-san, it's been long time.
Congratulations on your victory.
Have you gotten better at three player volleyball?
Thanks to you, we got a little better.
Promise us we'll meet in the finals.
All right.
You may rely on it.
I can't wait to see how good you got.
I'll watch your whole game from beginning to end.
See you later.
Jidōin High School won't cherish their champion title for much longer.
Professor…
Fujimi · Aoba
What are you doing, Ayuhara-san? That's not good!
Midori!
Double attack, right?
Fujimi · Aoba
What is this? They lead Fujimi by the nose.
It should've been the other way around.
For crying out loud.
They let them score another point…
Let's hold with judgment until after the game.
Fujimi · Aoba
We can't lose like this.
Tsutomu-kun, protect me!
Ah!
Tsutomu-kun!
Tsutomu-kun is the reason why I'm still on the court here today.
I'm sure he watches over me.
I'll show him a splendid double attack!
I'll show him the vanishing spike!
Midori! Double attack!
Kozue!
Here it is!
Tsutomu-kun!
Help… help me out!
You left me behind.
I need to live while you're gone!
Lend me your strength!
During the game against Aoba Academy, Kozue sees late Tsutomu's figure in the stands.
But the merciless attack of Yamamoto and Shirakawa continues on.
Fujimi finds itself in a tight spot.
"Tsutomu-kun watches over us."
"I have to win no matter what."
As Kozue is about to spike, a vision of Tsutomu emerges before her eyes.
Please next forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.