苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 056—
A living miracle
I returned to the court
to win the Interhigh tournament.
But we might lose in our very first match.
Tsutomu-kun.
I'm still not good enough.
Aoba High School, who won the first set,
leads in the second set as well.
Kozue.
Double attack.
Huh?
Tsu… Tsutomu-kun!
Kozue!
Attack!
It vanished!
It disappeared right before my eyes!
Fujimi High School's double attack!
Oonuma-Hayakawa-Ayuhara trio
makes an excellent play.
We did it, Kozue!
Thank you, Tsutomu-kun.
I won't lose.
Not when you're watching over me.
Fight!
Yeah!
All right, here goes nothing.
Kozue-kun!
Wait up!
Oh! Ayuhara's revolving receive!
Great, Fujimi!
Ayuhara-san!
Get a grip.
It's not like you, Kozue-kun.
Do your best, Kozue-kun!
Fight!
– Yeah.
– Fight.
Fight!
Fujimi · Aoba
It appeared that Fujimi High School, after losing
the first set, would lose the second one as well.
But thanks to Ayuhara Kozue's fierce attacks, point by point the tide has changed…
…and now it's a match point for Fujimi.
Attack!
Fujimi · Aoba
Fujimi High School wins the second set,
advancing to the final third set.
Will Fujimi be able to keep up that pace?
Is your wrist okay?
That's a good question.
No matter how strong your wrists are,
returning that spike directly was just reckless.
But I didn't return it directly.
I just knocked it down.
Thank you.
Ayuhara, looks like you've finally recovered.
Huh?
That last spike was calm and precise.
Am I right, Ayuhara?
You're slowly coming back into your usual rhythm.
You've overcome your grief, didn't you?
Yes.
We'll win through if we keep it up.
– Yeah.
– Yep.
Ahh.
Listen. First, focus on your usual rhythm.
Then make sure you respond to the tosser immediately.
When everyone gets the timing right, we can demonstrate the teamwork we've worked hard for.
No matter what they do,
we're not going to change our strategy.
Yamamoto – spike.
Everyone else – focus on receptions.
– Yes sir.
This is the way to best use our abilities.
We don't have another strategy against them.
Understood?
– Yes sir!
Aoba is a very strong team.
But looks like Fujimi regained their pace in the third set.
I'm glad.
Ayuhara-san was awesome in the second set.
She motivated the whole team.
Finally, the third set begins.
Fujimi · Aoba
We trained focusing on how to utilize Yamamoto's power to maximum.
I thought that would be the best strategy.
But looks like it doesn't work well in a team of six.
As a result, we're now going to lose against Fujimi.
But it will serve as a lesson for the next time.
Fujimi · Aoba
It's a match point for Fujimi.
– Okay.
– Yeah.
Good, good, good!
Ayuhara-san! Fujimi!
Fujimi · Aoba
Fujimi High School of Shizuoka prefecture,
defeats Aoba High School of Chiba prefecture…
…and advances to the second round.
– Thank you very much.
Ayuhara-san.
Let's meet again in the spring qualifiers.
Sure.
– Congratulations.
Shirakawa-san reception was great.
But it couldn't stand a chance against the Ayuhara-san · Hayakawa-san duo.
Thanks.
I'm curious which one of us
is going to advance to the finals?
Heh.
I think it'll be us.
Kozue and I are in the same team.
Basically, we have a double chance.
That's a strange logic.
– Yeah.
– I guess.
I see you haven't changed at all.
Huh?
Ah, that's…!
It's Tsutomu-kun.
Tsutomu-kun!
Kozue, what's wrong?
I'm not dreaming.
It really is Tsutomu-kun.
In the end, I wonder if I was seeing things again…
But I was so sure I saw him…
That'll be the first time I'll climb Mt. Fuji.
I climbed it just once when I was little.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I'm thinking so much about Tsutomu-kun.
Maybe that's the reason why
I saw him in the stands earlier.
Ah, that's no good.
Tomorrow's next match.
What am I doing?
I promised Tsutomu-kun to play splendid matches and continue playing volleyball forever.
I have to get over it.
Tsutomu-kun.
I'm sorry.
Ah!
Tsutomu-kun.
Tsutomu-kun!
Huh?
Did you call me?
Who are you?
Have we met before…?
I'm sorry, but I don't remember you at all.
I'm sorry.
I thought you were someone else.
My heart is still beating like crazy.
But who thought there could be someone that resembled Tsutomu-kun so much…
Like two peas in a pod.
Anyone could mistake him for Tsutomu-kun.
Yo!
Oh! Did I make you wait?
Damn right you did.
But after a closer look,
he doesn't resemble him that much.
Tsutomu-kun would never meet with that kind of girl after dark.
Tsutomu-kun living in my heart is a wonderful man.
Fujimi High School players' waiting room
Oh, dear.
The feeling after a game is always great.
Yeah!
Especially if you won.
Haha.
I heard Asahi is weaker than Aoba.
I guess we've got nothing to fear.
Yeah!
At this rate it's totally possible we'll win this through.
Of course we will.
Everyone of us does their best to get us to win, after all.
Kozue! Trouble!
Why are you in such a hurry, Midori?
Kakinouchi-san and Fukuoka High are in trouble.
Looks like their lose with zero points.
Huh?!
Who are they playing against?
It's Jidōin.
Chance ball!
Hey, Kozue.
Their trinity attack is even better than in that mock game back then, don't you think?
It's completely different in a real match.
Look in their eyes. They're obsessed with keeping their winning streak.
Jidōin · Fukuoka
Fukuoka scored zero in the first set, too.
It'll be a perfect victory at this rate.
Not even Kakinouchi-san's speed can counter that.
They go from reception to spike
in a blink of an eye.
I can't believe it.
Jidōin · Fukuoka
The Jidōin High School queens: Captain Yagisawa Kaori and her younger sisters Shizuka and Katsura…
…continue scoring into the second set with their lightning attack.
These three sisters are the top players in Jidōin.
It's like the three of them make up for the entire team.
Jidōin · Fukuoka
It's a set point for Jidōin.
Fukuoka High managed to get just two points
thanks to Kakinouchi's lucky spike.
Kakinouchi-san!
Jidōin wins with overwhelming strength and advances to the second round.
Let's go.
Kakinouchi-san.
Jidōin.
They don't even celebrate.
To them, victory is something obvious.
In order to win at Interhigh, we have to beat Jidōin.
I'll do my best. We can do this.
Kozue.
Huh?
What are you thinking about?
Nothing particular.
Oh? Sanjou-san.
Looks like Kakinouchi-san has lost.
Yes.
Will it be you or us who defeat Jidōin?
Tomorrow's semifinals will settle this.
We won't lose.
Neither will we.
Well the, let's meet in the semifinals.
Sure.
Sanjou-san is sure motivated, don't you think, Kozue
Yeah.
But suppose we advance to the finals.
Can we really win against Jidōin?
Midori, let's just focus on winning tomorrow's semifinals for now.
I'm looking forward to playing with Sanjou-san.
I heard that the volleyball club in Kōtoku,
Tōkyō's representative, was formed only this year.
Kanagawa should have no troubles.
I can't believe it! Look!
Wow…
Kōtoku · Kanagawa
They're losing 11 to 3.
But why? The game has just started.
How could they gain such lead in such short time?
Ah?!
That's the man from yesterday.
So he attends Kōtoku High School, too.
What a great serve.
Yes. It's pretty good, I'll give them that.
But is that really the reason as to why they gained such an enormous lead?
It's strange.
They have only two people targeted and yet they can't get control over the game.
They can't win like this.
Tōkyō's representative,
Kōtoku High School wins the first set.
Hang in there, Sanjou-san.
Ryuuji-san.
Hm?
See that girl standing in the passage over there?
That's Ayuhara of Fujimi High School.
Huh…
That's her?
Our captain and senior members kept making mistakes.
It's no wonder we lost so bad.
Don't you think?
It's over now. Regrets won't change anything.
But I'm frustrated.
Please play well in my stead tomorrow, Ayuhara-san.
Sure.
Well then, see you around.
See you.
Ayuhara-san.
There's a phone call for you.
A phone call?
I wonder who?
Hello? Ayuhara speaking.
Kozue-chan?
Tsutomu here.
Huh!?
Did I surprise you?
My name's Ryuuji.
Do I really resemble that Tsutomu-kun so much?
I'd like to learn what is he like.
Why don't you come to Yamato Shrine premises?
You're free, aren't you?
Huh?
To Yamato Shrine premises?
Yep. I'll be waiting there for you.
See you.
Yamato Shrine premises…
Kozue is asked by Ryuuji to discuss his resemblance to Tsutomu and she can't refuse.
Soon after, Fuji Youko appears before Kozue.
Youko shows Kozue a scandalous photograph with Coach Hongou.
She blackmails her to lose in the game tomorrow.
Confused Kozue asks Ryuuji for help.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.