苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 057—
A betrayal
Hello? Ayuhara speaking.
Kozue-chan?
Tsutomu here.
Huh!?
Did I surprise you?
My name's Ryuuji.
Do I really resemble that Tsutomu-kun so much?
I'd like to learn what is he like.
Why don't you come to Yamato Shrine premises?
You're free, aren't you?
Huh?
To Yamato Shrine premises?
Yep. I'll be waiting there for you.
Yamato Shrine premises…
Matsukaze Inn
Someone named Ryuuji-san wants to learn about Tsutomu-kun.
But what for?
Tsutomu-kun.
Just because he looks like Tsutomu-kun…
…I couldn't refuse his invitation.
Huh?!
Tsutomu-kun.
Tsutomu-kun!
Did you call me?
Who are you?
I don't think…
I'm sorry.
I thought you were someone else.
You're…
Yes.
I'm Kōtoku's captain, Fuji Youko.
Uhm…
I'm…
Former captain of the All-Japan's middle school team.
Fujimi High School's famous attacker, Ayuhara Kozue. Right?
I have heard a lot about you and wanted to talk to you face-to-face.
Talk to me?
How did you know I'd be here?
Hmph.
What does it matter?
Anyway.
Let's take a walk and have a little chat.
But…
You're waiting for someone, right?
Exactly.
It's no use.
Huh?
The person you're waiting for…
…won't come here.
What are you talking about?
How can you know that?
What on earth…?
That's a lot of questions.
Are you coming with me or not?
Give me a clear answer.
I don't have time to be here with you all day long, you know.
Let me say just this.
What I want to talk to you about…
…is really important to you and your volleyball club at Fujimi High School.
What will it be?
Really important to our volleyball club?
Really important to our volleyball club.
Really important to our volleyball club…
Listen carefully to what I have to say.
What is it so important to our club?
How did Fuji-san know about Ryuuji-san?
I have a bad feeling about this.
Hey, Fuji-san.
How further do we have to walk till you tell me what's going on?
Don't be so scared.
You're right.
I guess we can talk here privately.
Look at this.
Come on, come on.
Take a good look.
See?
Professor Hongou…
Professor Hongou…!
Hmm.
I don't want to underestimate Kōtoku High,
since they won so well against Kanagawa.
But, no matter how you look…
…their match was weird.
Kanagawa seemed to have no motivation from the start except for their two main players.
Something must have happened in their team.
I can't think of anything else.
However…
…we'll be fine.
Something like that won't happen to our team under any circumstances.
No matter what happens…
…once our girls stand on the court, they play with all they have.
I believe in Fujimi High.
Someone I know took that photo by chance near this shrine around midnight yesterday.
Professor Hongou wouldn't never touch a woman he barely knew like that.
It can't be.
Professor Hongou wouldn't do such thing.
This is nonsense.
This is bollocks!
You're such a baby.
You trust people so blindly.
Your professor is just another ordinary man.
Stuff like that happens from time to time.
Such a disgusting picture…
Things like that…
…can be treated only like this!
Who would need such thing!
It's disgusting.
It's filth.
It's filth!
Are you done already?
Save your breath, Ayuhara-san.
That was just a single photo.
I still have the negatives right here.
I can develop it how many times I want.
Fuji-san.
Why are you doing all this?
Do you even need to ask, Ayuhara-san?
All right.
Do you think you can win the game tomorrow after seeing this photo?
Fuji-san!
Are you telling us to lose on purpose?
In other words, you demand from me that I play a fixed game.
Don't be silly.
You misunderstood.
No one's telling you to play a fixed game.
I just asked whether you think you can win.
You're blackmailing us.
But we'll play like we always have.
It's just a photo.
So what if Professor Hongou dates someone?
It's none of my business,
or anyone's at Fujimi High's volleyball club.
Do you understand?!
What do you think is going to happen if I bring these negatives to a newspaper or magazine?
Huh?
"Fujimi High volleyball club's coach Hongou abandons his students to pick up girls at night."
I can already see the headlines.
It doesn't take a clairvoyant to figure out
he'd get fired on the spot.
I can even imagine your volleyball club being disbanded.
I… I can't believe it!
Are you going to win against us tomorrow,
or will you save your club and Professor Hongou?
Make up your mind fast.
I knew we'd reach an understanding.
With this, we're one step closer to winning through the Interhigh.
Now you did it!
The negatives!
Wha-What are you doing?!
Knock it off!
Wait!
Where are you going?
Hands off!
Ryuuji-san!
Ryuuji-san, please hand these negatives to me.
That girl is blackmailing me.
"Ryuuji-san."
"Please hand these negatives to me."
Let me try instead.
Ryuuji-san.
Please hand these negatives to me.
Ryuuji-san!
Youko.
Ryuuji-san, you're…
Yes.
He's a leader of delinquents from our school.
And a great volleyball fan, at that.
So you were partnered up.
Ryuuji-san was deceiving me from the beginning.
He used Tsutomu-kun to reach me…
Matsukaze Inn
We've sure came a long way.
Let's win tomorrow.
Let's give our best!
Yeah.
Dinner's going to be ready soon.
Eat to your hearts contents
and show me a good game tomorrow.
I can't see Ayuhara-san and Hayakawa-san with you, though…
Ayuhara-san got a phone call from someone similar to Tsutomu-san and went to the shrine downtown.
Someone similar to Tsutomu-san?
Hayakawa-san also received a call from someone and is out now.
Ayuhara-san…
Hayakawa-san too?
I see. Maybe she went to see some friends from Tōkyō.
We don't have to worry about them.
Yeah. They're different from me.
Damn right they are. Hehe.
Hey, that hurt.
Tell me about that Tsutomu.
What is he to you?
A lover? Or just a plain boyfriend?
Be quiet, Youko.
Wait, why?
Ayuhara Kozue is too difficult for you to handle.
If I had not come to help you,
we would have lost the negatives.
Let me warn you, Ayuhara.
You understand what's going to happen
if Fujimi wins tomorrow, don't you?
Keep that in mind.
Yes. Also…
If Fujimi wins, we'll mess up your pretty face a little bit.
I thought it was strange.
Sanjou-san's team must have been put under pressure as well.
We've trained so hard for this tournament…
…and now someone's telling us to lose it on purpose.
I can't believe it.
I don't care what happens to my face.
But…
But, that photo…
If that photo leaks out…
It doesn't take a clairvoyant to figure out
he'd get fired on the spot.
I can even imagine your volleyball club being disbanded.
Besides, it'd break Professor Shimizu's heart.
She likes him so much.
Professor Hongou! What have you done?
To think that he'd…
No, I still can't believe it.
You're such a baby.
You trust people so blindly.
Your professor is just another ordinary man.
Stuff like that happens from time to time.
What should I do?
Tsutomu-kun.
Tsutomu-kun…
Central Gymnasium
Today is the first semifinal match of the Interhigh volleyball tournament. The air is full of excitement.
The remaining four teams put up a fierce fight to advance to the finals.
The audience cheers their favorite teams loudly.
Especially Kōtoku High School, which wasn't expected to advance to the semifinals.
We can clearly hear enthusiastic cheers for their players all the way here.
Alright! Double attack!
Kōtoku · Fujimi
Contrary to most predictions, Kōtoku leads already 8 to 3.
Kōtoku, who yesterday defeated prestigious Kanagawa…
…today completely overwhelms the favorite for this match, Fujimi High School as well.
Oonuma just missed another Fuji's direct spike.
That last ball was by no means difficult to receive.
What's wrong, Fujimi?
The players look like they've almost given up.
It's no good.
Oonuma, Ayuhara, Hayakawa.
They're completely out of sync.
Here I go!
Don't mind, don't mind!
We'll get them this time!
– Yeah!
Nice! Nice!
Will it come?
The Fujimi's machine gun spike!
Damn!
Good, Ayuhara.
Keep it up, Ayuhara.
The others don't play any better than me.
What if they blackmailed not just me,
but Captain and Midori as well?
Hey, if I recall correctly…
That's a lot of questions.
Are you coming with me or not?
Give me a clear answer.
I don't have time to be here with you all day long, you know.
There's no mistake.
They blackmailed Captain and Midori, too.
We're going to lose.
At this rate we're going to lose it for sure!
Stupid Professor.
Stupid, stupid!
What was that look, Ayuhara?
It was filled with anger and hatred.
Ayuhara?
What happened to you?
Ayuhara. What's wrong?
Ayuhara! Tell me what's wrong!
No, it's not just Ayuhara.
Oonuma and Hayakawa have been looking here for a while.
What's with that look?
Does it have to do with your form today?
What on earth happened to you girls?
It's a set point for Kōtoku.
And a service!
Kōtoku effortlessly wins the first set.
Hayakawa, known to be an excellent receiver, gets three reception misses in the first set alone.
What's wrong, Hayakawa?
Get a grip!
Get a hold of yourself!
What's wrong with you?
Neither double attack nor machine gun attack work.
You can't even receive today.
You look like Kanagawa yesterday,
as if you were trying to lose on purpose.
What's wrong? Did anything happen?
Listen, and listen well.
I don't know what's happening in your heads.
But I believe in this.
In Fujimi High, no matter what happens…
…once you stand on the court, you play with all you have.
Oonuma.
Ayuhara.
Hayakawa.
Things outside volleyball are for after the game.
I believe in you.
You too, believe in me and fight.
Come on, now! Fight, fight!
What's wrong, Fujimi!?
Kōtoku · Fujimi
Ayuhara!
Get a grip!
The second set.
It's an one-sided game in Kōtoku's favor.
For the first time, Fujimi High School doesn't live up to its expectations.
Kōtoku · Fujimi
Fujimi is in danger.
You can do it! Become the best in Japan!
Ryuuji-san. You may look like Tsutomu-kun.
But on the inside you're nothing like him.
You dirty rat.
But I'm playing a fixed game myself.
I'm no better.
Save us, Naka! Ishimatsu!
I believe in this.
In Fujimi High, no matter what happens…
…once you stand on the court, you play with all you have.
Ayuhara-san!
Yay! That was pretty cool!
I want to play like that as well.
I don't want to play a fixed game.
Fujimi finally got the right to serve.
Will they take this opportunity to make their comeback?
I want to answer their cheering
from the bottom of my heart.
Things outside volleyball are for after the game.
I believe in you.
You too, believe in me and fight.
Professor. I want to believe in you.
I want to play to the best of my ability.
Ayuhara!
Fujimi!
Attack Number One.
Attack Number One!
Ayuhara-san, over to you!
I'll become the Attack Number One.
Tsutomu-kun.
Watch me!
Attack!
"This is my beloved court."
"A place where I play volleyball, sacrificing everything else."
"I can't betray this sacred place."
Kozue's anger against fixed game blew up.
Kozue's spike revives with the strength of Miyuki and Midori.
However, Kōtoku had already scored 11 points into the second set.
Can Kozue bring a turnaround?
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.