苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 058—
The decisive blow: vanishing attack
Central Gymnasium
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Contrary to most predictions, Kōtoku leads already 8 to 3.
Kōtoku, who yesterday defeated prestigious Kanagawa…
…today completely overwhelms the favorite for this match, Fujimi High School as well.
Oonuma just missed another Fuji's direct spike.
That last ball was by no means difficult to receive.
What's wrong, Fujimi?
The players look like they've almost given up.
It's no good.
Oonuma, Ayuhara, Hayakawa.
They're completely out of sync.
Here I go!
Don't mind, don't mind!
We'll get them this time!
– Yeah!
Nice! Nice!
Will it come?
The Fujimi's machine gun spike!
Damn!
Good, Ayuhara.
Keep it up, Ayuhara.
The others don't play any better than me.
What if they blackmailed not just me,
but Captain and Midori as well?
Ah!
Hey, if I recall correctly…
That's a lot of questions.
Are you coming with me or not?
Give me a clear answer.
I don't have time to be here with you all day long, you know.
There's no mistake.
They blackmailed Captain and Midori, too.
We're going to lose.
At this rate we're going to lose it for sure!
Stupid Professor.
Stupid, stupid!
What was that look, Ayuhara?
It was filled with anger and hatred.
Ayuhara. What happened to you?
I don't want to do it.
I can't imagine myself playing a fixed match.
That's as far as it goes.
Attack!
Damn! What is she thinking, that Ayuhara?!
Who does she think she is?
Ayuhara-san, do you know what happens if we win?
Kozue, don't.
Just like I suspected,
they threatened you, too.
I have decided.
I won't give in to their dirty tricks.
As if I could ever do such thing!
You want to break your promise to us?
You realize the consequences, right?
Stop it.
This is not the place nor the time for it.
But, Captain!
Cut them some slack.
It'd be a disaster if people knew this was a fixed game.
You should have changed your mind earlier.
It's too late for you to recover.
They can't have broken off the deal.
No one was ever brave enough to ignore my threat.
That serve just now was just a fluke.
Yes, that's got to be it!
Over to you, Midori!
T-They turned against us?
I-It can't be!
I can't believe it!
They really did!
This is my beloved court.
A place where I play volleyball, sacrificing everything else.
I can't betray this sacred place.
Looks like Ayuhara woke up from a deep slumber.
She throws one excellent spike after another.
Kōtoku · Fujimi
I take it that you want to drag your teacher into a scandal. Right?
Well?!
It can't be helped.
Huh?!
Very well.
Just don't say I didn't warn you.
Just see what happens.
Captain!
Only four points left!
All right! I'll help you!
Me too!
Oonuma-san's demeanor has changed.
Yes.
Whatever it was, they've recovered from it.
Then what was that until now?
Kozue!
Midori.
Captain.
We made it.
Yeah.
To think we actually tried to lose on purpose…!
There's no going back now.
We have to make our come back. Got it?
Let's show those scumbags what we're capable of.
Yeah!
Who would think…
Who would think they could fight back.
They're completely disregarding my intimidation.
Captain, it's strange.
What if they found out?
Of course they didn't.
That they got serious just shows they don't want to play a fixed game.
What if we try talking to them once more?
It won't work anymore.
Plus, the rest too motivated now.
Only four points left.
We'll just score them with our power alone.
After all, we're not some weaklings either.
Kōtoku · Fujimi
Damn it to hell.
They've become serious, too.
We have to do our best. Got it?
We'll be fine. You can count on us.
We won't lose!
Keep the serve!
How can they be so strong?
Volleyball.
I thought it was just some girls' game…
I never guessed it was such a serious business.
Kōtoku · Fujimi
Ayuhara throws marvelous spikes one after another.
Fujimi plays as if they were born again.
The tables have turned!
And now, a set point for Fujimi!
Kōtoku · Fujimi
The score is now 1 to 1.
The game continues into the third set.
I'd never have believed Ayuhara had such fighting spirit.
Alright, you're doing great!
Keep it up!
One last push!
Professor Hongou… Actually…
I'll listen to that later.
Right after you win the third set, that is.
Yes sir.
But be careful.
They've changed as well.
Listen up. We made it that far.
We can't let it go to waste.
Hit the ball like your life depends on it!
There is no other way for us to win.
Understand?!
Understood, Captain!
I'll play with all I have.
We will win for sure.
Just watch us!
Finally, the third set begins.
The server is Ishida from Fujimi High.
Ishimatsu! Give us a good serve!
Okay!
She did it!
Looks like the real match started just now.
Next one coming up!
Kōtoku · Fujimi
Fujimi's got unilateral lead.
I bet my butt they played a fixed game until now.
Don't you think?
Katsura, don't say weird stuff.
Both teams are trying their best.
Naka!
Sorry, it was just too strong.
Yeah, now that they know they have to win with their own strength, they got desperate.
Without their cowardly tricks,
they're just like a bunch of stray dogs.
Cowardly…?
Fine.
Let me show you the power of delinquents.
We have to win this set, no matter what!
Alright! Let's do it!
I won't let them make fun of us.
Exactly!
Good luck, Captain!
Strange. Youko looks different.
And not just her. Everyone.
Got it!
Captain…
Ayuhara-san, they've become really desperate.
Yes. We can't let our guard down.
Kōtoku
Having lost the lead, Kōtoku desperately hangs onto Fuji's strong serves.
Fujimi doesn't hold back.
Their performance has completely changed in the second set and now we observe a great comeback.
Kōtoku
Good!
Kōtoku barely scores a point.
We'll win.
We can win with our strength alone.
Kōtoku!
You can do it!
You're strong, and yet…
Why? Why did you blackmail us?
One more point! Let's show them!
Yeah!
What a motivation!
They're really on fire.
I can't believe they're the same people we played against in the first set.
Kozue, at this rate…
Let's go with double attack, Ayuhara-san.
Yeah!
Looks like Ayuhara-san has a plan.
Sis, it's their double attack.
A great technique.
It's something you must have devised after our last game.
Good going, Ayuhara-san.
Captain…!
Don't whine.
We won't lose to that technique.
Fujimi's team now brings the double attack into game.
But if the captain stays there,
there's no chance for the vanishing attack.
Kōtoku · Fujimi
Kōtoku gets quickly overwhelmed
by the still relatively unknown attack technique.
However, they're not ready to give up just yet.
She knows they can't win,
yet she refuses to give up.
It's as if she's a different person.
She forgot everything and focuses on volleyball…
Another double attack!
I want to try the vanishing attack no matter what.
If we only had the right conditions…
Hang in there, Kōtoku!
The sign for the double attack!
Kōtoku's captain is lined up with everyone else, standing in the right position.
It's the same as back then.
The vanishing attack succeeded for the first time in our game against Tenryū.
They're standing in the same formation.
Plus, Tenryū's captain, Suga, had similar posture and height.
"If we only had the right conditions."
Let's try this!
I've got this!
Kozue!
Attack!
– It's gone?!
– It vanished!
Kōtoku · Fujimi
I did it.
Given right conditions,
I can do the vanishing attack!
– You did it!
– Chief!
I'm so glad.
I won. I won…
Promise is a promise.
I won't let it end like this.
In the end, they focused only on attacks.
Yeah. It won't be too much of a problem for us.
With the lightning attack,
we've practically already won.
Don't let your guard down, though.
Have you seen the look on Kōtoku's faces in the last action?
They might've done something we couldn't see from afar.
Waiting room
Fujimi High School
What is it that you wanted to tell me?
Yeah.
Oonuma.
Sir.
Why did you agree to play a fixed game?
A fixed game…?
The truth is, the three of us got blackmailed.
Why didn't you tell me before?
Because…
We couldn't tell you about it.
Why couldn't you, now?
Actually…
U-Uhm…
It's about this. We were told they'll publish this in weekly magazines.
Professor Hongou!?
That's all?
Can you explain more?
It was taken when you took a night walk in the park the day before yesterday.
Can't you see it's just a poor photomontage?
It's a fake photograph you make by combining two photos.
I haven't stepped outside the inn the day before yesterday.
Yes. I can vouch for that.
I see. So that's how it was!
So, this means…
You three doubted Professor Hongou?
You made fools of yourselves. Get a grip.
We're sorry.
I know the tournament is tough, but to think that it takes this much to shake you up…
Oonuma. Ayuhara. Hayakawa.
It's not like you.
You need to stay calm.
If you don't,
Jidōin will beat you to a pulp.
Understood, sir.
He's right on mark.
We lost our composure.
What were we thinking?
But do you suppose Kōtoku will let it go just like that?
It'll be fine.
If they come to us with more bull,
we won't keep silent either.
Ayuhara-san.
Thank you for the match.
We need to talk about Ryuuji.
Let's meet at 6 o'clock near Yamato Shrine.
See you.
What did she want?
Did she say anything to you?
Nah, it's nothing.
"We've completely lost", just that.
Oh? What a let down.
They might be not that bad after all.
Yeah.
It's strange.
I don't feel any grudge towards Ayuhara Kozue.
On the contrary, I feel like praising her.
Even though she ruined our plan.
I didn't know volleyball was so fun.
Yeah. I got super absorbed at the end.
Hey, why don't we play more seriously?
– Agreed.
– I'm in.
What do you say, Captain?
Don't we have something to do before that?
You still want to do it?
Why don't we let them go?
It's not like anything's going to change.
Yeah, yeah…
Do you expect me to pull back now?
Thanks to that Ayuhara, all of our hard work so far went down the drain.
You have a point.
But winning the Interhigh
was too high a bar to begin with.
And yet we made it that far.
I can't look in Ryuuji's face after he lend us a hand.
But the match is over.
Ryuuji-san will surely understand this, too.
Alright, fine.
Forget it.
I won't ask you for help anymore.
I'll clean this up myself.
Where are you going, Kozue?
Huh?
Oh, I'll be right back.
Yo.
Ah, it's you, Ryuuji-san.
You were quite strong. I was surprised.
By the way, where's Youko?
She went to have a chat with Ayuhara.
You sure about that?
Where?!
Yamato Shrine
What did you want to talk to me about?
Don't play innocent.
Did you think we'll keep silent if you make fun of us?
Why doesn't it surprise me.
I hope you're ready.
Huh? She's gone?
Thanks!
Who was it?
He didn't tell me his name.
But I feel like it was this whole Ryuuji.
I'm not sure why, but he sounded like he was in a hurry.
Ah!
Maybe Kōtoku's captain…
Huh?
What about Kōtoku's captain?
I bet my arm they're at the shrine.
Why did you go as far as blackmailing us?
You are a very powerful team to begin with, so why?
It's none of your business.
A princess like you wouldn't understand.
Hmph.
We have our public image.
I wanted us to win no matter what.
Everyone keeps yapping, "delinquents", "delinquents".
I wanted them to see us in a different light for once.
And here…
You… broke your promise to us.
W-What are you doing?
My position will be gone because of you.
I'll mess up your pretty face!
No! Stop!
Good girl.
Stop!
It's over.
It's disgraceful.
Ryuuji! Aren't you frustrated we lost!?
I am.
But…
The game's over.
Let it go.
Learn how to lose, Youko.
Ryuuji!
Everyone's waiting for us.
I'll go with you in a sec.
Thank you.
You saved me.
You are really brave.
Kozue!
What happened, Ayuhara-san?
Don't be so distant!
Why didn't you tell us?
I'm sorry.
What happened here?
Ryuuji-san!
Lightning attack.
What?
It's the new weapon that the three Yagisawa sisters of Jidōin have created.
It's a terrible technique that combines the "trinity" with the "plus alpha".
Be careful.
That's all.
Even so, we didn't know it at all.
This is very useful.
Yeah.
The trinity is by itself difficult to deal with.
But it's "plus alpha"…
Eh, one problem after another…
Don't be so disheartened.
We have to think of something.
Captain, Midori.
I think I came up with something.
A way to counter it?
I'll gladly help.
We have no time to waste.
Let's head back.
Yeah.
Lightning attack.
Thank you, Ryuuji-san.
But in the final game,
we just have to do whatever it takes.
Although they won the semifinals…
…they learned Jidōin is going to use a fearsome unknown technique, the "lightning attack".
However, Coach Hongou doesn't have any countermeasure against it.
A semifinal match between Jidōin and Tōnan begins.
Kozue stares with full concentration,
but she can't see through it.
She approaches Ryuuji
in search of more information.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.