苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 059—
The ominous lightning attack
Kozue!
What happened, Ayuhara-san?
Don't be so distant!
Why didn't you tell us?
I'm sorry.
What happened here?
Ryuuji-san!
Lightning attack.
What?
It's the new weapon that the three Yagisawa sisters of Jidōin have created.
It's a terrible technique that combines the "trinity" with the "plus alpha".
Be careful.
Huh? Seems that's it.
Even so, we didn't know it at all.
This is very useful.
Yeah.
The trinity is by itself difficult to deal with.
But it's "plus alpha"…
Eh, one problem after another…
Don't be so disheartened.
We have to think of something.
Captain, Midori.
I think I came up with something.
A way to counter it?
I'll gladly help.
We have no time to waste.
Let's head back.
Yeah.
Lightning attack.
Thank you, Ryuuji-san.
But in the final game,
we just have to do whatever it takes.
"Lightning attack"?
Hmm.
Regretfully, I must say
I have no idea what it is.
I don't know if they're going to show it
in tomorrow's semifinals with Tōnan either.
But even though we don't know anything,
it doesn't mean we have to be scared.
Jidōin may have their lightning attack,
but we have our vanishing attack.
But Coach, we've already shown them our
vanishing attack in today's match against Kōtoku.
If we only had the right conditions…
Let's try this!
It's gone?!
Kōtoku · Fujimi
The sisters looked at us like a predator
observing its prey back then.
We did show them,
but there's nothing to worry about.
– Huh?
The vanishing attack works because the ball is put
in blind spots of the opponent team's players.
That's to say, to other people,
it looks like an ordinary spike.
See what I'm getting at?
I understand.
Even a simpleton like me
can understand your explanation.
Listen.
As I said, we have our vanishing attack
against their lightning attack…
…and we'll counter their trinity attack
with our double attack.
We'll play in the finals
the day after tomorrow without fear.
– Yes sir!
The double attack is our main weapon
against the Yagisawa sisters.
However, I'm afraid it won't be enough.
I agree.
If she could do the vanishing attack on demand…
…combined with the double attack,
we could stand a chance against them.
But the vanishing attack isn't yet complete.
So if I understand correctly, the vanishing and double attacks are on par with the trinity attack.
Exactly.
But if you add the lightning attack to the equation…
Lightning attack.
Lightning attack…
Just what is it like?
Jidōin · Tōnan
They did it again, Sis!
Calm down, calm down.
There's nothing to worry about.
Which team is going to win
and face Fujimi in the finals tomorrow?
Jidōin and Tōnan are going head to head,
fighting for a single point of advantage.
Go! Go! Tōnan!
Let's go.
Got it!
The match has just begun!
Alright, girls!
Don't miss any ball! Let's get them!
Yeah!
Got it!
Is the Yagisawa sisters' splendid spike
going to earn Jidōin consecutive victory?
Tōnan's Captain Higaki's and Akizuki's blazing duo
responds well with their delayed attack.
Jidōin · Tōnan
For the first time someone puts up
a decent fight against Jidōin's queens.
At this point it's hard to make any guesses
as to who's going to win.
Tōnan gains lead.
Excellent work of Higaki·Akizuki duo.
Their jumping power is something.
Especially Akizuki-san's.
They jump so lightly and high,
just like high-jump pros.
They can aim at the back from that height.
Even Jidōin can't defend against that.
The more I keep watching, the more I feel maybe it's Tōnan we're gonna play tomorrow against.
Hmm.
Aiming at the back when the sisters
are at the front is a good idea, all right.
But if any one of them were to fall back,
the delayed attack wouldn't work anymore.
Figures.
Huh? Why?
Jidōin · Tōnan
Higaki·Akizuki's delayed attack earns Tōnan another point.
Time!
Jidōin called a time out.
Who knew Tōnan would be able to hold their ground so well.
Well, remember how they're using a computer
to analyze the movements of the opponent team.
So not even a champion
can compete against a computer…
Computer?
That's why they're so strong.
Geez, even hearing the word "computer" makes my head hurt.
But can their computer
see through the trinity attack?
Trinity attack…
Now that you mention it, they didn't show it yet.
The real match starts now.
Understood, sir.
Let's do this!
Trinity attack.
Hang in there, Tōnan!
If I had to guess, the sisters are going
to show us the lightning attack now.
I have to watch it closely.
Ready?!
Okay! Shift!
Oh! Tōnan has changed
the lineup to receive the ball!
Here it is! Jidōin's trinity attack!
Take a good look, Ayuhara.
This perfect S-shaped formation must be
the result of computer analysis of the trinity attack.
It lets them to receive the spike
no matter where it lands.
Brilliant Yagisawa sisters' diversion.
They found an opening in Tōnan's formation
made specifically to counter their trinity attack!
I thought the trinity attack was all about spike…
Everyone at Tōnan must've been thinking likewise.
The sisters saw through it in an instant.
Not just that, they outsmarted it with a feint…
They're really fearsome.
I have to say, it's surprising.
That S-shaped formation
suggested by the computer…
You'd think it should be much more effective.
It shows that you can't always rely on the computer.
Not even a state-of-the-art computer
can compete with the minds of the Yagisawa sisters.
Jidōin · Tōnan
Don't sweat it!
The tide has turned!
Tōnan's S-shaped formation is powerless.
Jidōin uses the crushed morale
to continue its fierce attack.
Say, Kozue, why didn't Jidōin use the trinity attack
right from the start if it's so effective?
Jidōin is well aware that we're watching them play.
If possible, they wanted
to save it for the finals tomorrow.
Jidōin is almost certainly going to win this match.
Then tomorrow we'll finally face
the trinity, as well as the lightning attack!
They're getting squished like bugs.
Are we going to end up like them?
We have to do something!
Great, Jidōin!
Finally, Jidōin wins the first set leading by 8 points.
You can do this!
Professor!
I'm going to see with Ryuuji-san.
– Huh?
I'd like to ask him more about the lightning attack.
Fuji-san!
Huh?
I was just looking for you.
Fuji-san, please tell me where Ryuuji-san lives.
Ryuuji's address?
What business do you have with him?
What business…
I see it's something you'd rather not tell me.
In that case, I can't tell you.
Fine, have it your way.
I'll just call Kōtoku High and get Ryuuji-san's address from them.
What good is his address, if he's not home now?
What are you doing?
What the heck?!
That was…
Kōtoku's captain, Fuji Youko.
Don't tell me something happened again?
Hey, hands off me!
If you don't knock it off, I'll get mad, you know.
I want to know more of the lightning attack.
Lightning attack…?
What is that?
Jidōin's new secret weapon.
Ryuuji-san told me about it yesterday.
Ah.
Ryuuji went to spy on Jidōin yesterday.
He must've heard that name back then.
But just what is it?
Come with me.
Ayuhara-san!
Jidōin's serve.
Tōnan's reception.
Akizuki passes.
Higaki jumps!
It's the delayed attack!
Jidōin blocks!
It's Tōnan's turn to attack.
Reception. Ah! The ball flies over the net at Jidōin's site.
They receive it easily. Pass.
The sisters jump!
And a spike!
Jidōin · Tōnan
Tōnan didn't receive.
Yet again the trinity attack gains a point.
Jidōin completely controls the game.
What are they doing?
You can do better! Show us something great!
Shut your traps.
I can't hear them.
The second set has just begun
and it's already 5:0 for Jidōin.
Yo.
Hm?
A-Ah! You're…
Thank you for yesterday.
Are you making fun of me?
No, I didn't mean it like that…
Ryuuji, she's here to hear more about the lightning attack you told her about.
So, will you tell her?
What is this "lightning attack"?
I'm turning the TV off.
Please.
Hmm…
Please!
Ten to one that Jidōin will advance to tomorrow's finals.
Ryuuji-san, you're the only one
who knows about their lightning attack.
Please tell us how it looks like.
Trust me, I'd like to tell you.
Unfortunately, I don't know anything apart from what I wrote on that note.
I planned to intimidate Jidōin.
I had to collect some information first, so I went to spy on them and heard them say this phrase.
Do you want to know exactly they've said?
Yes.
"Lightning attack developed from the trinity attack."
"With that, we don't have to worry about Fujimi."
I must've thrown you off balance by telling you about this unknown technique just before the finals.
Oh, no, not at all.
In brawling, before we fight, we ought to know the strengths and weaknesses of our opponents.
The secret is to strike first.
Before your opponent gets to show their worth, you're like "whack…!"
…and knock them out before they know it.
But I guess it's pointless to explain the fighting techniques to you girls.
Strange, I feel like I've heard somewhere something similar to what he's just said.
But where?
Where?
I'm sorry, my tips won't be of much use to you.
Ah, right!
Thank you very much!
Huh?
Oh.
I knew I've heard somewhere something similar.
Now I know where.
If one was able to give such rotation to a volleyball…
But a volleyball is nowhere as lightweight as a tennis ball.
Of course!
We have to give it rotation twice like in the double attack.
Notes from the games that Tsutomu-kun has left behind.
Found it. This is it!
"In today's game, the Fujimi team had kept the ball on their side for too long."
"The Fujimi team had been too slow to interchange the ball with each other."
"Meanwhile, the opponents recovered again."
"All in all, Fujimi should have played more direct spikes."
Direct spikes…
Direct spikes.
Ah!
Knock them down with direct spikes before they unleash their trinity and lightning attacks.
If we do so, even Jidōin won't be able to score too much.
Direct spikes.
Direct spikes!
Another spike!
And it's a point.
Jidōin · Tōnan
Jidōin achieves overwhelming victory with Tōnan.
Tomorrow's final match is between Jidōin team from Ōsaka and Shizuoka's representative, Fujimi.
Ah! Ayuhara-san!
Oh, it's you, Captain.
I came up with a attack involving double spin.
Double spin attack?
Captain, I also came up with something.
We should serve more direct spikes.
Serve more direct spikes…?
Yeah.
Tomorrow's Interhigh decides who's the best in Japan.
Will Jidōin keep their record?
Or will the debuting Fujimi surprise us?
We look forward to see the battle between both teams.
Yes.
Double-spin attack.
More direct spike serves…
What do you think, Professor?
Whether these ideas prove useful against Jidōin depends on your training.
The finals are tomorrow.
Let's practice as long as we can!
– Yeah!
Professor Hongou.
Yes?
Why do you let them play so late?
What if they overdo it and exhaust themselves?
No, no.
Even if I told them to stop, they wouldn't listen.
They're just not that kind of girls.
Double-spin attack and direct spike serves.
They keep at it until the very last minute.
Oonuma. Takeichi. Ayuhara. Hayakawa. Nakazawa. Ishida.
You're all wonderfully motivated.
I'm so proud of you.
Trinity and lightning attacks.
I won't lose.
If I want to win… If I want to become
the best attacker in the world, I have to win!
I have to win!
Semifinal second game.
The confrontation between Jidōin and Tōnan…
…as expected, reveals Jidōin's overwhelming strength and ends up with their victory.
Kozue thinks:
"To win, we must break the Yagisawa sisters'
trinity attack no matter what."
New fears and uneasiness rise up in Kozue's heart.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.