苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 060—
The wheel-chaired supervisor
Matsukaze Inn
Finally, it's match point.
Jidōin is only one step away
from advancing to the finals.
Good going, Jidōin!
Tōnan · Jidōin
The Yagisawa sisters are on the front line.
Will they show us
their signature trinity attack?
Tōnan · Jidōin
Jidōin achieves an overwhelming
victory with Tōnan.
Tomorrow's final match is between Jidōin team
from Ōsaka and Shizuoka's representative, Fujimi.
No matter what, we have to break
the trinity attack. If not, we lose.
Everything is depending on this.
Fujimi High School Volleyball Club
Can't you tell them
to rest up before tomorrow?
Kozue!
I mean, I can't blame them
because of the finals tomorrow.
But wouldn't it be better
if they conserved their energy?
No, let them play.
Everyone is trying out their skills.
Hm?
They're all well aware
of how strong Jidōin is.
They also don't really know
how to counter that fearsome power.
That's why they're trying to give it one last push
and figure something out.
To each their own.
Serve as hard as you can.
Don't give up the ball to the Yagisawa sisters.
Sure.
That's not it.
Maybe it won't work.
I'm sorry.
Let me try one more time.
You did it!
Yeah. You see…
The curve ball spike that Oonuma and Ayuhara
are practicing could become a great technique.
But techniques that succeed only
2 or 3 out of 10 times can't be decisive.
It's similar to the vanishing attack.
They're not able to perform that every time either.
Yes… Also, it's possible
it might not vanish after all.
Huh? What do you mean?
Are you saying the vanishing attack
won't work against the Yagisawa sisters?
Well, I'm still not sure.
But I have to take that possibility
into consideration.
So how do you think we should play
in the game tomorrow?
I don't know.
Just like everyone else,
Professor…?
Curve ball serves.
Machine gun attack. Double attack.
Finally, that double-spin spike.
We have no way to test
how effective those techniques will be.
The Yagisawa sisters of Jidōin
are certainly too strong.
But I suppose it doesn't matter.
We have to hit them with everything we have.
Fujimi High School Volleyball Club
I hope it goes well tomorrow.
Yeah.
– We're back.
Oonuma.
Sir?
I know there's no point telling you
not to think about tomorrow…
…but try to at least
get a good night's sleep.
Aren't we going to hold a meeting?
Huh?
No, that's it for today.
After dinner, you have
the evening to yourselves.
You can go for a walk
or just go to bed if you want.
Everyone can do as they please.
Gather your strength for tomorrow.
Yes sir.
Where is Kozue?
Oh.
Now that you mention it,
she didn't come with us.
I thought she went with us.
I wonder where she is?
I'll go look for her.
It's no use.
It's impossible to give it
the necessary force by myself.
It's just not going to work unless two people
give it the proper rotation after all…
Chief!
You're still out here?
It'll be very difficult for Oonuma-san
to toss it perfectly every time.
Chief…?
Tomorrow is the finals with Jidōin.
I have to find a technique that'll guarantee
us a win against the Yagisawa sisters.
I see where you're coming from,
but don't overdo it, okay?
Yeah.
I know.
Even Professor Hongou told us
to get a good night's sleep.
Yeah.
Just a little longer.
Chief…
You're going that far?
Alright, Chief.
You have me by your side.
I wouldn't forgive myself
if I let her practice here by herself.
Don't worry, I'll help you out, Chief!
Thanks, Naka!
I'm ready!
Chief!
I'll receive your spike.
Jidōin's nothing!
Strike, strike, strike all you can, Chief!
The Yagisawa sisters can kiss our butts!
Here I go!
Yeah!
One more time!
It'll be easy for them
to return the ball.
She has to give it more rotation.
Next one!
Sure!
No, no, no!
That's not it!
Try to hit it stronger
and rotate it faster!
Alright!
Naka!
Nakazawa!
Are you okay?!
University Clinical Hospital
I'm sorry, Professor.
We shouldn't have been
training so late at night.
No, no.
I'm responsible.
I didn't stop you.
You were so focused
I just couldn't tell you to stop.
How is she?
She hasn't broken any bones.
But her thigh bone is fractured.
Professor…
She'll be fine.
But she shouldn't push herself for a while.
She'll get better with time if she doesn't.
Thank goodness.
But, because she was struck in the chest,
she'll need to go through precise examination.
She'll have to stay in the hospital
for a while, it seems.
I see.
I'll stay with her.
You two should head back to the inn.
Everyone's waiting to hear the news.
Well then, I'll leave it to you.
Professor, can I stay here
for a little bit, too?
Oh?
Ah, sure thing.
But don't be too late.
– Yes sir.
– Bye.
Chief.
Naka…
Naka, I'm sorry.
You must be aching all over.
No, it's okay.
But it sucks I won't be able
to see the finals tomorrow.
Naka…
I injured myself.
It's not anyone's fault.
On the contrary, I feel bad for making
everyone worry and take care of me.
I don't know what to say…
Chief…
Hey, Chief.
Good luck tomorrow.
Do your best in my place, too!
"Chief"?
Nakazawa-san, why do you
keep calling her "Chief"?
Cause everyone called her that
in the middle school.
Heh.
Right, Chief?
Yeah, but please,
stop calling me that.
Heh, okay.
Ah?
That man is the coach
from the Jidōin High School.
I saw him sitting on the bench
during the matches.
But who is that woman
in the wheelchair?
Huh? The Yagisawa sisters!?
That means she's…
What was today's match
supposed to be?
Is this how Jidōin plays? Jidōin that has a track
record of 3 consecutive victories at the Interhigh.
But… we won in an overwhelming victory
for the semifinals against the Tōnan team today.
Don't be so arrogant.
Do you think you can fool me?
I can see your matches
no matter where I am.
Listen well.
Your last opponent in the finals
is Shizuoka's representative, Fujimi High School.
If you think you can beat Fujimi
in your present state, you're in for a surprise.
But we've played a 3 vs. 3 match
with them before and they lost.
You stupid girl!
Volleyball isn't played with three people.
It's played between teams of six.
Besides… Higashida-san.
Yes?
Don't you think it was shameful?
I'm talking about that
three-players match with Fujimi.
We won, fine.
But we've also just shown them our trump card.
That wasn't very smart, don't you think?
Yes, I apologize.
I didn't think of it that way…
It's fine, Higashida-san.
It's not your fault anyway.
The one who deserves scolding
are these three hotheads right here.
Think before you act!
You may have beat Fujimi once.
But that just means they're
even more motivated to beat you.
I'm sure they're going
through special training.
That's the problem here.
We can't rely solely
on the trinity attack.
We need something
stronger and faster.
Something they won't see coming.
"Something stronger and faster
than the trinity attack…"
You understand?
Then let's get down to training right away.
– Yes!
Let's start!
Stop.
That was disgraceful.
You are completely disorganized.
Just look where you stand.
That pitiful display
can't be the trinity attack.
You won't fool
your opponent's block with that.
Listen closely.
What's most important is breathing.
Inhale and exhale slowly.
You have to stay calm and not lose focus,
not even for a second.
Do it again.
Continue, continue!
Yes!
That movement…
it's different from the trinity attack.
But I can't really say how.
What is the purpose of this change?
What if that's the "lightning attack"?!
Hm, you're getting
somewhat better.
Katsura.
Yes?
Your breathing is still not in sync
with Kaori's and Shizuka's.
Try to match it.
Okay.
Look, you're exhaling
too fast near the end.
Exhale more normally,
more calmly!
Supervisor…
You seem tired.
It'd be terrible if anything bad happened.
I think we should call it a day.
I'm fine, don't worry.
Alright, try it again.
Yes!
Oh!
Hang in there!
– Mom! – Mom!
– Are you okay?!
Please wake up!
– Mom! What's wrong?!
– Supervisor!
– Don't die, Mom!
– Are you okay?
– Mom!
– Supervisor!
So that's the Jidōin
High School's supervisor…?
But it looks like she's also
the Yagisawa sisters' mother.
That's who the woman
on the wheelchair was…
Medical Office
Doctor! Please come with me!
– Hang in there!
– Mom!
Mom…
Mom, don't die on us!
What… What's the fuss?
Why are you crying?
I'll be fine.
I'm not going anywhere.
Katsura, what's with you?
I don't remember
raising you to be so weak.
Mom…
Your mom isn't going to die.
I have to see the tomorrow's finals.
I can't leave you alone at this time.
Do your best tomorrow.
Yes…
Higashida-san,
I'll leave matters in your hands.
Y-Yes ma'am…
Yagisawa-san!
I told you she shouldn't push it.
Don't you understand
what you're told?
I'm sorry.
She just wouldn't listen to me.
I can't vouch for her stability
if this continues.
Let's get you back
to your room quickly.
Is Mom going to die
once the match tomorrow is over?
Katsura, what the hell
are you talking about?!
Don't be stupid!
But…
All we can do
is do our best in tomorrow's game.
That's all there is to it.
– Yeah.
Now, let's give it one last push.
Okay?
Please stop.
Ayuhara-san of the Fujimi High, right?
I've heard a lot about you.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Ayuhara Kozue of Fujimi High School.
She's the girl
who called me over.
You called the doctor over?
I'm sorry for the trouble.
No, I apologize for watching
your training without consent.
That doesn't matter.
Don't worry about it.
Ayuhara-san, I have a request for you. Promise me
you'll give tomorrow's game everything you've got.
I will.
As you've seen, my girls
are one hundred percent motivated.
I'm sure they'll fight like the devil.
Ayuhara-san.
I look forward
to seeing a great game.
Alright, let's start!
Have the girls returned to their dorm?
Yes.
You go, too.
We have an important match tomorrow.
No, I'll stay here.
Higashida-san.
I'm counting on you tomorrow.
No, not just tomorrow.
I entrust the future of the team to you.
I know you'll do well.
I can be at ease.
You can handle things in my place.
I can die at peace now.
What are you talking about, Supervisor?
You should get well
and continue to watch over the team.
No.
There's nothing
I can teach them anymore.
Supervisor…
You taught them all they need.
Alright, here goes.
Are you ready?
– Yes!
Kaori, Shizuka!
Try to receive the ball!
– Yes!
Ball.
Kaori!
Now you, Shizuka!
Get a grip, you two!
Katsura.
My cute little thing.
Come here.
Higashida-san,
I'm leaving them in your hands.
Okay. But…
Hurry up and go.
The team is waiting.
Very well.
I see.
I knew that the Jidōin's supervisor
was the Yagisawa sisters' mother.
I heard she won't be coming
to see the Interhigh due to sickness.
It looked like a very serious illness.
She traveled all the way to Tōkyō
to guide her players…
It seems her daughters
were brought up on the volleyball.
That passion for volleyball led Jidōin High School
to win the Interhigh for three consecutive years.
Yeah…
The Yagisawa sisters' mother raised them
to become such excellent players.
National Girls' High School
Volleyball Championship
Fujimi High School
players' waiting room
Listen up.
All you have to do is to try out
every technique you've trained, one by one.
And put all of your power into it.
Got it? That's all.
Alright, go!
– Yes sir!
– Yes sir.
The final match of this year's
Girls High School Volleyball Championships.
Ōsaka representative, Jidōin High School, vs.
Shizuoka representative, Fujimi High School.
Good luck, Fujimi!
Don't lose!
You can do it!
Jidōin won the last three tournaments.
The champions are challenged
by the brisk newcomers, Fujimi High.
Both teams
have lined up near the lines.
It finally begins.
Good luck, girls!
Do your best, Chief!
No matter how strong Jidōin is,
they're still human.
There's nothing to be afraid of!
Please don't raise the volume too high.
Is this okay with you?
Yes. Thank you.
The final game: Jidōin vs. Fujimi.
Jidōin · Fujimi
The match begins.
The server is
Hayakawa Midori from Fujimi High.
Kozue, now's our chance!
Attack!
There's no way that'd work
against them so easily.
Are they waiting
for the right moment?
What's wrong, Katsura-san?
Katsura!
– Katsura!
– I'm sorry, Sis!
How could you miss that serve?
I'm just so nervous.
I have to win for Mom…
Do you understand?
What are you talking about, Katsura?
Are you playing this game
for Mom's sake?
Huh?!
Don't do that.
We play for ourselves.
"For ourselves."
"For ourselves…"
Thank goodness.
We'll be able to play
a proper match.
Please watch us, Yagisawa-san.
We'll surely show you
a great game!
Fujimi scores the first and second point,
but Jidōin quickly regains their pace…
…and snatches point after point
from the confused Fujimi team.
With no particular instructions from Coach Hongou,
Kozue and the team start to catch up…
…but it's already too late.
They lose the first set.
"I can't lose this time."
Kozue faces the second set
with great determination.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.