苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 061—
The Interhigh finals
National High School Women's Volleyball Championship
The final match of the High School Women's Volleyball Tournament.
Ōsaka's representative Jidōin High School, vs.
Shizuoka's representative, Fujimi High School.
The match begins with Fujimi's serve.
Will the Yagisawa sisters use the trinity attack today as well?
Jidōin's sharp spike sends the ball
over to the Fujimi's side.
Ayuhara's direct spike!
Jidōin · Fujimi
And it's in!
What a great serve.
Jidōin · Fujimi
And it's a point.
Fujimi leads by two points already.
Perhaps owing to the tension of the finals,
the Yagisawa sisters don't seem to be in form today.
What's going on, Yagisawa-san?
What's wrong, Katsura?
I'm sorry, Sis.
I know that we have to win for our mom and I'm trying my best, but…
I can't do it.
Jidōin High School has shown great games until the semi-finals.
As said, the Yagisawa sisters haven't yet reached their peak.
On the other hand, the Fujimi's
Ayuhara-Hayakawa-Oonuma trio…
…seems to be getting better and better.
Katsura.
Are you playing the game for Mom's sake?
Huh?
That's not the case.
We play for ourselves.
For ourselves?
"For ourselves"?
"For ourselves"…
"We play for ourselves."
That's right.
In the end, no one's helping us out.
It comes!
I have to get it!
The Yagisawa sisters showed their trinity attack.
What do you think?
I think we can do it.
For myself…
It works best when I'm bold and play for myself.
Let's get them!
Yeah!
Don't mind, don't mind!
Go! Go! Jidōin!
Go! Go! Yagisawa!
Ishimatsu!
Don't rush it.
If you do, you'll lose the sight of the ball.
Jidōin · Fujimi
Jidōin begins with their counterattack.
Go! Go! Jidōin!
Fujimi desperately tries to catch up,
but the score is already 7 to 2.
If things don't change soon, it'll look very bad for Fujimi.
Good luck, girls!
I believe in you.
You can win. I know it!
Ah! Ow.
Ah, now I've done it.
Nakazawa-san, are you okay?
That was just my hand.
I beat it against the rail. Wow, it hurts.
Whatever.
Don't give up, girls! You can do it!
The Yagisawa sisters' spike earns another point.
8 to 3.
Jidōin High rules the match.
The gap between both teams grows wider and wider.
Show courage, show courage, Fujimi!
Go! Go! Ayuhara!
Go! Go! Hayakawa!
– You can do this!
– Good luck!
Tsutomu.
Are you watching?
If you are, please watch over Kozue-san.
We mustn't let the Yagisawa sisters intimidate us.
As expected, Fujimi's struggling.
Youko?
I thought you'd come to see the game.
I did.
I knew it.
I looked for you ever since I arrived here.
Fujimi struggles hard, don't they?
It's an out!
Ah, damn.
Jidōin · Fujimi
Fujimi High calls a timeout.
They can only use their trinity attack if all three of them gather under the net.
When one of them has to go to the defense, they purposefully let go of the right to serve.
Then they regroup at the forefront immediately and return to scoring points.
It's a great offensive technique.
They're overconfident of their speed now.
This is it.
This is the perfect moment to unsettle them.
Are we doing the double attack?
No.
They know the double attack.
They know how to deal with it.
Playing it now won't do us any good.
T-Then…?
Hm.
You first, Ayuhara.
Sir.
Alright.
They're in pieces.
What are they going to do?
I think they'll focus on regaining the right to serve.
Now that they're so nervous, it'll be a piece of cake.
That's right, Sis.
They don't stand a chance anymore.
Yeah.
We'll take the match back in our hands.
A direct spike!
It wasn't direct…
What… What?!
Damn!
They did it.
Katsura!
Sis…
Katsura.
Alright!
Now Ishimatsu's serve, then the machine gun attack.
Jidōin · Fujimi
Fujimi fiercely counterattacks.
They shook the trinity attack off for the moment.
Jidōin · Fujimi
Attack!
Fujimi High School is catching up.
Will the tables turn?
13 to 11.
Jidōin High tries to gain the upper hand again.
But Fujimi doesn't give up.
Fujimi's pretty good.
But it'll be fine.
Jidōin is sure to win.
Fujimi serves.
Yagisawa Kaori receives!
And…
A spike! Ayuhara receives!
Wow, it's so exciting.
You look exhausted.
I heard Yagisawa-san flied all the way from Ōsaka
to coach her team, despite the wheelchair.
That's right.
Just before the match she has collapsed and that's why she's here.
And here she is, all calm and composed.
What's her condition?
Yagisawa attacks mercilessly.
Fujimi High's Oonuma-Hayakawa-Ayuhara trio's teamwork is on par with the Yagisawa sisters'.
Damn!
They received the machine gun attack.
It won't work against them anymore.
Is that as far as it goes?
Jidōin · Fujimi
It's a set point for Jidōin.
No good.
We have to get the right to serve back.
No!
Don't use the machine gun attack!
Ah, that's…!
That's the lightning attack!
Jidōin · Fujimi
Jidōin wins the first set.
No sweat! No sweat! Fujimi!
The second set is already yours!
No matter how much Fujimi struggles,
they can't possibly win against Jidōin.
It's a huge success they made it that far.
The gap in their strength is just too wide.
Don't you think?
I don't care about the match.
I came here only to see Ayuhara Kozue play.
I wanted to see it once again with my own eyes.
All of the techniques we've used in the first set
won't do us any good in the second set.
What do we do, Professor?
Hmm.
Alright! Begin with the double attack right off the bat.
Double attack…?
But Professor, will it work against them?
Right.
We can't tell how effective it is until we try.
For now, let's try to unsettle them with
the double attack from both sides of the court.
Then comes the vanishing attack.
Yes sir.
However…
We can't believe in it blindly.
Just how effective is the vanishing attack going to be against the Yagisawa sisters…?
Is it no good?
I didn't say so.
I'm just saying we won't know until we try.
They're so fearsome.
Then, the Oonuma and Ayuhara's double-spin spike.
But that's still…
…an unpolished technique.
Doesn't matter.
Try however you can.
We have to try every technique we can.
That's what a game is about.
It's all about practice!
Each of you has to do her best.
There's nothing else to be done.
Reception.
Toss.
Spike.
If you play your role to the best of your ability,
it'll become the power of the entire team.
The match is decided by the eagerness of its players.
And the result?
The result doesn't matter.
On the court, focus on yourself…
…and using your skills to the fullest.
Professor Hongou says the same thing.
"Play your own volleyball."
Got it?!
– Yes sir!
"Focus on yourself."
"Fight what's before you."
"Play your own volleyball."
"A game is something we play for ourselves."
Yes.
I'm not playing for anyone's sake.
Not even for Tsutomu-kun.
It's only for me.
I'm playing for myself… for myself only.
Kozue!
Here it is!
It's the double attack!
Kozue!
Attack!
It vanished?!
So that's it.
So that's the ace in the sleeve they've saved so far.
I won't miss it next time.
It didn't vanish!
So it didn't vanish after all.
The enemy is not alone.
If the Yagisawa sisters spread out on the court…
…all the blind spots are gone.
The ball won't disappear no matter where you throw it.
They react instantly by moving with agility and power.
I see. Incredible.
They're precise like machines.
Captain!
Ah, damn.
Why did she drop it?
What the heck?
That wasn't an ordinary mistake.
Captain!
Yeah.
Again?
Why did she do that?
Something's up.
Captain!
Yeah!
Attack!
Don't tell me…
I was sure I had received it.
That spike just now was a curve ball.
Y-You're pretty good, Ayuhara-san.
Now…
What will you do?
What will you do, Yagisawa sisters?!
If we play the ball sideways…
Ayuhara-san, it won't work again.
As expected.
They're excellent.
Their teamwork is perfect.
They must've worked very hard for it.
Here it is! The trinity attack!
Alright!
Will they get it?!
Jidōin · Fujimi
Direct spike!
Such a common cutting technique won't impress the Yagisawa sisters.
This time I will definitely hit the ball correctly.
Kozue, what's wrong?!
M-My wrist hurts a little.
It might have injured some muscle.
Kaori is really an impressive player.
What are you talking about?
More importantly, what about your wrist?
I'll be fine if I put it in a supporter.
Besides, I still have my left arm.
Katsura-san seems to have hurt her leg, too.
Huh?
Alright.
Did it hurt?
Nah, it's nothing serious.
Are you okay, Katsura?
Yep.
I'm fine.
Ah, if I focus on just one of them,
I can follow her moves with ease.
Midori!
Ah!
Jidōin · Fujimi
I can't believe the trinity attack could be seen through so easily.
The final game of the tournament.
It's a match point for Jidōin.
I was too late.
I noticed it too late!
Lightning attack!
Ayuhara-san can see through our lightning attack!
Damn!
Dammit!
If I hadn't sprained my wrist, I'd receive it easily.
It's all my fault.
In the end, I…
– We did it!
– Sis, we won!
You played well!
Jidōin wins the tournament.
It's their fourth consecutive victory.
Let's not forget about Fujimi High School team that has fought very well.
All in all, I expected Fujimi to lose.
But that Ayuhara…
Ayuhara gets up.
You really do not see such a game every day.
You did well.
Hongou-san, Ayuhara-san.
You will be good rivals for my team.
Yagisawa-san.
The next time we meet, I won't lose.
Now I understand how is it like to play for oneself, relying on one's own power.
I am capable of destroying your trinity attack.
Rather than focusing on the three of you at once…
…we'll mark each one of you separately and watch your every single step.
Then we'll defeat you.
The next time we meet, we will win for sure.
Kozue loses the Interhigh due to an injury to her wrist…
…but she has no regrets in her heart.
At that time, Captain Sai's team from South Korea arrives in Japan.
They ask for a friendly match
the day after tomorrow.
The twelve players they contact…
…includes the name of Ayuhara Kozue.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.