苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 062—
The friendly match: the night before
Medical office
It's nothing serious,
but you shouldn't push yourself for a week.
Understand?
Yes.
I'm so relieved.
Yagisawa-san.
Ayuhara-san.
How is your injury?
Turns out it was nothing serious.
I'm happy to hear that.
You played great.
I really admire your courage.
I wish we could play a little longer.
Ayuhara-san.
Hayakawa-san.
Thank you for this incredible match.
We won't ever forgive this day.
Neither will we.
Even though we lost, I don't have any regrets.
Thanks to you, we got to know
the famed Ōsaka's fighting spirit.
Tell us, how's your mother?
Well, we're on our way to the hospital right now.
There's nothing to worry about.
I'm sure when she sees this pennant,
she'll recover immediately.
Well then, we'll be on our way now.
Till next time.
Bye-bye.
See you.
Their mother is in critical condition,
and yet they're so calm.
The Yagisawa sisters are excellent rivals.
Waiting room
Fujimi High School
How was it, Ayuhara-san?
It was a torn muscle.
I'm sorry for making you worry about me.
It should heal within a week or so.
A week?
Now that's a bad news.
– Huh?
What do you mean?
Actually, the day after tomorrow there will be
a friendly match against the Korean team.
The names of the twelve top players in the country
who will participate have just been announced.
Some of you were among them.
Oonuma-san, Ayuhara-san and Hayakawa-san.
But I guess Ayuhara has no choice but to decline.
Professor…
– Huh?!
We're among these top twelve players?
What should we do, Sis?
The game's in two days, huh…
We have to train right away.
That's right. You'd better hurry.
We've got to go to the hospital.
We can't keep mom waiting for so long.
Don't you agree, Sis?
Let's hurry to the hospital.
Is it Mom?
What if she…
Silence.
Don't say stupid things.
Hello?
Ah, it's you, Mom!
This is Kaori.
How are you?
How do you feel?
Oh, I feel very good right now.
I watched your entire game on the TV.
It was a good game.
You played just like I wanted you to.
But Fujimi High School was great, too.
Anyway, congratulations on your victory.
I don't remember the last time
when I was this happy.
Yagisawa-san, you shouldn't push yourself.
Just a little longer.
I heard that you're up in a friendly match
against a South Korean team.
Please show us what the Japan's best players,
the Jidōin High School is made of.
Okay?
Of course, Mom. But we're worried about you.
What are you saying?
Stop thinking about me.
Remember, you shouldn't
underestimate the Korean team.
– Yagisawa-san, please…
– Kaori.
Tell this to Shizuka and Katsura as well.
Come visit me after you win with the Korean team.
Only… after you win…
Yagisawa-san!
M-Mom…?
Mom!
What did she say, Sis?
She hung up.
Mother said we should visit her only after
we won the match against the Korean team.
Then she hung up.
You're the one who told her
about this match, aren't you?
T-That's right.
I didn't know what to do by myself.
So I called her…
I don't believe this.
Didn't it occur to you that she'd become upset again
when she learned about this game?
Shizuka.
Katsura, you too.
Listen close.
Our victory is the most effective cure to Mom's illness.
This means we have to win
against the Korean team, no matter what.
Mom always lived for volleyball.
She deserves that much.
Mom, we'll do our best.
You too hang in there!
Ayuhara-san.
Hayakawa-san.
We were chosen, too.
No surprise there.
Of course you'd get chosen.
I never dreamed we'd play together again so fast.
We're up against Korea. Do you think we'll bump
into Sai-san from the World Junior Championships?
Naturally.
Sai-san's bullet spike…
I suppose she polished it beyond perfection.
But no worries.
We have our Ayuhara-san.
Plus we beat them once.
I wouldn't worry about anything.
Kakinouchi-san, believe me, I'd like to play
with you more than anything…
…but unfortunately I can't due to a wrist injury.
I'm sorry.
– Huh?
– Really?
They're Akizuki-san and Higaki-san from Tōnan.
Yamamoto-san and Shirakawa-san
from Aoba are there, too.
What's with them?
They're creeping me out.
Ayuhara-san.
Oh!
Girls, may I have your attention?
Although Interhigh has just ended…
…please remember that the twelve of you
represent the best players in whole Japan.
I would like you not to forget about it,
and give your best in the match with South Korea.
In addition, since Jidōin High School's
Coach Yagisawa is hospitalized…
…I asked Professor Hongou
of Fujimi High School to supervise your new team.
Okay, well, we'll start training right away.
This training is all about making you into a real team.
The captain will be Yagisawa Kaori
from the Jidōin High School.
Yes sir.
Now onto the individual players.
I haven't decided anything yet.
I have to know you better before
I decide who plays in which position.
That's all.
Ah, one last thing.
Regretfully, Ayuhara Kozue of Fujimi High School…
…is excluded from the team for the time being
due to an injury to her wrist.
Ayuhara-san, don't you worry about anything.
Just leave it to us.
Katsura, don't say too much.
Let's begin the practice.
Here goes!
Catch.
Toss me the ball, Akizuki-san.
Ayuhara-san.
Seeing practice from the stands once in a while
is a good opportunity to learn.
Yeah…
What's with that halfhearted toss?
Hmph.
Kakinouchi!
Your tone doesn't help building a good teamwork.
Do we understand each other?
B-But…
I bet we're thinking the same thing.
Even if they're the best players in the country,
here they're just a bunch of random people.
This is no good.
But I just don't understand their attitude.
Ayuhara-san, did you see our practice?
Yes.
We can't possibly train like that.
Yeah.
It's every man for himself.
Especially the girls from Tōnan and Aoba.
Why can't they put some effort into this practice?
They seem to be thinking
about the tournament in next spring.
They don't want us to see
their techniques and style because of that.
Ayuhara-san.
I bet Aoba team holds a grudge against you
for losing in this year's Interhigh.
They're thinking of their revenge
at the next tournament.
Agreed.
Also, I was told that Tōnan is using computers
to analyze the power of the rival schools.
I'm sure they're seeing this match
as a way to collect more data on us.
There's no doubt about it.
With that kind of attitude,
it'll be really difficult to win the game.
What about the Yagisawa sisters from Jidōin?
Well, they're pretty angry, of course.
I'm going to the medical office.
Be right back.
Kozue?
I'm sorry, but I'm in a hurry.
It's okay.
Ayuhara-san?
Huh?
How do you know me?
Jin-yeong.
Oh, Sai-san!
Ayuhara-san.
Long time no see.
Thank you for your support in America.
It was nothing.
We trained very hard since then.
We came here to Japan
to test the results of it.
Sis!
I talked to Ayuhara-san first.
Then you came in and interrupted.
That was rude, Sis!
Sorry, sorry.
Let me introduce myself.
I'm her younger sister, Jin-yeong.
I heard a lot about you from my sis.
She told me you're an outstanding player.
She even showed me a picture of you.
That's why it doesn't feel
like I met you for the first time.
I'm also happy to meet you.
She's still in middle school,
but she's already part of our team.
She really wanted to come here to Japan
and play with you, Ayuhara-san.
You've no idea how excited she was about it.
Ayuhara-san, I'm glad we finally meet.
But, you see…
I hurt my wrist in the Interhigh finals.
As a result, I can't play for a while.
Huh?
Ayuhara-san, you can't play?
That's disappointing…
Ayuhara-san.
To be honest, I'm disappointed, too.
My bullet spike lost to you back in America,
but I'm confident we can win this time.
Excuse me.
Doctor.
Do you need anything?
Does it really take a week
until it heals up?
Hmm…
It does.
Please.
Could you please make it heal any faster?
I can't do anything.
I think it's obvious, but if a torn muscle
doesn't heal properly, there will be complications.
Eh…
Matsukaze Inn
Good morning, Professor Shimizu.
Good morning.
Captain and Midori didn't return last night, did they?
Yes. All the selected players
stayed at the gymnasium.
It's to unite the team, right?
I think so.
I think Professor Hongou's doing his best
to shape up the new team.
Ayuhara-san, you have a guest.
Huh? I do?
Oh, Sai-san.
What a surprise.
There's a favor I'd like to ask you, Ayuhara-san.
A favor?
I'm all ears.
I'll help you however I can.
Thank you.
We want to hold a practice match
before we play tomorrow.
Huh?
Do you know any team
that could play with us?
Sure. I'll try to help you out, Sai-san.
Please wait for me at the Central Gymnasium.
– Huh?
Yeah.
I'd like us to play with the Korean team.
Don't make fun of us, Ayuhara-san.
You can't possibly be serious?
They're our opponents.
Training with them is absurd.
Ayuhara-san.
You must have a reason for it.
Tell us what's going on.
Last year I participated
in the World Junior Volleyball Championship.
Our Japanese team fought
against the Soviet Union in the final game.
The Soviet Union…
Each country's top players one after another collapsed
under Shellenina's and Borchinskaya's killer spike.
Its destructive power was that fearful.
In order to counter that killer spike…
…we came up with a technique
we named "the two-stage reception".
But we had very little time to develop it properly.
In our training, we needed to simulate
a very strong attack similar to the killer spike.
At that time, Sai-san of the Korean team
came and offered us a helping hand.
I was so happy I literally cried.
Even though Sai-san's bullet spike isn't a curve ball…
…its speed and power were just like those
of the killer spike. It was perfect.
We started with the two-stage reception
training straight away.
Soon enough and with their help, we've mastered it.
Then, Sai-san said this…
We're fellow Asians, after all.
Please do your best in our stead.
That's what she said.
I understand, Ayuhara-san.
I'll play with the Korean team.
Me too.
Me too!
Thank you.
Me too.
Oh, Professor!
Count me in.
Let's go.
Professor!
Sai-san, as you know, Captain,
Ayuhara-san and Hayakawa-san can't play with us.
But I promise you
that we will do our best.
Thanks. Let's have a good game.
Let's have a good game.
Here goes!
Ah!
The spike… jumped over the net!
The ball moves freely as if it was a living thing.
There was no such spike when we played in America.
There's no way we can block or receive that!
Then there's that reception.
Our curve balls worked well
against Sai-san back in America.
But there's no way they're going to work now.
Jin-yeong-san's defense zone makes it
nearly impossible to break through.
Meanwhile, look at our new team…
I'm going to play in the best players' team.
Huh?
My goodness.
Why are you just standing there?
And here we are, trying our best
so that we can visit our mom in the hospital.
Hmph. Like I care.
Akizuki-san!
What are y—
Ah!
Can't you take it more seriously?
Wait!
You started it!
Don't fight!
We don't have time to fight.
You wouldn't believe the Korean team's strength!
Ayuhara-san.
I heard your Fujimi team holds
a practice match with the Korean team.
What's the meaning of it?
T-That's…
Fujimi High School
helping out the Korean team…
In my book, it's a clear case of a betrayal.
Yeah. What are you thinking?
Hongou-san.
Aren't you going to stop them?
It won't make much sense
to force them to get along.
I think it's better to just let them
blow off steam, Higashida-san.
I see. You have a point.
Excuse me.
Ayuhara-san, don't waste your breath.
There's no talking to people like them,
who lack any motivation whatsoever.
Yagisawa-kun!
Coach… Coach's condition has worsened!
Huh?!
Huh? Are you sure?
Yes! The hospital just called.
Yagisawa-kun, hurry up to the hospital.
B-But…
We'll handle this. Hurry up!
Sis…
Excuse us.
Ayuhara-san, I hate to leave
without making sure the team has united.
We leave it to you.
Okay?
Yagisawa-san.
I think you're the only one
who can bring this team together.
Sure.
Alright, hurry up!
Hurry!
I wish you luck, Ayuhara-san!
Professor, please let me join in for the game.
No.
Kozue, Professor's right.
You shouldn't do this.
The doctor ordered you
not to push yourself for a week!
Kozue!
Medical office
Doctor.
It's you again?
Bugging me won't make it heal any faster.
No, please heal it right now.
Listen to yourself, girl.
You're asking the impossible.
Impossible or whatever,
I have to show up in the match tomorrow!
You have to show up, no matter what?
Yes. No matter what.
No.
I think you're the only one
who can bring this team together.
Ayuhara-san, you can't play?
That's disappointing…
I was looking forward to it so much…
To be honest, I'm disappointed, too.
My bullet spike lost to you back in America,
but I'm confident we can win this time.
It's a real shame.
Please, Doctor.
I have to play.
No matter what…
No matter what!
Thank you very much!
I'll give you special injections at intervals of time.
This means I'll stay with you during the entire match.
Thank you.
Ka-Kaori… What was that spike just now?
Shizuka, toss the ball more precisely.
If you don't, it can't be spiked well…
Katsura, if you want to block well, then…
then go at it from above…
Mom…!
I gave her a shot for sleep.
Please keep your voices low.
Doctor…
Will Mom… Will Mom be okay?
It's unclear for now.
Please call me if her condition changes.
Mom, hang in there!
Katsura, keep your voice low!
She's finally fallen asleep.
We can't wake her up.
I know, but…
Don't cry.
You know Mom doesn't like crying.
Mom…
Mom.
You can't die on us.
Please, you have to live!
Mom…
Central Gymnasium
Japan-Korea Friendly Volleyball Match
Ayuhara.
I'm fine, Professor.
Doctor allowed me to play.
No, I did not.
It's just your determination
made the injury go away.
I see.
Listen up! In today's game,
there will be only five players.
– Yes sir!
– Yes sir.
Hello?
Ah, Yagisawa-san?
Professor!
Please let me.
Hello? This is Ayuhara.
Ayuhara-san.
Our mom… Mom's…
…she has just passed away.
Huh?! She passed away?
Y-Yagisawa-san…
I have no idea what to say to you…
Thank you, Ayuhara-san.
Believe me, I didn't want
to sadden you before the game.
But I want you to win today, no matter what.
I don't want to think… that we lost…
because we weren't there.
Sis…!
We…
We were talking about today's game
until just before she died.
Ayuhara-san.
Please.
Please, win this game.
Ayuhara-san, you're here?
Sai-san, I'm going to play with you today.
But I need to warn you.
We're going to win.
That's my line.
Ayuhara-san.
Korea · Japan
The Yagisawa sisters skip the match with Korea
because of their mother's death.
Kozue, trying to live up to their expectations,
participates and uses her injured wrist.
But, as expected,
the improvised team shows its flaws.
The players show lack of discipline and cooperation.
The Japanese team barely wins the first set,
mostly owing to Kozue's selfless attack.
But as a result, Kozue goes to warm the bench.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.