苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 063—
The mistaken player switch
Central Gymnasium
Japan-Korea Friendly Volleyball Match
Ayuhara.
I'm fine, Professor.
Doctor allowed me to play.
No, I did not.
It's just your determination
made the injury go away.
I see.
Listen up! In today's game,
there will be only five players.
– Yes sir!
– Yes sir.
Hello?
Ah, Yagisawa-san?
Professor!
Please let me.
Hello? This is Ayuhara.
Ayuhara-san.
Our mom… Mom's…
…she has just passed away.
Huh?! She passed away?
Y-Yagisawa-san…
I have no idea what to say to you…
Thank you, Ayuhara-san.
Believe me, I didn't want
to sadden you before the game.
But I want you to win today, no matter what.
I don't want to think… that we lost…
because we weren't there.
Sis…!
We…
We were talking about today's game
until just before she died.
Ayuhara-san.
Please.
Please, win this game.
Ayuhara-san, you're here?
Sai-san, I'm going to play with you today.
But I need to warn you.
We're going to win.
That's my line.
Ayuhara-san.
A "friendly game" sounds so pretty.
But it's just a facade for the audience.
I'd like to use this match as a training
for the spring tournament.
Now that we're here,
we might as well check out the level others play at.
That knowledge might prove essential
in the next championships.
I wonder how far can I go
with my injured wrist.
But I have to fight,
no matter what.
For the Yagisawa sisters…
and for myself.
Ayuhara is a problem.
Everything depends on how
she can withstand the pain.
Catch.
Toss me the ball, Akizuki-san.
What's with that halfhearted toss?
Kakinouchi!
Your tone doesn't help building a good teamwork.
Do we understand each other?
B-But…
This is no good.
But I just don't understand their attitude.
Ayuhara-san, did you see our practice?
We can't possibly train like that.
Yeah.
It's every man for himself.
Especially the girls from Tōnan and Aoba.
Why can't they put some effort into this practice?
They seem to be thinking
about the tournament in next spring.
They don't want us to see
their techniques and style because of that.
I bet Aoba team holds a grudge against you
for losing in this year's Interhigh.
They're thinking of their revenge
at the next tournament.
Agreed.
Also, I was told that Tōnan is using computers
to analyze the power of the rival schools.
I'm sure they're seeing this match
as a way to collect more data on us.
There's no doubt about it.
With that kind of attitude,
it'll be really difficult to win the game.
I won't go easy on you, Sai-san.
Ah!
Hayakawa Midori throws a falling leaf!
Jin-yeong!
Got it!
I thought she'd receive it…
– Good job.
– Thanks.
They've studied our game play pretty well.
Yeah.
We can't let our guard down.
Amazing reception. She can quickly calculate
the point of impact of the ball.
Korea gets the next serve.
The server is Jin-yeong, who has demonstrated
an outstanding reception just now.
She's claimed to be even better than her sister.
What kind of serve will we get to see?
Yamamoto-san!
What was that…?
I can't believe she missed that.
What a good-for-nothing!
Midori…!
No good.
They're going to mark Yamamoto now.
Japan · Korea
She's tall, but not nearly fast enough.
Sai realized that very fast.
Things cannot continue like this.
If it doesn't change,
we're going to lose.
– Midori!
– Gotcha!
Attack!
Excellent!
Incredible, Ayuhara-san.
Just being able to play against you
was worth flying to Japan.
You're pretty good, Ayuhara-san.
Looks like Yamamoto-san
got finally motivated.
Ah, leave it to me!
No good.
Looks like she regained her confidence.
The Koreans move to an aggressive counterattack.
Higaki-san, cover Yamamoto-san!
Did she hit her wrist?!
Medical office
Doctor.
It's you again?
Bugging me won't make it heal any faster.
No, please heal it right now.
Listen to yourself, girl.
You're asking the impossible.
Impossible or whatever,
I have to show up in the match tomorrow!
You have to show up, no matter what?
Yes. No matter what.
No.
Please, Doctor.
I have to play.
No matter what…
No matter what!
Doctor!
Thank you very much!
I'll give you special injections at intervals of time.
This means I'll stay with you during the entire match.
Kozue.
Kozue, how's…
How's your wrist?
I'm fine.
Thank you, Ayuhara-san.
Your receptions are good,
I'll give you that.
But you still haven't showed us
your famous curve ball spike.
Too bad.
Let's not disappoint our fans.
Yeah!
The coach told us to do our best,
but you're keeping her curve ball spike in secret.
What makes you say that?
Well, Ayuhara-san cannot execute that technique
with you here on the bench, can she?
So you're saying I was deliberately
left on the bench today?
Ayuhara-san wouldn't be able to execute it
even if I had appeared on the court.
Can't you see those bandages?
But she seems plenty capable
of striking regular spikes.
Do you really think I don't see
it's just an excuse?
Shirakawa-san…
Great, great!
Yamamoto-san finally shows what she's capable of.
How disappointing.
Something's off with Ayuhara-san.
It was nothing like her previous spike.
The Jin-yeong · Sai duo
takes advantage of Ayuhara's mistake.
Aim at Yamamoto-san.
Sure.
Time!
He realized it's time to switch Ayuhara.
You want me to switch with Oonuma-san?
B-But…
– Hurry up!
– Yes sir.
Rather than Ayuhara, who's just missed a spike,
the Japanese coach switches Yamamoto.
Considering her last mistake, I'm not sure
if this can be considered a fair decision.
Your spike was superb, Yamamoto-san.
Yeah. But no matter how hard I work,
seems like our coach won't recognize it.
Yes. And do you know why, Yamamoto?
I do.
It's a matter of favoritism.
You let Ayuhara-san play
even though she missed a spike.
But you pulled me out even when my spike succeeded.
What about reception?
Hmph.
You put me on the bench, because
Ayuhara-san had to cover for me. Right?
No.
Korea has marked you.
You didn't realize that?
They did…?
Since you're their goal,
I decided to go as far as pulling you out.
In effect, they don't know what to do now.
See for yourself.
Sanjou from Kanagawa
and Kakinouchi from Fukuoka…
…show a great cooperation.
Their spike causes chaos
on the Korean side of the court.
They owe their chance to Oonuma's tosses.
Japan · Korea
And now it's a set point for Japan.
Sis!
Aren't we going to use that spike yet?
I don't want to show it in the first set.
It's okay if we lose it.
We'll win the second and the third set for sure.
To our surprise, the Korean team
cannot score even a single point against Japan.
It shows that switching Yamamoto
was a splendid decision.
The pain has subsided.
It's sink or swim.
Let's do this.
Captain, please toss the ball to me.
Huh?
I want to win this set by all means.
Here it goes!
– Captain!
– Got it!
Attack!
No way!
Curve ball spike!
Ayuhara's powerful spike scores a point!
Japan · Korea
Amazing.
With Ayuhara's truly amazing spike,
Japan wins the first set.
Kozue, are you okay?
Yes, I'm alright.
Why are you pushing yourself?
Pushing?
Yeah!
Getting pain relief shots and all.
It's not Interhigh anymore, you know.
It's just a friendly game.
Ah, Midori, I can't believe you're saying that.
We always play seriously on the court.
I know.
I know, but…
Sai-san is going at it in earnest, too.
We can't disappoint her.
Outstanding…
What an outstanding game.
– As expected from Ayuhara.
– Jin-yeong.
I might've made a mistake.
About what?
I'm talking about my spike.
Its technique requires a lot of energy and focus.
Normally, I try to hold it back as long as possible.
But that was a bad idea.
Ayuhara-san plays her best spikes despite her injury.
I won't lose to her.
Just watch me.
Your sister's spike
is going to win us the second set.
After Japan won the first set with a great struggle,
it's time to begin the second set.
What kind of strategy will the Korean team play out?
I told you Ayuhara-san's bandages
were just for show.
She just proved it with her last spike.
You must be angry
that they have taken you off the court.
The outcome is already decided, though.
I guess.
But Sai-san's team kept a good pace
in the beginning of the first set.
Is this all they've got?
I sense that they still
have a surprise up their sleeve.
This time Sai and Ayuhara stick to the back…
…and we can observe a fierce exchange
involving the entirety of both teams.
If they've something prepared,
it's about time they showed it.
There's a favor I'd like to ask you, Ayuhara-san.
A favor?
I'm all ears.
I'll help you however I can.
Thank you.
We want to hold a practice match
before we play tomorrow.
Do you know any team
that could play with us?
Sure. I'll try to help you out, Sai-san.
Please wait for me at the Central Gymnasium.
The spike… jumped over the net!
The ball moved freely as if it was a living thing.
There's no way we can block or receive that!
It'll hit the net.
Huh?!
Kozue, are you okay?!
Yep.
I was so sure it'd hit the net…
I thought I shouldn't jump to receive the bullet spike.
It was very careless of me.
Missile spike.
The ball flies as if the player
controls its trajectory from a distance.
Ayuhara-san, you're something else.
Kozue.
That's terrible!
Your wrist is all swollen!
I'm fine, I'm fine!
This is bad!
Switch her immediately.
If she continues to play,
she may damage it for good.
Shirakawa!
Change with Ayuhara.
Y-Yes sir.
Don't exert yourself.
We don't stand a chance
in the spring tournament without you.
Take it easy.
Sure.
I'm sorry to trouble you again.
You're a nightmare for any doctor.
I don't care what you do to your body anymore.
Tend to her hand!
Save lectures for later.
Okay, okay.
I'm sorry.
But Sai-san's spike was so wonderful,
I just had to…
"Had to"?
Had to do what?
If I could receive it, I wouldn't regret anything,
no matter what happened to my arm.
That's how I felt.
I can't believe you, girl.
There's no cure for stupidity.
You… volleyball idiot.
"Volleyball idiot"…
"Volleyball idiot".
Shirakawa!
I don't see you on the court.
Sir!
What kind of game play can we expect
now that Japanese team pulled out Ayuhara?
The match is resumed.
Hayakawa-san!
Not even Kakinouchi-san can receive that…
Normally it shouldn't be a problem to accept it.
But combined with the bullet spike,
it's almost impossible.
The decision to pull out Ayuhara
seems to have not played in Japan's favor.
Sai-san's inconceivable missile spike
leads the Koreans' counterattack.
The Korean team shows
an overwhelming advantage in the second set.
Japan · Korea
Captain Sai's solo actions wreak havoc.
Japanese team should be ashamed.
You must receive that spike.
If this continues into the third set,
it'll be a disaster.
I can't receive that missile spike
no matter how hard I try.
I'm trying my best for Ayuhara-san's sake, too!
Kakinouchi-san sure is motivated.
I'm sure she'll show something good.
Higaki-san is only thinking
about the spring tournament.
She's given up on this game.
And yet, Ayuhara-san…
Attack!
I'm sorry.
But Sai-san's spike was so wonderful,
I just had to…
"Had to"?
Had to do what?
If I could receive it, I wouldn't regret anything,
no matter what happened to my arm.
Volleyball idiot…
That's exactly who she is.
Higaki-san can't even compare to her.
I'm no better.
I doubted Ayuhara-san's injury…
Here goes the missile spike!
Shoot!
Somebody receive it!
They did it!
The Japanese team's accepted Sai's spike!
Volleyball idiot…
I wonder if I just got a little closer to becoming one.
Thank you, Shirakawa-san.
Thanks to you, we can counter the missile spike.
Alright!
The real game starts here!
After losing the first set, the Korean team launches
a staggering counterattack with Sai's missile spike.
The set count is now 1 to 1.
The third set finally begins.
Kozue, benched due to her injuries,
gambles everything and reenters the game to fight Sai.
Sai executes her missile spike,
aiming to knock Kozue down.
Kozue jumps.
Where will the ball go?
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.