苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 064—
Great rivals
You must receive that spike.
If this continues into the third set,
it'll be a disaster.
I can't receive that missile spike
no matter how hard I try.
I'm trying my best for Ayuhara-san's sake, too!
Kakinouchi-san sure is motivated.
I'm sure she'll show something good.
Higaki-san is only thinking
about the spring tournament.
She's given up on this game.
And yet, Ayuhara-san…
If I could receive it, I wouldn't regret anything.
That's how I felt.
Volleyball idiot…
That's exactly who she is.
Higaki-san can't even compare to her.
I'm no better.
I doubted Ayuhara-san's injury…
Here goes the missile spike!
Shoot!
Somebody receive it!
They did it!
The Japanese team's accepted Sai's spike!
I wonder if I just got a little closer to becoming one.
Thank you, Shirakawa-san.
We can counter the missile spike.
Alright!
The real game starts here!
Japan just reclaimed the right to serve.
Can they regain the lead?
Japan · Korea
It's a chance to make a comeback.
But Sai-san by now knows full well
how to defend against our falling leaf.
She's going to play the falling leaf!
I got it wrong!?
I-I can't read it!
Sis!
Nice one, Hayakawa-san.
Showing us your falling leaf first,
then going back to a regular spike.
Good job, Midori.
Great, Hayakawa.
Keep it up.
This time it's the falling leaf!
Hayakawa's extraordinary attack builds
a solid foundation for Japan's counterattack.
Japan · Korea
Hayakawa keeps serving.
Japan slowly catches up.
Just a little longer, Hayakawa-san.
Hang in there.
We're almost tied.
Hmph.
What's so exciting about this match?
I'll play at my own pace.
You know, the falling leaf requires
a lot of energy and focus to execute.
So… we'll have our chance soon.
Midori!
Missile spike!
Missile spike.
Higaki-san!
Yet again Sai's missile spike hits the court
and gets Korea the right to serve.
Higaki-san.
We're sweating our guts out
and you're just standing there!?
If you don't like my play, fine.
I can switch with Ayuhara-san any time.
H-How could you say that?
Knock it off.
We're in the middle of the match.
Please, return to your positions.
Hmph.
The Korean teams regains their pace.
It seems nothing is going to stop them
from winning the second set.
I'll get it!
Chance!
Sis!
Coach.
If… If this keeps up…
Are you okay?
Yes, it's no biggie.
Nothing can be done
until we defuse their missile spike.
Japan · Korea
Japan's brought down to its knees
before Sai's merciless missile spike.
Korea controls the game completely.
We should focus on the next set already.
Ayuhara's absence hurts us badly.
If only my arm wouldn't be so numb…
If only I could play…
Japan · Korea
It's a set point for Korea.
Not good.
Not good at all.
Ayuhara-san.
It's horrible to see you suffer.
But I can't do anything.
My reception is good for nothing.
What should I do to help the team?
Japan · Korea
Korea wins the second set.
The set score is 1 to 1.
The game will be resumed in the third set.
What's wrong, girls?
Get a grip!
Higaki, switch with Yamamoto.
But I…
What, Yamamoto?
What are you waiting for?
Don't push yourself too much.
It's just a friendly game, anyway.
Yamamoto-san.
Do you think so, too?
No. It's just that… my reception…
It's fine!
It's a coach's task to know that.
You just have to do
what you know you can do the best.
Yeah.
Yamamoto-san.
Be careful.
There's not much time
until the spring tournament, you know.
Higaki-san!
Wow, so scary.
We should play seriously
because it's a friendly game.
Sai-san's team flied all the way to Japan.
We should show her some respect.
I believe that kind of thing
is up to individual players.
At least, I don't give a damn.
If I injured myself, I'd lose everything.
Right?
I can't…
I can't believe her.
Ayuhara-san.
I want to play at my full power.
It's possible I won't receive anything.
But I'll make up for it twice with my spike.
Okay. That's the spirit.
Good luck.
The tall girl's back.
Her spike is top notch,
but she can't receive a thing.
Listen.
She's the weakest link.
We'll use that to our favor.
I also realized something.
Their team was made hastily
and is visibly crumbling along the way.
My missile spike is going to send them into oblivion.
Fight!
Yeah!
Got it?
Wait for Hayakawa's play.
Then let Yamamoto spike the ball.
That way, we'll have plenty of leeway
to deal with the missile spike.
The rest is a matter of motivation.
Understand?
The game is coming to an end.
The third set begins.
The set score is 1 to 1.
A fierce attack begins right from the beginning.
It may be called a friendly game,
but both teams are very serious.
Sai-san's going to win through like this.
We have to throw them off balance
before she throws the missile spike.
Yamamoto-san…
We'll lose at this rate.
It's a pity I don't get to play against Ayuhara-san.
But that's just advantageous to us.
We're going to win, for sure.
Missile spike!
Alright.
Over to you, Yamamoto-san!
She did it!
Yamamoto-san!
Are you okay?
I'm so useless.
No matter how hard I try,
my body just won't react in time.
I can't do anything.
Yamamoto's confidence is crumbling.
There's no way her spike will be effective like this.
I know she can play much better than that.
I wonder if there's any way to restore
Yamamoto-san's confidence?
There's no way to predict the missile attack.
It's better not to waste time in useless attempts
and focus on my Japanese rivals.
It'll be more profitable
for the spring tournament.
The Korean team triumphs again.
Like a fish that returned to water,
they quickly score one point after another.
Japan can't keep up at all.
So far they only scored three points.
It's a one-sided game for Koreans.
Japan · Korea
What are you doing?!
– Try a little harder!
– What did we come here for?
The girls must be getting tired.
At first, Yamamoto's spike created us a chance.
But in such a state…
If I asked for time here,
it'd discourage her for good.
Coach.
What's that, Ayuhara?
I'd like to try only one play.
D-Don't let her! It's reckless!
Time!
Just one play.
K-Kozue…
What do you want to do?
It's… It must be because I'm not good enough.
Not at all.
It's just a gamble to create a chance for us.
It's entirely possible it'll fail.
Don't.
Alright, let's show them!
Yet another rotation in the Japanese team.
Ayuhara, who has severely injured her arm,
steps in Shirakawa's place.
What is their plan?
Ayuhara-san.
I admire your fighting spirit.
But it's a suicide.
I don't want to lose such precious rival.
I'm not acting out of desperation.
Sai-san.
If I get to destroy your missile spike with a single play…
…I'm willing to bet everything on that single play.
Ayuhara-san, you're crazy.
What can you do with these hurt hands?
What can you do?
She just smiled!
Ayuhara-san…
You.
Why did you let her on the court?
Doctor.
I don't have what it takes
to change Ayuhara-kun's way of living.
Way of living?
I'll get that!
Ayuhara-san!
Kozue!
I'm okay.
Ayuhara!
Coach, looks like I placed a good bet.
Yeah.
Kozue!
Take her to the medical office immediately!
Time!
Korea requests a timeout.
It's a very sportsmanlike move from Captain Sai.
She asked for a break to let Japanese recover.
You're finally awake?
What about the game?
Try not to move too much.
You can hear that applause, right?
What's going on?
Don't worry.
After seeing your reckless action,
your friends jumped back on their feet.
I see.
Thank goodness.
You keep doing things
I'm telling you not to.
Of course it's going to hurt.
I'm sorry, but…
Yeah, I understand.
That passion of yours
is a medicine that beats any drug.
Japan · Korea
Five minutes with Ayuhara Kozue was enough
to give the Japanese team their confidence.
The tables have turned.
We have a match point.
I'll make it a win.
Falling leaf!
Leave it to me!
This spike has to get through.
Kakinouchi touches the ball!
Watch me, Ayuhara-san!
Yamamoto's spike!
It goes in!
Japan · Korea
15 to 13.
With Japan's victory in the first set,
the match comes to an end.
Japan wins.
The Japanese team players
just stand in a daze.
The Korean team has lost.
But rather than disappointment, their faces show
satisfaction from knowledge they did their best.
A warm applause to both teams
for an excellent game.
Oh! It's Ayuhara!
Ayuhara Kozue shows up
accompanied by a doctor.
Ayuhara!
Ayuhara-san.
I— Ah.
Ayuhara-san, how are your hands?
Sai-san.
Your spike was incredible.
No, I have still a long way to go.
But I won't lose to your fighting spirit
and I'll work hard.
I'll work hard, too.
I couldn't ask for a better souvenir.
Thank you.
Let's meet again, Ayuhara-san.
Ayuhara!
I think we were in the wrong.
Volleyball is so beautiful…
What do you mean?
There's no way our statistical approach
was wrong all the way.
Yes…
We'll show you what we can do
in the spring tournament qualifiers.
This is my volleyball.
It's not just a game on the court.
Everyone in this hall is together with me.
Everyone is connected through this white ball.
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you, volleyball.
Yagisawa-san, I wish
you could've played with us.
Good luck.
Till the spring qualifiers.
It's so sad. They take the victory flag home,
but without their mother.
They're great rivals.
I'm sure they'll be able to move on.
It's time for us to go, too.
Yes.
It's time for us to go…
and face new challenges.
Fuji
A certain girl suddenly bumps into Kozue.
Her eyes, caring for Kozue's injury,
are beautiful and kind.
But upon hearing that it was caused by volleyball,
her look grows colder and more distant.
Soon enough, it turns out that the girl's
transferred into Kozue's school.
She becomes popular on her first day in the class.
But for some reason,
sends Kozue chills down her spine.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.