苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 065—
Burning hostility
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Thanks.
Thank you.
– Are you okay?
– Y-Yes.
I'm fine, really.
I'm really sorry.
I should've paid more attention.
No, it's my fault.
I'm sorry.
Oh? You have my blouse.
Looks like it didn't get dirty.
Thank you.
You have injured your wrist, haven't you?
Ah, yeah, but I'm fine.
The pain is gone already for the most part.
It's nothing serious.
But…
I was on my way to see a doctor anyway,
so there's nothing to worry about.
I only hurt it a little bit in a volleyball match.
Volleyball?
Did I say something wrong?
Ayuhara-san.
Huh?
Oh, it's just you guys.
What do you mean, "just us"?
Hey, who was that girl just now?
Did you get into a fight with her?
No.
Hmm? I don't know why, Chief,
but it looked as if she was pissed off at you.
Hmm…
If I was in her shoes,
I'd think it was weird, too.
But to think she changed her attitude so much
when she just heard the word "volleyball"…
I don't think I've seen her anywhere.
Ah, I know!
Maybe she's a new player who has been
recruited by Misawa Academy?
Misawa Academy?
Huh?
"Unfortunately, we lost at the Interhigh."
"But we'll win in the prefectural selections
next spring." I remember her saying that.
Maybe it's just like Ishimatsu's suggesting.
But…
But what?
No, it's nothing.
But I feel like there's a reason for her hostility.
You're acting weird.
Naka, cheer her up.
Hey…
Hey, Chief, how's your wrist…?
Hm?
Ah, it still hurts a little,
but it got a lot better.
By the way, where you were headed to?
A-Actually, we went to see you, Kozue.
Hehe.
We'd like you to help us out with homework.
Same goes for me.
You want me to help you out?
But I still haven't done it myself, either.
That's a bummer.
The school starts tomorrow…
What to do?
Please, can't you do something?
Ah, alright.
Let's do it all together.
I am going to hospital now,
but you can wait for me at my home.
Really?
You're a lifesaver!
But it's a public hospital.
It's going to take some time, right?
No, I'm going to Makimura Clinic
that has just opened nearby.
A doctor from the public hospital
recommended it to me.
Makimura Clinic
Check-up room
Good girl.
Thanks.
– Doctor.
– Hm?
When can I start using my arm normally?
I'd say, about a month.
Huh?
A month?
You have some very muscular arms
you don't see very often in girls.
And since it was a torn muscle…
…it'll take some time before it heals.
All patched-up.
By the way, you told me you did it
in the middle of a volleyball match.
Which school do you go to?
Fujimi High School.
Huh…
Did you strain it during a P.E. class?
No, it was during
the semi-finals of the Interhigh.
Interhigh?
Yes.
It's National High School Championship Tournament.
The Fujimi High School
volleyball club scored second.
Also, Ayuhara-san was the captain of the All-Japan
team that rocked the World Cup in the United States.
I see.
I'm afraid I don't really follow sports.
Besides, I was in Tokyo until just a while ago.
But Fujimi High School is known as a prestigious
school with excellent academic achievements.
Who'd have thought
they'd do so well in sports?
"Who'd have thought
they'd do so well in sports?"
It's like she's trying to make us feel
guilty for being good at volleyball.
Makimura Clinic
What's her problem?
But to think it'll take
a month before it heals…
If I focus on just one of them,
I can follow her moves with ease.
Midori!
Yagisawa-san.
I won't lose next time.
I know I can beat your trinity attack.
We won't try to see through all of you at once.
Instead, we'll mark each one of you.
That way, we'll be able to stay one step ahead.
We'll beat Jidōin in the spring
selection tournament in Tōkyō.
We'll become the strongest high school in Japan.
To accomplish that goal, I'll go through
any obstacle, any difficulty.
Yo. Have you finished homework?
Yeah, more or less.
Really?
Where did you get that tan?
I've been swimming all summer.
Hey, hey, I saw you on TV.
Ayuhara-san, you were so great!
Thank you.
I promise to win next year.
That's the spirit.
You truly deserve being the star of our Fujimi High.
Star?
Yeah. After seeing your activity everyone agrees you
and the members of the volleyball club are our stars.
Right?
I appreciate your enthusiasm,
but it's a little embarrassing to be called "star".
Ah!
Oh, finally it's over.
I barely made it.
Hey, there goes another of our stars!
Who, me? A star?
You didn't look particularly
all that great on screen, though.
Say what?
Pfft!
Ah!
Good morning, everyone.
– Good morning!
The summer vacation is over,
and we start the second semester.
But before we do,
let me introduce our new friend here.
She transferred here
from Shiratori Academy in Tōkyō.
She's Makimura Kyouko-san.
Nice to meet you.
Makimura?
As in, Makimura Clinic?
Hm?
That's a little wrong.
If you redo the calculations from the start,
you'll see where you've made a mistake.
Makimura-san gives off
a cold vibe when she's studying.
I know.
It's the same feeling I had back then.
It isn't just a cold vibe.
I can't express it well, but I feel
like she's hiding a terrible secret.
I just feel it.
But what is it?
And that coldness…
When I met her for the first time,
she seemed like a very bright and cheerful person.
What's the reason for that contrast?
I have no idea.
I have no idea, but I'm still curious.
Professor, I've finished.
Already?
Okay, let me see.
Yes, all correct.
Wow, awesome.
Makimura-kun is really diligent.
Makimura-san's something else.
Yeah. She's just like Yamada-san.
Makimura-san,
thank you for the other day.
No, I'm the one who needs to apologize.
My name is Ayuhara Kozue.
I heard about you from my parents.
That's nice to hear.
If there is anything you don't know,
please don't hesitate to ask.
For example, about my club's activities.
Thanks.
But to put it bluntly,
I have no interest in it whatsoever.
It's that cold look again.
Makimura-san,
why are you so hostile?
Say, that Makimura-san who has just transferred…
She's a real bookworm, isn't she?
Yeah, even more so than Yamada-san,
the best student in our class. She has no competition.
The Kozue I know from middle school
wouldn't be so carefree about this.
Aren't you annoyed in the least
for losing to Makimura-san?
But it's not like I'm paying
a lot of attention to my studies.
My head's full of volleyball.
You have a point.
Hey, Kozue, did anything bad
happen between you and Makimura-san?
Huh?
People are talking about how you suddenly got
very distanced ever since she's transferred.
Ah, that's not true.
But I can't blame people are thinking that.
Huh?
You see, Makimura-san's always
seems so… hostile towards me.
Let's change the subject.
Let's go practice, Midori.
Everyone's waiting for us.
Come on, hurry up.
I'm going first!
Yeah…
– Again…
– Ishikawa-san!
Your movements are still a little sluggish.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
My legs are always much better
in training than in the game.
Ayuhara-san, isn't it too early for you
to train with your wrist like this?
No, it's alright.
I'll use my left arm.
Plus, we have to think about
the upcoming spring tournament.
I can't just sit around,
even if both of my arms were damaged.
Then, let's get down to training.
Yeah.
Chief!
Chief.
Trouble! Ishimatsu
and Makimura-san are about to fight.
– Huh?
– Where are they?
Just outside.
Let me hear you say it again!
What's going on, Ishimatsu?
Makimura-san's talking trash about our club.
Especially about you, Ayuhara-san.
"Volleyball is worthless."
"But Ayuhara-san, who owes her
popularity to it, is even more worthless."
Huh?
What?!
Apologize to everyone immediately.
No, I'm not going to apologize for anything.
I didn't say anything wrong.
I only spoke the truth.
Then you…
Looks like we have to talk the hard way.
Wow, she has amazing reflexes.
Ishimatsu, cut it out.
Let go of me!
There's no way I can let it slide
when she's insulting all of us to our faces!
Let me go, let me go!
But if you resort to violence,
you'll play right into her hands.
But…!
Ishimatsu, if you get into a fight,
I'll be forced to ask you to leave the club.
Yeah. Our school has regulations
to deal with that kind of things.
Huh?
Hey, Ishimatsu.
Don't let what people say about us get to you.
Let's focus on training
for the spring tournament instead.
Let's go!
Indeed, Kozue's thinking only about volleyball.
"Volleyball is worthless".
And I'm even more worthless for playing it.
What was that all about?
Chief!
Ayuhara-san, get a grip!
Stop. There's no point in dwelling on it.
I should focus solely on volleyball.
Yes. From now on, I'll just ignore
everything about Makimura-san.
Oonuma, Ayuhara!
Sir!
What's up, Professor?
Hmm.
On our way back from the Interhigh finals…
…Ayuhara told me in the train she has
an idea how to beat the trinity attack.
Yes sir.
After thorough consideration,
I think it stands a chance.
Professor!
Huh? What kind of idea, Ayuhara-san?
Oh, it—
Heh. Don't rush it, Oonuma.
We'll try it out and get down to training
after the midterm exams are over.
Midterm exams?
Until the exams are over and the results have been
announced, I'll cut you some slack with the training.
We'll continue to focus
solely on the basic techniques.
– Yes sir.
This sucks.
Time for teachers to bully us again…
Midterm exams schedule
Well said.
– Geez, we don't have a single day free.
– Exactly.
No time for drilling.
You'll let me see your notes, right?
The teachers are just heartless.
Oh, no. The math and English exams
right on the first day.
I think my head is about to burst.
Lord, have mercy.
Hey.
Hm!?
Look at her.
"I'll pass every exam and you know it."
Volleyball club room
Since the exams schedule has been decided,
we'll suspend the training for 2 weeks from today.
The top 100 results will be posted
on the board in the corridor.
Please do your best, girls.
Wow, that's a shock.
Tell me about it.
Please put as much effort into studying
as you normally put into volleyball.
– Yeah.
– Yes ma'am.
Makimura Clinic
"Many people from Fujimi High School are also here
at the university. Everyone does pretty well."
"Kyouko. I know the transfer must've
been hard for you, so hang in there."
Letters from Brother are always about studying.
When I was little he always forced me to play
with him, even when I was busy. And now?
Kyouko.
What was that?
You were looking at your photograph
in the tennis uniform again, weren't you?
Hey, Kyouko.
I hate to repeat myself, but you're in high school now.
You should focus on your studies.
I'm well aware of that.
Kyouko!
I'm going to the library.
Makimura Clinic
Ah!
Oh! Ayuhara-san?
Ayuhara-san.
You're early today.
Oh, I know.
Since the exams are about to start,
you paused with the volleyball practice, right?
Yes. What of it?
Nothing. I only wanted to give you a bit of advice.
Advice?
Don't you think it's a little bit
too late to start studying now?
Too late?
Yes, too late.
If you start now, there's no way
you could get good grades anyway.
If that's the case, wouldn't you be
better off continuing your volleyball training?
To keep your fame from the Interhigh.
Although there's not much glory in sports.
Makimura-san, what did I ever do to you
to deserve that kind of treatment every day?
Treat you how?
I'm just giving you a fair advice
as a fellow high school student.
Because when I see you,
I just feel sorry for you.
Sorry?
Studying is number one priority for students.
And here you are, devoting everything for a stupid
game. What did you come to high school for anyway?
You make a fool of yourself.
A fool…?
So that's what the fight before was about.
But you're one to talk, who doesn't even know
the splendor of sports and keeps just studying.
Makimura-san, I will say just this.
I myself can't help but feel sorry for you,
who knows only how to study.
Whay did you say?!
Ayuhara family
I have to admit, Makimura-san
succeeded in making me angry.
Alright.
Oh, Kozue.
Kozue.
Kozue-chan, time to wake up.
Wake up, Kozue.
Time for school.
Just a bit longer…
You'll be late for your exam.
Exam!?
Are you sure that all-nighter was a good idea?
Yeah. Physically, I feel fine.
Ahh. Alright, let's do this!
She's finished already?
That was fast…
Tch.
I can't believe it.
Silence.
Behave yourselves.
There's not much time left.
Focus on yourselves.
Ah. It was so difficult.
What if I get a bad grade?
The results of the midterm exams are announced.
Kyouko gets the first place. In contrast to praise
from her classmates, she's not impressed.
Kyouko thinks:
"Just how far can you succeed in life
through volleyball?"
Meanwhile Kozue reveals that she's playing
volleyball to live a fulfilling high school life.
The conflict between Kozue and Kyouko
deepens further and further.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.