苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 066—
The identity of Makimura Kyouko
Fujimi High School
Move, move, move!
Was that… a girl?
1 year class C
Guys, it's the end of the world!
– What happened?
– You always make fuss over littlest things.
What's that about, Ishimatsu?
The result of the midterm exams
are about to be announced.
– Really?
– What a disaster!
I don't want to see…
Oh, Ayuhara-san?
Are you going to see the results?
Huh? Yes, I am.
So you take interest
in your grades, after all.
Hey, hey, have you seen my name?
Come on, let me see.
I can't see my name anywhere.
Ah, Makimura-san's first.
That's hardly surprising.
She's awesome.
Did you guys know?
I heard her older brother went
to study at Tōkyō University.
Her older sister is a shining student, too.
– Wow!
– I'm so jealous.
Their family is just something else.
Alright, so she's the queen of nerds.
So what?
What?
Midori.
Ah, Kozue.
I got better, I slid six places further up. See?
You're right.
That's great.
What about you, Kozue?
There!
Wow, you're seventh!
That's fantastic.
I'm so happy for you.
Thanks.
1. Makimura Youko
Oh, Ayuhara-san, are you going to see the results?
So you take interest in your grades, after all.
Makimura-san, Makimura-san!
You got the best score!
She surpassed even the almighty
Tanaka-san from Class A.
I admire her so much…
Congratulations.
You must be thrilled.
Not really.
It's not a big deal.
Huh…? Ah, y-yes, of course.
It goes without saying you'd be the best.
I never cared about the ranking
in the midterm exams.
Here you go, all goody-goody again!
But for us it's a great honor
to have the best student in our class.
Yes. You set an example for us.
Anyway, it's great to be the best.
After all, the exams are sink or swim.
You must take top places or you can
forget about getting into a good school.
I can't listen to you guys anymore.
"Great honor"?
"Good example"?
You've got to be kidding me!
What's your problem?
Ishimatsu, let them be—
Not a chance.
If we're to speak about honor to our class,
let's talk how Ayuhara-san…
…made our Fujimi High School's name
famous in the whole Japan!
The whole Japan!
Well, okay, but volleyball
doesn't go well together with studying.
Why?
Ayuhara-san trains day after day, everyday,
and yet she's seventh in the ranking.
Unlike this bookworm here
who has hardly ever seen any sunshine.
You heard me right, you bookworm.
I… I guess she has some point.
But the best is still the best, period.
But Ayuhara-kun's pretty good, too.
"Pretty good", you say?
What place are you?
Hah, don't even ask.
Studying is important,
but it's insufficient alone.
We have to invest more time
in our high school lives.
I guess club activities
are also important.
True, true.
No matter how much you cram, you won't be
of any use to society if you're not healthy.
Yes.
Ayuhara-san, if I recall right, you're up
for another tournament qualifiers next spring.
I wish you good luck.
I'll root for you.
Go! Go! Ayuhara!
Ayuhara-san.
Hm?
Is there something you need?
Last time I came to give you advice.
But now I started to wonder how far
can you succeed in life through volleyball?
First and foremost, it seems to grant you
popularity in the class, that's for sure.
Excuse me?
But you're a pretty simple person
if that's what makes you satisfied.
That's not it.
I just do my best to do what I want to do.
Princesses such as yourself
are unable to comprehend it.
I won't lose to you.
"How useful can volleyball really be"?
Makimura-san. The moment when I hit the ball
is when I feel the most complete.
I play volleyball to live a fulfilling high school life.
That's all there is to it.
You can cram or whatever.
Do what you want to do.
I won't judge you.
But I ask you not to judge myself either in return.
Ayuhara-san.
Ah, Professor Shimizu.
You're very energetic today.
I was worried I lost my touch
during studying for the exams.
I see.
It's about time for us to start preparing
for the qualifying round next spring.
– Yes.
– Right.
I just remembered. Ayuhara-san,
about the upcoming Sports Festival…
I've made you the leader for our
volleyball team. I hope you don't mind.
Not at all.
Autumn Sports Festival
– Good luck!
– You can do it!
Please get the equipment
for the first competition.
Yes ma'am!
Studying is the most important.
But you all focus on your volleyball.
Why do you even come to school?
You're so stupid.
But I managed to balance
studying and volleyball with great results.
Why don't you even try and play?
If you did, you'd understand
why we love sports so much.
Ayuhara-san.
Hey, Ayuhara-san.
It seems we're just incompatible.
We have fundamentally
different ways of thinking.
Yes. I think so, too.
Makimura-san, talking any more
would be a waste of time, don't you think?
"Going my way".
I'll walk my own path as well.
Ayuhara-san.
Excuse me. I'm busy.
She talks about sports with such disdain,
and yet she follows the rhythm so well.
Moreover, her posture is so good.
She's no ordinary bookworm.
Right.
Back then was the same…
What's going on, Ishimatsu?
Makimura-san's talking trash about our club.
Especially about you, Ayuhara-san.
"Volleyball is worthless."
"But Ayuhara-san, who owes her
popularity to it, is even more worthless."
What?!
Apologize to everyone immediately.
Looks like we have to talk the hard way.
Ishimatsu, cut it out!
Let go of me!
She showed fantastic reflexes back then.
Makimura-san is hiding something.
I'm sure of it.
Please prepare for the next competition.
Next up is a spoon race.
Feel free to join in.
Papa, Mama.
Let's participate together.
Alright.
It'll be my first time running in a while.
Mama, what about you?
Mama's tired.
Don't be like that.
Come with us.
Yeah!
Excuse me,
would you like to participate?
Oh, no, I'm fine.
It's Makimura-san's mother.
Mother!
Ah, Kyouko.
What are you doing here? You told me
you have tea party and won't make it.
Well, the tea party has been canceled.
Actually I didn't want to come,
but I happened to be nearby.
You make me proud, Darling.
You don't neglect your studies even for a day.
You're just like your siblings.
They always kept studying around the clock.
Thanks to their commitment, both of them
were able to enter the best universities.
Maintaining your physical health
is of course important.
But it's alright to take it easy with sports.
If you distract yourself too much,
it'll have a negative impact on your grades.
Yes, Mother.
Makimura family is a family of excellent minds,
your father being the brightest one.
Please bear it in mind
and keep studying hard.
Make every second count.
But Fujimi High School is known as a prestigious
school with excellent academic achievements.
Who'd have thought
they'd do so well in sports?
Now I understand.
She sounded almost like we should
be ashamed for doing well in volleyball.
Makimura-san's mother must resent sports.
Perhaps Makimura-san is trying to hide
that she's actually great at sports?
I bet that's it.
Even so, she hates it.
It's by the influence of her mother.
We're going to run together in an obstacle race.
I wonder how she'll do.
I'll keep an eye on her.
Next up is a freshmen obstacle race.
First-year students
are to assemble at the start line.
Assume positions.
Good luck, Midori.
Ready!
My heart's pumping.
Me too.
My folks are here to watch.
I hope we don't end up last.
Ah, Chief!
Hayakawa-san's leading!
Yeah!
She's our Midori.
Huh?
Hōgen Rebellion – 1156.
Heiji Rebellion – 1159.
Downfall of Heishi: 11… 1185.
Next!
Good luck, Chief!
It's not like you need it, but anyway!
It's no contest against that brainiac.
You're more than just a brainiac.
Makimura-san, I'm going to see your real self.
Assume positions.
That's weird.
What's wrong, Chief?
Why are they running evenly?
I knew it.
Excellent fitness.
– Kozue!
– Hang in there!
Run, Kozue!
It's her mother's fault.
She knows she's watched.
That's why she lost on purpose.
It's alright to take it easy with sports.
Otherwise it'll have a negative
impact on one's grades.
I feel sorry for you, Makimura-san.
Makimura Clinic
I lost, but I won.
Ayuhara-san.
I have to get to a first-class
university just like my siblings.
That's my goal. My fate.
I just don't have time
to devote myself to sports like you.
But if I were to get serious…
There's no way…
There's no way I'd lose to you.
Kyouko?
– Kyouko.
– Yes, Mother?
You must be tired.
Here, I made you a tea.
Not at all, Mother.
I didn't really apply myself to that run today.
That's good call.
If you had won, you'd soon start to get annoying
invitations from the sports clubs all around.
Changing the subject,
I'm going to Tōkyō tomorrow.
Your brother's condition has worsened.
Huh?
Unfortunately I don't think I'll be back in time
to help you finish the last exams.
You'll have to apply yourself
more during my absence.
Can I count on you, Kyouko?
Yes, of course.
Brother's not well again…
Eiichi.
Eiichi, hang in there!
Eiichi…
Eiichi. Eiichi!
Fujimi High School
Ayuhara-san won the race, didn't she?
Of course she did.
It's the star of our club
we're talking about.
She excels at sports.
Ishimatsu…
Now that you mention it, Makimura-san
was ranked very low as expected.
Yeah!
But at first she ran hand in hand
with Ayuhara-san, didn't she?
She just lucked out.
When it boils down to fitness, it's no contest.
Yeah. Our little bookworm
turned into a snail yesterday.
She was all like this…
Crawl, crawl!
It's Makimura-san!
Ah, oops!
Naka.
The exams are over.
It's time to get serious.
Wow, so scary.
Chief's in a foul mood.
But why?
Strange.
Kozue, you're not like yourself.
What's up?
Everything's normal.
I don't understand.
What's the deal with her?
Her performance yesterday
had nothing to do with fluke.
It was her own strength.
No one realizes it.
I'm the only one who knows.
Maybe Makimura-san actually likes sports?
Yes. It must be so.
Going back to the first time we met…
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Thanks.
Thank you.
My hand…
Are you okay?
Y-Yes.
I'm fine, really.
I'm really sorry.
I should've paid more attention.
No, it's my fault.
I'm sorry.
Oh? You have my blouse.
Looks like it didn't get dirty.
Thank you.
You have injured your wrist, haven't you?
Yes, but I'm fine.
The pain is gone already for the most part.
It's nothing serious.
But…
I was on my way to see a doctor anyway,
so there's nothing to worry about.
I only hurt it a little bit in a volleyball match.
Huh?
Volleyball?
What did I say to make her look so upset?
She looked so kind and bright at first.
But she changed her attitude by 180 degrees
once she heard the word "volleyball".
The first time I met Makimura-san,
she was so cheerful.
That must have been her true character.
Her coldness is just a facade.
She puts up that act out of consideration for
her mother, who has forbidden her to do sports.
Makimura-san must want to play sports.
But she can't, and to ease her frustration…
…she tries to convince herself that
she dislikes sports on her own accord.
She channels the frustration coming from denying
her own feelings into actual hatred for sports.
Kozue?
Huh?
Kozue, be honest with me.
Are you feeling unwell?
No.
You were staring blank
with a very grim expression.
I thought something was up.
I'm fine, really.
I told you already.
Come on, we have to train
counter for the trinity attack.
Midori, call Professor Hongou over.
Okay.
Ayuhara-san,
Hayakawa-san.
There's someone who wants to join our club.
I'd like to discuss it with you girls.
Could you come over to the club room?
Sure.
I wonder if we know her?
Why didn't she take the entry tests
in the spring and waited until now?
Oh, it's you, Makimura-san.
You're the one who wanted to join our club…?
Yes.
You're serious?
You've got to be kidding us.
Don't take this the wrong way,
but girls like you aren't fit to play volleyball.
Why?
Y-You have to ask? Geeks like you…
Uh, I mean, it just won't work.
I heard about you.
Do you believe a person like you,
who focuses on studying so much…
…can withstand our hard training?
Plus you hated sports, right?
Then why in the world
you'd try to join the volleyball club?
Please explain it to us.
T-That's…
Captain, I'm for it.
If she wants to join us,
why don't we let her?
Kozue!
I guess you're right.
There's no real reason to reject her.
Makimura-san, I don't understand
why you'd want to join our club.
However, I understand full well
that you're no ordinary bookworm.
Your excellent reflexes and fitness
couldn't escape my eyes.
Makimura Kyouko joins the club, but at the
same time Captain Oonuma Miyuki moves away.
Kozue takes over and tries to talk about
numerous insults received from Kyouko.
She goes as far as putting Kyouko
through special training sessions.
Even during this training,
Kyouko's eyes remain cold and tranquil.
But Kozue's eyes are even colder.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.