苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 067—
The ruthless Captain Kozue
Again a belly landing.
Pull yourself together!
Okay!
Keep it up, Ayuhara-san.
Roger.
Hey, looks like our nerd
is doing well.
At least when
it comes to receptions.
I can do more than just study.
To prove it, I'll challenge
the entire volleyball club.
My goal…
…is you, Ayuhara-san.
I'll show you that I can match you
in every way at volleyball.
I just can't wrap my head around
we why let Makimura Kyouko join our club.
Because we accept
newcomers without prejudice.
Of course, but there's no way that girl
can seriously devote herself to volleyball.
Exactly. She must be
scheming something.
I'll bet she joined
to be Kozue's rival.
She's a very proud girl.
Hmph.
I'll bet the second we squeeze her a bit,
she'll run away in tears.
Yeah.
Let's try it.
Damn.
Let's end your practice here.
Huh?
Please.
Let me join your practice.
Does somebody want
to partner up?
Me, me!
I'll do it, Ishimatsu.
But…
Okay then, Hayakawa-san.
Coming.
C-Captain!?
Why can't I go?
Hehe. It's because
you'll end up in a fight.
Tsk! And here I was thinking I'd finally get
a chance to beat her to a pulp, fair and square.
Here we go!
What's going on?
That nerd…
Yeah. Midori seems to be holding back a bit.
Still, it's impressive how she stands her ground.
She's surprisingly talented,
don't you think?
Yes.
I knew it. She was just
pretending to hate sports.
While it's undeniable
she still has to learn the basics…
…she possesses amazing
reflexes and jumping power.
Wait a moment.
I'm guessing that you're holding back
because I haven't played before.
I don't need your sympathy.
Wha—
I'm a part of the volleyball club, too.
Please train with me like you'd train with the others.
Very well.
No more holding back.
We'll join in, too.
Thanks.
Captain…
It's fine.
She's looking down at our club…
Or rather, at volleyball.
What are you doing?
Stand up! Stand up right now!
Too slow!
Where's your enthusiasm?
Once more!
Here goes another!
And another!
What are you doing?
Come on!
She's still trying.
But the root to her motivation in volleyball
seems to be the opposite of ours.
Stop!
Huh?
Are you okay?
I'm fine. You'll have to do
a lot more than that to break me.
I won't lose!
I won't lose.
What do you think?
Was it too much for her?
I'll bet she won't be back.
Next time she shows up,
I'll teach her another lesson.
Makimura-san, your eyes…
Your eyes were so cold.
Today was my first day
and I'm already aching all over.
I didn't think I was so weak.
Those were fun times.
But I chose the path of studying.
Not just because
my mother told me to.
I have my pride and I want
to prepare a bright future.
I don't want to spoil that future
by having pointless fun.
That's why I chose this path.
That's the lifestyle I chose.
I have to put an end to this
before Mother comes back from Tōkyō.
My challenge
to the volleyball club…
I won't lose to Ayuhara-san,
no matter what.
Volleyball Club Room
So Miss Nerdy
hasn't come back, after all.
Of course she hasn't.
It's a miracle she endured
a single day to begin with.
What are you talking about?
She's been on the court for a while.
She's finishing with the warm-up.
– Huh?
What? Ishikawa-san,
are you serious?
Yes.
Wow. Looks like Kozue's
intuition was right again.
I think Makimura-san
is even tougher than we are.
Well, I don't know about that, but she has
developed a fighting spirit comparable to yours.
Yeah.
No way, Ayuhara-san.
You're giving her way too much credit.
Yeah. We'd better teach her
another lesson.
No. You're not allowed to bully her anymore.
But I guess there's no talking to you girls.
She's doing all of this on purpose
to force herself into choosing the path of studying.
So she does hate volleyball, after all.
She's trying to conquer our club
by challenging me.
I won't lose.
I will surpass Ayuhara-san.
Let's wrap this up for today.
I have some news to announce.
Please come closer.
What's the news?
Actually, I…
– …decided to leave the club.
– Huh?
What happened, Captain?
First of all,
I'm going on to university soon.
Now the final sprint for the entrance exam starts
and it eats up all of my free time.
I want to give it my all.
I talked to Professor Hongou about this today.
He understood and agreed with me.
I'd like to say that my life
here at the volleyball club…
…was very fulfilling thanks to
Ayuhara-san and everyone else.
I have no regrets.
B-But the spring tournament
is around the corner.
If we lose our captain now, then…
My role here is over.
I'm sure you'll do fine.
My final duty here
is to appoint the new captain.
New captain…?
I'd like to appoint Ayuhara-san
as my successor.
Huh?
I'm for it!
Yeah, yeah!
It has to be Ayuhara-san!
Exactly!
W-Wait a minute!
I'm still a junior.
Ishikawa-san and Takeichi-san, who are
second graders, are better choice than I am.
Ayuhara-san, it might have been valid
at the time when you just joined our club.
We'd love to see you
as our new captain.
We'll be in the final year, anyway.
Yes, exactly.
The mainstay member of the volleyball club must
be a second year like you, Ayuhara-san.
– Right, girls?
– Right!
Exactly.
Everyone agrees to it.
Ayuhara-san, it's okay.
I… I'm not sure
that I'm qualified for this.
Ayuhara-san, no one
is qualified at first.
But every member of the volleyball club
still wants you to be their captain.
The rest is just a matter
of your effort.
And if you're talking about qualifications,
no one loves volleyball more than you, Kozue.
Isn't that plenty enough?
Midori.
So, it seems like this is a unanimous decision
to make Ayuhara Kozue-san the new captain.
Alright!
Let's win the upcoming
tournament, Captain.
Well said!
Ayuhara-san,
say something to them.
Huh? U-Uhm…
Thank you for your kindness.
Sure thing, Chief!
You can count on us!
We'll see how you'll
manage your training.
I became their captain.
I wasn't prepared at all.
Now I have to deal with Makimura-san,
who hates me and volleyball.
It's hopeless. There's no way I can build up
good teamwork with a person like her.
Ayuhara-san.
Captain…
You're the captain
from today on, remember?
I-I think I'm going to withdraw
from the captainship.
Because of Makimura-san?
Yes.
Don't be too hasty.
Aren't you the one
who has noticed her talent first?
But I was wrong.
She doesn't really want
to play volleyball.
She's doing all of this
just to challenge me.
And what's wrong with that?
Whether Makimura-san gets along with the team
or not is a great test for the new captain.
A test for the new captain…
A test.
You're right.
I'll try to make it work.
I'll openly accept
Makimura-san's challenge.
I'll fight so that Oonuma-san can leave
in peace before the tournament.
I'll challenge myself as well.
And I'll show that I can deliver.
Alright!
You can do it.
Show me some energy.
Ayuhara-san sure is motivated.
I can totally see
the tournament coming.
Makimura-san,
it'll get harder from here on.
I'm prepared.
Makimura-san!
A middle schooler could
receive better than you.
What did you say?
At best you barely touched the ball.
You should use your full body.
B-But it's impossible for me
to get everything perfect in a single day.
Didn't you join our club
of your own free will?
Stop making excuses.
I'm not going to listen to them.
Those aren't excuses.
I have just as much talent
for this sport as you do.
Fine. But you don't play
volleyball with words.
Improve your technique
before you open your mouth.
That's exactly my plan.
Very well.
I'll train you myself, then.
Huh?
But first, I want to make it clear
that you can leave anytime you want.
Finally, Ayuhara-san went all out.
It's no wonder.
That girl was just asking for it.
Right, Hayakawa-san?
Y-Yeah.
Ayuhara-san can be
really tough sometimes.
But I feel like Makimura-san
won't give in so easily either.
How mean…
She keeps aiming at places
just out of my reach.
That'll be enough for today.
I have one question.
Let's hear it.
Why do you keep serving
only at places you know I can't reach?
I understand hard training,
but this just feels like bullying to me.
I can answer that question.
I can't blame you, since you have
no experience playing volleyball.
Serving the ball so that you can't receive it
is the goal of every opponent you face.
We train to learn how to respond
to the most insidious balls effectively.
I won't lose to her.
Sooner or later I'll catch up to you, Ayuhara-san,
and then I'll make you eat my dust.
Hey, Kozue.
Hm? Is there something
you want to tell me, Midori?
Ah, no, not really.
Chief!
You were so cool.
That was one hell of a training!
Stop calling me that already.
O-Okay, Captain.
– What's with her?
– Dunno.
Maybe it was a bad call to let
Makimura-san into our club, after all?
Kozue.
You seem different…
I'll make it work.
For our victory…
and for Makimura-san.
I won't give up, Ayuhara-san.
I'll prove that volleyball is worthless
and can be played by anyone.
I can't believe that the dignified Makimura-san
has fallen asleep during the class.
Right?
I heard that it's because
of Ayuhara Kozue.
I heard she puts her
through hellish training.
They call her
"the demon captain".
Shh!
The whole school
is already talking about it.
Maybe Kozue is a little overzealous
in her new role as captain?
What…?
I'm just taking my training very seriously.
Stop spouting nonsense.
Nonsense?
What's with you two?
Captain. Hayakawa-san, you too.
I'm just telling you that as a friend.
The whole school's already gossiping about it.
Thank you, but now let's focus on
the tournament that's just around the corner.
From now on we'll train
30 minutes longer.
Got it, girls?
30 minutes?
Now, back to practice!
Come on! One more!
There's more!
Once more!
What are you doing?
What's that?
He's from the newspaper club.
That photo can't leak out.
Hey, you!
Hand over the film.
Right now.
– Did anybody give you permission?
– Yeah, that was low!
Wait up.
Spare you energy and let him be.
We're almost done.
Continue!
Ayuhara-san really is a demon.
If they post pictures of us like that,
our club will get criticized even more.
Kozue sure has changed.
If this goes well,
I'll be able to destroy her in one go.
– Check that out.
– Whoa, man…
New Captain's Tough Love
So that's how they practice…
"New Captain's Tough Love", huh?
Can you believe they're girls?
Yeah, I wouldn't have guessed
a girl could be so ruthless.
Hey, speak of the devil.
Don't look in her eyes.
You'll provoke her.
What are we gonna do?
It's a nail in the coffin.
This is no longer
only Kozue's problem.
Our entire club is at stake.
What's my problem, exactly?
Kozue!
I don't think we have time for this.
But, Captain!
Captain.
Let's go…
Huh? Me, playing volleyball?
Look for yourself.
It's all here.
W-What is our school's
newspaper doing here?
A girl from your school
has left it today in the clinic.
I already had my suspicions.
I saw you putting ointment on your bruises
in the middle of the night.
I'm sorry.
But I have my reason—
Spare me your excuses.
You have betrayed
my expectations.
You fed me lies that you were
staying late in the library studying.
I won't forgive you.
Our family is elite.
You have to get into a good university,
and then become a good wife—
Enough!
I'm not your doll, Mother.
Kyouko!?
Same goes to my brother.
You forced him to quit
tennis against his will.
He got into a good university, fine!
But then he got ill!
Kyouko!
What are you talking about?
I've had it.
My life is not yours to dictate.
From now on,
I'll be making my own decisions.
Kyouko.
Kyouko!
Kyouko…
Don't play volleyball, Kyouko.
No matter what Mother says,
I don't want to lose against Ayuhara-san.
I got a call from your mother.
Huh?
Whether you leave or stay
is your choice.
But before you decide,
I want you to take last 10 serves from me.
It'll be a match
just between you and me.
Ten serves.
Fine.
Midori, toss me the ball.
Huh?
A spike, then a direct reception?
Hurry up.
Now you'll show your true colors.
Just like I hoped you would.
Here I go.
Okay!
You pass the first serve,
more or less.
Next!
Stand up!
I won't lose.
I can do it.
Both of them are dead serious…
That's enough, Kozue.
We still have three serves left.
Toss the ball.
Fine, I'll do it myself.
Stand up!
Two serves left!
Stop.
– That's enough, don't you think?
– Yeah.
Your match is over.
Chief…
Makimura-san!
Hang in there.
Ah! That's awful!
I lost the match.
But you all saw her true colors.
Your oh-so-great captain.
How much of a horrible egoist she is.
You're wrong.
– Oonuma-san.
– Oonuma-san!
Makimura-san, you might have won
the school newspaper, but here, it's your loss.
Huh?
Ayuhara-san has been doing this
with you in mind.
You, on the other hand,
have taken the route of a coward.
Ayuhara-san… what?
It's Ayuhara-san
who noticed your talent.
She wanted to make you
into a regular player at our club.
Me, a regular player?
– Huh?
"Everyone here is my enemy."
She certainly didn't use
gentle manners…
…but she tried her best to change that attitude
and make you into a part of the team.
It was a hard trial that Ayuhara-san
imposed on herself.
Don't you still believe me?
You just saw your team mates
stand up for you.
Who do you think
you owe that to?
– I see it now…
– So that's how it was…
Ayuhara-san!
New captain's first job is over.
In the end, my feelings
didn't reach Makimura-san.
Ayuhara-san!
– Ayuhara-san!
– Makimura-san!
Captain!
Now I understand everything, Captain.
Captain…
Kozue!
– Kozue!
– Captain!
While Kyouko
reconciled with Kozue…
…she remains conflicted with her mother
regarding her entrance to the volleyball club.
One day, despite her daughter's protest, Kyouko's
mother storms the club and approaches Kozue.
The only thing she cares about is to get
Kyouko into a top grade university.
A raging conflict occurs between her and Kozue,
who's trying to live her youth to the fullest.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.