苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 068—
Birth of a New Trio
– Ayuhara-san!
– Oh?
Ayuhara-san.
Did you finally understand?
Captain…!
Makimura-san.
So you know…?
Captain. Captain…
Makimura-san.
Makimura-san…
How reckless!
What's a taxi doing here?
Who could that be?
Wow, she's wearing a kimono.
Volleyball Club
What a stench.
Is this your dressing room?
Huh? My mother's here?
Are you sure it's Makimura-san's mother?
Yes. She's in the locker room.
What are you going to do,
Makimura-san?
Huh? Yeah.
It's just like I feared.
Excuse me, Captain.
I'll be back soon.
I'll go with you.
Continue with your practice, girls.
Got that?
Yes.
I'm begging you.
Kyouko.
I heard you.
But I already answered you
this morning before going to school.
But, Kyouko!
I don't have much time.
There are only three days until the tournament.
Three days!
N-Now you're up in a tournament?
Yes, and that's why I need you
to stop wasting my time with your drivel.
Drivel…?
What I'm saying is drivel to you?
Yes. Right now, it is.
W-Why…?
I only want what's best for you.
So wanting you to get into a top-notch
college is drivel…?
Calling, studying, it's all drivel…?
I can't believe it.
You can cry all your want
but that won't change my mind.
It just proves how little
you care about my feelings.
This conversation is over.
Let's go, Captain.
Ma'am…
Please let Makimura-san do
what she wants.
This is your fault.
Huh?
You're the one who ruined
Kyouko's chances for a good future.
What did we ever do to you?
How it going in there?
Tell me.
She sacrifices her studying
to play ball with you girls.
Now is the most crucial time for her studying.
I know that.
I'm a student just like she is.
But, you have to understand…
Watch your tongue, young lady.
I can't believe
the way you're talking to me.
But you're misunderstanding the nature of sports.
Working with everyone towards a common goal
is completely different than studying by yourself.
But that isn't what she needs right now.
No. Sports are the most important
when we're still young.
There's no way we can do it
once we grow older.
Nothing is worth giving up on your education. Not even sports.
No matter how much I try talking to you…
…you just won't understand my message.
Our ways of thinking are completely different.
That's why I came here to bring Kyouko home.
And I'm telling you…
I'm telling you it's useless.
Your Kyouko won't quit volleyball.
How do you know?
Is this the stance you're taking?
It's so irresponsible.
I can't believe you're their captain.
Makimura's mother was
at the end of her rope, wasn't she?
She just couldn't reach an understanding
with Ayuhara and the rest of the team.
Excuse me, but…
…frankly, I don't understand
that woman myself either.
Of course not, after all, you're their coach
and you need to support them.
But I'm willing to bet that in the exam period,
any other teacher would agree with her.
What kind of person are you hoping to raise
if you focus only on education, Professor?
You're seeing it wrong.
I want to give my pupils a good start
by getting them into best schools possible.
It's my way of showing affection for them.
Oh?
By best schools,
you mean prep schools?
Hongou-kun!
I just can't get this into my head…
I wonder if Makimura-kun
gave up on going to college?
Seems like it since she
went and joined the volleyball club.
Well, technically, I guess women getting accepted
into good schools is an empty dream anyway.
So only boys can go to universities?
Is that what you're trying to say?
Well I think that it's good
that she's playing volleyball.
Did you hear that Makimura-san's
mother was here yesterday?
Yeah, she almost tore their club apart!
She must've been one energetic old lady.
Makimura-san!
Ah, I'm sorry.
Don't apologize.
Makimura-san,
treasure your tenacity and fight!
Yes.
The qualifiers start tomorrow,
so I wanted us to take it easy today.
But I was wrong.
One more round!
Yes.
I'm thinking of making Makimura-san
into a regular player.
Regular That's a bit too soon, don't you think?
I guess. And her form was really poor today.
But, then again, the school gossiping about what happened
with her mother might be getting to her.
I want to make her
feel better about herself.
You're the captain.
It'll be fine.
Makimura-san will
catch up in no time.
I know she can do it.
Also, I'll be there to cover for her
in her first two or three games. Right, Kozue?
Huh? Cover for her?
Isn't that the reason you put her
on the court with me today?
You realized?
We've known each other for so long,
I can basically read your mind.
You can count on me, okay?
Even if it takes a little time,
she'll become a great player for our team.
Yeah, I think that, too.
Makimura Clinic
Good boy.
Kyouko?
Ah… I'm home.
Hey. Kyouko, wait.
Is she finally home?
She's been coming home very late these days.
What should we do, Dear?
You should try talking to her, too.
Later. I have to finish the report
for the conference.
You always dump the parenting on me.
Kyouko…
Ahh.
I hate that I have to sneak around
just to go to my room.
Brother…
Congrats.
Precision was always your strong point.
Want me to be your coach?
What?
You rascal!
I see you're getting ahead of yourself.
City Gymnasium
Can we expect another Fujimi victory today?
Tournament Qualifying Venue
Or will the debuting
Enshū High School surprise us?
Fujimi · Enshū
I don't think we have to worry,
but they sure are motivated.
I wonder when they'll notice.
Last!
Chance!
Listen closely.
Pay attention to their player no. 11.
Huh?
They're going to mark Makimura-san.
They're marking Makimura?
Should we get her off the court?
Makimura-san?
No, we'll handle it, Coach.
Alright. I'll leave it to you.
Makimura, don't fail us.
Precision was always your strong point.
Makimura-san,
treasure your tenacity and fight!
Wow!
Pass!
It's coming!
Attack!
Nice!
And Fujimi wins the first match!
You have what it takes,
Makimura-san!
Really! Your last reception
was super awesome.
Fujimi · Enshū
Ah, I'm so glad.
The first match is over.
Oh?!
A strange person…
But why'd did he take a photo of me jumping?
I wonder who that was…
He looked too strange
to be a reporter.
Also, why'd he take a picture of just me in here?
Oh?
It's Brother.
It's Brother!
When did you get back, Brother?
Hey. Just a second ago.
I forced Mom to take me here.
Are you going to stay here?
Yes, but only until I get better.
Are you okay, Brother?
I'll get you something.
Don't be silly.
I don't need you to be my nurse.
I'll get back to tennis soon.
That's good to hear.
I see you're back, Kyouko.
Welcome back.
Oh, and I heard you're playing volleyball, Kyouko.
How was your game today?
Tell me every detail.
Come on, I want to hear it.
I heard from Mom
that you were playing a game.
Please refrain from taking about
volleyball while you're here.
I see you haven't changed, Mom…
See? That's what happens
when you talk too much…
That's not it.
You're way too overprotective, Mom.
But you know I'm right.
You should rest.
Let's get you into bed.
No, no, I'm fine, Mom.
Moderate exercise.
Appropriate nutrition.
Right no, that's the best medicine for me, Mom.
I-I know, I know.
But still…
It's okay.
At least let me finish my tea.
Mother…
She doesn't see how she's bothering Brother.
Kyouko. Don't just stand here.
Don't you have to study?
Yes, yes.
Kyouko…
Don't be such a nag, Mom.
Misawa · Fujimi
Fujimi High vs. Misawa Academy.
It's a match between mutual enemies.
Both teams have assumed their positions,
awaiting the whistle.
The game's about to start any second.
Mihara-san.
Long time no see, Ayuhara-san.
I'll show you how good my team has become.
I have worked hard
since the last time.
I have worked hard too, Ayuhara-san.
Let's have a good match.
Their strength is on par with ours.
But the more experienced team
players will end up taking the win.
Stay calm, girls!
We can do this!
Yeah!
I can see the ball very well today.
I'll be fine.
Oh, Kyouko…
Ah! Kyouko!
It was a very light serve.
Don't worry.
You should be sitting.
Attack!
Doesn't she feel any pain?
Damn!
Wow, Fujimi High School team's
players really are fabulous.
Don't you think so too, Mom?
But Captain Ayuhara
scores all the points by herself.
Haha. Mom, it's everyone on the team,
including Kyouko, who make this possible.
She spiked the ball that Kyouko received.
Are you okay?
Yes.
I'm feeling great right now.
Let's change. Go forward.
Okay.
Huh? It's him again.
It's the man that took a photo of me.
H-He's gone!
Ayuhara, what's wrong?
Where are you looking at?
Ah, over there.
Why? What for?
Nice!
Kozue!
Makimura picked it up!
Kyouko!
You did great.
Makimura-san!
It's coming.
Got it.
Over to you!
Attack!
Kyouko.
Ah?
M-Mother…
Mother is here.
Along with my brother.
One!
Two!
Last…!
Makimura-san!
Volleyball, it's bigger than a tennis ball.
So I can receive it precisely.
Kyouko…
Attack!
Alright, Makimura!
Excellent!
Fujimi defeats Misawa
and advances to the next round.
The spotlight today belongs to Makimura Kyouko
and her excellent assistance to Captain Ayuhara.
She's a great successor to prior Captain Oonuma,
who had left the team just a little ago.
A loud applause sounds thorough the gymnasium.
Misawa · Fujimi
Let's properly welcome our new
regular player, Makimura-san!
Let's get along!
You were great, Makimura-san.
Thank you.
But I got a lot of help from
Ayuhara-san, Hayakawa-san and everyone else.
Just the opposite.
It's you who covered for them.
I'm a bit jealous, Makimura-san.
Huh?
I had to let go of volleyball
to be able to focus on mu entry exams.
But you chose the opposite path.
– Good game.
– See you later.
Huh?
Mihara-san…?
I'll go ahead, Kozue.
Mihara-san.
What happened today, Ayuhara-san?
It felt like you weren't
your usual self today.
Like you didn't show me your true skill.
I'm sorry you had to see me like that.
No, don't mention it.
It's just that you're a role model to my team.
Me, a role model?
Yes. Everyone at our little volleyball club
wants to play like you.
To tell you the truth, if it wasn't for you,
I would have quit volleyball a long time ago.
That's all.
Please win the tournament for us.
A-Alright.
I wanted to win against you just once.
Mihara-san…
I saw my dream today.
What do you mean?
My dream has always been
to play tennis at the Davis Cup.
Today, I saw that dream in Kyouko.
But that was Kyouko, not you.
No…
My body has grown weak
and I can no longer pursue my dream.
Kyouko does it right.
She does what she wants.
That's a very egoistic point of view.
That's right.
I'm egoistic and I stand by it.
Kyouko!
Really, Kyouko…
A strange man with a camera?
I wonder why'd he take photos of you.
I understand reporters,
but he was just focused on me.
Hmm…
Maybe he's a fan of yours?
Kozue, maybe you're going to get proposed to?
Are you serious?
Here I am opening up to you
and you make fun of me.
I think you've been a little too tense
ever since becoming captain.
We have the tournament on our plate now.
So you'd better think up some strategies for it.
I am thinking about them.
I know. It's the birth of the new trio:
Ayuhara · Hayakawa · Makimura. Right?
Hehe. Midori.
That's a great idea. Let's do this!
– Let's do our best.
– Yeah!
A mysterious photographer targets Kozue.
On the train that goes to the competition venues.
During training sessions in Tōkyō.
Kozue is constantly bothered
by an elusive shadow.
"This cannot continue."
Kozue makes that firm resolution in her mind
while working hard at the practices.
But she doesn't realize
that even scarier things await her.
Please look forward to the next episode!
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.