苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 069—
The Black Shadow Approaches
Let's see…
Hmm.
I'd say the main obstacles are…
Fukouka and Jidōin.
Then Kanagawa Girls' High School.
It's a pair.
We'll get to play with Sanjōu-san again.
And let's not forget about Tōnan.
Still, it's a pity that Shirakawa-san and Aoba
have lost in the preliminaries.
Ayuhara-san, I can see your cards.
Oh?
Wow, Captain has a joker.
I'll be safe for a while.
I usually take money for stuff like that, you know!
Well, you won't get
a single penny from me.
Hey, what do you think about this pose?
It looks pretty cool.
Attack!
Maybe I'm worrying too much?
Or maybe he was sent by another team?
Ayuhara-san.
Huh?
Here, it's your turn.
Pick a card.
Come on, speed it up.
Now it's my turn.
Let's see, let's see…
Maybe this one…
Oh!
Got it!
It's the joker!
That's why I didn't want to play old maid.
I even knew you had the joker and I still picked it…
Alright.
Let's grab something to eat.
Look, over there!
Ah!
Hey, mister!
Wait!
– Wait for us!
– Mister!
How many do you want?
Oh, there you are.
We'd like to buy some.
Oh, four sets. Just perfect.
We'd like them all.
W-Wait!
We were here first.
Yeah, but we're ordering now.
Find someplace else.
Where else can we buy breakfast?
Those servings were the last.
We've sold every one today.
First come, first serve.
You cut in the line!
Yeah, you robbed that food from us.
What?
Watch who you're talking to, girls.
Don't you know the name of
Shirakawa Academy?
Oh, we heard about it.
They're famous for their weak teams.
They're going to participate at the Interhigh.
Huh?!
We belong to the volleyball club
at Shirakawa Academy.
That explains everything.
We've been told that you guys are all mouth.
You had it coming.
Wanna fight?
Yeah, provoking us is a bad idea!
Naka, Ishimatsu.
Back off.
But, Chief!
Those bimbos…
"Bimbos"…?
I apologize for them.
Hmph.
Oh.
I think I've seen you somewhere?
Aren't you that Ayuhara
from the Junior World Cup?
I see.
You're Fujimi High's captain.
So you're Fujimi High…?
You're going to Tōkyō
with us to compete, right?
That's correct.
I heard your school was terrible.
But the real thing is even worse than the rumors.
"Chief"…
"Ishimatsu"…
It's like you're from some yakuza movie.
Let's go.
I'm starving.
My fists are ready for some action.
I think your stomach could use it more.
C-Captain…
I'll give you my breakfast.
Really? You will?
Yes. My mom has made a lot of onigiri.
If you're hungry,
you should have just said so.
You're so reliable.
Your mom is the best.
Captain, you're my happiness.
Shirakawa Academy?
Yes, I heard of them.
They're know for their rough playing style.
AThey're like a men's team.
We just met with some of their team.
Yeah.
I heard about it from Hayakawa.
She told me you had a fight.
Yes.
But I can't blame Ishimatsu and Naka
for getting angry with them.
"Looking at the results from the qualifiers,
we're bound to win."
That cocky attitude
won't lead to anything good.
Tell this to Ishimatsu and Nakazawa:
If you have so much energy,
use it on the court.
Yes sir.
Oh?
We're passing Yokohama.
Better start preparing.
Yes sir.
It's them.
That's the Fujimi team over there.
Which one is the "Chief"?
It's the one with yellow hairband.
You think she's glaring at us?
Wow, how scary.
Are they even a team?
Ayuhara-san, don't let it get to you.
Fight your battles on the court.
Isn't that what Coach said?
You're right.
Umegaoka Senior High School
Fujimi High School training session
Here goes!
Alright, that's enough warming up.
Let's move on to offensive training.
Yes sir.
Strong attackers prefer to stay
on the left side of the front line defenders.
But Ayuhara is ambidextrous
so she doesn't need to go by the book.
I should focus on how to make
the best use of Makimura.
Her impressive speed lets her excel at receptions.
but her spikes still need polishing.
Maybe if I put her in the setter position,
she could fill the gap Oonuma left?
Setter… it's a very important
and responsible position.
She has to be able to assess the situation quickly
and pass the ball to the spiker at the best time.
Here I go!
Can she do it?
We have Ayuhara.
She'll be able to fend off the attacks.
As a setter, she only has to toss at Ayuhara.
As long as we have Ayuhara,
Makimura can be a successful setter.
So cool.
Kozue, once more.
Sure.
Great.
It's no good…
The real thing will be different.
You'll get back on track in no time.
I know.
But it's not just that.
There's something in the back of my mind
that keeps bugging me.
Midori.
Let's try again!
Alright, I'm fine now.
So it was the sound of the shutters.
This isn't like you, Ayuhara Kozue.
When did you become so panicked?
Ah, Midori, you go on ahead.
I forgot something.
Okay.
L-Let go of me!
Let me go!
Help! Somebody save me!
Somebody… Somebody…!
She's late.
Huh?
I wonder if Kozue's still training…
It's gotten so dark outside.
Damn, what if she got assaulted?
What?
Yeah, by some molester.
I mean, Chief is really beautiful and popular.
I'm gonna check up on her.
I'll go with her.
Me too!
What a rough girl.
Any trouble on the back?
No.
She inhaled so much of the stuff
she'll be knocked out for a while.
But she scared me to death.
I almost let her escape.
She hit me like a volleyball, too.
My wrist's all numb.
Where should I park?
Where there will be no audience.
Oh?
What is this place?
What am I doing?
You're Tsutomu-kun.
Tsutomu-kun, it's you.
Why are you here?
Ah, I know.
You're here to drive us, right?
Why are you laughing, Tsutomu-kun?
Tsutomu-kun.
You're that man.
You photographed me at the Interhigh.
You're the one who's been stalking me.
Oh?
That's not it…
Tsutomu-kun…
Tsutomu-kun…!
Someone!
What should I do?
Help!
Papa! Mama! Midori!
Make it stop!
This isn't good.
She's regaining consciousness.
I'm still inside that truck?
I can't move.
I see you're awake.
It'll be over in a moment.
Hey, no talking.
Who is that man?
He looks like a doctor.
He's using a computer.
What are they examining me for?
Besides, that photographer…
I bet they were sent by some team.
Since I can't do anything right now,
I'll at least try to remember your faces.
This is incredible.
Huh? What is?
She has equal muscle strength
in both of her arms.
Really, it's ideal reading for a spiker.
Ah.
Now I remember.
We were once examined
with an electromyogram before.
Alright, I'm finished.
Detour
Hold it! Wait!
Who are you people?
Which school hired you?
They're stuck.
It's now or never.
Damn…
Alright!
Hey, watch it!
I'm sorry!
Hey!
You're Fujimi's captain, right?
You're that girl from Shirakawa Academy…
Let go of me!
They got away.
For crying out loud!
If only that girl from Shirakawa
didn't get in my way…
Hey, you.
Where are you manners?
How about an apology?
Apology? For what?
You've got some nerve.
"For what", she says.
You just bumped into me, remember?
But that's all because of that truck…
I know. Of course.
It was you.
"Of course"?
Why don't you fight fair and square,
like the fellow high school students we are?
Kidnapping me and making me go through
some examinations… it's all like a bad movie.
What is she talking about?
I don't have a clue,
but I don't like it.
Don't play dumb!
If you were innocent…
You wouldn't… There's no way
you would show up right here, right now.
What's wrong with you?
Our hotel is just over there.
We just wanted to get some fresh air.
I'm done listening to your excuses, you scum!
Say what?
Watch it, Ayuhara!
We won't ignore the name calling.
Who do you think you're talking to?
To you.
To the Shirakawa Academy's volleyball club!
I didn't quite hear you.
Fine, let me repeat it for you.
Scum!
What's your problem?
Are you okay?
Chief. Chief!
I'm here.
Chief…
Shirakawa's coach says he won't sit around and
accept that one of his best players has been injured.
I see.
What are we going to do?
Chief, say something…
I have no idea.
We just have to wait for Professor Hongou.
Kozue. They kidnapped you and studied
your body with an EMG against your will.
They have to be punished!
True, but none of them
are willing to admit that they did it.
The situation would look a lot
better if only we had some proof.
But we don't have any, do we?
Chief…?
I'm trying to think,
but everything's is a blur now.
What a mess.
If Shirakawa presses the matter…
It might be possible that
the committee will suspend you.
Suspend?
Captain, Shirakawa's coach just left.
What did Professor Hongou say?
Uh, I'll go again and ask.
It was very nice of you to come.
If they take it to the committee, we'll lose unless
we prove they're linked to the kidnapping case.
But if we don't, she'll get suspended for sure.
What do I do…?
We're going to the committee.
So you can kiss good-bye to the tournament.
No… Don't!
Please… Anything but that!
It's too late.
Fujimi Academy will lose in the first match.
Serves you right.
Please, don't! Spare us!
And why should I listen to you?
Rot in hell, you cow.
No! No!
Somebody save me!
You're finished.
Save me!
What's wrong, Kozue?
You're sweating like crazy.
Oh, Midori…
I just had a nightmare. It was terrible.
A nightmare?
Kozue, are you still thinking
about that kidnapping?
What are we going to do if Professor Hongou
gets called before the tournament committee?
It'll be fine, Kozue.
Even if it happens,
you haven't done anything wrong.
Come on Kozue…
Don't think about it too much.
It's a hazy moon.
I feel as if someone's watching me.
W-Why am I the only one
who was targeted?
Kozue!?
This isn't good.
Kozue's losing it.
If this keeps on,
she'll hinder the game against Kanagawa.
Kozue.
If you don't get a grip, we'll all fall apart.
Ah.
I'm sorry, Midori.
Kozue, you must be tired.
I think you should go to sleep.
You're right.
Thank you.
First that suspicious photographer, now this.
One weird thing keeps happening after another.
Something's got to be up.
I'm sure of it.
The incident with Kozue
is revealed to public.
And Hongou announces that he's pulling
Kozue out of the first match.
This decision deals a shocking blow
to the team as well as Kozue herself.
Their first match is against Sanjou
and Kanagawa Girls' High School.
The match begins
accompanied by Kozue's anxiety.
Please look forward to the next episode!
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.