苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 070—
Kozue's suspension
Fujimi High School
Volleyball Club Guest Room
Listen up, girls.
I believe you all know about the incident
with Ayuhara from the last night.
This morning, I received a summons
from the committee regarding this matter.
The committee?
This is serious…
Silence!
You're to continue with your training
during my absence.
Especially you, Makimura.
Y-Yes sir.
I want your toss to be flawless.
– Got it?
– Yes sir.
Ayuhara.
Assist Makimura in her training.
Make sure that her toss
is precise like a razor.
Yes sir.
What's going on?
I should be practicing attacks
for tomorrow's game.
Hayakawa.
You'll practice attacking from Makimura's toss.
Understood, Hayakawa?
Y-Yes sir!
Professor Shimizu.
I'm leaving the rest to you.
Okay.
Alright, girls. Let's leave the matter
of Ayuhara-san's incident to Professor Hongou.
Instead, let's finish eating earlier
and hurry up onto the court.
An emergency meeting
assembled by the tournament committee.
Ah!
We're going to the committee.
You can kiss good-bye to the tournament.
– Fujimi Academy will lose in the first match.
– Serves you right.
Tōto Daily
Editorial Room
This is Tōto sports section.
I have interesting information
about Ayuhara Kozue.
Hello? I can't hear you very well.
I wanted to tell you about
an incident with Ayuhara Kozue.
What? An incident with Ayuhara?
Excuse me, but who the hell are you?
Doesn't matter. Did you know that Shirakawa
called an emergency meeting with the committee?
What meeting?
I don't know about any of this.
I see. Then go to Tōzai Tower at 10 o'clock,
to the conference room on the fifth floor.
You won't regret it.
Hello? Hello?!
Who are you?
He hung up.
It might be a prank,
but it won't hurt to check it.
Murata, you knew Fujimi's Hongou
in your college days, didn't you?
Yes, I did.
I just got a call about Ayuhara.
Go to Tōzai Tower.
Check the conference room at the fifth floor.
Did something happen with Hongou?
No, looks like Ayuhara has done something.
It might turn out into a good scoop.
Ayuhara?
Man, I didn't see this coming.
Do you have any idea
what we're gonna find, Murata-san?
I don't know it myself either.
All I know that there was some incident
with Ayuhara Kozue of Fujimi Academy…
…and Shirakawa assembled a meeting
with the committee in this regard.
Fujimi Academy, huh?
They made it out of the preliminaries.
That Ayuhara is their captain, right?
And they've taken it to the committee…
We might have found a real gem.
It's still nine.
We still have some time.
Alright. Why don't we stop by the gym
to see Fujimi Academy's practice?
You want to meet with Ayuhara Kozue?
I'd like to talk to Hongou, if he's there.
Good, Makimura-san.
Keep it up.
I wonder how the meeting goes…
Kozue!
Oh?
Ah!
I've done a terrible thing,
even if it wasn't intentional.
What if they pull me out of the match now…
Suspension.
Suspension!
Fujimi Academy… without Ayuhara-san?
Fujimi · Kanagawa
Fujimi loses their first match.
Thanks for letting us win, Ayuhara-san.
Don't look so grim.
Come on, let's train.
Oh? Yeah, sure.
I'm sorry for making you worry.
Let's do our best!
Good girl.
Makimura-san, are you ready?
Toss the ball at this spot!
Okay!
Ayuhara-san, please pass the ball.
Attack!
That was great.
Once more!
Are you Ayuhara Kozue-kun?
Oh?
Y-Yes, I am.
And you are…?
I'm Murata of Tōto Sports.
Where is Coach Hongou?
He's not here. He has a meeting with
the tournament committee.
He went already?
That's too bad.
Okay, let me ask you instead.
It seems something serious happened yesterday.
Can you tell us what was it?
But nothing has happened.
What's up?
Oh, you're from the press?
Did you get wind of it already?
Got wind of it?
So we were right.
I told you, nothing has happened.
Y-Yeah!
Why are you here?
You write whatever suits you, anyway!
That's harsh.
I studied with Hongou at college.
I thought I could lend a hand, so I dropped by.
As if I'm going to believe you.
Time for you to leave.
You're disturbing our training.
Never show your faces here again.
Leave at once!
Get the hell out!
I scared them away.
But I wonder why they were here?
Alright, I'll go spy on them.
W-Wait, Ishimatsu!
The press is already on the move.
We've reached a point
where plain apology won't suffice.
Professor Hongou…
Please, do something.
Interhigh Committee Meeting
Authorized Persons Only
It is unquestionable that your team's captain has
badly injured one of my most important players.
It's so bad she won't be able
to show up in the match.
How are you planning to take
the responsibility, Hongou-san?
I understand and acknowledge the allegations
of Shirakawa Academy's coach.
However, it is apparent that Ayuhara Kozue was
a subject to a great mental shock at the moment.
She misunderstood the situation
and caused an accident in confusion.
She didn't act out of malice.
For this reason—
Just a second.
So what if it was a misunderstanding?
It doesn't change anything for us.
First of all…
I know what you're trying to say.
But let's not forget why we're here.
It doesn't concern just Shirakawa Academy.
First and foremost, we should try together to
make the tournament go as smooth as possible.
How about we take a vote how to proceed?
We'll decide what to do with Ayuhara.
Whether to let her play
or suspend her.
Maybe we should let her?
I don't know.
I agree.
Let's begin.
Those who are for that Ayuhara is only warned and
thus can continue to participate in the tournament…
…I ask you now to raise your hand.
Those who are against, please keep your hand down.
By the decision of the absolute majority, the incident
with Ayuhara doesn't interfere with the tournament.
We'll allow her to stay.
Please wait, Chairman!
I know it's not my place to stay
against the decision of the committee…
Professor Hongou must have ordered
this training in anticipation of my suspension.
No… Even if that was the case,
he'll do something about it.
Please, Professor.
Please get them not to suspend me.
What takes them so long…
Yeah, it's been going on
for two hours already.
I wonder what they're going to say.
No idea.
Ah, they're still in the meeting.
I wonder if Professor Hongou succeeded?
How was the meeting,
Professor Hongou?
Did you reach an agreement?
Please, give us something.
It was about Ayuhara, right?
Hongou.
Oh, it's you, Murata.
Long time no see.
What happened?
It concerns Ayuhara, doesn't it?
Yes.
You'll know sooner or later,
so I'll tell it now.
Ayuhara Kozue badly injured
a prominent player from Shirakawa.
Now she's going to take responsibility
as a consequence.
She won't show up in the first match
of the tournament.
Huh?
Huh?!
Alright, here we go.
Are you ready?
Yeah!
Good. Makimura-san,
remember that timing.
You and Midori were in perfect sync.
Let's take a short break.
I owe it to you, Ayuhara-san.
Your reflexes are incredible.
Just one last push.
You can improve your trajectory even further.
Yeah. I'll work on it.
Oh, look at the time.
It's already eleven o'clock.
I was so focused on the training
I completely forgot about time.
I know, right?
This must be why I'm feeling
a hole in my stomach.
I'm sorry.
Let's have lunch, girls.
I'm starving!
Me too.
We'll get back here
after we eat.
What do you think is taking
Ishimatsu so long, Midori?
Professor Hongou, too…
They must be having lunch somewhere.
I see. I understand.
Even so, what you did there was
completely daring.
Yeah.
Believe me it wasn't an easy decision to make.
There's no going back now.
I just hope you're not
underestimating your team.
If Fujimi lost in the first game,
all your efforts would go to waste.
I know that, of course.
But I hope that this will give
them more motivation.
If we lose in the very first match
just because we pulled Ayuhara out…
…it only means we've never
stood a chance to begin with.
Yeah…
By the way, you wanted to talk
about Ayuhara and that EMG incident.
Yes.
I'd like to ask you for a favor.
I want to find out who was behind this
and why they did it.
Do you suspect anybody?
No.
If Ayuhara's EMG data
was leaked out to the public…
…it'd be of great benefit
to every team in the tournament.
It'd be so disadvantageous to us
that it might directly translate into our loss.
In short, this information is something
the other teams may be after.
I can't say for sure,
but that'd be my main bet.
This is where I could use your help.
I understand.
I'll get to it at once.
I'll let you know when I find something.
Please do.
I don't need to tell you not to tell anyone
what we've talked about here.
Sure.
Kanagawa High School
Volleyball Club Room
Attention.
I just received an information…
…that Ayuhara Kozue of Fujimi Academy was
suspended for tomorrow's game due to a fight.
Wow!
I was expecting a difficult struggle,
but it seems it'll be an easy victory for us.
What's wrong, Sanjou?
I know it's bad to take joy in people's misfortune,
but this means you'll be in a comfortable match.
Yes?
Yes sir.
Not at all. Ayuhara-san…
I refined my skills
so that I could defeat you.
So, no matter what,
you better show up tomorrow.
I'll be waiting for you.
I'm eager to compete
against your awesome play, Ayuhara-san.
Great! That's it!
Thanks.
They have no idea…
Let's call it a day, girls.
Just a little longer, Kozue.
Makimura-san's in good form, too…
It's okay, Midori.
It's enough.
I think it's better that
we take a good rest before tomorrow.
You have a point.
Alright, you won.
You were great, Makimura-san.
Thanks.
Still, Ishimatsu sure is late.
It's taking too long.
I'm sure things are bad.
Captain!
Ishimatsu.
Captain, you won't believe it.
What happened?
It's not like you, Ishimatsu.
They…
They decided to suspend you, Captain.
W-What?
One moment, Ishimatsu.
Y-You're taking your jokes too far.
Tell me you're just kidding. Right?
I wish I was.
That's what the committee
has decided, for real.
So it came to what I feared the most.
N-No way.
Did Coach Hongou
fail to persuade them?
Actually, the one who voted against leaving
Captain in the tournament… was Coach himself.
No, it can't be.
This is terrible.
Yeah.
I don't buy it.
You must be wrong.
There's no way Coach would do such thing.
At first I didn't believe it either.
So I asked twice to be sure, but…
But…
If they take Kozue away from us now,
we're done for.
Let's get back to the hotel.
Let's go.
Okay.
Coach, please explain it to us.
Is it true that you actually persuaded
them to suspend Captain?
Coach!
What were you thinking?
What are we going to do tomorrow?
Coach.
Do you think the game
tomorrow is that important?
What?
What do you mean, Coach?
Ayuhara.
What do you think?
Tell me what you think
about what I've done.
I… I'm not entitled to have an opinion
about your decisions, Professor.
It's just…
Just what?
If this leads to our loss
against Kanagawa tomorrow…
I'm against it.
Loss?
Don't get cocky!
Listen, Ayuhara.
What kind of decision would you have expected
if the situation had been the other way around?
B-But this is different!
I didn't ask you.
Well, Ayuhara?
What would you do if you had been injured
and your team had lost because of that?
But that was a misunderst—
Don't be stupid!
So what if it was a misunderstanding?!
We must take the responsibility nonetheless.
It's the least we can do to apologize to them.
Well?!
One last thing.
I didn't think for a second
that we'd lose the game without you.
Hayakawa.
Now that Ayuhara can't play…
…I'm making you their captain for tomorrow.
Got it?!
Huh…?
Kozue, what should I do?
This is hopeless.
There's no way we can win without you.
Please say something, Captain.
Makimura-san's toss,
Midori's attack.
How well will it work against Kanagawa?
Makimura-san has never played.
It'll be her fer first appearance in a match.
We have no other choice but to rely on her.
I'm sorry I dragged you all into this mess.
But I know you can do it.
Please win that game.
It's no use…
Our team is losing already,
before the real battle has even began.
In the end, we're nothing without Kozue.
Who is it so late?
Makimura-san practices
her toss all by herself.
Thank you, Makimura-san.
You're doing this for our team's sake…
Oh?
She can do it.
I know in my heart she can.
You're right, Kozue.
We'll surely win the first game.
I promise.
The first match, Kanagawa vs. Fujimi,
is about to begin.
Sanjou's serve opens the match!
Fujimi's reception.
It's a chance for Fujimi.
– Here, here!
– Go!
Truly regrettable.
Fujimi loses their chance.
Kanagawa · Fujimi
It was a complete miss.
Indeed.
The toss was completely mistimed.
As expected, the absence
of Ayuhara Kozue can be noticed easily.
In addition, Kanagawa has improved a lot
since they've played last time.
Especially Sanjou's spikes
have become really powerful.
And now we get to see
her second serve in this match.
I regret you couldn't make it
here today, Ayuhara-san.
But I won't hold back.
We're going to win.
Sanjou's long serve!
Nakazawa picks up the ball.
Another chance for Fujimi.
Makimura-san, over to you!
Attack!
No, no.
Makimura-san is hitting the ball too tensely.
The game will end in chaos like this.
Kanagawa · Fujimi
Another missed toss.
Fujimi Academy has already lost two points.
In the end, their team is powerless
without Ayuhara-san.
Kanagawa beautifully scores a point!
It's hard to believe!
Hayakawa touched the net.
Midori is nervous as expected.
Professor, why don't you ask for time?
T-This is bad.
We're too stressed.
I have to do something.
My misses threw everyone off balance.
What to do?
Kanagawa's splendid direct spike.
Fujimi is helpless.
They're completely overwhelmed.
4 to 0.
Makimura-san, what happened
to your yesterday's tenacity?
No, I shouldn't blame her.
Makimura-san looks
completely disheartened.
If this… If this keeps up,
we'll lose in our first match.
We're already so far back.
Coach, we need time!
I can't touch that ball even once.
This is absurd.
This is absurd…
Coach.
Why aren't you asking for time?
Why?
Why…?
The first round of the tournament
starts with Kozue missing.
It's Fujimi vs. Kanagawa.
The Midori · Makimura duo is powerless
against Sanjou's powerful spike.
Fujimi quickly loses the first set.
The second set begins.
The Fujimi team finally starts to bite back.
Kozue is relieved, but then the mysterious
photographer shows up again.
She leaves to chase him.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.