苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 071—
A Setter's Responsibility
Ayuhara.
Whatever the reason,
if you're aim to be a good sport…
…you're going to have to take responsibility for your actions.
We'll voluntarily pull Ayuhara out of our game
against Kanagawa Girls' High School tomorrow.
– We won't allow her on the bench either.
– Huh?
Listen to me, Ayuhara.
Sports should be respected.
Because of that, your kind of behavior
cannot be tolerated.
Cannot be tolerated.
Cannot be tolerated!
Kanagawa · Fujimi
Good luck, girls.
Midori, Makimura-san… I'm counting on you.
I practiced so hard, and yet
when push comes to shove, I can't do it.
Regrettably, Fujimi loses another chance
due to their sloppy play.
It seems like Makimura is rushing things too much.
Causing unnecessary complications to simple plays.
Kanagawa · Fujimi
But it is her first match, I suppose.
In my opinion,
she has great potential.
Five to zero.
Kanagawa scores another point.
They're demanding too much from her.
The players ask for time.
To tell you the truth,
I pity Makimura.
She has no experience with real matches.
Who could expect her to play at such a high level immediately?
Looks like coach Hongou is ignoring
the Fujimi players' request for time.
Why won't you call a timeout?
The more this continues,
the worse Makimura-san's form gets.
At least…
At least change out Makimura-san
and let her rest for a while.
Or give her some advice.
Just do something.
Kanagawa · Fujimi
We're going to lose the first set.
No, not just the first set.
We'll lose the entire first match.
Do something,
Professor Hongou.
Why won't you call a timeout?
Don't you have anything to say?
Professor.
Are you sure it's wise
not to ask for time here?
Professor…?
Calling time out won't give us any gain.
Huh?
It's just…
Just?
If only Makimura could demonstrate
all the skill she possesses…
Winning against Kanagawa
would be a breeze.
Even without Ayuhara.
But at the moment, it looks like
Makimura-san is completely powerless.
Exactly. Which is why I don't want to call a timeout.
Huh?
Look at her.
It's her first match and she's already,
expected to fill Ayuhara's void.
If I called a timeout or announced a change here,
Makimura would lose the rest of her confidence.
I'm afraid she might not ever get over it.
But we can't hope to win this way.
What you also need to realize
is that she's our only setter.
Makimura is also filling
the void left behind by Oonuma Miyuki.
Of course, there's a clear
difference in their abilities.
But we've got to make up for it somehow.
It's said that a burning man is capable of anything.
So that's what I'm trying to achieve!
By putting pressure on them?
Yes. I know they have
much more potential.
Soon enough they'll start to bite back.
That's why I won't help them any more.
Only they can help themselves.
They have to feel it.
So that's why you refuse to call a timeout?
Exactly.
And if we succeed here, all of the players
including Makimura will grow even more.
Only then can Fujimi hope to win.
But now?
Now they can't even
win the first match.
Kanagawa · Fujimi
But it might have been too big a gamble.
No! They can do it.
I believe in you, girls.
Please make it through this!
Toss!
Makimura-san!
Makimura dribbles.
Fujimi's setter, Makimura's
form is very bad today.
I can't help but wonder why Hongou
doesn't changed out Makimura already.
A toss!
And this time it connects!
Hayakawa's spike!
And a block!
Kanagawa blocks the spike easily.
It's pretty obvious that all the problems can be linked
to Makimura's lack of experience.
Damn.
First he pulls Ayuhara out,
and now he refuses to swap her?
What is Professor Hongou thinking?
Honestly, I can't figure out his plan either.
At this rate they're not just going
to lose the first set, but the second set, too…
Yeah, and Ayuhara's chance to get back to the court will go right along with it.
Ayuhara-san, I can only imagine
what you're going through.
But Hayakawa-kun is making mistakes, too.
It looks like she's afraid of the ball
when she spikes.
That's it. While it seems that
the problem lies with Makimura-san…
Now there's a problem with Hayakawa as well.
Huh? Hayakawa-san?
Midori expects too much from Makimura-san.
First, we urgently have to change
Hayakawa's defense strategy.
Right now Kanagawa's controlling the game.
Changing it at the last moment
may not be enough, though.
Yes. Professor, we have
to change the strategy for Midori.
Time!
Finally.
Hayakawa!
Sir!?
Professor...
Hayakawa Midori was called by Coach Hongou.
Is he going to swap her?
I don't think so.
What good would it do?
Still, Makimura seems to be at her limit.
Midori's… smiling?
He never scolded me before.
Makimura-san. Try to be more fluid
and natural in your movements when tossing.
Just try to raise the ball
as much as you can. Okay?
If you can do it,
I'll do the rest.
I believe in your toss.
Coach scolded me for putting you under
too much pressure with my high expectations.
Is that really it?
It's too late.
This will be the last point!
So let's get them!
Yeah!
It doesn't matter if we lose this set!
Let's show them hell!
Trying hard even in the face of defeat…
That's right.
Send the ball as high as possible.
I just have to get over my slump.
I can do it!
Then we'll catch up in the second set.
High!
The highest you can!
So high!
Another missed toss?
Attack!
What power!
It worked.
We finally did it!
That was easier than I thought.
You too, please hang in there
until I recover my toss.
Good. Great!
Perfect.
Looks like we still stand a chance.
Huh?
Reporters' section
He's that suspicious man from before.
So he's a reporter, after all?
He's sitting there and even has a sash.
Sun Sports
He's the reason why I can't participate
in today's game in the first place.
Huh?
He's here?
Fujimi's counterattacks tenaciously.
Another one of Hayakawa's
long spikes scores a point.
Keep it up.
You're doing great!
Professor…
Your last minute strategy change.
Looks like it served its purpose.
Alright, I can do this.
We'll be fine.
While it might be impossible
to catch up now…
…there's a ray of hope
for the second set.
15 to 7.
Even after being fiercely chased by Fujimi
in the last moments, Kanagawa wins the first set!
Now we're talking.
We can do this.
Let's keep it up into the second set.
Looks like they've regained their form.
Unbelievable.
They've scored 7 points.
But…
In the second set, we won't
give them a moment to breath.
I was scared you'd end up
with just one or two points.
Are you kidding us? There's no way
that'd happen with Ishimatsu around.
Correct. You can win even without Ayuhara.
If you work hard, that is.
But bear in mind that if you lose
the second set now, it's all over.
Finally, the second set…
Go! Go! Kanagawa!
If they lose now, it's all over.
The second set.
Can we really win?
It's sink or swim.
Losing in our first match…
It just can't happen.
I'll fight like a lion
for the sake of our team.
Damn!
Good job!
There it is! Hayakawa Midori's
trademark falling leaf.
What are you going to do, Sanjou-san?
That's not how you
should receive the falling leaf.
You should know that by now.
That's not enough.
– If we lose now…
– …it's game over.
There won't be
second chances.
Damn…
Stop worrying!
Listen to this cheering crowd!
Both sides are fighting for a single point,
and the public is going crazy!
We can't lose.
But we can't win like this either.
What's wrong?
Oh, it's nothing.
Just…
Just?
I don't think we can win like this.
Don't be silly.
It'll be fine.
You're thinking too much.
But…
I know! I'll try tossing a curve ball
to Hayakawa-san like Oonuma-san did.
Let's try!
Shoot…
Another missed toss from Makimura.
And just when it finally seemed like
she had regained her form…
What did she hope
to accomplish by tossing like that?
Maybe I can't throw curve balls
like Oonuma-san after all?
Makimura-san, that toss…
Was it…?
I'd like to try it once more.
Sure. Let's try it.
A curve ball toss, huh?
Nice thinking.
Fight, fight!
We'll leave it to you!
Amazing. They let me play my way
and motivate me in such a critical moment.
I'll make this succeed, no matter what.
I'm curious as to what she's going to do.
A curve ball toss…?
A curve ball toss!?
A curve ball?!
She did it!
Fantastic!
It was incredible!
If you can repeat that,
it'll be our victory.
Fabulous, Makimura-san!
It's the birth of a new duo!
I can't believe Fujimi is so strong
even without Ayuhara-san.
It seems that your decision was spot on.
Kanagawa · Fujimi
Fujimi's implacability allowed them
to win the second set.
An unbelievable transformation
from Makimura Kyouko.
It's the birth of a new duo in the
Fujimi team, the Hayakawa · Makimura duo.
I'm sure they'll get the third set—
Huh?
Excuse me,
But where is the press area?
Why are you ignoring me?
Maybe he's the man
Hongou has told me about?
If I want to find out who he is,
I have to reach him before he escapes.
Follow that car.
Oh!
Taxi!
Let's go too, Youko.
A newspaper company's armband
and now a sports car?
This just keeps getting more and more suspicious.
Excuse me, could you turn on the radio?
The station that's broadcasting
the volleyball match. Thank you.
Hayakawa's curve ball scores another point.
Fujimi slowly gains lead.
We've finally caught up.
Kozue took the taxi ahead.
Alright, pull over to the left.
Park the car and wait.
Huh?
I thought you wanted to follow me?
Now that he thinks he's no longer followed,
he should head straight to his destination.
But this area…
Oh? That's the place where
they threw me out of the truck.
This is where I met
the players from Shirakawa.
Sanjou's reception. Toss. Spike!
Fujimi blocks! How powerful.
Meanwhile, Kanagawa is powerless.
Huh?
Oh!
I made it this far…
Fourth floor?
No… Sixth floor?
Seventh…?
Eighth?
Tenth floor…
The new Hayakawa · Makimura's duo
cannot be compared with the first set.
And another spike!
Good for them.
But I have to keep looking.
This is hopeless.
There's no way I can find him here.
How am I supposed to find out where he went?
Ryuuji-san?
Oh, Ayuhara-san?
What are you doing here?
Same thing as you.
We're tailing a suspicious cameraman.
You too?
Yes, I tried to investigate him before.
You did?
I thought he might be
involved with Tōnan College somehow.
But now I'm sure of it.
Tōnan College?
Yes.
They own this place.
Huh?
I heard Tōnan gathers a lot of data on their
competitors and enters it into a computer.
Now that you mention it, I think I heard
someone call them "the computer college".
Fuji-san, if I'm not mistaken, you're going
to face them in the second game today.
Yes, that's correct.
That's why I had hoped that we would be able
to uncover their unfair methods before the game.
This time we're going
to fight with our own power.
Good luck.
You didn't hear it from me, but I admire how strong
Youko has gotten ever since she started training.
We think they have data on us as well, though.
Volleyball is not math.
Your opponents aren't computers,
they're human.
Yes. Exactly.
We'll show them they can't compute us.
Hayakawa's spike!
And it's another point.
We should get going
or we'll be late to our game.
Fuji-san...
Yeah, See you later,
up the tournament ladder.
Of course.
See you.
Ayuhara-kun.
Ayuhara-kun!
Oh? Murata-san.
Come here.
– Look at that truck.
– Huh?
That's the one where they kept me.
I knew it.
That's the nail in the coffin.
I think I finally have my scoop, Ayuhara-kun.
Are you going to write about it?
Y-You know how things work.
Then I'd like to ask you to wait
a bit before you publish it.
Huh?
If you expose them now,
Tōnan will get disqualified from the tournament.
But I want to face them in a match.
I want to show them that one can't win
at volleyball in such a sneaky way.
Game's over.
15 to 13.
Fujimi High emerges victorious!
And Kanagawa goes home.
Ayuhara-san, you have some
amazing team mates. Congratulations.
Thank you.
Thank you, everyone.
As Shirakawa's team, we're entirely satisfied
after hearing your genuine apology.
So?
Do you know who did it to you?
Yes.
I still don't have any definite proof,
so I'll keep it to myself.
I sincerely regret that I thought
it could be you.
I'm terribly sorry.
You don't have to apologize any more.
As long as you understand.
Besides, my wound has almost healed.
I should be able to play in our match tomorrow.
I see.
Thank goodness.
Can't you tell who it was, though?
Which team?
I'll let everyone know,
when I know for sure.
I'm sorry I doubted you.
Hey, hey, hey!
Big news!
Check this out!
Tōnan won!
They finished Kōtoku off like it was nothing!
Kōtoku? As in Fuji Youko?
That strong team?
They lost…?!
This is absurd.
We just talked.
She promised me they'd win.
I can't believe Kōtoku
could be defeated so easily.
Tōnan College is scary.
Tōnan College's careful and precisely orchestrated
actions send chills down your spine.
Kōtoku is powerless.
They've shown that they're just
as worthy winners as Jidōin and Fujimi.
Good performance and fighting spirit
will always prevail.
It's the essence of sports.
And yet, Tōnan tries to compute that…
I promise you that I will avenge your defeat.
A girl who came from the Okinawa archipelago,
Isahara Kana, possesses a deadly technique.
The triangular attack she had developed from
karate's "Principle of Triangle" stirs the Fujimi team up.
With the aim of returning to
her homeland in Okinawa…
…Kana's triangular attack conceals certain painful
memories that keep bursting onto Fujimi's court again and again.
Can Kozue defend against
this powerful new technique?
Please look forward to the next episode!
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.