苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 072—
The Okinawan attacker
It's the first time Mabunni High School from Okinawa
has qualified for the Interhigh volleyball tournament.
They won their first match 2 to 0.
In today's episode we'll be asking Captain Isahara
Kana about the current situation in Okinawa.
Good morning, Isahara-san.
Good morning.
I grew up in the southern part
of the main island of Okinawa.
I see.
It's quite hot there, isn't it?
Yes.
This is where the last large-scale battle
of the Pacific War took place.
People around here
must've had it rough.
A lot of vacant lands around here
were once inhabited by the families…
…that eventually
fell victim to the war.
I… see.
Fathers, mothers, old people
and children. Even babies.
There's not much working force left
to build new houses.
Or graves, for that matter.
I see.
That's horrible.
I feel so sorry for the people
who live there now.
We don't have time to pity them.
Yeah. Mabunni High
is a powerful team.
They crushed their opponents
in the first match like it was nothing.
It was Captain Isahara-san
who just talked, right?
Oh, yeah.
That's her, that's her!
They're going to show
their first game?
We'll see how they play.
I can't wait.
Well, they do have great power.
But their precision is lacking.
It appears that the Mabunni players
don't even realize that…
…but they made it so far owing
mostly to Isahara-san's power.
Impressive.
That's her spike!
Awesome.
Is it your own technique?
This is my triangular attack.
Let me see it again.
We've been winning so far
through this spike alone.
Go! Mabunni
A replay wouldn't kill them.
And yesterday,
it worked as expected—
No, it worked even better
than expected in your first match.
Yes.
But tomorrow you're facing Fujimi,
the favorite for this season.
Yes. The "favorite"
is a good way to put it!
Are you feeling confident?
Yes.
But they have Ayuhara Kozue
on their team—
Back in Okinawa, we played
against the United States once.
It was a military
high school team.
One of their players played with Ayuhara-san
in the Junior High World Cup.
Her name was Cassie-san.
Cassie…
Did she say Cassie?
As in that Cassie?
They were supposed to be far superior,
yet we beat them easily.
This is why we're not afraid of
Ayuhara-san nor Hayakawa-san.
We'll take them head-on.
I see.
Wow, such confidence.
I guess we can't
loosen up on this one.
Right, Chief?
Yes. You're right.
They said they'll take us head-on.
We have to respect that.
Yeah.
I'm ready for some action!
Aw, I'm so mad.
I really wanted them to replay that spike.
Huh?
Relax and take a look at this.
It's all written here.
Oh.
– Whoa, let me see.
– I have to read it.
– Show it to me.
– Let me have it.
Hey, don't pull…
Alright.
"First, she jumps in parallel
to the ground."
"Then she hits the ball with the edge of her right hand,
using her momentum to send tremendous power."
Hmm?
Let me try.
Alright.
Ishida-san,
don't overwork yourself.
Even Professor Hongou said:
"The triangular attack requires familiarity with the
triangular stroke of the Okinawan Karate school."
Hmm?
Karate, as in this?
Yes.
The Okinawan people, who lived between China
and Japan, were forbidden to carry weapons.
So they've learned to use
the human body as a weapon instead.
Yes.
The triangle strike uses the momentum
from kicking one enemy…
…to defeat two additional
opponents in succession.
It's a karate technique.
Kicking doesn't apply
in volleyball, obviously.
They use knifehand strike instead,
but the transfer of force works the same.
The ball…
…flies with great force,
but with no spin, right?
Yes.
Then we'll be fine.
Remember how we were able to receive
Shellenina's killer spikes, after all.
It'll be okay.
This is different, though.
Why?
If Isahara hits the center of the ball,
the impact will be as strong as you said.
But…
If she purposefully hits
the ball off-center…
…the ball will spin.
Yes.
The problem lies in predicting
where it's going to land.
Its direction is completely
up to Isahara.
If she's figured that out,
Isahara's triangular attack…
…will be able to fool
the receiver completely.
Captain Isahara Kana
Kozue!
Hm?
Let's go to sleep.
It's your first match
tomorrow, remember?
We might have already played, but you were
banned from participating the last time.
I'll bet you have a stage fright. But just ease up
and play like your usual self, okay?
Thanks.
What are you thinking about?
The triangular attack.
What's there to think about?
Didn't Professor explain everything?
I know.
But I wonder
if that's all there is to it.
Huh?
Isahara-san is the only one on their team
who has mastered that incredible technique.
Don't you find it odd that
Cassie's team lost to them?
Midori.
What if Professor is keeping
something from us?
Huh?
Hahaha.
You're thinking too much.
You're just a little nervous
after being away from the team.
Maybe you're right…
Come on.
Time to sleep.
Hmm…
Hey, hey, girls.
It's written here that Isahara-san's
sister committed a suicide.
Huh?!
For real?
I have a weak point
for those kind of stories.
They're just like a movie.
"Her 19-year-old sister, who worked
at a US military base store…
…had to undergo a body search because
she was suspected to have embezzled money."
Wait a sec.
So they stripped her naked?
Yeah, sounds like it.
That's awful.
"The following day she went to officially
protest accompanied by her mother. "
"When she heard that the complaint had been
rejected she cut her own wrist with a kitchen knife."
I totally get her.
If someone stripped me naked
based on false charges, I'd freak out, too.
But you always
freak out, anyway.
What?
Come here, you!
Sorry. I take that back.
Apparently, Isahara-san
took it very badly.
She said she'd blow the American base
to bits to avenge her sister, if she could.
Wow, how scary.
But I sympathize with her.
"To the US military
high school people."
"My thoughts have changed
after a victory in the volleyball match."
Changed how?
"I've come to realize that maybe we can reach
an understanding with each other through sports."
How long are you going to read?
Come on, it's way past curfew.
– Okay.
– Yes, mom.
Good night.
Midori, let's show 'em tomorrow.
Yeah.
I'll work hard.
Mabunni High.
Isahara Kana.
Triangular attack.
Midori told me I was thinking too much,
but I know something's up.
Something I just
don't understand yet…
The game between Fujimi
and Mabunni is about to start.
The match is opened by
Fujimi's setter, Nakazawa.
We got the first point.
It's the Mabunni Captain Isahara's
triangular attack.
We'll receive it this time.
Ah!
Naka.
Naka!
Are you okay?
I'm sorry.
Captain Isahara of Mabunni High
launches another triangular attack.
On top of that incredible power,
she's giving it arbitrary spin just like we feared.
How scary.
Mabunni!
Good going!
Go, go! Mabunni!
Be it Fujimi or whoever,
we won't lose to anyone.
We won against Cassie
and the American team.
Sis…
Sis, hang in there!
We greatly regret
the incident with your sister.
Get out!
However, we—
Fight!
We must be strong!
We won't win against
the American team like this.
The match is around the corner.
On the court, we're not
America or Okinawa.
We follow the same rules
and fight equally.
Volleyball is amazing.
It dissolved my anger
and sorrow with sweat.
We will win.
For my sister.
For my mother.
And finally…
For Okinawa as well.
Good luck!
Isahara-san!
Go, go! Mabunni!
See you soon!
Good bye!
Good luck!
Onwards, Mabunni!
Take care!
Captain Isahara of Mabunni High
keeps playing the triangular attacks relentlessly.
We can win this.
That's the least we can do.
Another successful
triangular attack.
Fujimi's ace Ayuhara Kozue's ban from
the first match shows in her subpar form.
In contrast, Isahara Kana's skillful
triangular attacks completely overwhelm Fujimi.
Where did the radiant Ayuhara go?
We're eagerly awaiting the outcome of this match.
We have to receive
that triangular attack somehow.
What is the secret
behind this technique?
How did they defeat Cassie?
Ayuhara-san!
Attack!
Damn.
Isahara's triangular attack
has failed for the first time.
Fight!
– Fight!
Ishimatsu!
Hayakawa-san.
We're just starting.
Where is your confidence
from our earlier match?
It's just like you expected.
Seems like the worst is over.
Mabunni has no other tricks.
I pity them.
You shouldn't think like that.
Huh?
It's rude to the girls who are currently
fighting with all they have.
You… You're right.
Isahara-san's getting tired.
Her technique is great,
but she can't keep it up for a long time.
Kana!
What is this?
You won against
that famous Cassie!
You can't fail the expectations
of the people you left in Okinawa.
It wasn't supposed to be like this.
It's over…
It's all over.
Finally, it clicked.
Now I understand
why Cassie lost to Mabunni.
I can't look at Isahara-san…
Ayuhara-san!
Ah!
What are you doing, Ayuhara Kozue?
You vowed to do your best, no matter what.
Attack!
Excellent, Ayuhara-san.
Not at all.
It's all thanks to your toss.
The tide has changed, starting with
Makimura Kyouko's prominent assistance.
Mabunni High's excellent performance
from the beginning has completely vanished.
The course of the game clearly shows the
difference in experience between the two teams.
Attack!
Great, Fujimi!
Waiting room – Fujimi
It was an easy game in the end.
Yeah, and I was so anxious because
of all the speculation from the press.
You didn't look it at all last night.
All's well that ends well.
Let's keep it up
in the quarterfinals.
Thank you, Makimura-san.
Huh? You're thanking me?
For what?
Your perfectly timed toss
slapped some sense into me.
So you realized it, too, Ayuhara?
Hey, Ayuhara-san,
what is Coach referring to?
I don't want to believe this, but…
I think it's possible that Cassie
lost to Mabunni on purpose.
Huh?
Oh.
Cassie must have heard
about Isahara-san's sister.
She probably started to feel sorry
for her and lost the heart to fight.
Yes. I believe
that's what happened.
And that was the biggest weakness
of the Mabunni's triangular attack.
They didn't realize their technique
was not suited for high endurance game.
But it's not my place
to criticize Cassie.
If Makimura-san hadn't
helped me back then…
…I would've lost my way
just like Cassie did.
At some point I couldn't think about anything else
but the sad things that happened in her life.
I'm worried.
How will Isahara-san take
today's disappointment?
– Ayuhara-san.
– Oh?
Isahara-san!
Thank you for everything.
We're flying back to Okinawa.
Wow, already? Don't you want to
go sight-seeing Tōkyō for at least one day?
I don't have time to.
We have to head back
and resume our training immediately.
We have to work hard
to keep up with this modern world.
When we're good enough,
we'll challenge the American team again.
Huh?
Our defeat today
has made realize me something.
Perhaps Cassie and her team
deliberately let us win back then.
I-It can't be.
It's fine.
I can't stand being pitied.
We're still a weak team.
It's frustrating. But we can get good
and play the game again on equal footing.
I wonder if my line
of thinking is weird?
It's not.
Isahara-san, it's really,
really incredible.
Thank you.
We'll challenge you some day too,
Ayuhara-san.
You can count on it.
That's the spirit.
We'll be waiting for you.
Good bye!
Good bye.
Thank you, Ayuhara-san.
Fujimi wins one game after another
in the spring tournament.
But a certain event
causes Kozue to be concerned.
Despite their promise a year ago, Aoba Academy
didn't make it through the qualifying round.
Kozue meets with
Yamamoto and Shirakawa.
But their reunion is shadowed
by an unpleasant development.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.