苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 073—
The bold operation "Phantom"
Central Gymnasium
All-Japan High School
Women's Volleyball Tournament
It's the second half of the spring
Interhigh tournament.
Straight from the Central Gymnasium, today I will
be commenting on another breathtaking match.
Nansō · Fukuoka
Good luck, Nansō!
The main attacker
of Fukuoka High from Kyūshū…
…is Kakinouchi Yoshiko, whose
prominent career goes back to middle school.
A point!
As usual, she throws incredible spikes.
Today Fukuoka faces Nansō High School, who won
with the famous Aoba Academy in the preliminaries.
Captain Nakayama's calm composure
can be admired in her team's careful teamwork.
Here it is!
Nansō's renowned quick offensive!
And it scores them a point.
They're both pretty good.
Whoever wins,
it'll be a tough match.
Nansō · Fukuoka
Kozue.
If Fukuoka wins…
I still remember our match with
Kakinouchi-san from three years ago.
I can understand how Nansō
gets to play against Fukuoka.
What I can't wrap my head around
is how they defeated Aoba.
What do you think, Midori?
I'm curious, too.
How could Yamamoto-san
and Shirakawa-san lose so early?
The way I remember Aoba from last year,
there's no way they wouldn't make it out of qualifiers.
Aoba is a school that focuses on sports and
gathers the best players from all over the country.
How could they lose?
Something must have happened to
Yamamoto-san and Shirakawa-san.
Oh?
Hey, Kozue.
Isn't that Yamamoto-san?
Huh?
Where? Where?
Over there.
The ball flies back and forth.
It's a real battle.
Nansō · Fukuoka
Nansō just tied the score.
Both teams are doing well, very well.
Yamamoto-san.
Long time no see.
I missed you.
Hi.
I can't believe you guys
lost in the preliminaries.
You must feel disappointed.
We were too weak.
That's all there is to it.
It can't be.
We know best
how strong your team is.
What happened?
You can tell us the truth.
It may not be worth much,
but I'd like to be of some help if possible.
Stop pitying us.
Volleyball is just a game anyway.
I don't intend to play it anymore.
No way!
There's no way you'd quit.
You're just unwilling
to accept defeat, aren't you?
What makes you think so?
If you meant what you said,
why would you come to see the game today?
You… You have a point.
Yamamoto-san.
We love volleyball.
From the bottom of our hearts.
So I can understand your feelings
caused by the defeat in qualifiers.
We're the same.
You—
…hate it!
I hate it.
The reason why we lost against Nansō
is very simple, really.
Every single one of us at Aoba
had become too sloppy.
But Aoba's team is comprised only
of aces such as you and Shirakawa-san.
That girl is no good.
She's changed for the worse.
Shirakawa-san has?
What do you mean?
Her selfishness.
As long as she
was doing well, the team…
It didn't matter
what happened in the team.
She's become a huge egoist.
So far, my spikes were the center of our offense.
The others had to deal mainly with the defense.
At that point,
our team was well balanced.
If Shirakawa-san continued
to focus on reception, things would go well.
But she wanted to become
an attacker like me.
She longed for the flashy
and cool image of a spiker.
But…
She lacked the talent.
Wouldn't you agree, Ayuhara-san?
As a spiker, you should know what I'm getting at.
Yes. The talent.
Soon enough,
everyone followed Shirakawa-san.
Spike.
Spike!
And spike again.
We stopped
receiving and tossing altogether.
It's no wonder that we lost.
All because of…
…such foolishness.
That's why I grew
very tired of volleyball.
– But…
There's nothing
for us to talk about.
Good bye.
Yamamoto-san!
What was that?
Shirakawa-san!
Hello. You've just talked
with Yamamoto-san, haven't you?
I watched you the whole time.
Then why were you hiding?
I don't want to see her face.
She's avoiding me, too, isn't she?
I don't know what
Yamamoto-san told you, but…
…she's the reason
why Aoba lost in the preliminaries.
It's true that last year
her spike was outstanding.
But since we lost the last Interhigh,
we obviously had to change strategy.
But Yamamoto-san, who is 185 cm tall,
can hit the ball from a great height at a steep angle.
It's very intense, and can be said
to be comparable to the university level.
Even if you changed your strategy…
…you shouldn't let go
of Yamamoto-san's spike.
Yes.
I know that.
But…
The atmosphere has become unbearable with her
attitude of superiority. It left no room for anyone.
Yes… Back then,
it was like that, too.
No good.
Throw me a better toss.
No matter how good were our players,
we couldn't win like that.
In the preliminaries,
Nansō won the first set 15 to 13.
The second set was 15 to 4.
Nansō · Aoba
Do you see what
this miserable score means?
Everyone gave up
in the second set.
Everyone, except for Yamamoto-san.
It was a revolt against her one-man play.
Shirakawa-san said the opposite
to what Yamamoto-san did.
I don't know who to believe.
Do you, Kozue?
Which one of them
was telling the truth?
Well, everyone is telling things
as they have experienced them.
Hmm.
So did both of them lie?
No, that's not what I meant.
I meant that you can't believe
what Yamamoto-san says.
Do you remember
our friendly match with Korea?
While everyone else
has lost their confidence…
…Shirakawa-san was the only one
who could receive Sai-san's missile spike.
Somebody…!
Shirakawa-san's reception was flawless.
At that time, she perfectly captured
the pattern of Sai-san's missile spike.
Shirakawa-san was remarkable back then.
I don't believe Yamamoto-san's
words that Shirakawa-san…
…wouldn't care what happened to the team
as long as she played well.
I can't imagine her being so selfish.
Neither Shirakawa-san,
nor Yamamoto-san.
It's impossible for me.
Yamamoto-san claimed she didn't realize
the importance of reception.
According to her, Shirakawa-san wanted to focus
solely on spikes to become a new star of their team.
I don't believe it.
You're right.
But then why are they
blaming each other?
There must be some reason for it.
It must be also the reason
as to why they lost against Nansō.
Fukuoka wins!
Nansō, who has defeated Aoba before,
kneels before Fukuoka's strength.
Fukuoka advances to the quarterfinals.
Tomorrow, they're going to face Fujimi.
– So it's Fukuoka.
– Yes sir.
Be careful, you two. You know hardly anyone knows
our playing techniques as well as Kakinouchi.
We need to drastically
revise our strategy.
– Yes.
– Yeah.
"Drastically revise our strategy"…
Easier said than done. What can we do so late?
Do you have any good ideas, Kozue?
Falling leaf.
Double attack.
Kakinouchi-san knows them all.
Hey, Kozue.
A-Ah, yes, you're right.
You're still thinking
about these two, aren't you?
Midori, I'm really…
…curious, you mean?
You've got to be kidding me.
We don't have time for them.
We need to think
how to face Kakinouchi-san.
– Kozue!
– I-I know, alright.
Kakinouchi-san.
We finally meet again!
It's not like I missed you or anything.
Yeah, we were friends,
and now we're enemies.
Well said. Friends will be friends,
but a game is a game.
I'm going to fight
with all I have.
Yes, we won't be able
to relax with you around.
The pleasure is all mine.
Oh?
Oh.
They're Nansō.
The ones who defeated Aoba.
Alright, I'll be going.
We have to devise a plan
how to defeat you tomorrow.
Be my guest.
We're unbeatable!
Just like us.
Kozue.
You're Nakayama-san
from Nansō High, right?
Yes, I am.
I'm Ayuhara from Fujimi.
There's something I've meant to ask you.
Kozue, don't.
You can't do this.
Nakayama-san, you defeated Aoba Academy
earlier in the qualifying round. Is that right?
Yes.
What I wanted to ask is
what was the cause of Aoba's defeat.
I'd like to hear your opinion.
Is it so strange that we defeated Aoba?
Kozue, you're being rude.
What are you going to do
after I tell you?
I'll be frank.
We marked Aoba.
It was a huge shock to us
that they lost in the preliminaries.
We'd like to know
the reason for their defeat.
By all means,
I'd like to hear your opinion.
Very well.
You go ahead, girls.
As you know, Aoba is a school that focuses on sports
by inviting best players from all over the country.
Each and every player
has very good skills.
But before they came to Aoba,
every one of them was either a captain, or a star.
In the end, every player
is just looking for themselves.
I saw it on the court clearly.
That's what we've aimed at.
Matsukaze Inn
Yamamoto-san,
Shirakawa-san, Nakayama-san.
Which one of these three
was telling the truth?
I don't think no one
was lying in particular.
But something essential
feels missing.
Something essential?
If I knew what it was…
Of course, all three
told the story from their perspective.
But notice how all their versions
have one thing in common.
Every player in Aoba
wanted to be the center of attention.
And that's what leaded
their team to destruction.
Yeah.
It's the reason why Aoba lost.
We have to be careful, too.
Now that you mention it,
I'm always in the spotlight as well.
Maybe one day it'll cause a problem
with my team, just like it did for Yamamoto-san?
I know.
What's wrong, Kozue?
During this meeting, we'll discuss what kind
of strategy to use against Fukuoka tomorrow.
Before we start,
Ayuhara wanted to tell you something.
We've played a lot with and against Fukuoka's
Captain Kakinouchi-san in our middle school days.
It means, she knows
a lot about me and Midori.
I don't think my spike nor Midori's serve
can hold any surprises for her.
I gave this matter a lot of thought
and figured a way around it.
I think that in the game of tomorrow,
me and Hayakawa-san could turn to defense…
…and we could leave the offense to
Ishimatsu, Naka and Takeichi-san.
No way!
Without you two—
This is reckless!
– Right?
– Yeah!
Impossible.
This is suicide. Right, girls?
We can't do it!
Wait.
I think it's an interesting idea.
Enough to give it a try.
Alright.
Why don't we give it a go?
The quarterfinals are about to begin!
Fujimi vs. Fukuoka.
It's a comeback of Fujimi's spiker,
Ayuhara Kozue.
She hakes hands with
Fukuoka's Captain Kakinouchi Yoshiko.
We're looking forward
to a great game.
She's here after all, Kozue.
Over there, too.
Yeah.
That's surprising!
Ayuhara has only jumped.
It's Ishida who hit the ball!
Nonetheless it was an amazing
quick offense.
Fukuoka couldn't defend at all.
This time it's got to be Ayuhara-san.
Fukuoka · Fujimi
Ah!
Ayuhara-san doesn't attack?
It's strange.
What's going on?
Fukuoka · Fujimi
It's a set point for Fujimi!
Fujimi wins the first set!
Their daring strategy
worked great against Fukuoka.
It worked great.
It worked great!
For time being our plan
apparently has worked.
But now Fukuoka
is going to adjust to it.
Change of plans.
Ayuhara.
Coach.
I'm sure that Kakinouchi-san
expects us to change our tactic.
I'm fairly sure they're going
to mark me in the next set.
It's also worth noting that the girls
just started to get the hang of the offense.
I suggest that we don't change anything.
That should mislead Kakinouchi-san.
All right, we don't change anything,
just like Ayuhara said.
– Show me what you've got.
– Yes sir. – Yes sir.
The girls come up with very good ideas
if we give them a little freedom.
Yes, and now almost everyone
has learned to spike.
Spikes are the alpha and omega of volleyball.
Ayuhara withdrew from it of her own accord
and let the others enjoy the attention this time.
It was a nice move.
She's a great captain.
I knew it.
She still thinks I'm going to attack.
Attack!
Fukuoka · Fujimi
What a block!
Fukuoka counterattacks.
It's the Kakinouchi's
merciless spike.
And another point!
Time!
Looks like Kakinouchi
no longer marks Ayuhara.
What do you think?
Kozue, let's get back to attack.
No. If we change our tactic now,
we'll be doing them a favor.
Kakinouchi-san's
only waiting for us to do it.
We must think ahead.
Makimura-san. Ishimatsu. Naka.
– Hang on.
– Yeah.
If we changed anything,
they'd lose their confidence.
Ayuhara-san must have realized that.
She has really grown up.
Ayuhara-san sacrificed her spotlight
for the sake of their strategy.
I… I can't compare to her.
I'm sorry, Ayuhara-san.
I lied to you.
The truth is that our school has announced
a prize for the best player in the field.
This is why I—
No, every one of us has competed for recognition
and has caused our team to fall apart.
Yamamoto-san.
Shirakawa-san.
I'm sorry.
No.
I should be the one apologizing.
Fukuoka · Fujimi
This time, Ayuhara-san…!
Kakinouchi-san.
Ayuhara-san…
I lost to your phantom.
"Phantom"? I see.
I like the sound of that.
Fukuoka feared Ayuhara-san's attack that
could come any moment and that was their doom.
Operation "Phantom":
great success!
Oh?
Ayuhara-san, Hayakawa-san!
Congratulations.
Thank you, Ayuhara-san.
So, what's up?
We're sorry we've dragged you
into such a pitiful drama. I feel embarrassed.
In the end,
we won't quit volleyball.
In volleyball
you need a team of six to play.
We forgot such a basic
and most important thing.
You made us remember that.
We owe it to our game.
Ayuhara-san, Hayakawa-san, you have our thanks.
We'll see you
in the summer tournament.
See you then.
Yeah.
Bye.
E-Excuse us.
I'm happy for them.
I've been playing volleyball all this time,
but I finally begin to understand its true difficulty.
Oh, it's the three
Yagisawa sisters from Jidōin!
Long time no see,
Ayuhara-san. Hayakawa-san.
Yes. Good morning.
I've graduated this year.
I took over the training
of my sisters after our mother.
We'll be playing against San'in
in the quarterfinals.
Of course,
we're going to win.
Then it's the semifinals tomorrow.
This time we'll pay you back
for our defeat last year.
Hayakawa-san.
You're really cute.
See you on court.
We can't lose, Kozue.
Yeah.
The time of confrontation
with Jidōin has come.
With Yagisawa Kaori as the new coach,
Jidōin became even stronger than before.
Kozue's confident that they can
defend against the trinity attack.
But Oonuma Miyuki,
who came to cheer for Kozue…
…admonishes her explaining that
Jidōin must have more up their sleeves.
What techniques to expect?
Kozue begins to worry again.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.