苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 074—
Mysterious player No. 4
All-Japan High School Women's Volleyball
Spring Tournament
Today's game is the quarterfinal
between Jidōin and San'in.
Jidōin · San'in
The set score is now 1 to 1.
Jidōin
Jidōin is clearly leading
in the third set.
Jidōin
Now!
Another one of
Jidōin's trinity attacks.
The Yagisawa sisters have been using this technique
since last year's Interhigh to great success.
Kaori, the oldest sister, is no longer on the court
since she has graduated from school this year.
But her absence was filled with the arrival
of a new player, Nishimoto, wearing shirt number 3.
She's doing a great job at assisting
the two younger Yagisawa sisters.
Yagisawa Kaori, who became Jidōin's new trainer,
is known to have been pleased with the new player.
Man, I haven't seen such a strong team
playing in a long time.
There's no doubt that they'll be
our opponents in tomorrow's semifinals.
That makes me nervous.
Maybe the Interhigh is too high a bar for us?
Knock it off, Naka.
Worrying won't do us any good.
Makimura-san is a beginner,
how do you think that makes her feel?
There it is!
The trinity attack again.
Makimura-san.
That was Jidōin's trinity attack.
Could you see
who hit the ball?
No, not at all.
The player with the number 3 has integrated
very well into Kaori-san's place.
Yes.
But we'll be fine.
We'll be fine!
– Huh?
She might play as well as Kaori-san, but
the trinity attack won't work against us anymore.
But they're still
super strong.
Oh! Again!
It's like an impenetrable wall.
I can't see at all
who hit the ball.
It's because you're trying to watch
all of them at once.
You won't be able to see
anything that way.
Pick a single player and try
to only follow their movements.
I guarantee that
you'll see through it easily.
Seriously? I can't believe
it's that simple to figure out.
Yeah. If it was so easy,
we should have figured that out long ago.
It's like Columbus' egg.
Well, it is simple,
but did it ever occur to you?
Why don't we give it a go?
Let each of us pick a player to watch.
Alright, I like that idea.
Okay, so Midori and I
will follow Shizuka-san.
Takeichi-san and I
pick Katsura-san.
And the two of us
choose the player number 3.
Nice, Nishimoto!
Keep it up!
Now!
I saw it.
I could see it.
Huh? R-Really?
Captain, it was Katsura-san.
She hit the ball.
Yes.
Shizuka-san was only a decoy.
Same goes to player number 3.
I see.
So, do you believe me now?
We have a way to see through
their trinity attack 100% of the time.
You're right.
I saw the ball clearly enough.
We can finally do it.
We'll crush their trinity attack.
Fujimi High Waiting Room
I understand the gist of the defense
against the trinity attack.
But what about the offense?
Yeah. Since Captain Oonuma graduated,
we're not playing any double or vanishing attacks.
What are we going to do? We don't have
that many options left, besides the mobile attack.
We'll be fine.
We don't need either the double
or the vanishing attack.
The trinity is an attack technique
made on the belief of a 100% success rate.
That it can't be received,
no matter what.
Their strategy doesn't consider
that someone could ever receive that spike.
And that's their weak point.
I see.
I know my theory is true because of what happens
immediately after they finish executing their attack.
Their players lose all their
rhythm and coordination.
I'll aim at that gap
with my spike.
Then, the mobile attack.
I think that'll be enough.
So we're good as long as we manage
to defend against the trinity attack?
Kozue might be right.
Yes.
Jidōin will probably panic once they realize
their main weapon is no longer useful.
Then they're ours.
We'll use Midori's falling leaf.
Ishimatsu and Naka's spike.
Takeichi-san's feints.
Makimura-san's curve ball toss.
I think the operation "phantom" that defeated
Fukuoka will be very useful as well.
Oh? Oonuma-san.
– Oh, it's you, Senpai.
– Long time no see.
Captain.
She's not our captain anymore.
She's a senpai.
Right, Senpai?
Wow, so cool.
I'm determined to go to college, too.
It's been a while, girls.
I'm glad you're all doing fine.
Did you come all the way
to Tōkyō to cheer for us, Senpai?
That's so nice of you.
Yes.
It's against Jidōin, right?
I was so curious
I just couldn't sit still.
Thanks.
It's nice to have
a senpai like you.
Thank you, too.
Ayuhara-san.
I know it's probably not my place
to speak up about this…
…but I heard your speech just now.
I think you're being a bit optimistic.
I mean, you saw the game today.
I think Jidōin's trinity attack
is just as powerful as last year.
And I agree with you, absolutely.
I don't understand what you're getting at.
Their coach, Yagisawa Kaori-san let her team
use the trinity attack in the game against San'in.
She didn't even care to conceal the technique
even though she knew they weren't strong.
I can't help but wonder why.
If the trinity attack really is
Jidōin's decisive strategy…
No coach would allow their team
to use their best weapon so freely.
So you believe they have
another trick up their sleeve?
Yes, I'm afraid so.
Kaori-san is young,
but very smart.
I think she's well aware you studied
the trinity attack in the last game.
One more thing.
I noticed something strange
when today's game was just about to end.
Jidōin · San'in
Kaori-san kept switching the players
on the court, one after another.
The reason was rather simple: she wanted to
prepare everyone on her team for future matches.
But there was this one peculiar girl
that she didn't let on the court.
Player number four.
Number four?
Yes.
She wasn't a beginner.
In fact, she was quite relaxed,
as if the match was boring to her.
I didn't notice.
I'm pretty sure
she's their secret weapon.
Player number four.
It's like Oonuma says.
Player number four…
She's probably the key
to Jidōin's new strategy.
Professor Hongou.
Professor!
Is it okay to leave them
as they are?
If Ayuhara can't survive today
and tomorrow games by herself…
…she'll never have been anything
but a random volleyball freak.
Professor…
She has to beat players on
Yagisawa Kaori caliber to become a star.
Or rather, to become a player who leads
the Japanese women's volleyball world.
Ayuhara has to challenge
herself more and more.
Then…
Yes. I'm going to leave it up to her
to think up a strategy to beat Jidōin.
We'll see what comes out of it.
A player that carries the future
of Japanese volleyball on her shoulders.
It seems important to me
as a goal to achieve.
How about you, Professor Shimizu?
Do you agree?
Yes.
I was so focused on the trinity attack that I didn't
even notice the arrival of the player number four.
A strategy that
defeats them both.
Does it even exist?
A new strategy to defeat
that mysterious girl…
A strategy that defeats
both trinity and No. 4.
Jidōin · Fujimi
Today it's the much-anticipated semifinal of the spring
Interhigh tournament. The public is very excited.
As they should be, because the game today
is between Jidōin from Ōsaka and Fujimi from Tōkai.
Volleyball fans surely remember how these two
schools faced each other in the finals last year.
In a very close game, the Jidōin's
trinity attack clashed with Fujimi's double attack.
And even though it was Jidōin
who emerged victorious in that game…
…Fujimi's form was still
outstanding nevertheless.
Just listen to that applause.
The rematch between these
great rivals is about to start.
Alright, here I go.
Player number four.
What is she up to?
Whatever it is,
we will prevail.
Kozue.
I will never have the opportunity
to play against Jidōin again.
Good luck, Ayuhara-san.
Thank you, Senpai.
A victory sign?
It won't be so easy, Ayuhara-san.
I can see it.
Attack!
We did it.
We did it!
Kozue, it's just as you said.
We managed that well.
We can do this!
Yeah.
We must keep up this pace.
Excellent play from Fujimi.
Last year Jidōin's trinity attack was a heavy shock
for them, but this time they've skillfully broken through.
No!
It is only just the beginning.
– Easy-peasy.
– Yeah.
It was just a test.
They're testing your strength.
Looks like we can do it.
Yes. We can't let up now.
Got it, girls?
– Of course!
– Leave it to us.
Hmm.
Oonuma was right.
There's something peculiar about her.
Jidōin · Fujimi
As soon one side scores, the other one
catches up. What a balanced game.
The teams are fighting fiercely.
It's hard to say which one is the stronger.
Stop fooling around.
Take it seriously.
Yes, mom.
What's going on?
Is she that calm?
Or is she just
pretending to be?
I'm absolutely certain
she's no ordinary reserve player.
It's coming!
Okay.
It's Shizuka-san.
Midori, give us a good serve.
Sure.
They're in turmoil now.
Now's our chance.
Let's sweep this up
in one go. Okay, Midori?
Yeah.
Got it.
It wasn't just a fluke, was it?
Yeah.
They've prepared well.
Doesn't matter.
We still have our little surprise.
Watch out, girls.
If they come up with something now, they will
take down your balance in the blink of an eye.
You have to notice that,
Ayuhara-san.
The number four…
I'm afraid of her.
No. We just have to give them
more and more pressure.
We need to win this fast.
We can worry afterwards.
Falling leaf!
Jidōin · Fujimi
Professor.
Don't you think it's strange?
If their player number four
is the key to their new strategy…
Why do they keep her
on the bench?
They're saving her for later.
Jidōin · Fujimi
Alright.
She's not coming out yet.
Maybe they gave up
on the first set?
Chance!
Over to you!
– It's coming!
– Watch them closely.
Jidōin · Fujimi
Hey, Coach…
Not now.
Maybe they had planned
to lose this set?
It's not that.
Look over there.
They don't want Tōnan's spies
to capture their techniques on a film.
I-I see.
Yes.
They want to keep their secrets
until the finals.
Jidōin's team is in chaos.
Apparently the shock from having their main
weapon, the trinity attack, beaten was too much.
It's a set point for Fujimi.
Fujimi is strong!
They've definitely got
control over this game.
Fujimi seizes the first set
with the score of 15 to 8.
The trinity attack
is done for!
I don't believe it.
I don't believe that's all the famous
Interhigh queens from Jidōin are capable of.
The problem is the next set.
Do not let that camera go out of your hands
as soon as the second set begins.
Got that?
Yes.
Sis, I can't believe our trinity attack
would have become so ineffective against them.
Typical Ayuhara-san.
She has improved a lot.
That's just the way it goes
when Ayuhara-san is your opponent.
I'm sure they'll use her
in the next set.
We have no idea what to expect.
We're just going to have to take them head-on.
What's there to worry about?
She's just a human. Just like us.
Yeah. What could they
possibly come up with?
Yeah, yeah. It's just a flying ball
we're talking about.
You have a point.
With that attitude,
the next set…
…is already lost.
You're blinded by euphoria.
This is an ancient wisdom.
As soon as you get overconfident, you lose.
Coach…
The first set was excellent.
But you need to stay
even more focused now.
If they were to show you a technique
you didn't know by heart…
…no matter how basic it was,
it would cause your rhythm to collapse.
You'd end up losing just like
what happened to them in the first set.
I see.
I think I understand.
Vanity leads to defeat.
It's alright to lose the second set.
We'll first check if they have
any more trump cards.
Got it, girls?
– Yeah!
– Got it.
Oh!
No. 4.
She's finally here.
The second set.
Can Jidōin pull
themselves together?
Will Fujimi continue its streak
from the first set and win the match?
Focus on No. 4.
Understood?
Right.
She's terrible…
It's here!
The trinity—
Where is the ball?!
There it is!
Jidōin's new technique.
Or is it? I'm not so sure
if it's new anymore.
It's hard to tell
what exactly has happened.
We got it.
– Here they go again!
– Again?
I have to see it.
Jidōin · Fujimi
That was her purpose.
To enhance the trinity.
It's no longer "trinity attack"…
It's more of a "tetrad attack".
I can't see the ball.
Where did it go?
I could only see a shadow.
So that's their new trick.
That's right, Ayuhara-san.
A terrible new attack
hits the Fujimi team.
It's Jidōin's new weapon:
the somersault smokescreen.
Kozue is powerless against this new technique,
and Fujimi ends up losing the second set.
Kozue frantically looks for a solution
how to dispel the smokescreen.
But it seems that Jidōin's
technique is invincible.
The Fujimi team find
themselves in a serious pinch.
Please look forward
to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.