苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 075—
Sommersault smokescreen
Jidōin · Fujimi
Alright.
She's not coming out yet.
Maybe they gave up
on the first set?
Chance!
Over to you!
– It's coming!
– Watch them closely.
Jidōin · Fujimi
Hey, Coach…
Not now.
Maybe they had planned
to lose this set?
It's not that.
Look over there.
They don't want Tōnan's spies
to capture their techniques on a film.
I-I see.
Yes.
They want to keep their secrets
until the finals.
Jidōin's team is in chaos.
Apparently the shock from having their main
weapon, the trinity attack, beaten was too much.
It's a set point for Fujimi.
Fujimi's strong!
They started to control the game.
Fujimi seizes the first set
with the score of 15 to 8.
The trinity attack
is done for!
I don't believe it.
I don't believe that's all the famous
Interhigh queens from Jidōin are capable of.
Jidōin · Fujimi
The third set.
The score is 14 to 3.
Jidōin's secret weapon
overwhelmed Fujimi.
The trinity attack, or more like "a tetrad attack" now,
was enhanced by the player number four.
It's a powerful technique.
It's a set point for Jidōin.
Fujimi's completely powerless.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Go! Go! Jidōin!
It's the set point, girls!
Keep it up!
You're almost there.
Don't panic.
Fight!
– Yeah!
Naka!
I've got this.
Attack!
I can't see their movements at all.
The ball is gone, too.
Ah!
What's wrong, Ayuhara-san?
Aren't you going to do something
against our new technique?
I can't see.
Who hit the ball?
I can't see them at all.
It's hopeless.
Jidōin · Fujimi
Jidōin wins the second set
by a landslide.
Who hit the ball?
What kind of attack is it?
Neither Fujimi or us can tell.
Jidōin's new technique has paralyzed Fujimi.
Kozue.
– Professor.
– Professor…
I really cannot find the right words
to describe this new technique.
It's based on the same trinity attack
that Jidōin has used at the Interhigh a year back…
…but this new variant
alters it in an indescribable way.
One thing is certain:
it's executed by four players simultaneously.
Jidōin's strength is really fearsome.
Jidōin's going to win.
So the game's over, huh.
Tomorrow we'll be playing
against Jidōin.
I'm dreading that technique.
We'll be fine.
We'll figure it out
on slow-motion.
Even if we figure out how it works,
can we win against that speed?
Of course.
Tonight we'll drill to do so.
According to our data,
Fujimi was supposed to win.
But I don't think it's possible
for them anymore.
Yagisawa Kaori.
What a horrible and fearsome
technique you have made.
You take after your mother
with your talent.
Way to go.
Let's keep it up.
Professor…
What should we do?
I can't follow their movements at all.
What to do?
I don't know what to tell you
except that you have to follow them anyway.
That's why I'm asking you, how?
I don't know that either.
We have to look closer.
Professor…
That's it.
We need to understand their movements.
Good luck, girls.
Jidōin · Fujimi
The third set opens.
Is Jidōin going to continue
with their fearsome technique?
To call it "fearsome"
is an understatement.
With three players, it can still be deciphered.
But what's happening with the fourth player?
It all happens so fast.
No one can really tell what's going on.
It's a terrible play
that exceeds boundaries set by common sense.
Let's get them!
– Yeah!
Ishimatsu!
Ishida-san.
It hurts…
I-It's like we're playing in the dark.
We can't see anything.
We didn't understand
the trinity attack at first either.
But once we started to mark each player
separately, we became able to see through it.
Now.
Oh.
I saw it!
This time it's different.
Even if we try to mark each player,
we can't follow them at all.
No matter how fast they are,
there's no way that wouldn't work.
I don't get it.
It's like an opaque wall.
Why can't we see what's going on?
As expected, Fujimi is helpless.
They still haven't found a way
to counter the new attack.
Even when they somehow manage
to get the right to serve back…
…they get obliterated
by Jidōin immediately after.
Things look grim for Fujimi.
Jidōin · Fujimi
It's the same as last year.
When one of the Yagisawa
sisters returns to baseline…
…they deliberately lose
and then they make a change.
They want to keep them together.
We'll end up losing
with 3 to 4 points again.
Professor…
I think there's still time to recover
if we grasp their movements now.
I can't see.
No matter how hard I try,
I can't follow them.
We'd better hurry.
What to do?
We're sinking fast.
I know!
Let's try watching them from behind.
Kozue!
Why did you waste such a chance?
Watch them!
Great, great!
Here it is again!
The killer technique.
Fujimi is completely helpless.
Time!
Did you see anything?
Nope.
We have got the gist of it.
Huh?
Really, Professor?
Oonuma went around the gym
and watched them from behind.
It's a sommersault.
A sommersault?
Yes.
Kawaji, the player no. 4
makes a sommersault.
So it's a sommersault.
She jumps into the air in front
of the Yagisawa sisters and Nishimoto.
What happens next?
She uses her sommersault
to conceal the trinity attack behind.
But why does it work so well?
It's because we focus on the trinity
and lose sight of the ball.
That's what makes
this trick so successful.
I see. So it's a human smokescreen
for the trinity attack, so to speak.
Professor…
S-So, what's our strategy?
I don't know yet.
– Huh?
First, we have to
see through Kawaji.
Pay attention only to her.
If we can read her,
we'll make some progress.
Got it?
Watch only Kawaji.
– Yes sir.
Alright, go!
I want to break that technique.
I'm with you!
Yeah!
Were you watching Kawaji
like I told you?
– Yes sir.
Yes sir.
But…
What is it, Hayakawa?
Kawaji-san's movements
are clear to me now.
But what about the Yagisawa sisters?
I still couldn't see the ball.
I don't know how to react.
I could see the ball, though.
Huh?
At least I think so.
What do you mean?
Explain it, Ayuhara.
I think I'm able to tell the moment
the ball is going to come out.
I'm still not sure what's going on
behind Kawaji-san's smokescreen…
…but the moment the ball
is going to fly out is more or less clear to me.
But you still don't know
where it's going to jump out from.
Kawaji-san is able to execute her move
in roughly one place under the net.
Yeah.
Furthermore, they can't the ball
while Kawaji-san is moving.
So…
I see.
I understand.
Exactly.
Hey, hey, what did she mean?
Ah…
Ah, uhm, you see,
it's like this…
It means that…
Nakazawa.
Ishida.
– Sir.
You can just focus at the side of the net.
Ah, right!
I see.
I understand now, too.
Since they can't hit the ball
from where Kawaji-san's moving…
…they have no choice
but to aim at either side of the net.
Alright. Divide into two groups
and mark both sides of the net. Got it?
That way we should
be able to counter it.
– Yes sir.
Alright!
Go!
– Yes sir!
Fujimi used up their strategy time.
The players are returning back onto the court.
How effective will prove Coach Hongou's defensive
measure against the Jidōin's new weapon?
It's a truly extraordinary match.
Watch both sides close.
Catch the glimpse of the ball.
That's the way to tackle it.
I'll cover right side.
Okay, I'll take the left.
I can see it!
That was no good…
I could see the ball,
but there wasn't enough time to react.
How do you like it?
Did you really think it would be so easy?
The trick we have
come up with is very effective.
We'll just continue to score points
and there's nothing you can do about it.
Even though we could see the ball,
it's still very fast.
If this keeps up and they score more points,
everyone will lose heart.
There must be something…
There must be something
that can be done.
They missed it
but it was still good.
As expected from Fujimi.
That seems to be their limit, though.
Let's end it quickly.
They're going to keep using
their technique till the end.
The game's already over
unless we interrupt their streak.
Keep the serve.
Sure thing.
I'll get it this time for sure.
That's the spirit.
Even if we look at the sides,
her vortex is just too distracting.
Even if we see the ball,
it'll be always a split second too late.
What to do?
How to keep focus?
Attack!
Alright!
That was great.
I realized something.
Like it or not, Kawaji-san
draws our attention away.
Even if we observe the sides,
we'll be a split second too late.
All that we have to do
is to not let her distract us.
What do you mean?
It's simple.
We just don't have to look.
Not have to look…?
We'll close our eyes.
– Huh?
Just close your eyes and keep waiting
till you hear the sound of a spike.
Once you hear it,
open your eyes.
Once you do,
you'll see the ball right away.
Somehow, I don't think
it's gonna work.
I just tried it.
It's easier than I thought.
Come on,
try it yourselves.
Okay, then. I'll cover the right side,
while Ishimatsu will focus on the left.
You can count on me.
Finally, it's Fujimi's serve.
The server is Hayakawa Midori,
known for her falling leaf serves.
I can see it!
I can totally see it.
Ah!
Right on!
We did it.
Good job,
Ayuhara Kozue.
Once again, she has managed
to make our effort go in vain.
They close their eyes
before our attack.
Yes.
This technique is done for.
Now that they're able
to receive it, it's game over.
Even more, they immediately go from offense
to a strong spike we can't really counter.
Let's take Kawaji off the court.
Jidōin's no. 4, Kawaji
is being swapped.
Evidently she has fulfilled her role
in the new attack.
Jidōin is powerless against the Fujimi's unusual
strategy where the players close their eyes.
The match goes on.
Fujimi serves.
Jidōin's trinity attack.
Fujimi's speed and curve ball attacks.
It's a truly fierce rally.
Fujimi counterattacks ferociously.
Jidōin · Fujimi
Fujimi's pretty good.
I can't predict the outcome anymore.
Ayuhara Kozue.
Film Fujimi as well.
It won't hurt to study them both.
Attack!
Jidōin · Fujimi
A remarkable
response from Fujimi.
They're just a single point behind.
– Higashida-san.
– Hm?
Put Kawaji back.
Huh?
Are we going to use that?
We were saving it for finals.
If we lose now,
there won't be any finals for us.
We have to survive today first.
Player change.
Just like we practiced.
Got it?
Yes. I'll do it.
Show them.
Okay.
What are they doing?
Why are they calling her back?
They want to go back
to that trick again?
I don't think they're going
to do the same thing.
I'll bet this is
something different.
Fight!
– Yeah!
Ah! Direct spike!
That's… our double attack
combined with the direct spike.
They have reused the sommersault
we have seen previously.
This time, they use it to change
the direction of the ball to a steep angle.
It's more effective
than our double attack.
Keep it up, Katsura.
Let's win this in one go.
If you're careless,
you can forget about tomorrow's finals.
Jidōin's fearsome.
Jidōin · Fujimi
It's as if the ball's alive.
How precise can she get
with that spike?
Time!
Fujimi calls a timeout.
The semifinals
are approaching their finale.
Will it be Fujimi or Jidōin
that advances to the finals tomorrow?
I think it would be best to attack
before Kawaji-san gets the ball.
Yes.
What if we focus on
playing at Katsura-san?
Katsura-san seems to be exhausted
from all those difficult plays.
I think that if we play this way, we can proceed
without giving the ball to Kawaji-san.
Alright.
You have my blessing.
Attack!
Katsura!
Katsura, are you okay?
Come on.
Stand up.
It's time to end this,
Katsura-san.
Midori!
Give us a good serve.
Attack!
The semifinals are reaching the end.
Kozue defeats Jidōin's
tetrad attack one after another.
Now her team faces the last obstacle.
"Katsura-san is tired."
"Aim at Katsura-san."
That's Kozue's message.
Katsura is under a centralized attack.
Finally, Kozue aims
the decisive last spike at Katsura.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.