苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 077—
Confrontation with the machine
Ayuhara-san.
Huh?
Let's go.
Okay.
Ayuhara-san!
Makimura-san, one more time.
Huh?
Hurry up.
Sure.
Katsura-san!
I can't hit it.
No matter what I try,
I can't use my spike.
You missed three spikes.
What's with you?
I can't do it.
I can't spike.
She still hasn't recovered from the shock
of that accident with Katsura-san.
It's nothing serious.
I'm just a little stiff, that's all.
Ayuhara!
Continue.
I understand
what you're going through.
But you'll need
to challenge yourself once again.
Professor Shimizu,
could you please massage her arms?
No problem.
Oh, I'm fine.
It's okay.
I'll do it for you.
See? Your muscles
are all tense.
Too much tension
won't do you any good.
Maybe you should take an EMG test
to check up on your muscle health.
No, anything but that.
I still remember how they kidnapped me
and put me through all those tests in that truck.
Tōnan's did a very thorough job.
Actually, it feels like we're up
against a computer.
You should rather relax.
Yes.
Ah!
Time for Tōnan's warmup.
So that's their
computer-managed warmup?
It's like a puzzle game.
I don't like this.
Humans aren't machines.
– Yeah.
– Exactly.
They're like robots
playing volleyball.
We're competing
against machines.
Ah! Let go of me!
Somebody…
Somebody help me!
They kidnapped me to analyze
the strength of my muscles.
But that was just
the tip of the iceberg.
The players in the Tōnan team
no longer play like human beings.
Every one of them has become part
of a machine. All run by a program.
Ayuhara-san, I wanted you
to know who you're playing against.
We were focused on Tōnan High School
during this championship.
We wanted to find out why these girls are even
playing volleyball, when they're practically like robots.
Or rather, we wanted to make it clear to them
that it's wrong to play volleyball like machines.
And I spoiled your plan.
Ayuhara-san.
Katsura's state isn't your fault.
If Katsura was a little stronger…
…it's quite likely that you would've been
the one who couldn't play volleyball now.
Imagine if it had been the other way around.
What would you expect from Katsura then?
Ayuhara-san.
I want you to win against Tōnan.
I want you to show them
the real volleyball.
That's the reason
why I brought you all the way here.
I understand.
Go get them, girls.
Kozue.
Finally, the finals.
The last match of this fierce tournament.
Tōkai's representative, Fujimi High…
…versus Tōkyō's representative, Tōnan Academy.
The teams are lined up on the court.
In their last match Fujimi defeated Jidōin,
who had been the champions for the past three years.
Will they be able to keep their
winning streak in this match as well?
Or will the victory go to Tōnan, the so-called
"computer academy" that is playing a perfect game?
We hereby open the All-Japan High School
Volleyball Tournament Finals.
Go! Go! Tōnan!
Will Fujimi be able to do something
against computer analysis?
Or has volleyball entered into a new era?
We look forward to this match.
Look at their complacent smiles.
Can they really predict
what we're going to do?
The outcome of this game
was already computed, Ayuhara-san.
I don't believe it.
They can't just calculate our moves
in advance with a computer. That's absurd.
We've entered into our computer
all the data we had on Fujimi.
Especially the data on Ayuhara-san.
It's all perfect.
Even if you have collected our data,
and you have calculated our moves…
I want you to show them
the real volleyball.
For Katsura's sake.
I don't want to lose to machines.
But I can't use my spike.
Keep the serve!
– Keep the serve!
Here goes!
I knew it.
They hit the ball like they already knew
that Makimura-san would miss.
It was just a surprise attack.
I-I don't think it was just that.
Heh!
It was just a fluke.
Get ready.
Naka!
Are you okay?
Yeah, I am.
But I thought the Captain's spike
was gonna score.
I'm sorry.
It's okay,
it's okay.
Yeah. We'll make them
double pay.
Right?
– Yeah!
Something's not right.
It's not just Tōnan's computer analysis.
Something's up with Ayuhara-kun.
Captain!
I have to get it right this time.
No matter what I try,
I can't use my spike.
Tōnan
Tōnan's attack is sensational.
They quickly shift from a precisely calculated
defense formation into a thunderous counterattack.
It's like the six of them
are united as one.
Or, to put it in different words,
they move like gears in perfect sync.
Tōnan · Fujimi
This time, for sure!
Damn!
I won't make it.
Captain!
You're on the wrong side!
Kozue!
Hold on, Captain!
Ayuhara-san's body is still tense
from all that stress.
It might be difficult
for her to recover.
This will be a good test
for her maturity.
Right now, all we can do is wait
for her to recover from that shock.
She has to recover on her own.
You're trying hard, Ayuhara-san.
But it's all in vain.
Kozue, get a grip.
You have to spike.
For everyone's sake.
I know that.
But I can't hit the ball.
I just can't.
This isn't good.
They're only going
to discourage themselves.
Captain!
We're going to lose to a machine.
This is unbelievable.
I have to regain my spike
right now.
Let's finish this game.
Tōnan's changing
formation again.
Captain!
Makimura-san tosses me the ball, and they're already
prepared to receive my spike at my usual hit spots.
Even though I know that, at that moment it's already
too late to change the direction of my spike.
Is this the power
of the computer's analysis?
I want you to win against Tōnan.
For volleyball and for Katsura.
Ayuhara hits the ball!
She did it!
Ayuhara hit the ball.
Kozue, you hit it!
You hit it, didn't you?
I was finally able to spike.
Ayuhara's spike misses!
So what?
It's fine.
One step at a time.
I hit it, but—
It's okay, Kozue.
It really is.
But it didn't score.
Relax. It's no biggie.
Just relax
and do your usual thing.
Thank you.
Forget about Katsura-san, too.
Yeah…
Alright!
Let's follow our captain! Fight!
Look at them, so cheerful.
Alright, next up
is the windmill strategy!
I have to score.
It's not just a matter of hitting or not.
I have to earn us some points.
Ayuhara-kun is in a tough spot.
Damn!
Yet another one
of Tōnan's strategies!
Despite their efforts, Fujimi gets
thoroughly blocked and can't score any points.
They're completely powerless.
They have such a huge lead.
Higaki-san and her team
don't look anywhere near happy.
They're growing impatient.
Of course they are.
We're gonna win this.
Hey, cheer up a little, will ya?
Hah!
You're dead right.
Ishimatsu, you can be
so smart sometimes.
She's right.
I guess it's time to get serious.
Oh? You're telling me
you weren't serious all this time?
Huh?
Just messing with you.
Right, Captain?
Yes.
Let's get them, girls!
Say what you want,
but I know you're all very nervous.
Professor Hongou
still isn't asking for time.
I guess that means I somehow have
to make a breakthrough by myself.
Damn those volleyball robots.
Here it is!
Good!
Oh!
Ayuhara has spiked again.
It didn't deceive Tōnan's
defense formation, though.
Tōnan · Fujimi
Finally, Ayuhara showed us
the spike we all know.
But Tōnan's shifting formation
returns it easily.
I spiked the ball with my left arm
and it didn't leave any impression on them.
What kind of spike
do I need to surprise Tōnan?
Professor Hongou.
I'll let them continue.
B-But…
Ayuhara's offense
is utterly diffused.
I know it full well.
The problem is Tōnan's players.
How they execute with a perfect precision
their computer's instructions.
How do we fight it?
I don't know that yet.
Anyhow, we need
something extraordinary.
The spikes are the only technique that could
make a difference. There's no other possibility for us.
But can a bunch of human girls
take on a computerized team?
We believe in volleyball.
We love volleyball.
It's not an exaggeration to say
that we have devoted our lives to it.
Everyone is watching us
play volleyball.
But what… is volleyball?
Is there anything we can do
against a computer?
Did you want to win so bad
that you had to destroy her life?
Ayuhara Kozue,
the great attacker, my ass!
No matter how much
we devote our lives to it…
Does it justify
hurting other people?
Is such volleyball
worth anything?
It hurts…
I don't want us to lose
against a machine.
Y-Yeah! We'll show them
our human volleyball!
Time to get serious.
We just have to grit our teeth.
Why are they even
playing volleyball?
Why am I?
I don't know.
I don't know anything anymore.
What is volleyball?
11 to 0.
Tōnan is dominating.
In the end, it seems that humans
are destined lose against computers.
Nonetheless Fujimi doesn't seem
to want to give up yet.
Serves you right, Ayuhara-san.
You poor little thing.
I remember how you sobbed
when Mom has passed away.
We promised that we'll play forever,
the three of us.
Katsura.
How did we end up here?
"No hope for recovery…"
"Won't be able to play anymore…"
This is insane.
It's all her fault.
No matter what Kaori says,
I will never forgive her.
Shizuka.
You can't let yourself
go that way.
And what way is that?
You know what I'm talking about.
You can't blame Ayuhara-san
for Katsura's injuries.
Say what you want.
Ayuhara-san was the one who kept aiming
at Katsura because she was the weakest.
Yeah, and? It was a sensible tactic.
Blaming her won't change anything.
I'm done listening to you.
No matter what anybody says,
I will never forgive that girl. Never.
Do you intend to retaliate?
Do you really think retaliating
would make Katsura happy, Shizuka?
Katsura.
How are you feeling?
Everything's… dark…
Kozue!
This is what I get.
It's my punishment
for getting too full of myself.
Tōnan · Fujimi
We're more tired
than we had anticipated.
Maybe we wanted
to finish it too early?
Let's take it easier
in the second set.
Do you see it, Professor?
I mean Tōnan's players.
Huh?
What are you talking about?
It's the sweat.
The sweat.
Sweat?
Sweat…
Also, they're panting like crazy.
Why didn't I notice that sooner?
Alright, let's try it.
It's the sign!
Huh? A-Attack?
Double attack? Now?
Tōnan · Fujimi
And it's a point!
Tōnan wins the first set by a shutout.
I knew it.
No matter what I try,
it's all hopeless.
Their computer has predicted
our every single move.
Tōnan's players may have
received our double attack…
…but they didn't notice
its physical impact on their stamina.
We're going to lose.
There's nothing we can do.
I can't win against a machine.
A machine that has no soul…
Fujimi loses motivation
after losing the first set by a shutout.
"We cannot win
against a computer."
Hongou approaches discouraged Kozue
and says with a firm voice:
"Ayuhara. Player change."
There's someone on the bench
whose data wasn't analyzed by the computer.
Katsura recovers consciousness.
Kozue regains motivation.
Who is going to win the finals:
the humans, or the machines?
Please look forward
to the next episode!
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.