苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 078—
An excellent victory
Tōnan's feint scores them
another point.
Ayuhara completely misses the ball.
Finally, the they lose the first set by a shutout.
Fujimi · Tōnan
The first set's over.
15 to 0. Tōnan is dominating.
Good job! Good job! Tōnan!
The end of this year's Interhigh
spring tournament is drawing near.
Fujimi High School, who has defeated one
opponent after another including the mighty Jidōin…
…vs. Tōnan Academy,
known as "the computer academy".
The first set was completely one-sided.
In the end, humans
cannot win against computers.
They're like volleyball robots,
controlled by a computer.
The kinds of volleyball we play
are worlds apart.
Captain.
Kozue, come on.
Get a hold of yourself.
This set has cost Fujimi a lot of strength.
The players are visibly exhausted.
The shock from the tournament favorite,
Ayuhara not having made a single point…
…will be difficult
for the Fujimi team to deal with.
The audience is watching in silence, bewildered by
a clear result in the fight between man and machine.
For the first time I start to believe that
they might lose no matter what they tried.
Nonsense.
How could a human
lose against a machine?
I could understand us.
But Ayuhara-san?
They'll jump back on their feet.
I'm sure of it.
I'm sorry.
No.
It's okay, Ayuhara.
– Huh?
I won't deny that no matter what tactic
we try, they defend against it completely.
But I have noticed something important.
As they were approaching the set point, they were
sweating and out of breath, including Higaki.
Fujimi · Tōnan
They're human after all.
Yeah.
Of course they are.
Now you're saying "of course".
But weren't you earlier under impression
they're precise like robots, Ishimatsu?
Hmm.
If you put it that way…
This is important. No matter
how perfect a plan their computer devises…
…they're still the ones
that need to carry it out.
They're normal girls,
just like you are.
Go! Go! Tōnan!
Alright!
We just have to tire them out.
Yeah, but how?
"How?" Hmm, that's… Uhh…
Their computer must have calculated
how tired they are going to get.
Yeah.
However, their computer's strategy
was derived from the analysis of our play.
That's their weak point.
– Huh?
Let's make things simple.
What you think will happen if we play randomly?
They'll collapse.
Exactly.
We'll stop playing according
to any plan or common sense.
A chaos.
Operation "Chaos".
This is how we're going
to attack them.
Huh…
But if we play chaotically,
we're bound to lose a lot of points.
Yes.
But there is no other option
for us to face Tōnan.
Alright.
The second set is to stir them up.
Misses are fine.
Selfish play is fine.
Just play however you like.
– Y-Yes sir.
– Yes sir.
One last thing.
Ayuhara.
Sir?
Change with Ishikawa.
Huh?
You want me to replace Ayuhara-san?
C-Coach.
Go!
Yes sir.
H-Hey.
What is Ayuhara-kun doing?
Wow, that's terrible.
I know she's missed, but that's too much.
Looks like the chance for Ayuhara-kun
to recover is getting further and further away.
Oh?
Ayuhara-san's benched?
Heh. It's only natural if she misses her spikes,
even if she is their captain.
But our strategy didn't account for this.
We'll be fine. She's a reserve player anyway.
There's no way she can compare to Ayuhara-san.
Ishikawa-san.
Let's do our best.
For our Captain's sake, too.
Yes.
– Well said. Let's score a lot.
– Yeah! – Yeah!
We'll show them what we have!
– Yeah!
The second set begins.
Fujimi team seems lively again.
They're very motivated
to win the second set.
But how good will the decision
to change Ayuhara turn out to be?
The ball enters the Fujimi's side!
Fujimi · Tōnan
Fujimi scores the first point.
It was a rather lucky spike, but Fujimi's
fighting spirit is met with a warm applause.
Alright, we did it!
It's our first point!
It's just like Coach said.
Let's make it the first step of our comeback.
– Yeah!
This is for the best.
I'd drag their feet.
It was just a stroke of luck.
We can't let it happen again.
Exactly.
Let's stay calm.
Just you watch.
I'll teach you a lesson you won't forget.
Will Fujimi's luck last?
Takeichi has the ball.
Are you okay, Naka?
I'm sorry!
No worries.
Yes. Misses are fine.
Fujimi didn't enjoy their one point for long.
Tōnan's got the right to serve back.
Tōnan serves!
Someone…!
Tōnan changes formation yet again!
Fujimi · Tōnan
They flawlessly score a point.
Fujimi's powerless.
The tied the score to 1 to 1.
Tōnan continues their offense.
Good job! Good job! Tōnan!
Fujimi · Tōnan
I'm sorry, Midori.
I don't know anything anymore.
Volleyball.
Volleyball I've played all this time…
That I sacrificed everything for.
That has made me unable
to say goodbye to Tsutomu-kun.
That has become
the only thing I have.
Volleyball is the only thing
that's left for me.
My volleyball…
has wounded Katsura-san so badly.
I didn't think it's something
I need to use to hurt others.
My inability to use spike
must be God's punishment.
Losing to a machine volleyball
is my well-deserved retribution.
Katsura.
How are you feeling?
Good, Sis.
How is Ayuhara-san doing?
You should rest,
not think about her.
Don't worry about me.
How is the match going?
Fujimi lost 0 to 15 in the first set.
They let Tōnan lead
in the second set as well.
Really?!
Ow…
Don't move around, silly.
Relax, Katsura.
Fujimi's bound to lose.
Where's Ayuhara-san?
What's she doing?
She's no good.
She was benched after the first set.
Serves her right.
Shizuka, you seem
to misunderstand something.
Huh?
I'm sure seeing me collapse
must have been a shock to you.
But I don't hold a grudge
against Ayuhara-san.
I lost against Ayuhara-san,
the best attacker in whole Japan.
It was a splendid match.
I bet Mom would've been
proud of me, too.
Of both of us.
Katsura, that doesn't change—
Sis, what are we doing?
Ayuhara-san's losing to some computer,
watching the game from the bench.
Is that our rival?
Where is her willpower?
She makes me want to beat her.
Take me to the gym at once.
I want to give
Ayuhara-san some courage.
She has no right to treat me that way.
Sis, take me to—
Katsura,
you know you can't move.
Come on!
Katsura.
I understand.
I'll go to the gym on your behalf.
Shizuka…
I'll tell her what you
just said to me, every word.
If Ayuhara-san doesn't react to that…
I'll slap her cheeks
till they're crimson red.
Leave it to your sis, Katsura.
Okay. Thank you.
Fujimi · Tōnan
It's an one-sided game for Tōnan.
Not Hayakawa's spikes, nor Makimura's feints
don't seem to work. There's no chance of winning.
"No chance of winning"?!
Don't screw with me!
Bring Ayuhara-san—
Yeah.
Bring Ayuhara Kozue back!
Yeah!
Bring Ayuhara-san out!
This is incredible. The crowd is cheering
for Ayuhara, demanding her back on the court.
No… I can't do it.
Time!
Fujimi calls a timeout.
Will the coach put Ayuhara on the court?
Ayuhara-san.
Shizuka-san…
How is Katsura-san feeling?
I have done an unforgivable thing.
Stop, we don't have time
for this right now.
I'm here to relay a message
from Katsura to you.
Huh?
Katsura-san's message?
I don't hold a grudge
against Ayuhara-san.
Ayuhara-san's losing to some computer,
watching the game from the bench.
Is that our rival?
Where is her willpower?
She makes me want to beat her.
She has no right to treat me that way.
I want you to tell her this,
and see how she responds:
"Show me the victory
of human over machine."
"If you are our rival, that is."
"If you are our rival, that is…!"
Katsura-san.
Katsura-san…
If you understand Katsura's feelings,
please show her your answer, Ayuhara-san.
I understand.
I'll do what I can.
I'll be watching you.
Professor Hongou.
Ayuhara.
Please, let me on the court.
Okay.
Go get them.
Kozue.
The game resumes.
Ayuhara came out.
There's a loud applause.
But what difference
can Ayuhara make?
Good luck.
Ayuhara-san!
Show us what you're made of!
Go! Go! Fujimi!
I'll play with everything I have once again.
I want to repay my debt for Katsura-san.
Watch me, Katsura-san.
Look who showed up.
What does she hope to do now?
Whatever.
Only five points left.
Let's finish this!
– Yeah!
– Midori!
– On it!
Attack!
Alright!
She did it, she did it!
Keep it up.
I'll give you a nice serve.
Let's show them!
– Yeah!
Falling leaf.
It's the falling leaf!
Fujimi · Tōnan
Why did you miss?
You should receive it
with a blindfold.
But it was much stronger
from the usual thing.
I'm not a machine.
The fault is yours.
There's no way
our computer isn't right.
Fujimi · Tōnan
An excellent spike from Ayuhara!
She's recovered and impresses everyone
with a very strong performance.
Her good form transfers to the whole team.
Is Fujimi going to catch up?
They aggressively continue to attack!
Fujimi · Tōnan
Volleyball dictated by a machine
cannot be called the real volleyball.
There's only one thing
I can do for Katsura-san right now.
I don't think it's going to
erase my guilt entirely.
But that's still
something I have to do.
Tōnan stands dumbfounded
before the reborn Fujimi's attack.
Each of their player is exhausted and the computer
dictated formation shifts no longer work.
Finally, it's a tie!
It's a set point for Fujimi.
The ball is at Fujimi's side!
Fujimi · Tōnan
Fujimi shows a complete change
compared with the first set.
The computer
didn't predict this at all.
They'll do fine now.
The third set is safe.
We did it.
We did it!
It's too early to celebrate.
No. It's fine.
Apparently their computer went mad.
No matter who my opponent is,
I am still me.
I'll fight with all I have
till the bitter end.
Sis, how is the third set?
It's like you said.
Fujimi is leading.
I see.
Shizuka kept her word.
Ayuhara-san did too.
Yes.
Do you want me
to put the TV a little closer?
No, it's okay.
I don't need to look at it
to know exactly what's going on.
How Ayuhara-san looks and how she moves.
It's as if I was right there.
Now's her spike.
See?
You're right.
I know for sure that
they'll win the game.
I'm a little tired.
Katsura.
Don't worry.
Ayuhara-san's victory
is a wonderful gift.
I have to repay.
Seeing her, I am burning to be able
to play against her again.
Katsura, people like you…
…are already asleep?
Ayuhara-san's willpower
pales before yours.
Little by little,
I see what's before me.
It's a battle to protect
the things I believe in.
I'll win, not only for Katsura-san,
but also for myself.
Keep it up, Ayuhara!
Ayuhara's comeback made wonders.
The computer is completely powerless
against Fujimi's remarkable offense.
Fujimi · Tōnan
The game approaches its climax.
It's a match point for Fujimi.
Attack!
It vanished?!
And it's a point. The last play of today's game
is Fujimi's dreaded vanishing attack.
Tōnan Academy was completely overwhelmed
by the Ayuhara · Hayakawa duo's play.
Fujimi achieves a miraculous victory
after it has reforged itself anew.
Kozue.
Midori.
Captain…
Words do not reflect
the magnificence of Ayuhara's comeback.
All I can say is that
it was truly, utterly brilliant.
You were watching me, right?
I was.
Congratulations, Ayuhara-san.
Katsura-san.
I'll tell Katsura
about a great human victory.
Captain Ayuhara Kozue, who was surprisingly
put out and then back onto the court…
…today showed us a great willpower.
Her perseverance in spite of the grim circumstances
has motivated the whole Fujimi team.
Tōnan Academy, who has chosen to embrace
the progressing industrialization…
…watches their opponents
take the pennant with longing expressions.
You did well, Fujimi High.
After winning the spring's tournament,
Fujimi's team has decided to go on a trip.
On their way, Kyouko is approached by a creepy
biker group looking for a pretext for a quarrel.
In Kozue's eyes,
nothing serious has happened.
Next day, a female delinquent in a red leather
jacket, Maya, appears before Ishimatsu.
Fujimi receives a challenge from an ominous
group calling themselves the Mighty Six.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.