苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 079—
The girl who wears a leather jacket
Victory
I wonder if Mitamura-kun will be there?
Nobody will show up.
It's Sunday.
So what if it's Sunday?
They'll all be there to welcome us.
I think so, too.
After all, we have won.
Maybe the whole school
is coming to see us.
But you care only about
Mitamura-kun, don't you?
It's okay if there's no one
to welcome us.
What matters most is that we know
we did our best ourselves.
– Don't you think so, Ayuhara-san?
– Yes.
Oh, look.
We're already so close to Mt. Fuji.
Come on, girls.
Let's get ready.
Let's see, let's see…
No one's here.
What a disappointment.
That's strange…
I don't believe not a single person
came to pick us up.
What are you doing?
Exit is this way.
Yes, yes.
We're going, we're going.
Gates
I think our parents
are outside, Kozue.
That's where Mitamura-kun
must be waiting for you, too.
Victory
Mother…
Congratulations on your victory!
Victory
We have fought hard.
We wanted to have nothing to be ashamed of
when we look back in five or ten years.
That's all.
Honestly, we weren't thinking of anything grand
such as winning for our school or for the city.
And yet you've all come here
to celebrate our victory with us today.
I'm not sure if we deserve it.
Of course you do!
He's right!
You're our friend!
I love you, Kozue!
I'm sorry for you,
but the only thing I love is volleyball.
Rejected, rejected.
Professor Hongou.
It is honorable that your girls are so modest,
but I think sometimes they are too modest.
What do you mean?
I think they deserve a bit of rest
after so much trouble.
Of course, I do not want
to criticize your methods.
Oh, no, by no means.
That's a great advice, Mr. Headmaster.
I've already told them to rest
during the Golden Week…
…and let themselves forget
about volleyball for a while.
Hmm?
Makimura proposed a trip.
That's a great idea.
Good, good.
Watch out!
Now I understand why they won.
Good, good.
"Many are the hills,
the mountains of Yamato.
Yet when I ascend heavenly Kaguyama,
the peerless mountain…
…when I look down on the land, where the land
stretches, hearth smoke rises everywhere.
Where the water stretches,
water birds fly everywhere.
Ah, a splendid country,
this land Yamato of bounteous harvests!"
I think I have read it somewhere.
What was it again?
Kojiki, right?
Kojiki – the oldest extant chronicle in Japan
Man'yōshū – earliest Japanese poetry anthology
It's Man'yōshū.
Emperor Jomei.
Ah, of course.
Let's go.
– Yeah.
– Okay.
A deer!
Hah, a deer!
You're such a kid.
Ah! You have to wait
for your turn.
Who is it?
Who is it?!
It's me.
Why the heck are you
scaring off poor animals?
Poor?
They're pretty sly, you know.
Sly?
They're weak,
so they beg for food.
Those beasts approach only to take food,
not because they like you.
I can't stand parasites like them.
They don't deserve anything.
But I have even less sympathy
for those who let themselves get duped like that.
Hey!
Wait up.
You're worse than the fawns.
I scared you with nothing.
Coward.
Coward?
You messed with the wrong person, gal.
My name is Ishimatsu.
I'll make you not forget that.
Ishimatsu?
I've got to tell you, Ishimatsu,
you've got one hell of an attitude.
Out of my way.
You're ugly, but strong.
Do you play volleyball?
Volleyball?
So, you too?
I'm a regular player
in the Fujimi High School team.
Huh, the number one
high school in Japan?
So, what difference does it make?
What?
I may hate begging fawns,
but I hate weak posers like you even more.
Are you trying to make me mad?
It's working well!
Ishimatsu, what are you doing?
Ah, I think I know her.
It was Ayuhara just now, wasn't it?
Hey, watch you honorifics!
I have no respect for her.
Just look at her big eyes and round face.
She'd be better off dancing
rather than playing volleyball.
Oh, she's here.
Goodbye, Ishimatsu-san.
Who was it just now?
Never mind her.
Geez.
Outta my way,
outta my way!
I've heard that only about one
in thousand deer hates people.
I like you.
You should have a bit more courage.
But it's not like
you guys live long, anyway.
She made fun of us, but what's more,
she tortured innocent deer.
I can't quite imagine it.
Shut up!
Don't interrupt!
Ishimatsu, calm down. We could afford
this hotel thanks to Hayakawa-san.
If we keep yelling,
they'll drive us out.
Alright, alright.
But wait, there's more.
She said that in her opinion it's absurd
that we're number one in Japan.
Huh?
Word for word,
"I hate weak posers like you".
Wow, she said that?!
Then she started
to talk trash about Ayuhara-san.
Rather than playing ball,
she should play on stage.
That's terrible!
And you just stood there
letting her talk all that?
I won't forgive her that!
Yeah! Let us know
next time you see her.
I'll cut her to pieces for Chief.
Oh, no! Is this how
Yamato girls behave at the table?
They're late.
They got full, so they went
to play some table tennis.
We spent a little too much today.
Don't worry, we'll economize tomorrow.
The moon's out.
Yes.
"On the horizon – isn't that the same moon
that rises in spring over the Hill of Mikasa?"
A poem by Abe no Nakamaro
(Kokin Wakashū 9:406)
It's so beautiful…
Especially at night.
It's so quiet.
Ah, it's those bikers again!
Left: Uguisu Falls
Right: Takisaka Walking Path
Ishimatsu, are you done?
Everyone went ahead.
What's taking you so long?
How much more are you going to drink that water?
I'm going, I'm going!
She doesn't get how great
this water is. Geez.
I'm going without you.
Takeichi-san, wait.
Hurry up or
I'll go without you for real.
Your stomach will hurt,
Ishimatsu.
Oh, come on. It was clear,
just like drinking water.
Let's take a break.
Yeah.
Oh, I'm so tired.
How much further do we till
Yagyū Kaidō?
I'd say we're halfway there.
Let's wait for Ishimatsu here.
Yeah. Maybe they've stopped, too?
Man, they're moving fast.
Hurry up and you'll rest
as long as you want.
They're sure taking their time.
Look, they're already here.
Oh, they're here.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Let's go.
We're going already?
Not even a little pause?
From now on it'll be even more scenic.
You'll be enchanted.
Various religious structures made of stone.
First an okagetōrō,
then a kasajizō.
After we pass through the forest,
it's a gorintō.
A large temple in Nara Prefecture.
Then after we pass it,
it's one of the National Treasures, Enjō-ji.
I don't think I'm gonna make it.
She's like a walking history book.
You don't have to take history classes
to enjoy the scenery.
But it's nice to focus on something other than
receptions, blocks and attacks once in a while.
You're one to talk.
What is that ball doing on your back?
Professor Hongou told us to forget
about volleyball for a couple of days.
And here you are.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
It was out of habit.
I feel kind of lonely and insecure
if I don't have one around.
Kozue, you're a real
volleyball freak.
Oh? This time it's Makimura-san.
Makimura-san, we'll be going ahead.
Sure.
I'll catch up to you shortly.
Watch out!
Ah!
Are you okay, Tobe?
Heave-ho.
Alright.
Damn, that was close.
You hurt?
I'm unscathed,
but the lamp doesn't seem to work.
You've got to be kidding.
We can't drive in the dark anymore.
I'm sorry.
Really, girl.
Sorry won't cut it.
Do you have money
to pay for the repairs?
Yes. Uhm…
But I have to return to hotel first.
Where is it?
It's a guest house
near Shin'yakushiji.
It's in the opposite direction.
Too bad.
You're with friends, aren't you?
Talk to them and let them
come up with something.
Oh!
We'll be waiting at Enjō-ji.
I'll keep this as collateral.
Let's go, Tobe.
Yeah.
Geez.
Don't they have better places
to drive through?
Oh?
It's Makimura-san.
What happened?
Don't you worry, Makimura-san.
When it comes to money,
I can always ask my Dad.
Come on,
there's no need for that.
They're the ones
who have to be more careful.
But how do we make them
return the sketchbook?
I'm sorry to give you
all the trouble.
It's just a sketchbook.
They can keep it.
That's no good.
All you promised them
was to go to Enjō-ji.
Yep. We'll go to Enjō-ji.
Then we'll kick their asses.
Yep.
So, you want to solve it
with a brawl?
Now, now.
Let's not be so direct.
Kozue, what do you think?
For now let's just go to Enjō-ji.
Then we'll see.
Maybe they threw a false accusation.
But what if they didn't? We'd better not run off.
Captain,
sometimes you're too soft.
Forehead, how much
do you know about engines?
Engines? Ah, well,
I know a thing or two.
Wow, it's so beautiful.
So you came after all.
Do you have the money?
Yes, we'll give it in a second.
Oh, that's great.
Take your time.
Ah, it's you who fell, isn't it?
Hm?
Yes. So?
Oh my goodness!
You're bleeding.
Huh?
You must've injured yourself
when you feel.
Don't move around much.
I'll help you out.
I'm sure I'd feel something, though.
What a cool machine.
What is that?
"Mighty Six".
It's the symbol of our group.
Whoa, even cooler stuff.
What does it refer to?
It sounds pretty rad.
Hey, it works fine.
Hey!
Oh!
I'm glad it's working again.
Well then.
Hey! W-Wait up!
As if I'd listen to you.
Damn!
Captain!
Grab me once again,
and I'll show you my "falling leaf".
Let's go!
Damn it to hell!
Wait.
How was it?
Now you see?
Tobe, Tani.
You can't underestimate them.
You were absolutely right, Maya.
I'm convinced these girls will be
worthy opponents for our Mighty Six.
Waking up so early really gets to me.
I know it's bad to sleep for too long,
but man, I'll need a day outta my life after that trip.
He looks strong, doesn't he?
I love Buddha
when he makes such a face.
It's you!
I've been waiting.
For me?
Anybody from your group would do.
But it'll be easier
if it's you, Ishimatsu.
Wanna come with me?
What for?
Well, I see you're still angry,
are you not?
You're offended because I dared
to criticize your team and your captain.
Don't start with this trash again!
See? You're threatening me again.
Stop being so impudent
or I'll make you so.
Impudent?
Oh, is that how you see me? Then what if I say
that Ayuhara is a weakling and a show-off?
You've asked for this!
Stop messing around.
If you want to fight me this bad,
I'll take you to just the right place.
How does that sound?
Or maybe you chicken out?
Ha! It's you who should be chickening.
Alright.
Come.
Have you seen Ishimatsu?
No, I thought she's here already.
Not even a trace of her.
Where could she be?
I'll look for her again.
We're here.
We're sorry about yesterday.
You tricked me!
You said we'd fight one-on-one.
I never said anything like that.
One-on-one fights are boring.
I was thinking more
about a six-on-six fight.
Why don't you
introduce yourselves to her?
Me first.
Tani.
I'm a former tennis champion.
You'd better take me seriously.
I'm Tobe.
I have fourth dan in jūdō.
Kamura.
I'm a soccer goalkeeper.
Kasagi. I'm a boxer.
My name is Tamiya and I have won
the national championship in wrestling twice.
That leaves me.
I play volleyball a little.
The six of us
are the Mighty Six.
Ready?
Go!
Go, go, go!
We challenge Fujimi High School,
the number one team in Japan.
Ishimatsu!
Ishimatsu…
Ishimatsu takes the The Mighty Six' challenge
all by herself and receives severe beating.
Kozue watches wounded
Ishimatsu in terror.
She wants to avoid pointless fights
and unnecessary conflict.
But the Mighty Six's continued taunting
put her patience to the test.
Finally she's pushed over the edge when Maya
starts to drive her bike in a blindfold.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.