苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 080—
Bitter determination
We're here.
Sorry about yesterday.
You tricked me!
You said we'd fight one-on-one.
I never said anything like that.
One-on-one fights are boring.
I was thinking more
along the lines of six-on-six.
Why don't you
introduce yourselves to her?
Me first.
Tani.
I'm a former tennis champion.
You'd better take me seriously.
I'm Tobe.
I have fourth dan in jūdō.
Kamura.
I'm a soccer goalkeeper.
Kasagi. I'm a boxer.
My name is Tamiya and I've won
the national championship in wrestling twice.
And that leaves me.
I play volleyball, a little.
The six of us are the Mighty Six.
We challenge Fujimi High School,
the number one team in Japan.
Ishimatsu!
Ishimatsu…!
Kozue!
Kozue, I think I know
where Ishimatsu went.
Really?
A man working in the temple
saw Ishimatsu…
…riding a motorcycle with someone
heading towards Ashibi Woods.
It's gotta be someone
from the Mighty Six.
Ishimatsu is in danger!
We have to go save her, Chief!
Yes.
Shut your mouth!
Hmph.
You can drop the tough act.
If you don't stop screaming like crazy,
you'll dry up your throat.
W-What the heck?
Alright, now you listen to me.
As mentioned earlier, we want to
make a name for ourselves in sports.
Volleyball or whatever,
we want to fight strong opponents.
If there's a mountain, we climb it.
If there's someone strong,
we fight them.
That's the way we live.
It's who the Might Six are.
W-W-What a-are you
talking about?
T-T-There's no need t-to stutter.
Well, there you have it.
Make sure you pass that to Ayuhara.
And if your team gets any ideas to run away,
we'll chase you, even to the bottom of hell.
There's no escape. Got it?
Who said we'd run away?
Ishimatsu ain't no coward!
Good! Don't forget those words.
Hmph! Right back at you.
Heh, I've got to admit,
I do like that temper of yours.
Now go to Ayuhara
and tell her about our challenge.
We'll be waiting
for you at Enjō-ji.
Laters!
Damn! Damn! Damn!
Cornering me
and treating like a fool!
Ishimatsu, please,
don't complicate things any further.
Ishimatsu!
Ah. C-Captain!
What happened to you?
What happened?
Come on, tell us.
Captain!
Those scumbags!
What's going on, Ishimatsu?
What's wrong?
Ishimatsu.
You can tell me.
I'm so angry!
Huh? They challenged us…
Yes. They want
to hold a match with us.
What's going on
inside their heads?
Challenging us,
the No. 1 High School in Japan.
That's a good one.
No, you've got it wrong.
They're serious. Real serious.
It's better to let
sleeping dogs lie.
You shouldn't fall
for their provocations, Ishimatsu.
So you don't accept
the challenge?
Exactly. Just ignore them, we don't have
any obligation to play with them.
Are you kidding me? You weren't there,
you have no idea how serious they are.
If you're telling us to run,
then count me out.
Ease up. We're here to go
on vacation, not to play volleyball.
Captain is absolutely right
when she says we should ignore them.
No. I disagree.
It's cowardly to run away
from the enemy.
I can't stand when someone makes a fool of us.
We have to teach them a lesson.
Aren't you angry?
Ishimatsu, stop getting so
worked up over nonsense.
One of the most celebrated temples in Japan
Makimura-san, our destination
is Hōryū-ji today, right?
Yes.
Then we'd better
forget about it quickly.
Let's go.
Ah! C-Captain, wait up!
A haiku by Masaoka Shiki
"If you eat a persimmon,
the bell rings in Hōryū-ji".
The pagoda in Hōryū-ji is the oldest
wooden building in the world.
Just how old?
The temple was commissioned by Prince Shōtoku,
which makes it about 1200 or 1300 years old.
Series C 10.000 yen notes (1958)
Ah, that's the guy
from 10.000 yen bills.
It's so wonderful.
Shaka Sanzon – Gautama Buddha attended by two figures
Shitennō – Four Heavenly Kings of Buddhism
Shaka Sanzon and Shitennō.
They just don't get it. Fine.
I don't know about them, but I simply
don't ignore when someone calls me a coward.
Captain thinks they're harmless.
But she couldn't be more wrong.
Besides, I promised them
we'd have a match.
Are you telling me
to go back on my word?
This is it. Look, that's the temple
that can be seen on the 10.000 yen bill.
Right?
Yes, you're right.
It's Hall of Dreams.
Ah, indeed.
Oh?
Where's Ishimatsu?
Wasn't she with you?
Strange.
Where could she go?
Ishimatsu!
Come on!
You can do it!
Okay, it's my turn.
You did it!
Right on!
Alright!
What's up, Maya?
Look there.
Oh, it's her.
Is she back
with the reply already?
She has more backbone
than I thought.
Alright, let's go talk to her.
Yo. You're earlier
than we thought.
I like it.
Yeah, but…
What did Ayuhara Kozue say?
Uhm…
Come on, Ishimatsu-san.
You'd better not turn us down
after all that bravado.
I'm afraid I have to.
What?
Captain didn't listen to me at all.
That's why… That's why
I'll take you on by myself.
It'll be just me.
Don't screw around.
What can you do by yourself?
Let's do it like this. I'll try to receive
three spikes from each one of you.
If I get 10 out of 18
throws right, I win.
What do you say?
Does that work for you?
Yes.
Alright.
Let's start with me.
Let's go.
Tamiya, don't hold back!
Show her your best shot!
We've looked for her all over the place.
I don't think she's here.
Kozue, why don't we split up
and search for her at different places?
Yeah, maybe she went back
to the guesthouse.
Midori, Naka,
check there.
Ayuhara-san, I think she might have
gone back to Enjō-ji to meet with the Mighty Six.
What if she went there
to fight them all by herself?
You have a point.
I hope she didn't, though.
Makimura-san, Takeichi-san,
please check Enjō-ji.
Try to avoid trouble.
I understand.
Forehead and I will search for her
here in Hōryū-ji again.
We meet at the guesthouse.
Show the girl her place, Tobe.
Here I go.
Who's next?
Bring it on!
Alright, time for a little exercise.
Just to warn you,
I play volleyball as well as soccer.
Don't hold it against me
if you break a bone or two.
Quit your yapping.
Are you gonna play or not?
Or maybe you're too scared?
Heh. Don't cry after.
What are you doing?
Stand up.
I won't let those
pieces of garbage win.
Here we go!
Dammit!
Hey, it's getting boring.
Stand up already.
Is that all you have?
Are you gonna run cry in your captain's skirt?
Where did your boldness go?
Tell us, Ishimatsu-san.
I'm still waiting for my turn.
I still haven't spiked
a single time, Ishimatsu.
I can't find her anywhere.
She's really not here.
I see.
Ishimatsu.
Where did you disappear to?
I have a bad feeling about this.
Really bad.
Bring it!
Or are you just gonna
stand there, knucklehead?
Heh. Have it your way.
Looks like game's over.
Not quite yet.
Color me surprised.
You're pretty obstinate.
Okay, I'm the last one left.
Toss.
Okay.
Catch.
She fell, she fell.
– Hey, hey!
– Is it over?
– Oh!
– It's Ishida-san!
Ishida-san!
Stop it!
Why did you attack her?
We're here.
Are you hurt?
Makimura-san…
You ganged up on her
six-on-one, you cowards!
Say what you want,
but we're not the ones who started it.
We didn't force her to volunteer.
Don't blame us.
She broke her promise.
If you have something to say,
then play a volleyball match with us.
I-It's so annoying.
Annoying? Then come fight me.
I'll take you on any time.
Knock it off!
It's dangerous!
What are you doing?
Let's go!
Tell Ayuhara Kozue this:
If you refuse to play against us,
we'll force you to.
You know we're serious.
The Mighty Six
do not go back on their word.
Make sure Ayuhara hears it.
Is that clear?
Till next time.
Kozue, are you going to remain silent
after what they had done to Ishimatsu?
It's not just Ishimatsu.
They bullied us, too!
Yeah! I can't stand people like them.
I'm itching to teach them a lesson!
Let's settle this in one go!
– Yeah! – Let's get them!
– Captain…
Makimura-san,
what's your opinion?
As far as I'm concerned,
their behavior is appalling.
But to them,
everything is just a game.
So is their "challenge", and I don't think any one
of us wants to play volleyball for fun with them.
So you say it's all good
if they insult and attack us?
Sorry, but I'm with Ishimatsu.
Besides, if we actually ignore them,
they'll follow us as long as it takes.
You've heard what that Maya girl has said,
she'd force us to play no matter what we decide.
What do we do, Kozue?
Leave this matter to me.
Kozue, what are you
planning to do?
I don't know yet.
For time being,
I'm going to approach them directly.
I'll try to talk to them
and stop from further harassing.
I'll make them apologize
to Ishimatsu as well.
Ayuhara-san, I'll go with you.
It's fine.
I'm the captain.
I'll go by myself.
Kozue!
– Captain!
– Captain…
Ah!
Her eyes.
It's not just a game to her.
She's feeling alive,
right here, right now.
Ayuhara Kozue…
we finally meet face to face.
Yes.
There's something I want to say
to you and your Mighty Six.
Hey, Maya.
What's up?
Wait a sec.
I'm all ears.
I want to say two things.
The first thing is
I want you to stop harassing us.
The second thing is that I want you
to apologize to Ishida Matsue, the girl you bullied.
– Say what?
– Is she serious?
– You've got to be kidding me.
– Who do you think we are, lass?
I'll kick your ass.
Silence.
Okay. I'm fine with both
of your requests.
Are you for real, Maya?
We're going to bow our heads
to these lowlifes?
Shut your trap.
Stay out of this.
Ayuhara, we have
a condition of our own.
Huh?
Just one condition.
Play a game of volleyball
with us, the Mighty Six.
Huh? W-What?
I don't want to hear
that you can't. Listen.
We'll play no matter what.
No matter what.
No. We can't do it.
We're not going to play
without a permission from our coach.
Huh? You're more naive
than I expected.
You don't have to tell him.
It'll be our secret.
No. It's out of question.
We won't play with you.
Kozue!
Midori.
We will.
When I see someone strong,
I just can't let them off the hook.
I want to try and challenge them,
no matter the cost.
If I don't, I'll feel dead inside.
My heart doesn't feel a thing.
I want to feel alive.
It's the best thing in the world!
She has the same look in her eyes she had
when she did the handstand on her bike.
So you're saying that there's no way
you will play volleyball with us?
Yes. There's no way
we will play with you.
Maya, are you sure about this?
Yes.
T-Think it over.
You haven't practiced it yet.
Don't do it.
It'd be better
if you had more experience.
Maya, it's too dangerous.
I want to do it now.
When I see someone strong,
I just can't let them off the hook.
I want to try and challenge them,
no matter the cost.
If I don't, I'll feel dead inside.
My heart doesn't feel a thing.
I want to feel alive.
It's the best thing in the world!
Watch out!
It's too reckless.
We've got to stop her!
Are you stupid?
There's no stopping Maya.
But if she falls, she'll—
She won't.
Just watch!
Ayuhara, I hope you're aware that she's
doing this only because you don't want to play.
Damn, there's a hole ahead!
S-Stop!
– She did it!
– Hell yeah!
Kozue, watch out!
She's driving here.
Enough!
She's serious.
I understand her.
Perhaps riding a motorbike with
a blindfold is reckless and stupid.
But even so, I can understand her feelings
and the drive to dedicate her life to it.
Alright.
I'll accept your challenge.
I respect your drive.
You win, Maya-san.
Please take off your blindfold.
We'll play against you.
We accept your challenge.
Really?
That's good.
We'll play tomorrow.
We'll let you know
time and location later. Okay?
Yes.
Seeing Maya recklessly putting her life at risk,
Kozue gives in and accepts the challenge.
Fujimi team heads back to the guesthouse
and starts to practice in the open air.
But Inomata and Ishimatsu, irritated by lack of
contact from Maya, secretly go out to investigate.
Inomata protects Ishimatsu,
but gets injured.
The match draws near.
Will Kozue and the others
be able to defeat the Mighty Six?
Please look forward
to the next episode!
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.