苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 081—
One-set match
Ah!
We challenge Fujimi High School,
the number one team in Japan.
If there's a mountain,
we climb it.
If there's someone strong,
we fight them.
That's the way we live.
It's who the Might Six are.
Fujimi High School, no. 1 in Japan.
We challenge you!
Do you accept it?
We do.
We'll play tomorrow.
We'll let you know
time and location later. Okay?
Kozue.
Captain.
What can I say? We'll fight against
the Mighty Six tomorrow.
But we only play because we don't want
to lose our face as Fujimi High School.
– Fight!
Good morning!
– Good morning.
– Morning.
You're up so early.
Are you practicing for a volleyball game?
Yes.
We're not the only ones
who took their jerseys.
Apparently none of us can completely
break away from volleyball.
Even though that was
the whole point of this trip.
– Let's go.
– Yep.
One-two! One-two!
Fight! One-two!
Fight! Fight!
One-two! Fight!
One-two! One-two!
Let's get started
with the training, guys.
Huh? Training?
Heh! Come on, Maya.
It's just a bunch of girls.
But you don't even
know the rules.
I know them more or less.
We make our own rules.
You can't break the rules
if you don't know what they are, big boy.
Get your butts up.
Alright, I'm convinced.
Let's give it a go.
Besides I think it's better
not to underestimate those girls.
Don't forget that we challenged them
because they're the strongest out there.
Okay, play the balls I throw you
back to me the strongest you can.
Alright.
I'm ready!
Kamura.
So cool!
Misses, it's noon.
You must be hungry.
I made you plenty of onigiri!
Whoa, I've been waiting for this!
I'm so out of energy
and can't train anymore. Gotta refill!
I'm going ahead!
They still haven't contacted us.
What's going on?
Who in the world
is this Maya anyway?
She must have a great deal of confidence,
otherwise she wouldn't have challenged us.
Kasagi!
Tobe!
Tamiya.
Hit the ball as hard as you can.
What?
What's so funny, Maya?
Looks like it'll be
an interesting match.
I see.
Heh! We'll show them
the power of the Mighty Six.
Alright. Line up.
We'll practice receptions.
We're still at it?
It's to defeat the best team
in whole Japan.
One! Two! Three!
Nice!
Hey, Ishimatsu,
It's going to get dark soon.
I wonder what are they doing.
Maybe they chickened out?
They're not like that.
But yeah,
what the heck are they doing?
Let's take a short pause.
I'd say it's more
than enough for now.
But I wonder where they are.
They should contact us
as soon as possible.
Hey, why don't we go have a peek
at what they're doing?
Sounds nice to me, but do you have
any idea where they are?
They aren't exactly hardest to notice,
so it shouldn't be too difficult to find out.
You're right. Let's go
while the rest is taking a break.
Look at her.
She takes it too seriously.
Agreed.
At first I thought it'll be fun.
But a volleyball training?
Come on.
Who needs a training?
We're the strongest.
We're the fearless Mighty Six!
You don't have to tell me, man.
Yo! Look who we have here.
Yo.
Why are you goofing around? Shouldn't you
be on your way to Suzuka for the race?
We've decided to have some fun
before we go win that rally.
Oh? Is sightseeing so fun?
We take a sightseeing toll.
Hah! That's rad.
See you later.
Let's go!
Do you really think they're up there?
Someone saw them drive up that hill.
It won't hurt to have a look.
Watch out, Ishimatsu!
Ah!
I guess it wasn't them.
Yeah, but they do have
similar vibe around them.
Just as expected, not a soul.
We'd better head back.
You hear that?
We haven't contacted you yet.
Did you come here
to spy on us?
O-Of course not.
You're lying.
Spies annoy me.
B-But we're innocent.
Tell him.
What a cliche line.
We can't let you go back.
You're annoying, too.
What!?
Oh? You couldn't wait for the match
and came to pay us a visit?
Let's play.
Catch.
Let's go.
Bring it on!
Don't do it, Ishimatsu.
I won't run away from the ball.
Come on already.
Don't cry after.
Is that all you have?
Good.
I like your spirit.
I'm Ishimatsu
of Fujimi High School.
Cut it out!
Forehead!
Forehead.
Now two went missing.
What happened this time?
I can't believe it.
What are we going to do
if they tell us to hold a match now?
Oh, they're here!
Time – six o'clock.
Place – AB Motors.
AB Motors?
If you ask people in town,
they'll point you in the right direction.
See you.
Good that you have seven people.
Looks like one of you won't be able to play.
Huh?
What do you mean?
Forehead!
Forehead.
Captain…
Forehead!
AB Motors Co., Ltd.
Land Transport Bureau certified factory
How are you feeling,
Forehead?
Yes, thank you, I'm just a little sore.
I'm angry I can't play, though.
You should've stayed
at the guesthouse and rested.
Oh, don't be so cold.
At least let me cheer for you.
You crack me up.
AB Motors.
This is the place.
They deal with motorcycles, huh.
It looks like a factory
manufacturing motorcycles.
Somehow I doubt they have
a volleyball court here.
Maybe we'll play
on an assembly line?
Let's go inside.
You have kept your promise.
Very good,
like true champions.
Here, let me show you
where we're gonna play.
Assembly line.
Just saying.
There.
Huh?
Oh!
T-That's—
It's a motorcycle test course.
It should be good.
The court is okay,
but it's getting dark.
We'll light it up, of course.
Lights!
Pretty nice, don't you think?
Yes.
We have no objections.
Just one last thing.
We're going to need a referee.
I'm fine if we play without one, but maybe
she can do it since she can't participate anyway.
Okay, I'll do it.
Everyone's ready?
We'll play one set.
Good?
Good.
Let's go, Mighty Six!
– Yeah!
Hah, it's like we play
against a circus troupe.
Begin the match.
Show us what you've got!
Serve.
Point for the Mighty Six.
Server change.
Third point for the Mighty Six.
Don't be discouraged,
we're only at the beginning.
Don't fall for that trap.
Fight!
– Fight!
Ah!
Who are they?
They're just a few of our fans.
It's livelier that way, isn't it?
Turn it down!
Here I go!
Attack!
Fujimi High – six points,
Mighty Six – eleven points.
Good luck, Mighty Six!
We'll be waiting for you in Suzuka.
Yahoo!
They're playing very aggressively.
– Let's push them back.
– Yeah! – Yeah!
Fujimi High School – eight points,
Mighty Six – eleven points.
They're getting tired.
Let's push further.
– Fight!
All right!
Kozue!
Perfect sync!
And a body blow!
Fujimi High School – eleven points,
Mighty Six – eleven points.
So the time has come.
Just you and me, Ayuhara Kozue.
Attack!
Fujimi High School - fourteen points,
Mighty Six, thirteen points.
The game isn't over yet.
Here we go.
Ah! Kozue!
Attack!
They did it!
I mean, we did it!
Fujimi wins!
Mighty Six loses!
Captain!
Kozue!
Captain…
Kozue.
Ah!
She injured her leg.
Captain.
Use this.
Ah, you're bleeding!
Maya-san.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Let's go, Mighty Six!
– Yeah!
What a girl.
She called her "captain"…
I-It hurts.
Kozue, is everything okay?
Kozue!
Captain…
Kozue's team wins
with the Mighty Six.
But Kozue's wound sustained during the fall onto
the motorbike got tetanus and she collapses.
Her life is in danger
if she doesn't get an antitoxin.
A terrible storm breaks out.
Contact with the outside world is cut.
Maya learns about Kozue's crisis
and drives in the thunderstorm.
She hurries to deliver the antitoxin.
Will she make it in time?
What happens to Kozue?
Please look forward
to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.