苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 082—
Run, Mighty Six
Hm? Captain's fallen behind again.
You're right.
Maybe she takes a rest
somewhere again?
There's something off
about her today.
It's the last day of our trip…
Maybe she sat down
because her wound hurts so much?
Hm…
I asked her about it this morning
and she said it's not that bad, though.
But…
But?
She said she's feeling a bit weak.
It's only natural.
It's her first trip in a long while.
She must've built up a lot of stress
in the spring tournament.
Yeah, besides, we just played
against the Mighty Six. You can't blame her.
Kozue!
Captain!
– Captain!
– Ayuhara-san!
Why do I feel so weak
from the morning today?
Honestly, I'd love to turn back
and just stay in bed all day.
But I'd worry the girls if I did.
Captain!
I'm going, I'm going.
Kozue, is your leg really okay?
Yes, it is.
I'm fine, really.
Let's go.
We're almost at the summit.
Just one last push. Come on!
– Yeah!
Heave-ho.
Heave-ho!
Whew.
Looks like our Chief has recovered.
She's the first again.
We made it!
What a great view.
It was tough,
but I'm glad we made it.
You can see Nara from here.
Huh? Even though it's that far?
Yes. It seems that's really it.
We have come a long way,
much further than I expected.
We're near the prefectural border.
Look, you can see Suzuka over there.
And behind that mountain,
it's Ōsaka and Jidōin High School.
Now that you mention it, didn't the Mighty Six
have some business in Suzuka?
Maya…
Damn.
At first I thought they're
just a bunch of delinquents.
But Maya had this
mysterious charm around her.
She had this inner restlessness,
pushing her to find new challenges.
Kozue, why are you spacing out?
I wasn't thinking about anything in particular.
I was only admiring scenery.
That's fine, but you haven't eaten
even a single onigiri.
I have no appetite.
Kozue…
Chief, is it because
of your injury?
It's fine.
See?
Leaving that aside…
Yes? What is it?
I-I'll have an apple.
Okay! I'll give you mine.
But could you give me
your onigiri in return?
Sure. Here.
It was too easy.
Oh my god, a lightning!
Thunderstorms in the mountains
can be dangerous.
I'm scared.
Let's get to safety.
C-C-Captain!
Ishimatsu, don't panic.
Don't forget your belongings.
– It got dark so fast!
– Hurry up!
Damn.
Wait.
It's going to start raining on the way.
It'll be a disaster.
We need to find a shelter somewhere.
But we're in the middle of nowhere.
It hurts…
Kozue!
– Captain!
Kozue, what's going on?
Hang in there!
I'm fine.
She has terrible fever.
Is it because of her injury?
What if…
What if, what?
What if…!
Talk to me, Makimura-san!
There's someone coming!
Ah! Mister!
What are you girls doing here?
You should get to a shelter soon.
One of us is sick.
Can you tell us where the next village is?
If you go down the mountain, there is one about
an hour from here. But they have no hospital there.
Oh, right. There is a medical shelter
from the University of Ōsaka nearby.
They also have a pharmacy, and there's a doctor.
But I'm not sure if he's working today.
That's great!
Where is it?
Kozue!
Chief…
It hurts…
Ayuhara-san!
Found it!
Oh, I see you need help.
Luckily, today there is
a university doctor on duty.
Thank goodness!
Unfortunately,
you'll have to wait a bit.
He was called down to the village
for an emergency.
Anyway, please come in.
Let's get your friend on bed for now.
Yes sir.
Makimura-san, you…
Your father is a doctor.
You know what's happening to Kozue, don't you?
Hey, if you do, please tell us.
What if Chief…
Kozue.
Hang in there, Kozue!
Captain!
There's no way that's it.
Ayuhara-san's…
No, it can't be.
I could be wrong.
Please, let me be wrong.
God, I'm begging you.
Don't let me be right.
The manager told me you're here.
What's going on?
Doctor!
Ayuhara-san is…?
Alright, girls.
Stay calm and listen to me.
It's tetanus.
It's quite serious,
but we don't have an antitoxin here.
I'll contact nearest hospital.
What happens
if she doesn't get treated?
She's going to die.
W-What are you talking about?
Hello?
Hello!
Hello!?
I can't hear you well.
Huh!?
A landslide?
What about a helicopter?
Cut the crap!
If she doesn't get it, she'll die!
Hello!?
Alright.
Let's try the faculty now.
Hello?
Hello?!
Hello!
There was a landslide on the way to Yagyū Highway
from Nara City and the road has been blocked.
Helicopters can not take off
in this storm either.
I was about to call Ōsaka University.
But looks like the landline was cut, too.
Doctor, Chief… Ayuhara-san… is she really going
to die if she doesn't get the antitoxin?
Please do something, Doctor!
I could cut out the wound.
But in her condition I would have to
amputate the leg below the knee.
Wait a sec!
But if we're lucky,
amputation could save her life!
But if Kozue can't play volleyball anymore,
she'll be devastated beyond imagination!
There's still hope.
You can't do that!
Hey, do you have a death wish!?
C-Captain… Captain is…
Our captain is…
Captain?
Ayuhara Kozue?
Captain.
She got a sedative injection.
But she can still feel the pain…
If we do not do anything, her respiratory system
will be affected next and she will suffocate.
We have to get her the antitoxin.
How much time do we have
before she has to take the drug?
The sooner the better.
I would say that the midnight is the limit.
We can't wait any further than that.
Every minute counts.
After that I have to amputate
and hope she pulls through.
I'll bring you the antitoxin.
Huh?
Have you gone mad? There's a terrible storm
out there, and the road to Nara is shut off.
It'll be fine.
I'll go to Ōsaka through Suzuka.
Please promise me, Doctor, that you
won't amputate the leg before 12 o'clock.
I understand.
Take this with you.
I trust you, Doctor. If you cut it before
the promised time, you will regret it.
Got that?
Yes.
All right! Let's go!
– Yeah!
– 'Aight!
Let's go!
If all went according to the plan, they should've
reached the medical university by now.
All right. I'll make sure an ambulance
gets the drug there as fast as possible.
It won't reach them
before midnight.
Please give it to me.
I'll deliver it personally.
Three and half an hour…
It took longer than expected.
We go at full speed.
Got that?
– Yeah!
Fine, here you go.
Thanks!
Okay, let's get going!
I'll hold them back.
Hurry up!
Hurry!
Tani…
Tobe.
We're fine.
Take this!
It's over, Captain.
Kozue, watch out!
You're… Tsutomu-kun!
Tsutomu-kun, please answer!
Tsutomu-kun!
Tsutomu-kun,
I want to be with you!
Don't come here.
Kozue, stay away!
Don't come to the light!
It's too early!
Tsutomu-kun!
Tsutomu-kun…!
Captain!
Chief!
Ah!
Ishimatsu!
She didn't make it after all.
Ayuhara Kozue!
Don't die.
Don't you dare dying!
Maya-san!
Captain…
Ayuhara Kozue.
The Mighty Six
keep their promises.
Maya-san!
Hurry up and take this.
We made it in time, huh.
Thanks to the on-time delivery
of the antitoxin, Kozue's life is saved.
This success wouldn't happen
if it wasn't for Maya's great effort.
Maya walks away.
When Kozue learns of it,
she begins to think about Maya.
One day, a boy appears before Kozue.
He evokes in Kozue feelings
that vaguely remind her of Tsutomu.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.