苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 083—
The whistling fellow
Stay away!
Don't come any closer!
Stay away from the light!
Doctor, please wait.
Please give her time until 12 o'clock.
– Please!
– Please, Doctor!
No.
We can not wait any longer.
Kozue, please forgive me.
Forgive me…
Ayuhara Kozue!
Don't you dare dying!
Maya-san!
Captain…
Ayuhara Kozue.
The Mighty Six
keep their promises.
Maya-san.
Doctor!
She doesn't need
amputation anymore.
– Wonderful!
– Thank goodness!
But we have to watch
her condition for a while.
Now it all depends
on her resilience.
No problem.
No problem at all.
When it comes to resilience,
no one can beat her.
Kozue was through so much
and always pulled through.
That's right.
Captain is as tough as steel.
It seems like a miracle
happened in this storm.
We have to thank Maya-san!
I can't see her anywhere.
She is really healthy.
I guess she owes it to volleyball.
There is nothing to worry about.
– Thank goodness.
– That's great to hear!
Kozue.
Kozue!
Shh!
Keep your voice down!
Miss…
She's fine.
Kozue… I worried so much.
You look so pale…
We are really relieved that things
are getting better here.
We owe it to Doctor Noma here.
Pleased to meet you.
My name is Noma.
Pleasure is all mine.
My name is Ayuhara.
We are really thankful.
Oh no, there is no need.
I only happened to be here.
But I have to say
she took it really well.
I am very happy that her
parents have come here.
Yes, they got here very fast.
Fortunately she got
a bit better by now.
I'm to blame for everything.
After all, it was all my idea…
Don't blame yourself.
It's all in the past.
Do you think worrying is what
Captain would have wanted?
I heard that there is a risk of developing
a pneumonia after getting infected with tetanus.
She will be fine.
The fever came down
and I gave her antibiotics.
I see. She had certain heart condition
when she started middle school.
Yes…
You don't say?
I would never have guessed.
She is a picture of health now.
You don't see it very often.
What about her leg?
Will she be able to play again?
There is no doubt about it.
It would be a different story if she
had taken the antitoxin even an hour later.
But now,
she is going to be fine.
Truly, it was a miracle.
It feels so good!
It's like yesterday
was a bad dream.
Kozue?
Kozue.
Oh, it's so bright…
Kozue, how are you feeling?
Mama!
Kozue, Papa and Midori
are all here.
W-What happened to me?
You're finally awake!
Midori? Girls?
What happened?
You got tetanus.
Tetanus?
Yes. Your wound from our match
against the Mighty Six got infected.
W-What happened next?
Kozue.
What matters is
that you're alive now.
Ah…
Everyone here saved your life.
They even drove all the way to the university
hospital in the storm to get you the antitoxin.
Wow…
You did…?
No. It was Maya-san
and the Mighty Six.
Mighty Six…
But why?
A terrible storm broke out yesterday.
The road has been blocked.
The contact with
the outside world has been cut.
We had to get the antitoxin
from the university medical hospital in Ōsaka.
But an ambulance
would have never made it here.
So Maya-san and her group
tried the impossible.
Very well.
Let's race.
I don't think I'll ever have the opportunity
to race to save someone's life.
Come!
They took that challenge.
Then they delivered the antitoxin
before 12 o'clock like they promised.
Your life was saved.
Maya-san won the race.
I… I didn't know
Maya-san was like that.
Where is she now?
Let me talk to her.
She's not here anymore.
She came here by herself, then she disappeared.
By herself?
What about the others?
What happened to the Mighty Six's members?
Why aren't you saying anything?
Midori.
Forehead.
Ishimatsu.
Ah…
Did she say anything?
Did she just disappear without a word?
She said one thing.
That if we don't save you,
she won't ever forgive us.
If you don't save her,
I won't forgive you!
Maya-san…
Thank you.
You put your life on the line
in order to save mine.
Girls, let's play.
I want to finally see
the ball fly again.
I'm fine already.
Don't you want to feel again
what's it's like to receive, to spike?
Why are we still here?
Looks like she's fallen asleep.
Yes.
But it's amazing how much strength
and energy those kids have—
Shh.
I'm alive.
I'm so lucky.
Maya-san… I want to play volleyball
as soon as possible.
My love belongs
to the volleyball field.
Just like yours
belongs to the motorcycle.
Maya-san, thanks to you,
I've learned a lot in the last few hours.
I won't look back.
I will live my youth looking up,
challenging the world…
…just like you do every day.
Kozue?
It's been only a week, at least put on
a hat to protect yourself from the sun.
I'm not a kid anymore.
I'll be fine.
By the way,
I have something for you.
Here, it's a letter from Midori-san.
Thank you.
Alright, I'll be going.
Please don't go far.
Okay, okay.
I'm off!
Be careful!
Ahh, it feels so good.
Let's take a look.
That's so like Midori. Everything's so pretty,
from the handwriting to the envelope.
Alright, then.
"My dad told me that you are
recovering slowly but steadily."
"We're overjoyed
that you're still here with us."
Professor Hongou was visibly relieved when
we told him and told me to congratulate you.
We exercise every day
for the next tournament until dark.
We're a bit rusty after the holiday.
But the training is already showing results
and we start to regain our form.
We all, Professor Hongou and us,
greatly desire that we will win again.
"…that we will win again."
"Please be patient and take
your time to recover, Captain."
They're doing their best.
And here I am,
just sitting around.
I feel like I was left behind.
What a sorrowful whistle.
It's him.
Oh! Yuuko!
"Yuuko"?
Oh, excuse me.
Oh, wait.
You dropped this.
Thanks.
Don't mention it.
Sorry I freaked you out
back there. Take care.
What a strange,
yet familiar feeling.
My heart never pounded like this,
no matter how strong opponents I faced…
She's like her twin.
To think she's just
a random stranger…
He seemed to mistake me
for someone else.
He clearly called me "Yuuko"…
Kozue, you look flushed.
Did your fever go up again?
I'm fine.
I just walked a lot.
I told you not to
overexert yourself.
I'm really okay, Mama.
Ahh!
But really,
look at that wondrous sunset.
I didn't know the air in the mountains
was so clear and beautiful.
Oh, great mountains!
Kozue?
Kozue.
Kozue, did something
good happen?
What makes you think so?
You look really cheerful.
Well, it's no wonder.
I'm able to walk again.
You have a point.
Oh, it's him again.
"Him"?
Yes, it's someone I met during walk.
Nothing special.
He looks really handsome.
Maybe a university student?
Him? Handsome where?
He was rude to me.
He mistook me for someone else.
Kozue, how old are you?
For real, Mama?
I'm 17.
Come on, Mama, how could you
forget your own daughter's age?
But why are you asking me that
all of the sudden?
Oh, it's nothing.
We'd better get ready for dinner.
Mom's being weird.
"Kozue, how old are you?"
"17."
"Yes! The best age there is."
17 years old Kozue.
Adolescence feels so good!
Wait, did I fall in love?
No way…
When I transferred to Fujimi Academy
and met Tsutomu-kun for the first time…
My heart was racing, too.
But it feels different now.
When I looked at him…
It was almost hypnotizing.
It was hard to breathe.
It was such an exciting sensation.
But I don't understand
this strange feeling.
Huh? Tetanus?
Yes.
It was a terrible storm.
She needed immediate treatment,
and was about to die.
No car could make it.
Not even helicopters.
Then how did she survive?
She got the antitoxin from
the nearby medical university hospital.
It was delivered by some bikers.
Bikers?
I heard about some bikers causing chaos in
the mountains. I wonder if it were them?
By the way, I heard
that he comes from Tōkyō.
He's a second-year
university student.
I can't believe you, Mama.
How could you ask him that?
I only happened to overhear
some gossip.
You wouldn't have the courage
to ask him anyway, would you?
I would.
So, what's his name?
You should ask him yourself.
I don't care enough.
But what did he come here for?
If I had to guess,
I'd say maybe hiking?
Hiking.
I wonder if that's all there is to it.
When he called me Yuuko,
he paled as if he saw a ghost.
Maybe it meant
something traumatic for him.
Yuuko!
He went down early this morning.
I see.
Yes, and then he told me that
he found something interesting…
…on the way to the mountains.
Some broken motorcycles.
Huh? Where?
Where did he see them?
How do I get there?
First you have to cross a river.
Then you pass a lumberjack hut.
Thank you!
Hey! You can't push yourself yet!
That way is too dangerous for you!
I knew something bad
happened to Maya-san's group.
I need to check it.
Excuse me, mister. Did you see
a young man pass through here?
Never mind.
Hey, wait up.
There.
Oh?
What is he doing?
It's a sad story.
Three years ago,
a girl lost her life on this rock.
That girl…
was Yuuko-san.
Yes, I believe that was her name.
They went for a walk and wanted
to take a photo there…
…when the rock suddenly
collapsed under her.
It was a terrible sight.
She was such a cute girl.
The boy comes to visit her grave
every year ever since.
He always puts
such beautiful flowers.
I have dark memories
of my own, too.
Tsutomu-kun's death.
Even now, I feel it
engraved deep into my chest.
Really, she looks just like her.
Yuuko-san has died in these
mountains whereas I lived on.
One life was taken away,
and one life continues on.
Watch out!
What was she doing!?
What were you thinking?!
I… I…
Were you trying to kill yourself?
You should be more careful!
Your life was just saved.
Do you remember how much everyone
struggled so that you could survive?
Or did you forget that already?
Wait!
Hop on.
B-But…
It's not the time to be embarrassed.
Don't you care
what happens to your leg?
Are you fine if you
can't play volleyball anymore?
I'm sorry.
Wow, you weigh more
than I thought, chubby girl.
Hey, I'm not chubby.
What's your name?
Ayuhara Kozue.
Well, that name isn't so bad that you
had to jump into water.
Stop making fun of me.
Let me get off.
I'm sorry,
I'm sorry.
I'm Yushima Jirou.
U-Uhm…
Please let me get off.
It's embarrassing.
I'm happy.
Huh?
You startled me
when we met for the first time.
I thought you were
a ghost of my little sister.
Little sister?
Yes, remember how
I called you Yuuko?
It's the name of my little sister.
If you're not careful,
you'll end up like her.
You're right, but I wanted to see the crashed
motorbikes that I was told you found.
Crashed motorbikes
are not people's lives.
Yes.
– Miss!
– Kozue!
Oh! Mama!
Alright, from here
you better go on alone.
Yes.
Be careful and take
good care of your leg.
You can bet I will heal soon.
I don't want to waste any more time.
I will walk by myself,
with all I have like I always did.
The Fujimi team travels to Nagano
to train for the next Interhigh.
There, Kozue once again hears
the beautiful melodic whistle.
She meets Yushima again.
In the meantime Fujimi
is challenged by Aoba Academy.
Kozue gets to see Yamamoto's eerie figure on
the court again, along with someone unexpected.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.