苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 084—
That person is my rival
Fujimi High School Girls Volleyball Club
Liberté Mountain Retreat
Ishida-san.
Calm down.
There's no rush.
No, they've gotta hear this good news
as soon as possible! Alright, I'm off!
Really…
Fight! Fight!
Coach!
Big news!
– What is she talking about?
– Did something happen again?
What is it, Ishimatsu?
Coach!
What in the world happened?
Ow!
You better not be saying
that you burned our dinner.
She's coming!
Captain is coming!
Kozue?!
Captain?
Did she recover already?
Yahoo!
We just got a telegram.
She'll be joining us tonight!
Wah!
I see.
Ayuhara's coming…
I hope they're doing well.
Even if I was left behind
a little, I won't lose.
Right after this summer
training camp is the Interhigh.
I'd better do my best.
What a pretty stream.
Ah? Yuuko!
"Yuuko"?
It feels so good…
I'm Yushima Jirou.
I'm Ayuhara Kozue.
I'd better hurry.
And with that flawless counter, the boxer guy
collapsed on the ground like a sack of potatoes.
Next up was the jūdō dude. The ball was like "wah!"
and there, he flies all the way through the court.
With a single blow!
Next up was the wrestling guy.
Come on, that's enough.
Looks like it was
one funky match.
I wish I had seen it.
Really, you're right.
I'm sorry we played without
your permission and that I hurt myself.
It's fine.
You've already apologized.
I'd like to meet them.
Sounds like they're quite funny.
Yes. They're very nice people.
You look just like
my sister Yuuko.
She was so cute…
She died in that mountain.
At first I thought
you're like two peas in a pod.
But when I looked closer,
I realized I was wrong.
She seemed more fragile
and helpless than you.
But when I look into your shining eyes,
I see the power in you.
That melody…
It's not my imagination.
It's the same.
You're… Ayuhara-kun.
Ayuhara-kun, is it you?
Yushima-san.
Well that's really a surprise
that we met here again coincidentally.
When did you come here?
Actually, just now.
I see. How's your leg?
It's in perfect shape, thanks.
That's good to hear.
You know, I thought about writing a letter
to the clinic when I get back to Tōkyō.
But I'm terrible at writing.
I wrote something, too.
Huh? When?
About two weeks ago,
when I was allowed to leave the hospital.
Then it must have arrived
a little bit after I left.
If I had stayed a bit longer,
I probably could've read it.
Why don't you tell me
what you wrote now?
Then I'll be able to reply
without any more delays.
No.
It's not something
you can say out loud.
Why?
Well, a letter is a letter.
I see.
Then how about writing it again?
You'll be here
for a while, won't you?
Yes.
Then that settles it.
Let's meet here tomorrow
at the same time.
Then I'll read your letter,
and give you my response.
Does that work for you?
Yes.
Ah, Yushima-san…
Hm?
Are you camping here
with your friends?
Not quite.
I'm here for my work.
Work?
One of my colleagues from the university
asked me to do something.
Kozue!
See you tomorrow.
Okay.
Good night.
Who was he?
Do you know him?
He's just someone I know.
How close are you?
Did you want
something from me?
Ah, yes, the meeting is about to begin
so I came to pick you up.
Uhm…
Let's go, then.
Strange…
What is?
Hey, hey, come on, don't hide things from me.
Is he someone special to you?
I just told you,
he's just someone I know.
I smell something fishy.
We'll be late to the meeting.
Ah, Kozue!
Wait for me.
Alright, attention.
I'm holding a dodgeball.
It's much heavier
than a volleyball.
From today on,
we'll practice receptions with it.
It's to strengthen your
wrists and thighs. Understood?
– Yes sir!
– Yes sir.
Good. Ayuhara, you first.
Sir.
Here we go.
Ayuhara-san!
Were you hurt?
I'm fine!
I see.
Alright, let's continue.
Can you believe she's been
hospitalized for a month?
Well, that's Chief after all.
She's our true captain.
Alright.
Hayakawa, you're up next.
Yes sir!
Yamamoto-san.
Ayuhara-san.
Ayuhara-san, I haven't forgotten
about the promise we made in the spring.
That we'll grow above and beyond
and meet you again in the summer Interhigh.
Yes.
Volleyball isn't
an individual game.
You reminded us the most important thing:
that it's a game you play in teams of six.
We need to thank you properly.
Yes, exactly. I think we'll reciprocate best
by winning against you on the volleyball field.
Alright. It's not going
to be easy, though.
We're even stronger
than we were in the spring.
Just like us.
See you at the Interhigh.
Yes. Until the Interhigh.
Okay, let's go!
Oh? It's Aoba's Coach.
What did he come here for?
To pay his respects, of course.
We're number one team in Japan, after all.
I think he's here to ask us for a match.
Don't you think so too, Kozue?
Yes, that might be it.
Don't pay attention to them.
Let's get going with the training.
Come on, toss me the ball.
Sure.
We are already in a very advanced
phase of our training program.
But you know as well as I do that training
and practice are two different beasts.
I was very excited when I learned
that your Fujimi team is here with us.
Would you agree to a match with us?
We'd be very thankful.
But we have just finished basic training.
I think it's too early for us to play—
That should be enough
for a practice game.
We don't have to play right now.
We're willing to wait
two, three days.
I see…
Please.
Hayakawa-san!
Come here for a bit, girls.
– Yes sir!
We'll hold a practice match against
Aoba Academy the day after tomorrow.
I knew it.
Fine by me.
Bring it on!
I'll finish them all by myself.
Nakazawa, Ishida.
S-Sir.
Aoba Academy is a sports school that gathers
the best players from all over the country.
You do know what they're
capable of, don't you?
Last time we played against them,
Yamamoto and Shirakawa…
…rather than playing together, were competing
with each other and that's what made them lose.
But I heard now that they've learned their lesson,
they're undergoing some immense training.
Even if it's just a training game,
make sure you take them seriously. Got it?
– Yes sir!
Good. Resume training.
All right, let's get going.
You can do better.
I never thought that
I'd see Yushima-san again so soon.
To Yushima Jirou-sama
From Ayuhara Kozue
What's your name?
Ayuhara Kozue.
It has a nice sound to it.
I'm Yushima Jirou.
Please let me off.
No, I can't.
I'll carry you all the way.
U-Uhm… It's embarrassing.
I'm happy.
Huh?
Ah, Kozue!
Ko—
Sorry for being late.
Don't be.
I had to stay late at work.
– At work?
– Yes.
Uhm…
Here.
Hm?
It's the letter I promised.
But I didn't write
anything special.
I only wrote I'm thankful for your
kindness and such stuff. That's all.
Ayuhara-kun.
I think it's better
if I don't accept this letter.
Huh?
I saw a shadow
of my late sister in you.
I thought you were
a cute girl, like my sister.
But you're not my sister.
It's better if this doesn't go
any further than that.
What do you mean?
Yushima-san, you're a nice guy.
I'm glad I got to know you.
That's what I think.
But why can't I be friends with you?
Why can't I write letters to you?
You see, people write things in letters
that they can't express in person.
That's what would happen
if I answered your letter.
This is why…
Sorry, but I still
don't understand what you mean.
Ayuhara-kun, you have already found your goal
in life. You have a great career ahead of you.
That should be the most
important thing for you right now.
And that goes for me, too.
We have to respect each other.
See you.
Yushima-san!
Kozue…
What's with you, Ayuhara?
Come on.
What's wrong?
Where's your form?
You won't receive
Aoba's spike like that.
You can't forget how great
Aoba's attacker Yamamoto is.
Coach, let me instead.
Stand up, Ayuhara.
Yes sir.
Kozue…
Let's go, Ayuhara.
Tōwa Silk KK Gym
Thank you very much.
Kozue, look.
Ah!
What's wrong?
Who is he?
Hm?
Oh, him?
It's the captain of
Tōto Sports College Volleyball Club.
He was asked to be a temporary lecturer
for this camp at a request of Mr. Matsuki.
Alright!
Now show me your spike!
Yamamoto!
Yes sir!
Hit it with more power!
Yes sir.
Maybe it was too soon.
Oh?
Oh, sorry, I was thinking out loud.
It might've been too early to let them play.
I heard that Yamamoto
has mastered a tremendous spike.
What kind of spike, I wonder?
Yushima-san is…
Yushima-san is the coach
of my rival school?
Kozue learns that the beautifully whistling
Yushima is actually her rival.
Yamamoto's spike turns out to be even sharper
and more destructive than at the previous Interhigh.
Everything starts to collapse when Midori gets
injured by the ball closing in on her at high-speed.
Makimura and Ishimatsu quickly join her
and get knocked out as well.
What kind of secret lies
behind Yamamoto's spike?
Please look forward
to the next episode!
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.