苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 085—
The Devilish Mammoth-Spike
Tōwa Silk Gymnasium
Keep it up!
Alright, you've got this.
– Yeah!
– Yes!
Naka, Midori.
Steady, now.
– Yeah.
– Let's do our best.
We're ready.
Maybe it was too soon.
Huh?
It might've been too early
to let them play.
But I did hear that Yamamoto
mastered a tremendous spike.
What kind of spike, I wonder…?
Ah!
Professor Hongou.
Aoba Academy didn't put
Yamamoto-san on the court.
What?
I wonder what their game is?
Looks like it's their coach's strategy.
Are you kidding me?
They're not taking us seriously.
Let's make them regret giving us
that handicap. Ain't that right, Chief?
Huh?
It must be Yushima-san's decision
to put Yamamoto-san on the bench.
What's their goal?
Fujimi is confused.
Even though they have no reason to be.
It is common to hold the best player, after all.
Oh, Hayakawa is the server, huh?
Will we be alright, though?
Yes.
Just leave it to Yushima.
He can tell the place where the ball
is going to land the moment it's hit.
Oh, no!
Nice, nice!
Good.
Yushima-san is smiling.
Ah!
Falling leaf…?
The players from Aoba
are using my technique.
Yushima-san.
It's worse than I anticipated.
And here I thought Yamamoto-san was
the only one we had to worry about.
Really…
They've all improved so much.
Their coach seems
extraordinarily knowledgeable.
He just keeps smirking at us.
And he's acting like
you aren't even here.
It's only natural.
We're on different sides, right?
Still…
Still what?
One laughs best
and one laughs last.
Yushima-san.
You have already found your goal in life.
You have a great career ahead of you.
That should be the most
important thing for you right now.
And that goes for me, too.
We have to respect that.
You knew back then, didn't you?
That we'd face each other
as enemies.
Why didn't you tell me that?
Why?
Yushima-san, that was dishonest.
Yushima-san.
Ayuhara-kun.
I think it's better
if I don't accept this letter.
Huh?
I saw a shadow
of my late sister in you.
I thought you were
a cute girl, like my sister.
But you're not my sister.
It's better if this doesn't go
any further than that.
You didn't tell me
the whole truth back then.
Ayuhara-san!
Ah!
He doesn't smile anymore…
Ayuhara-san
seems to be confused.
It'd be worrisome if they put
Yamamoto-san on the court now.
Yes. The problem is when
they're going to let her play.
They're probably going after
dealing a psychological shock…
…and make her entrance
as dramatic as possible.
Yushima-san, you didn't smirk
at my failed reception.
In fact, you look
kind of angry.
Just like back then…
Watch out!
What were you doing!?
It was dangerous!
I…
Yushima-san is mad at me.
He's mad for me playing so bad.
What's wrong with me?
I'm on the court and my thoughts
are somewhere else completely.
Here, I'm not Ayuhara Kozue.
I am the captain of Fujimi volleyball club.
Attack!
Nice one, Kozue.
Keep it up!
That was much more
like our Ayuhara-san.
Splendid.
It's just like at the last Interhigh.
She's fully regained the pace
from the last Interhigh.
Yes.
I guess it's about time
I showed up.
Will they lose their patience
and let Yamamoto-san out?
Look at them.
Coach Matsuki lectures Yamamoto.
They're not breaking a sweat.
Fujimi's attack hasn't
changed in any way.
Now only the vanishing attack is missing.
Are you sure I shouldn't join yet?
Don't rush things.
Yushima-kun will let you
play soon enough.
Double attack.
Okay.
Finally, it's the sign.
So much pressure and yet Yamamoto-san
still hasn't come out.
She must be annoyed,
just sitting there on the bench.
She closed her eyes?!
She's trying to accept it
automatically.
It went so well
at the last Interhigh…
Ayuhara-san, you finally
started to play like your usual self.
But we have significantly improved
since the last time we played together.
Player change.
Yamamoto.
I'll show you just
how much we've improved.
I see…
They showed they can beat
the vanishing attack.
They'll use our low morale
to deal the final blow.
Yushima Jirou.
You're a really dangerous man.
Show it to me,
Yamamoto-san.
Your new spike
I've only heard rumors about.
I won't hold back.
Beating you on the court
is my main goal.
It's not that fast.
Midori can handle it just fine.
Oh! Midori!
Midori…
Hayakawa-san!
Why didn't she receive it?
It looked so strong that
Hayakawa-san must have hesitated.
Hesitated?
Whether to hit it
or to get away from it.
I'm sure that must have been it.
Don't be absurd.
As if Hayakawa-san would ever
think to run away from the ball.
She's not like you, Takeichi-san.
How dare you, Ishimatsu?
Shh! The game's about
to resume. Be quiet.
The ball hit Midori
before she could receive it.
This spike isn't just about power.
Something's wrong with it.
Professor Shimizu.
How is Hayakawa?
It seems to be a light concussion.
It's nothing serious.
But she really wants
to talk to the girls.
Talk to the girls?
The ball grew bigger.
I… I have to tell them!
Please stay calm.
You must absolutely rest
after receiving a blow to the head.
Let's get you comfortable.
Stop thinking about the ball.
Try to sleep at least a little bit for now.
Wait.
"The ball grew bigger"?
What did she mean?
I don't know.
She just kept repeating it.
That's…
Maybe that's the signature feature
of the new Yamamoto's spike?
Here she goes!
I'll avenge Hayakawa-san.
Ah! The ball…
The ball is getting bigger!
I can't believe it.
But it really is.
I can see it getting bigger.
Ishimatsu!
It's almost like a ghost!
No wonder Hayakawa-san
could not do anything.
D-Damn…!
It'll take more than that to take me down!
Ishida-san!
Time!
Ishimatsu, are you okay?
Ayuhara-san, this is my
mammoth spike.
I'm curious how you'll respond.
Now you can show me
how much fighting spirit is in you?
How will you respond to the mammoth spike
that Matsuki and I have developed?
As you are aware, Yamamoto's new spike
creates an illusion that makes the ball bigger.
And I'll be honest, I don't have
the slightest idea what the trick is.
Therefore, I'm not going
to tell you to receive it.
But don't be afraid of it.
Try to grasp its secret. Got it?
Don't make them
do that, Professor!
Huh?
Do you want them to follow
Hayakawa-san and Ishida-san?
It's a very powerful spike.
If they fail to receive it,
they're bound to get badly injured.
If they keep receiving these
lethal blows one after another…
Ah! The ball…!
Professor Shimizu
is completely right.
My initial order was reckless.
Then what do we do, Coach?
Do we just throw in the towel?
There's no need for that.
They succeeded one or two times, fine.
The question is if they can make it always work.
It's possible this spike might need special
prerequisites, just like the vanishing attack.
What do you mean,
Makimura-san?
Well, the vanishing attack
depends on chance.
If its requirements aren't met, it simply won't work,
no matter how much talent Ayuhara-san has.
I feel this is the same.
So it's also dependent on chance?
That's our bookworm.
Ayuhara.
What do you think?
Well…
Let's resume the match.
Okay. But only if everyone
in the team agrees.
– We do.
– Agreed.
Alright. Go!
At least try to confirm
whether that spike depends on chance.
Yes sir.
I was hoping they would give up.
I won't hold back, Ayuhara-san.
Actually, it's hard for me, too.
Whereas Yushima-san watches
one your player…
…fall to the ground after another
without batting an eyelash.
The game continues.
How are you going to respond
to the mammoth spike, Ayuhara-kun?
You'd better not fall to the ground
like your other two players did.
You're going at it without any plan?!
That's too dangerous!
It begins!
Alright, bring it on!
Makimura-san!
Wait!
What do you mean by "wait"?
Please, let's end the game here.
Are you withdrawing from the game?
Yes. I'm sorry,
I know this is embarrassing.
But our team
is like ducks at the arcade.
Please, let the game continue.
Ayuhara!
Professor, I still haven't had the chance
to receive Yamamoto-san's spike.
I can't just walk away.
I think Yamamoto-san
would feel bad about this, too.
Please, give us at least one last shot.
One last chance for me and Yamamoto-san.
If I really can't receive her spike,
only then I can forfeit this match.
Yamamoto-san,
this is my challenge to you.
I'm serious.
It means a lot to me.
I understand, Ayuhara-san.
I respect what you're saying.
Thank you, Yamamoto-san.
Yushima-san.
On the court, we're enemies.
By fighting Yamamoto-san
you taught, I will fight you.
Oh, no! Ayuhara-kun still doesn't
know the terror of the mammoth spike!
There's no way she can accept it!
Shirakawa-san,
I'm ready any time.
Kozue. Are you really sure
you can accept Yamamoto-san's spike?
Am I just trying to playing strong
in front of Yushima-san?
Too late. I can't go back now,
no matter what happens.
No! Ayuhara-kun, don't!
Ayuhara-kun!
No good!
I can't receive it at all!
Yamamoto! Stop!
Ayuhara, fall back!
Ayuhara. How was it?
Did you read it?
I didn't.
I lost to Yamamoto-san.
If Coach didn't stop me,
I would've miss it and gotten injured.
I'm happy.
Looks like I bested you, Ayuhara-san.
Yamamoto-san, you did it!
Ayuhara-san.
We recovered thanks to you.
This is Aoba's new strength.
Congratulations.
Shirakawa-san, Yamamoto-san.
So in the end,
you abandon the game?
That's a shame.
Yes. We're sorry.
We apologize
for such an outcome.
No, no.
But I've got to tell you,
I look forward to the next Interhigh.
If Fujimi is so overpowered
by Yamamoto's spike…
…it'll be our ticket to becoming the
number one volleyball high school in Japan, heh.
Congratulations, Aoba Academy.
You too, Yamamoto-san.
But I feel so humiliated.
I couldn't do anything
against the mammoth spike.
Ayuhara-kun.
Yushima-san.
Uhm… Here.
Hm?
It's the letter I promised.
But I didn't write
anything special.
I only wrote I'm thankful for your
kindness and such stuff. That's all.
Ayuhara-kun.
I think it's better
if I don't accept this letter.
Huh?
I saw a shadow
of my late sister in you.
I thought you were
a cute girl, like my sister.
But you're not my sister.
It's better if this doesn't go
any further than that.
What do you mean?
Yushima-san, you're a nice guy.
I'm glad I got to know you.
That's what I think.
But why can't I be friends with you?
Why can't I write letters to you?
You see, people write things in letters
that they can't express in person.
That's what would happen
if I answered your letter.
This is why…
Sorry, but I still
don't understand what you mean.
Ayuhara-kun, you have already found your goal
in life. You have a great career ahead of you.
That should be the most
important thing for you right now.
And that goes for me, too. We have to respect that.
See you.
Yushima-san!
Fujimi team tasted a bitter defeat
after being shown the mammoth spike.
In order to regain their hurt pride,
the girls begin rigorous training on the court.
But the secret of the mammoth spike remains
a mystery as Kozue tries her hardest to grasp it.
Trying unconventional ideas,
they receive a soccerball with Mitamura.
During one of those intense training sessions,
they surprisingly find a hint to the secret.
Please look forward
to the next episode!
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.