苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 086—
Twisting reception
Nagano
It's so regrettable we had to
leave early because of my injury.
Especially after yesterday's defeat.
If Professor Hongou hadn't stopped me back then,
I'd end up like Ishimatsu, Makimura-san and Midori.
The ball's getting bigger.
The ball's getting bigger!
The ball's…!
Midori was so sure she could receive Yamamoto-san's
spike, yet it hit her at full speed right from the front.
On top of it, she has hurt her wrist.
Poor Midori.
I hope she gets well soon.
Usually they're so cheerful,
playing cards, talking about everything…
But today, they're so quiet.
I seriously think
it was my fault.
That's not true, Professor.
I suspected it was still
too early to let them play…
…and heard a lot about Yamamoto's
new spike, but I still ignored it.
But who knew her spike
would be this powerful?
Why does the ball in
Yamamoto-san's spike gets bigger?
There is no way for a single volleyball
to stretch or shrink that much.
There has to be a secret somewhere in the way
Yamamoto hits it so that it appears to get bigger.
But just what is
Yamamoto's way of hitting?
Ah… The ball!
The ball gets bigger.
The ball gets bigger!
Ah! The ball…
Midori!
Midori, wake up!
Midori, it's okay!
Ah!
Midori.
Are you okay?
It was just a dream…
Fight! Fight!
Just look at Chief.
She receives every single one, even though
it's with a dodgeball and so insanely fast.
She's amazing, don't you think?
Alright, why don't I
give it a go as well.
Me too! Even if I have to use my forehead,
I'll show you I can receive them as well.
Yeah, yeah!
I can't wait for my turn.
– Alright, next!
– Yes sir.
Hayakawa-san,
you're still—
My wrist is already healed.
I can move it just fine. Here, see?
Hayakawa.
Don't fool around.
Really, it's okay.
Just look.
Next.
Coach! Please.
I'm really fine.
Coach!
Ishimatsu, come.
Yes sir.
Coach…
Hayakawa. Suppose you overstrain
and crush your wrist again.
What do we do if you can't
play in the Interhigh?
See where I'm getting at?
For now, keep it at basic training.
Got it?
Alright. Let's go!
– Forehead!
– Forehead.
Forehead.
– Forehead…
– Are you okay?
Okay…
Bring it on!
Professor.
I think it's enough.
Good. The training is over for today.
Why stop now, Coach?
I can still go on.
– Huh?
Ayuhara.
Alright. Let's go.
Yes sir.
Geez, Kozue.
Even if it's you, there's a limit
how long you can train.
Sometimes she spooks me out.
Alright, that's it for today.
Coach, I can still train.
I can't finish yet.
What?
Kozue!
Coach…
Please, hit it harder.
Yamamoto-san's mammoth spike
were much tougher than that.
I have to receive that mammoth spike.
Doesn't matter how.
Ayuhara family
I'm home.
Welcome back.
You sure have it rough,
training every day until so late.
Huh? Ah, yes.
Don't overexert yourself.
There's a letter for you.
Here.
A letter?
From who?
Huh?!
Yushima Jirou
Tōkyō Suginami-ku Higashida-machi 2 chome
A letter from Yushima-san.
But why… Why?
Yushima-san.
Yushima-san…
Uhm…
Here.
Hm?
It's the letter I promised.
But I didn't write
anything special.
I only wrote I'm thankful for your
kindness and such stuff. That's all.
Ayuhara-kun. I think it's better
if I don't accept this letter.
Huh?
You see, people write things in letters
that they can't express in person.
That's what would happen
if I answered your letter.
This is why…
Sorry, but I still
don't understand what you mean.
Yushima-san.
You see, people write things in letters
that they can't express in person.
That's what would happen
if I answered your letter.
This is why…
No!
Yushima-san, you…
You are my enemy.
As long as I'm unable to receive Yamamoto-san's
mammoth spike, you are my enemy, Yushima-san.
You are my enemy!
If there is a time to see
Yushima-san, my enemy…
…it's only after I'm able
to receive the mammoth spike.
I don't know what
is written in this letter.
But, Yushima-san,
while you are my enemy…
…while I'm unable to receive
the mammoth spike…
…I can't.
I just can't read
a letter from you.
Hey, come here for a bit.
Captain plays soccer!
– Huh?
See?
Mitamura-kun, stronger!
What on earth is she doing?
I know.
Captain's trying to determine the way
the mammoth spike works.
No matter how confident she is about her wrists,
receiving a hard football from such a short distance…
If this continues, she will hurt
her wrists and it'll be a disaster.
Kick it the hardest you can.
Is this all you have,
Mitamura-kun?
You don't mean it, Ayuhara-kun.
Kozue, it's too dangerous.
Stop it.
If you continue this,
even your wrists will give in.
The mammoth spike
was much harder.
The ball got bigger.
It was unnatural!
Don't you remember
how it hit your face, Midori?
Alright…
I'll kick it the hardest I can.
But I need to warn you,
Ayuhara-kun, don't be sorry later.
Sure.
Alright!
Hayakawa-kun,
pass me the ball.
O-Okay.
Okay… let's begin.
Kozue!
Ah!
Let's continue.
It looked kind of similar.
It looked similar!
Mitamura-kun,
kick it even stronger.
Huh?!
That's enough.
Mitamura-kun, please.
Hayakawa-kun.
Throw the ball in my direction
so that it bounces off the ground.
Kozue…
Midori, do as he says.
Hurry up, Midori!
Let's do this!
Kozue!
Kozue.
Captain…
Chief…
Ayuhara-kun.
We did it.
Kozue…
Chief…
Coach. The football got bigger,
just like in the mammoth spike.
What?!
I see! Great!
Mitamura-kun, can I ask you
to repeat that shoot tomorrow?
Yes sir.
I'll borrow a camera from
the movie club and we'll tape it.
Volleyball club room
– The mammoth spike!
Let's play it back at slow motion.
– Start.
– Got it.
Mitamura shoots the ball with all his might
like Yamamoto, without giving it any rotation.
The ball gets deformed
the moment it's hit.
But since the ball
does not rotate…
…it does not disperse energy to the outside
as happens usually, but holds it all to itself.
A ball played this way
dents back and forth repeatedly.
The accumulated energy
moves the air inside.
It moves in all directions depending on
the air flow within, which drives it uncontrollable.
Rewind the film.
What do you think?
I think that explains it well.
That's the way the magnifying effect
you know is produced.
Because of those fluctuations, the receiver
is misled to think it's a curve ball and loses focus.
The ball flies at tremendous speed.
You've already experienced
the consequences of those blows.
The terrifying power of that spike
deserves its name of "the mammoth spike".
The mammoth spike.
Okay, training time.
See you on the court in five minutes.
– Yes sir.
We'll imitate the mammoth spike
using this baseball bat.
As you know, you can't receive it as usual.
You could hurt yourself.
At first, the direction
you send it doesn't matter.
For now, try only to get
familiar with the spike.
Well then. Ayuhara.
Yes sir.
Ready?
Here we go.
Next!
City Gymnasium
Interhigh Preliminary Round
Shuzenji · Fujimi
Makimura Clinic
Oh, it's you,
Mitamura-kun.
That's not how I know you.
What's going on, Hayakawa-kun?
You look really sad.
Has your condition worsened?
No, I'm just a little worried.
They're taking long with the checkup results.
I'm anxious.
There's nothing to worry about.
Come on, hop in.
Huh?
The first qualifier match.
You want to see it, don't you?
You came all the way here
for me, Mitamura-kun?
Thank you.
It's started, but we should
make it for the second set.
Come on.
Okay.
Miramura-kun, wait.
Huh? What's wrong?
I'm sure we'll win the first match
even without my support.
Please take me
to the school instead.
Huh?
Hayakawa-kun.
Can you promise me that
you won't use your right hand?
I'll be fine.
I just want to be used to
the mammoth spike when I go play.
But it will be a catastrophe
if you also hurt your left wrist.
It'll be okay.
Come on, kick me the ball.
Hayakawa-kun,
be careful!
I wanted you to teach
me the mammoth spike.
You threw me
a normal ball just now.
Mitamura-kun,
you won't full my eyes.
Come on, do it seriously.
She found out, huh…
Don't hold back!
Hayakawa-kun!
Are you okay?
Let's stop it, Hayakawa-kun!
No, we can't.
Keep going, Mitamura-kun!
But…
Please.
I told you to stop,
Hayakawa-kun…
We did it.
We did it!
Mitamura-kun!
Hayakawa-kun…
Y-You…
Mitamura-kun!
Thank you so much.
As Hayakawa discovered,
if you receive it while twisting your body…
…you'll give rotation to the mammoth spike,
which will disperse its energy to the outside.
Once the energy gets dispersed,
the mammoth spike becomes a regular spike.
That nails it.
Regular spikes are a piece of cake.
Thank you, Midori.
I know the match is just over,
but let's gather on the court.
– Yes sir!
Twisting reception.
We can receive
the mammoth spike.
I can't wait for the Interhigh!
Yamamoto-san, I'll show you
I can win against your mammoth spike.
Midori and Mitamura's special training
results in discovering the twisting reception.
Fujimi team livens up having
a way to deal with the mammoth spike.
Yushima appears again.
Kozue confronts him
despite hard feelings.
"You cannot win volleyball
with reception alone."
"You are going
to lose against Aoba."
…Yushima says coldly to Kozue.
A new anxiety builds up in Kozue.
Please look forward
to the next episode!
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.