苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 087—
The phantom spike
You can do it, Minamihama!
Minamihama · Fujimi
Again, the Fujimi team's spike
has earned them a point.
The third day of Tōkai district preliminaries of National
Women High School Volleyball Championships.
Fujimi team keeps their form
from the spring.
Double attack.
Yeah.
Let's go.
Makimura-san!
Good luck, Fujimi!
Good, Fujimi!
Ayuhara-san!
The double attack worked well!
Minamihama · Fujimi
Fujimi advances to
the semifinals with ease.
Captain Ayuhara, Hayakawa and Makimura's
excellent trio definitely take the spotlight today.
The Fujimi team is not only the absolute favorite in
these tournaments, but also quite a crowd pleaser.
Fujimi High School
players' waiting room
I'm so hungry.
Hey, hey, let's grab something
to eat when we get back.
– Yeah.
– Good idea!
What about you, Captain?
I'll go with you.
Ah, Coach.
You did great, girls.
I have no complaints.
So tomorrow are the semifinals.
We'll be fine.
Just leave it to us.
Hey. Confidence is good, but
overconfidence always sinks the ship.
Sorry for that.
Of course, our goal
is to win the Interhigh.
But that'll work only if we play
every single game in earnest.
Got it?
– Yes!
Good. That's it for today.
Don't lose your focus.
It's going to get more difficult from here.
– Yes!
Have you seem Professor Hongou?
He was in such good spirits.
Yeah. That's a rare sight.
It's because
we won with such ease.
Yeah, besides, we've finally found a way
to defend against Yamamoto-san's mammoth spike.
Yes. All thanks
to your research, Midori.
Yeah. Let's name it
the "fleeing reception".
Hey!
You're such a joker.
But I have to admit,
I feel a load off my mind.
Until Midori's discovery I couldn't help ruminating
about how we're going to face the mammoth spike.
Everyone felt the same way.
But it's all right now.
We can defend against it.
Yeah. Yeah!
Midori gets back on the court from today.
All that's left is to come out of the qualifiers.
Oh?
Was it just my imagination?
Ah!
Oh, so beautiful.
Please let me get off.
It's embarrassing.
I'm happy.
Huh?
I didn't read the letter from Yushima-san
and tore it apart instead.
Stupid, stupid Kozue.
Ayuhara family
I'm home.
A-Ah, yes, she just got home.
Please hold on for a second.
Who is it?
Yushima-san. Here.
Oh!
Hello? Yushima-san?
It's been a while.
I'm calling from the Fujimi train station.
I'd like to meet with you.
I understand.
Be right there.
So it wasn't my imagination, after all.
Mama? Mama,
I'm going out for a bit.
You're going already?
Don't be too late.
Sure! See you!
I want to run like some stray dog.
Ahem. Calm down…
I'm only able to meet you now.
Now that I can counter the mammoth spike,
I finally no longer feel inferior to Yushima-san.
Now that my self-doubt is gone,
I want to meet you.
I'm so selfish.
Looks like you made it
to the semifinals.
Yes.
Why did you come
all the way here to Fujimi?
I'm here because of the preparations for
the Interhigh. This time it takes place in Shizuoka.
I see.
What a beautiful sunset.
How are your friends?
Their injuries.
Injuries?
Ah, Midori was hurt the most,
but she's back on the court from today.
That's good to hear.
Yamamoto's spike is
stronger than I had anticipated.
She's knocked out a lot of players
in the Tōkyō's preliminaries as well.
In one case, our rivals
surrendered midway.
Just like us in
the Nagano training camp.
Yes. Exactly.
We've devised a way
to receive the mammoth spike.
Oh? That's all?
Huh? "That's all"…?
Just that won't win you
the match, Ayuhara-kun.
"Just that"?
But that's plenty!
Yushima-san, every one in our team
has worked hard to complete this technique.
I can't… I can't forgive
calling it "just that"!
You didn't read my letter, did you?
I-I'm sorry, I didn't.
I came here to apologize for it, but…
No need to.
You can do whatever you want
with the letters you receive.
D-Don't say that.
I did something I deeply regret.
I was so sad and angry with you for not telling me
that you worked as Yamamoto-san's coach…
…that I actually tore
the letter apart.
It's okay.
It's no big loss. I've already said about half of what
I wrote now that we stand next to each other.
But let me tell you
the other half.
Every spike, no matter how powerful,
will definitely be destroyed some day.
Do you understand, Ayuhara-kun?
Every spike?
You've just told me that you've learned
how to receive the mammoth spike.
What does that change,
though? Not much.
But if you like congratulations,
here you go. You did well. Bravo.
Yushima-san…
If all you have is reception alone,
you might as well go play in the park.
What did you say?!
You're angry, huh?
How lovely.
Let go of me!
Hey.
I'm going home.
I'm staying at
Seizansō in Shizuoka.
Receiving the mammoth
spike is not enough.
If we managed to take on any spike, no matter
how hard, only then we'd be equal to Aoba.
That's what we believed.
Reception alone
won't win us the match.
If we want to win against Aoba, we have to
come up with a spike that's even stronger.
Even stronger spike…
Yamashina · Fujimi
Fujimi wins the first set
by a landslide.
The first match of the
preliminaries' semi-finals.
The Yamashina High School team has played
well and shown us a great team play.
However, they lost to the fast and sharp
attacks of the Fujimi's captain.
Alright, keep it up.
– Yes sir.
One more thing. Ayuhara.
It's important to play seriously,
but don't overdo it.
Yes sir.
Yamashina · Fujimi
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Receiving mammoth spike
alone won't win us the match.
We have to devise
a strong spike.
I'll get it!
Even stronger spike…
What a spike!
Ayuhara's incredible spike
sends chills down the spine!
Where does that girl
hide all that energy?
At any rate, the gap between
Fujimi and Yamashina grows very fast.
It's no good.
No matter how hard I try, my strength and physique
just cannot compare with Yamamoto-san's.
It's hopeless.
I can't find a stronger spike.
It's a pipe dream!
You'll never catch up to me.
Give up.
It was just a dream…
Every spike, no matter how strong,
will eventually get received.
We've got the reception covered.
But…
If all you have is reception alone,
you might as well go play in the park.
But no matter how hard I try,
I just can't match Yamamoto-san.
How do we overcome that?
There's no choice but to use
the opponents' strength to our advantage.
Direct spike.
The stronger the opponent is,
the more effective it is.
But, the mammoth spike…
It's so strong that it's got Midori,
who's good with receptions, out of the game.
Now we can barely receive it.
If we further empower it with
the direct spike, it'll be a suicide.
The double attack is ineffective, too.
So is the vanishing spike.
A new spike. One that's stronger
than everything else.
It's impossible to come up
with such thing on the spot.
I'm not a superman.
I want to fall in love.
I want to live
like a normal teenager.
I'm an ordinary
high school student, after all.
Fujimi's Demonic Captain
scores 12 points by herself!
"Fujimi's Demonic Captain".
Oh, my.
That kind of reputation
won't help you find a husband.
No way!
I want to be a good bride.
Ha, looks like
I've hit a sensitive spot.
It's because they're rude
to call such a cute girl "demonic".
Is that not a good thing? They're praising
your tenacity and fighting spirit.
I know that much.
Kozue, I know you're feeling nervous
with the preliminary finals around the corner…
…but I think it'd be good
to ease up a little.
Yes…
You had such a scary look on your face
that you really looked like a demon.
Mama…
Relax, I'm just kidding.
But I'm glad that you're so motivated
about volleyball with Midori.
Why?
At first, Midori was just a rich lady
who didn't know the hardships of life.
Look at her now, injuring her hands
because of a game of volleyball.
Huh?
Midori…
W-We did it!
Midori couldn't participate
in the first round due to her injury…
…yet she's worked so hard
to develop a new reception technique.
Now, thanks to the hint she's discovered,
we're able to receive the mammoth spike.
That's right.
I have to work hard, too.
Kozue? Is something wrong?
I think you said something?
No, never mind.
I'm going out for a bit.
Ah, Mama, do you know if there's
any high wall of concrete nearby?
A wall of concrete?
I don't know about walls, but there's
an old building to be demolished soon.
Thanks!
Ah, it's near the highway! Got it?
A spike even stronger
than Yamamoto-san's.
The only choice is the direct spike,
that uses the opponent's power.
I have to do it somehow.
Sorry!
Thanks.
I'll help you out.
Huh?
You're training volleyball.
I have a powerful throw.
I'm a boy, after all.
Alright then, let's play. I'm—
I know you.
You're "demonic captain".
Wow.
I'm Masao.
Let's go!
Damn, it's no good.
I'll break my arm like that.
The mammoth spike
is many times more powerful.
This training is useless.
It's hopeless.
I'm sorry for dragging
you into this, Masao-kun.
I guess the direct spike
is just impossible.
It's impossible…
I'll leave it here.
It's no good.
Even if we do make it through the preliminaries,
we don't stand a chance at the Interhigh.
There's nothing we can do!
I should go play in the park after all.
Yushima-san!
Right! He's at Seizansō in Shizuoka.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
It's Yushima.
Hello?
They hung up…
I can't ask him. I just can't ask him
to give me a hint to find a new spike.
That'll show him I'm weak.
Let's focus on the remainder
of the preliminaries for now.
Shizuoka Minami · Fujimi
Another excellent
spike from Ayuhara!
Tōkai district qualifying
round is drawing near.
Today Shizuoka Minami, who has defeated
Misawa Academy, fights against Fujimi, the favorite.
Fujimi wins the first set
with the score of 15 to 6.
They keep overwhelming
their rival in the second set as well!
Ayuhara's spike
earns yet another point.
She's a true high school
volleyball demon.
Even if we win this match,
it's all over when we face Aoba.
There's something
strange about Ayuhara today.
What's going on
with her spikes?
"Reception alone".
"Just that".
My dream of a stronger spike
is just that: a dream.
It's an elusive phantom.
Shizuoka Minami · Fujimi
Fujimi wins the match and proceeds
as the Tōkai district representative!
What a farce.
You weren't the real
Ayuhara Kozue today.
Hm? That phone call…
Ayuhara family
Hello? Ayuhara by the phone.
Hello?
Oh, Yushima-san.
Do you need anything from me?
Congratulations on
your victory today.
…or so I'd like to say.
But what was that?
I watched the whole thing, you know.
Are you the Fujimi's Ayuhara?
Are you the Ayuhara I know?
Huh?!
What a jerk.
What a jerk!
I know it myself the best.
I wanted you to talk about
something else. Anything at all.
What a jerk. Screw you!
Kozue?
Yes?
Oh, Yushima-san?
Yes. She's fine.
Tomorrow?
Yes, I understand.
I'll let Kozue know.
Are you sure
you're not hungry?
Why do you keep asking?
Well, that's because
I'm really starving.
I'm not hungry at all.
Is it because you're mad at me?
Is that all you wanted
to talk to me about?
Hah, got me.
I don't really want
to talk about volleyball today.
I'd like to talk to you
about lots of things besides volleyball.
The weather is so good.
Everyone looks happy.
It's so peaceful.
Why don't we call truce?
You must be tired
from all that pressure.
Let's stop worrying
and just hang around today.
Does that sound good to you?
Yes.
Great. Let's go!
Ah! My balloon!
Miss, can you get it for me?
Sure! I'll get it back in a second.
I can't hit it!
The balloon is too light.
It's too light, so—
Go back to your court!
That's the spike
you've been looking for!
Yes!
Looks like you're back
to your usual self.
Make sure you complete it.
The phantom spike.
I was set on developing
a strong spike.
But any strong spike
will get eventually received.
But if the spike
escapes the receiver's hands…
The phantom spike.
No… I'll show everyone
that it's very real.
I'll show them.
I'll show them!
Finally, the Interhigh starts.
Kozue, inspired by the way
balloons fly up, thinks of new spike.
Meanwhile, Yamamoto's mammoth spike
keeps knocking players out.
Kozue relives the terror
of the miracle ball.
Fujimi team, burdened with heavy expectations,
plays the first match against Shikoku representative.
However…!
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.