苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 088—
The great test at the Interhigh
Hmm?
Kozue. Kozue!
What are you so worked up
about in the morning?
Sorry, sorry.
15. Interhigh Tournament
held at Municipal Gymnasium in Shizuoka
– Is Kozue still sleeping?
– Yes.
– Wake her up.
– I'm going.
Ayuhara Kozue (Captain)
I'm sorry, Mama.
Are you okay?
Don't scare me like that.
What were you doing?
Good morning, Papa.
Morning.
Kozue. Starting today, the Interhigh
is starting to make headlines.
Well, the main thing is that
it takes place here this year.
You have to win.
Thanks for the food.
Everyone at my office will be
following this tournament closely.
Now that you mention it,
our neighbors talk a lot about it, too.
We're counting on you, Kozue.
I can't. I just can't.
I have no idea how to do it.
There's no such spike
that behaves like a balloon.
It was a phantom, after all.
A phantom spike.
Kozue.
Thanks for the food.
I'm gowwing choo shkool.
What's going on with her?
I don't know.
She's spacing out a lot recently.
Although I know for sure that I can't invent
a spike that behaves like a balloon…
…I keep thinking about it
all the time.
Why can't I think
about anything else anymore?
If I managed to find such spike,
I'd get praise from Yushima-san.
Maybe that's…
That was my goal all along?
No. No!
That's not it.
My goal is to win the Interhigh.
I need to win against
Aoba to that end.
And if I want to win against Aoba,
I need to devise a new kind of spike.
Even if it's impossible,
I have to do it.
I have to.
I have to!
Certain Victory!
Fujimi High Volleyball Club
Good luck, Fujimi!
What are you doing, Kozue?
It's time to go.
I know.
By the way, Captain, we wanted
to talk to you about something.
Hm?
It bugs us that everyone
expects too much from us.
Exactly. My mother
makes such a drama about it.
My pops is completely crazy.
You see, he has this shop.
He went and planned a campaign
for the next sales season with our name all over it.
Now he's all like,
"you'd better not lose, kid".
Damn right. Geez, they have to make such
a fuss about it just because it's held in the area.
I know, right? I guess
that's the price you pay for success.
Oh! Girls, it's Principal!
Ladies of the volleyball club.
Your great effort has brought
our school a great success.
For two consecutive years, you have the honor and
the right to compete in the Interhigh Tournament.
Since the tournament this time
is held here in Shizuoka…
…we, the Fujimi High School,
place very high expectations on you.
Please, ladies of the volleyball club.
Show our rivals our strength
and the best of your ability.
Give us an outstanding victory.
Please don't fail the expectations
that are placed on you.
Fujimi High School
Good luck!
National Women's High School
Volleyball Championships
– Hey!
– Fujimi students.
I'm with Shizuoka Daily.
Ayuhara-san, anything you want to say?
Since the tournament is held in your area,
you must be extra motivated, right?
– Ayuhara-san.
– Uhm…
"Fujimi High School wins
the Interhigh twice in a row".
We can already
see this headline.
We're counting on you.
You have no choice but to win.
Everyone expects
victory from you.
– Please give us victory.
– Good luck.
Okay.
Professor, everyone puts
a lot of pressure on them.
I'm afraid
it's going to backfire.
You're right.
The expectations are really high.
But that alone
shouldn't be a problem.
Ayuhara-san.
Finally, it's the time.
We've been waiting
a long time for this day.
Ayuhara-san,
let's meet in the finals.
Yes.
– Good luck.
– Thanks.
Just look at them.
How they're facing Aoba.
Even though they've learned
how to counter the mammoth spike…
…no one boasts about it.
The shock from seeing the mammoth spike
at the training camp in Nagano is still around.
To tell you the truth,
I'm still afraid.
Oh…
Ever since that time…
I can't forget about it.
The cheering and expectations
of the local people are working against us.
Now… Now is the worst time
to think about the outcome.
Another one Yamamoto's
mammoth spikes!
Aoba · Tōnan
That's one frightening
attack, for sure.
Its strength makes me think
of a dynamite explosion.
Although they scored fourth in the last season,
now they're one of the favorites for this tournament.
They're completely overwhelming Tōnan Academy,
known for their computerized gameplay.
I'll get it!
Receive it.
Ah! Tōnan's Captain Higaki
has collapsed!
She doesn't stand up.
Looks like she injured her wrist.
She's leaving the court. It seems
she has received a considerable damage.
Tōnan's done for
without Higaki-san.
Aoba
Aoba · Tōnan
She knocked out of the game
a person like Higaki-san…
Yamamoto-san's spike.
It's much more powerful than
what she's shown during the practice.
I'm their captain. I can't lose spirit,
or we won't even win the first round.
You're invincible, Fujimi!
Good luck, Fujimi!
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Ladies and gentlemen,
finally comes the Fujimi team.
We are all very excited about whether this team
will succeed in winning the summer championships.
Go steady, Midori!
Yeah!
Throw them the falling leaf.
We'll destroy their spirit in one go.
Yeah.
The first match is against
Yoshida High from Shikoku.
Judging from both teams' match history,
it should be an easy game for Fujimi.
No way!
That's unexpected! Hayakawa
makes a mistake right at the beginning.
Midori, what was that?
Sorry.
Forehead!
I felt kind of paralyzed…
What the hell, Fujimi?!
Makimura-san, you too?
I'm sorry.
Come on!
What are you doing?!
You can do better!
Give back my money!
Fujimi · Yoshida
That's really unexpected.
It's one mistake after another.
The Fujimi team is in turmoil.
Professor…
Yes.
How is Ayuhara going
to overcome that crisis?
How will they recover?
I expect— no, I fully trust
their iron will and their strength.
Come on, girls!
We can do this!
Please, don't miss!
Good going, Makimura-san!
This time, it's a mistake
from Captain Ayuhara!
Perhaps it was too much to expect them
to win both the spring and summer tournaments?
Time!
I'm sorry.
Coach, please…
Please say something.
Hm… say something, huh?
What should I say…
I know your strength the best.
No need to say anything.
B-But… aren't you
going to scold us?
How old are you, Forehead?
I'm 17.
Look around.
See the stands?
It's possible there's someone there
who will make you a bride in the future.
Huh?
No way! Hah!
If I scolded you in front of him,
I'd make you look bad.
Hm? The Fujimi team
looks quite relaxed.
What's going on?
They're going to get serious.
Don't take your eyes
off Ayuhara-san.
Sure.
I'm so glad.
Professor's joke lightened up
the atmosphere.
Even though I'm your coach, I can't
control what's going on in your mind.
The only ones who can do that…
…are us only, right?
Exactly.
That's right.
We have what it takes.
It's just that our spirit
and our body isn't in balance.
Focus
Alright.
Listen, girls, it's like Coach said.
It's all about our minds.
Stop thinking about
unimportant things right away.
I want every one of you to concentrate
and show everyone what you can do.
– Yeah!
Alright. Concentrate!
Concentrate.
Let's keep going!
Concentrate!
Concentrate.
Ayuhara's spikes score
one point after another!
I have to admit,
that's a magnificent comeback.
The focused Fujimi team
shows a great counterattack.
Focus
Concentrate.
Fujimi · Yoshida
Fujimi
"Fujimi has narrowly
won the first game".
"Meanwhile, Aoba
steamrolled Tōnan".
For God's sake, Kozue.
Don't make me nervous.
Dear, I don't think it's appropriate
to take it this way, after all they won.
That was really
not a good performance.
We won, okay.
But we've yet to face Aoba.
The only thing that'd make me
feel calmer would be a new spike.
Hm? Wait a minute.
I don't have to hit it all the way.
It's okay if I just graze it.
It'll become a curve ball
depending on how I graze the ball.
Ariake · Fujimi
Aoba maintains its momentum
and easily destroys Matsuki
The vanishing attack finally out!
Fujimi defeats Denshō
The unstoppable mammoth spike
Match canceled due to players' injuries
Kozue, did you see
the newspapers?
They get players off the game
left and right.
I heard one of them is so badly injured
that it'll take a month for her to recover.
Seeing Aoba's form,
it's unthinkable they'd lose.
But if we want to win,
we have to defeat them somehow.
I don't want us
to repeat Nagano.
Don't worry too much.
The quarterfinals aren't even over.
Let's cheer up and keep training—
Chief, I meant to ask you
this before, but…
Keep training, keep training…
But what exactly are we training?
A-Ah, that's…
Kozue, if you thought of a technique
that'd be on par with Yamamoto-san's spike…
Tell us so right away.
I know no such thing, Midori.
I want to tell you.
I want to put everyone's
mind at ease.
But for now, I have nothing.
I have nothing…
Hey!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Whoa! It's you, Pops!?
Thanks for your hard work, girls!
Thanks for looking after my kid.
Pops…
Shut up! You stay silent!
It's a small gift from our store
to your volleyball team.
My goodness, the whole city
is going crazy about that volleyball thing.
Everyone's talking about it even outside
the store. We want to celebrate your victory.
I can't believe you, Pops!
You're embarrassing me.
We've just advanced to the quarterfinals.
The victory is still very far away.
You foolish girl!
Are you implying Fujimi could lose?
Stop being so pessimistic.
Alright, everyone.
Please help yourselves.
See?
It's very tasty.
Come on.
Have a bite.
Don't hold back.
It's all yours.
All PTA officers
Ladies of the volleyball club.
The name of Fujimi High is now known
in the whole prefecture— no, in whole Japan.
You're invincible, Fujimi!
It was possible thanks to the active participation
of everyone at the volleyball club.
The board of the PTA
is very proud of you.
To celebrate this…
Yawn…
…we have arranged
a small gift to you.
Please do your best to win and promote
virtues and honor of our Fujimi High School.
Members of the Fujimi
volleyball club!
Please make our dream of
winning twice in a row true.
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Kitaoku · Fujimi
Fujimi has narrowly won the first game and
advanced through the second and third match…
…but today, they've yet
to show us anything interesting.
It's no good.
Everyone's tense again.
I have to do something.
Alright.
I'll set an example for everyone
and pull them out of this slump.
Ah! Direct spike!
It's a point.
Captain Ayuhara finally
shows what she can do.
Kozue.
Chief…
Remember, girls.
It's all about focus.
Concentrate.
Yeah.
Good job, Midori.
Alright, girls!
We can do this.
The Fujimi team has jumped back on their feet
encouraged by Captain Ayuhara.
Many doubts about
the Fujimi team
Another walkover due to player injuries!
The terrible Aoba's mammoth spike
The best four get together.
Concerns about Fujimi
Aoba · Jidōin
Fujimi · Shimosaki
We're finally
in the semifinals.
Oh? That man over there,
isn't he from the Volleyball Association?
You're right.
It's Chairman Yamada.
Weird, I've always believed that they have enough
to do with the World Championships.
What is he doing here
at the Interhigh?
I was wondering the same thing myself.
Right, Kozue?
Yeah…
Ah, Yushima-san!
Ah…
Well, that's about it.
Yamamoto. Shirakawa.
The rest is in your hands.
– Okay.
– Sure.
Alright, see you.
Thanks.
Oh?
Hey.
It's been a while.
I came to see the game
with Chairman Yamada.
Huh?
What is Chairman doing here?
We'd better talk about your team.
What's going on with Fujimi?
Seems like you have some trouble lately.
You're in semifinals now.
How's your discovery?
I don't think you've
finished it yet.
At this rate Aoba really
is going to win this tournament.
His words sound so cold.
Naturally, Yushima-san
is on Aoba's side.
That's why he's
so distant towards me.
Anyway, good luck.
Ayuhara-kun.
I expect a lot of you.
Ayuhara-kun!
I expect a lot of you!
I expect a lot!
Anyway, good luck, Ayuhara-kun.
Ayuhara-kun.
Ayuhara-kun!
Fujimi fights fiercely
in the semifinals.
But Kozue can't think
about anything besides the new spike.
"Step by step, point by point.
Keep your teamwork."
…says Hongou.
But Kozue grows impatient.
She rushes the match,
thinking nervously about Aoba.
Finally, it's the match point.
Kozue misses her timing and her spike
draws to unexpected outcome.
Please look forward
to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.