苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 089—
The fleeting spike
Women High School
Volleyball Championships
The All-Japan Interhigh tournament
slowly approaches its end.
Today's the first semifinal match.
Both teams are warming up.
The first semifinal match.
Shizuoka's representative,
Fujimi High School, vs. …
Shimozaki · Fujimi
…Kyūshū's representative,
Shimozaki High School.
The game will begin shortly.
Oh?
He's Yamada-san, the president
of the Volleyball Association.
There's Yushima-san, too…
Huh!?
Yamamoto-san of Aoba
is with them!
We can receive
your mammoth spike.
It's great that you've found a way
to receive the mammoth spike.
Volleyball cannot be won
with reception alone, however.
To win with Aoba, you'll have
to devise even stronger spike.
Apparently, you haven't
discovered a new spike yet.
In that case, the victory
will go to Aoba.
No. I'm still
thinking about it.
That balloon…
A spike that moves like a balloon.
Kozue!
Kozue!?
Huh?
What are you doing, Kozue?
The game's about to start.
Fight!
– Fight!
A spike that will crush
Yamamoto-san's mammoth spike.
That floats like that balloon,
then suddenly drops.
Kozue!
Ayuhara-san!
Wow, that was close.
It was almost an out.
What's going on, Kozue?
Are you feeling unwell?
Hm?
No, everything's fine.
You sure? That's good to hear.
But you're acting weird, Kozue.
Powerful spikes always get received
at some point, no matter how strong they are.
A spike that lightly escapes the
receiver's hands like a balloon.
If I had such technique, I'd have a way
to counter Yamamoto-san's mammoth spike.
Kozue!
It's not about the power.
What if I lightly snap my wrist?
Chance!
What was that, Kozue?
I have to snap it further.
It had no spin at all.
Naka!
Relax your arm
and snap your wrist further.
Kozue!
I'm trying, Midori.
I'm trying to make a spike
that escapes receivers' hands.
This time for sure.
Strange…
Did I hit it too hard?
Maybe I hit it too hard…
Professor, something's off.
Something's off
about Ayuhara-san.
Thanks to their excellent play, the Fujimi
team advanced to the semi-finals.
But Captain Ayuhara hasn't
found her rhythm today yet.
So far, the game continues
with Shimozaki High School in the lead.
And now,
Shimozaki serves.
Shimozaki · Fujimi
How long will this keep up?
Oh?
Ayuhara…
I can't believe that girl.
She's not playing
against Shimozaki.
What do you mean?
I mean, she's only thinking
about the match against Aoba.
She's looking for a new technique
during an actual match.
I turned a blind eye to it until now,
but we'll lose if this continues.
Time!
Coach Hongou from
Fujimi High stood up.
He calls a time out.
Listen close, girls.
Each and every team that participates
in this tournament trained very hard to get here.
The stronger prevail
over the weaker ones.
It's that simple.
Today, you're playing in the semifinals
against Shimozaki High.
Don't forget that.
That's all.
– Yes sir.
Alright. Go get them!
Fight!
– Fight!
Ayuhara.
Sir?
Don't lose track of
what's before you. Now go!
Y-Yes sir.
Ayuhara's on to something.
Something that will counter the mammoth
spike of Yamamoto from Aoba.
What have I been thinking?
I'm on the court.
It's not some training camp
in the sticks.
I'm now on the real court,
playing against Shimozaki High.
I'm part of the Fujimi team!
This is no good. I'm still thinking…
I'm still thinking about Yamamoto-san's spike.
Ayuhara Kozue.
You're playing against Shimozaki now.
Get a grip,
Ayuhara Kozue!
Last one!
Chance!
Ishimatsu!
Ayuhara-san!
Nice, Kozue!
Exactly! Show them
what you've got!
Shimozaki · Fujimi
Whatever it was that Coach Hongou
said to his players, it seems to have worked.
Captain Ayuhara
has regained her form.
They undoubtedly
overcame their slump.
It's the set point
for the Fujimi team.
– Fight!
– Yeah! – Yeah!
Now's our chance!
Ishimatsu!
Shimozaki · Fujimi
Fujimi wins the first set.
Despite a bumpy start, Captain Ayuhara has
recovered, which has inspired the rest of the team.
As expected of Fujimi High School,
the spring tournament champions.
Shimozaki · Fujimi
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Come on!
Attack!
Kozue!
Makimura · Hayakawa · Ayuhara's
machine attacks and double attacks!
The second set is completely
dictated by the Fujimi team.
Attack!
Professor, just what kind of spike
did Ayuhara-san try to find in the first set?
I can't think of anything.
Well, all I saw is that she tried to relax her arm
and give the ball some kind of spin.
She's really working hard to find a way
to counter Yamamoto-san's spike, isn't she?
Well, I'm just as worried as she is.
Although I don't believe we have the time
to experiment with the finals around the corner.
Excuse me. I don't want
to sound cowardly.
It's just that our best option is to
stick to the techniques that we know best.
You're right.
Kozue!
Attack!
Woohoo! We did it!
Nice, Naka!
Finally, it's the match point for Fujimi.
Looks like they'll advance to the finals!
What's wrong, Kozue?
Are you okay?
Ah, my shoulder's just
a little stiff. I'm fine.
Alright!
It's the match point!
Let's get them!
– Yeah!
Nice!
With this,
we're in the finals!
Oh, no!
My arm went numb!
Ah!?
The ball…
The ball!
Huh?
Out! It's an out!
Shimozaki · Fujimi
Fujimi High School's Captain Ayuhara's spike
descending phase strangely slowed down…
…and it landed right in the middle
of the opponent's court.
With this,
Fujimi advances to the finals.
Say, Kozue,
how did you do that last spike?
Err… I'm not sure myself either.
You're kidding me.
No, I'm serious.
Huh…
Come on,
let's hit the showers.
Let's go, Kozue.
How could the ball float like that?
More importantly,
how did I hit it?
Ayuhara-san.
Yagisawa-san!
Finally it's the finals, huh?
Good luck.
Thank you.
The second semifinals game.
Aoba Academy vs. Jidōin High School.
Good luck to you too,
Yagisawa-san.
Thanks. I'd love to say
"meet you in the finals".
But this time I'm not that confident
considering Aoba's spike.
Come on.
It's not like you.
I know, right?
In the end, I'm nowhere as strong
as Katsura or my older sis.
Of course,
I'm not giving up.
I'll do my best
till the bitter end.
I'd better not
disappoint my sisters.
Kaori-san joined
Mignon Couture, right?
Yes. She was elected into
the All-Japan team.
For the World Tournament?
That's terrific.
I have to work hard, too.
Well then, see you.
– Uhm…
– Yes?
How's Katsura-san?
Katsura? She's fine.
Look, she's sitting over there.
See?
Katsura-san.
Hey. Ayuhara.
Yes, Professor Hongou?
We're going back
to school for training.
Fujimi High School
Ayuhara!
Try to repeat the last spike
that won us the match.
Here goes.
Once more.
Alright, that's enough.
Coach…
The technique was the same, but the angle
between arm and wrist was somehow different.
I'm not yet sure exactly how.
We'll try to find that out tomorrow.
Okay, Ayuhara?
Yes sir.
Okay! That's it for today.
Training's over.
– Yes sir!
Hurry up!
Jidōin still tenaciously fights back
despite losing the first set.
I knew it.
Aoba's gonna win.
I don't know how to repeat it.
I told you, it was a fluke.
I know, but are you sure
you don't remember anything at all?
Hmm… I remember I spaced out
for a moment, but wasn't sure why.
It'd be great if you could repeat it.
Anyway, Kozue.
Maybe it's best not to think about it,
then it may suddenly come to you again.
How's the game?
As expected, Aoba got the first set.
Now they're in the lead.
Yamamoto-san
is in excellent condition.
Jidōin's trying to keep up
using their famous trinity attack.
Can they overcome their crisis?
Are you okay?
Yagisawa of Jidōin
receives the mammoth spike!
Jidōin · Aoba
She received it! Yagisawa
received the mammoth spike!
Ah! Yagisawa-san!
Is that it for Yagisawa?
No! She stood up!
Yamamoto's mammoth spike
scores another point!
With Jidōin's captain barely able to stand
on her feet, it's an one-sided game.
It's a match point serve for Aoba.
Jidōin sends the ball back—
Shirakawa tosses the ball!
Yamamoto spikes!
Aoba triumphs.
Tomorrow, Aoba will meet
Fujimi in the final match.
At first I've tried to hit
the ball really hard.
But I overdid it
and my arm got numb.
How do I repeat that?
What do you think, President?
Aoba's Yamamoto is a good fit.
Players waiting room
Players like Yamamoto in the All-Japan team would
make the World Championships very interesting.
Huh? All-Japan Team?!
All-Japan team that'll play
in the World Championships.
So that's the reason why
President Yamada went to see the Interhigh.
We need new power to regain the leading
position at the World Championships.
So when are you going to announce
your decision, President?
Well, I haven't decided
on Yamamoto yet.
I'm also interested
in Fujimi's Ayuhara.
The match tomorrow is not only
about winning the Interhigh.
It's also about winning
the place in the All-Japan team.
Light, like a balloon…
Just when you feel like it'll contact,
it floats away from you.
How did I do that?
Ayuhara-san.
Huh?
Ah!
Katsura-san!
Katsura!
Jidōin · Fujimi
Hang in there, Katsura!
Katsura. Katsura!
Katsura!
Stretchers!
Get stretchers in here!
Ayuhara-san.
I can play a little if it's not straining.
Why don't we play together?
Katsura-san…
It's obvious that you're
developing a new technique.
Let me help you.
Okay, Ayuhara-san?
Thank you so much.
Let's get going.
Ayuhara-san.
Good luck tomorrow.
Oh!
This is it!
This is the way I hit it.
This is what will win
against Yamamoto-san.
against her mammoth spike!
With a bit of luck Kozue
succeeds to repeat her spike.
But it's not fully finished yet.
Kozue trains relentlessly
till the last minute.
Finally, the match
against Aoba is about to start.
Takeichi and Ishimatsu fall down
before Yamamoto's mammoth spike.
Aoba wins the first set
with overwhelming advantage.
This continues into second set as well. With the score
of 13 to 7, Fujimi team faces its gravest pinch.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.