苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 090—
The finals! 13 to 7
How do I overcome the power
of Yamamoto-san's spike?
Aoba · Tōnan
I'll get it!
Receive it.
Tōnan's Captain Higaki
has collapsed!
She doesn't stand up.
Looks like she injured her wrist.
She's leaving the court.
It seems she has received
a considerable damage.
Tōnan's done for
without Higaki-san.
Aoba · Tōnan
Even Tōnan's deadly precision they had developed
with powerful computers couldn't save them.
If we want to have any hope of winning, we have
to figure out how to overcome Yamamoto-san's spike.
I have to develop
an even stronger technique.
A spike even stronger
than Yamamoto-san's.
The only choice is the direct spike,
that uses the opponent's power.
I have to do it somehow.
Damn, it's no good.
I'll break my arm like that.
The mammoth spike
is many times more powerful.
This training is useless.
It's hopeless.
It's no good.
My strength cannot compare with Yamamoto-san's.
There's no way I can hit the ball stronger than her.
I just can't do it.
But if I make it escape the receiver's hands
like the ballon did back then…
Miss, can you get it for me?
Sure!
I can't hit it!
The balloon is too light.
It's too light, so—
It finally worked
at the end of the semifinals.
I know it's possible!
Chance!
Oh, no!
My arm went numb!
How do I repeat it?
It's not about power.
It's in the way
I moved my wrist…
I can't recall anything.
How do I repeat that spike?
What do you think,
Mr. President?
Players like Yamamoto in the All-Japan team would
make the World Championships very interesting.
I agree.
We need new power to regain the leading
position at the World Championships.
When will you announce
your decision?
Well, I haven't decided
on Yamamoto yet.
I'm also interested
in Fujimi's Ayuhara.
The All-Japan… So that's the reason why
President Yamada went to see the Interhigh.
Oh, Yamamoto-san.
You're late.
Did they interview you?
I'll fight in the tomorrow's game
with all I have to qualify for the All-Japan.
Will they choose me
or Ayuhara-san?
I can't do it!
I simply cannot.
How did I do
that spike then?
Let's try again. Let's try reliving
everything that happened before.
Think of that match.
I'm sorry I was mean to you.
Give me one more chance, okay?
Back then…
Back then, I stood like this.
Fujimi had 13 points.
Shimozaki had 4.
Shimozaki threw a spike
at my left and I dove.
Then, the revolving reception.
I think it hurt more
back then, though.
The ball flies up high.
Takeichi-san tosses.
Then Naka grounds it
and it's a match point for us.
Then after Makimura-san's serve,
this is when the miracle happens.
It was heavy.
I wanted to return it directly.
My arm feels numb,
just like back then!
I did it!
It was the same!
Now to learn how to
get it right every single time.
Oh?
Don't mind me.
Keep going.
O-Okay…
Looks like that balloon
did inspire you.
What's wrong?
Do you think
I'm spying for Aoba?
That's not the case.
What is it, then?
I don't want to fail
in front of you.
It's too hard for me
to listen to critique from you.
Clearly you're not very
confident in your spike yet.
That's right.
Even if you get it right
100% of the time during practice…
…it'll be useless all the same
if you can't do it during a match.
Is your technique
some sanctum?
If you have a stage fright
in front of me…
…what will you do in front of
hundreds of people in the audience?
I'm not afraid of those hundreds
of anonymous people.
It's only about you,
Yushima-san.
Whatever.
I'm not interested
in that frail a technique.
Wait, Yushima-san.
I'll try it.
Good.
Calm down.
Stay calm, Kozue.
Jump high like just before.
Then use the body's momentum
to drive wrist into it.
I'm sorry.
It just happened
involuntarily.
Your sharp look
was too distracting.
What are you thinking now,
Yushima-san?
Ayuhara-kun…
You don't know it yet, but
tomorrow's match will decide…
…whether you or Yamamoto
will be selected for the All-Japan.
I'm afraid that unless you master that technique,
you're going to lose to Yamamoto.
And I'd hate to see that, not as
a volleyball player, but as Yushima Jirou.
I'd really hate that.
Today is the day.
The final match between tenacious Fujimi High and
Aoba Academy with its ominous mammoth spike.
He's here,
he's here!
Ishimatsu,
your dad's here!
Yeah, I know.
I bet he'll be yelling from the front row.
So embarrassing.
There will be also members
of the Volleyball Association.
I heard everyone from the
shopping district will be here, too.
Ah, they'll make the game
even more difficult.
Don't sweat the small stuff.
If they start embarrassing you,
just pretend you don't know them.
Easier said than done. You don't know
my old man, he's always yelling.
My daughter's always had a temper. When we
changed her diapers, she was kicking like the devil.
She'll surely give a lot of trouble
to Fujimi's opponents.
He's always telling
that diaper story to everyone.
He just has no idea how sensitive
girls are. I can't stand it.
Everyone's trying
to distract themselves.
I'm glad my family
didn't come here.
I don't want them to see me getting
knocked out by the mammoth spike.
Don't you worry.
We have Hayakawa Midori's
twisting reception.
We'll receive those
bombs with ease.
I'm glad you're here, Ishimatsu.
If we lived in the Middle Ages,
you'd be a great samurai.
A samurai?
Wow, now that's cool!
I swear on my life I will stop
Yamamoto in her tracks.
Watch out, Ishida-san.
Oh? You have a fever.
She's right.
You'll get dizzy like this.
Ah, doesn't matter.
It's just a tiny cold.
I see. That makes sense.
Now I understand
why Yamada-san's here.
I believe he's planning to give
an official announcement after the match.
Shouldn't we let
Ayuhara-san know beforehand?
About her being
the candidate for the All-Japan?
Don't you think
it'll encourage her?
No.
It could have
the opposite effect.
What do you mean?
At the moment she's focused on the development
of a new technique. We'd only distract her.
Oh! Coach.
What's up?
Ishimatsu has a fever.
Hm? What?!
It's not that serious, but maybe
we should make a rotation just in case.
Yes. I agree.
I can't believe we've lost
Ishida-san's fighting spirit.
It will be a very hard game.
We've been waiting
for you, Fujimi!
Go, go, Fujimi! Fujimi!
I can do this. I'll make my place in
the All-Japan team with my mammoth spike.
I wonder if you left
your sanctum, Ayuhara-kun.
It's finally starting.
I'm so excited.
Hey! What the hell is this?
She's sitting on the bench!
I told you I'm fine.
You're helpless.
Listen, Ishida.
We simply can't take any chances
when it comes to the mammoth spike.
The mammoth spike.
How far can we go
with the twisting reception?
The Interhigh finals
are about to start.
The match will be opened
by Hayakawa from Fujimi.
They put Takeichi-san
instead of Ishimatsu-san.
Will Hayakawa's falling leaf
score a point so soon?
Ah, Aoba receives it!
Yamamoto's already
launched her mammoth spike!
The mammoth spike…!
Takeichi-san!
Twist your body!
Are you okay?
I… I'm sorry.
She took me by surprise.
It won't happen again.
Takeichi-san…
I'll use the mammoth spike
till I break my arms.
Please watch me,
President Yamada.
How are you feeling,
Takeichi-san?
I'm sorry, Coach.
It's fine.
Coach, let me
on the court. Please.
Alright.
Fine. Go ahead.
Show them what you've got.
Ishida will replace Takeichi
that has left the court due to an injury.
The match is resumed.
I've been waiting
for you, Kiddo!
Maybe a yelling dad
isn't that bad.
Do you feel better, Ishimatsu?
Yeah. I feel just dandy.
Here goes my next target.
A feint from Fujimi's Hayakawa!
Good! Shirakawa
skillfully saves the team!
You won't win
against Aoba that way.
If you don't get your act together,
you'll get blasted in minutes!
The ball goes
to Yamamoto again!
Is she targeting Ishimatsu?
I've got it!
What… What are you doing?
What the hell?!
She was about to tip it!
Sorry, Ishimatsu.
I just couldn't watch it.
Mind your own business.
I could've handled it
myself just fine.
– Thank you, anyway.
– Sure thing.
Was that intentional?
Ishimatsu's position
was somewhat perplexing.
You'll be mine
with the next blow.
Another mammoth spike
from Yamamoto!
It's here!
I'll show you what a girl can do!
She did it!
She did it, she did it!
Way to go, Kiddo!
That's my girl over there!
Ishimatsu?
I received it.
I received it!
I received it…
I received it.
Ishimatsu!
W-What's happened!?
In boxing, there's a condition
called "punch drunk" syndrome.
When one receives repeated cerebral
concussions, they begin staggering.
Similar thing happened
with Ishida-kun.
The mammoth spike's power can be
compared to that of a boxer's blow.
I received it, Pops.
I received it like I promised.
Aoba · Fujimi
Ishimatsu's collapse was
a little too much for Fujimi.
They lost the first set
with a huge point gap.
Aoba's streak continues into second set
as they scored 12 points already.
And another point!
It's 13 to 3!
Aoba
This time for sure!
Not even Fujimi's novel reception
technique seems to help much.
How do you like it,
Ayuhara-san?
The players seem
to be at their limit.
What's wrong, Fujimi?
Especially Ayuhara, who plays
a rather mediocre game today.
It seems that the game
has reached its peak.
I wouldn't be so sure.
Hmm?
It's evident that
Ayuhara-kun's in a slump.
That shot isn't just a theory.
I know it can be achieved.
She can find it.
Ayuhara-kun, hurry up
and find a way out of your slump.
I made it,
I made it.
What's going on? Huh?
What's with your sorry faces?
It's all on the scoreboard.
Aoba · Fujimi
They swept the court with us
using their mammoth spike.
Mammoth spike?
Why is this still a thing?
Get a grip!
It's Mitamura-kun!
Remember our
soccer practice.
Did you forget
what I've taught you!?
Hey, Mitamura.
Did you really teach
them volleyball?
Huh? You know
I'm not playing volleyball.
I just showed them the mammoth spike's
nothing compared to the power of a soccer ball.
That's right.
We got discouraged by the incident
with Ishimatsu without me noticing it.
Kozue?
Yeah.
Looks like Midori
feels the same way.
Alright!
Be my guest!
I'm the one who discovered
the way to receive it!
Good luck, Midori.
Attack!
They made it! The spell of the
mammoth spike was finally broken!
All thanks to the radiant
Ayuhara · Hayakawa duo!
Great, great!
You're doing good!
Don't give up!
Yes!
The game's on.
You did it again,
Hayakawa-san… Ayuhara-san.
But it's already too late.
They'll choose me
for the All-Japan.
You have one last chance.
Ayuhara-kun, it's all in the spike
you'll defeat Aoba with.
Oh, it's you.
We've been waiting.
I'm sorry for being late.
I made it somehow.
Aoba · Fujimi
Huh?!
13 to 7, huh?
Looks like we're in for
one interesting endgame.
That's…
Is that him?
The Interhigh final
is coming to an end.
Both teams have been triumphing
for the last ten days.
A fierce fight not to break this streak
continues on under President Yamada's calm gaze.
The most outstanding player in this match
will get qualified for the All-Japan team.
Will it be Kozue
with her fleeing spike?
Or Yamamoto
with her mammoth spike?
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.