苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 091—
She made it to the All-Japan
National High School
Women's Volleyball Championship
I'm sorry I'm late.
Hm?
Oh, it's you.
We've been waiting.
Aoba · Fujimi
I made it somehow.
Looks like we're in for
one interesting endgame.
Kozue!
Hm?
Ah!
What's wrong?
Ayuhara. Hayakawa!
Oh!
Inokuma.
Coach Inokuma…
What is he doing here?
After the World Junior Volleyball
Championships have ended…
…he said he was going to teach volleyball in
a certain country, and flew somewhere by himself.
I remember him saying he won't be
returning to Japan for a while.
Don't you think it's weird that
he has suddenly appeared?
Shirakawa-san…
Coach Inokuma.
I… I still remember.
I remember our days
at the Miyazaki training camp.
Let's go!
Wait!
Stop! I've had enough!
I'm not that coward anymore.
You'll see how I've developed.
Shirakawa-san!
Shirakawa-san seems
to be distracted.
Why?
Ah!
I see… Shirakawa-san's distracted
by Coach Inokuma's presence.
Let's mark Shirakawa-san, girls.
Aoba's nothing without
Yamamoto-san and Shirakawa-san.
Things will surely get easier
with Shirakawa-san out of the picture.
Maybe we can still do it.
Shirakawa misses
again and again.
Next to Yamamoto, Shirakawa is
Aoba's most important player.
Why is she suddenly
so unfocused?
Fujimi mercilessly
keeps aiming at Shirakawa.
Aoba · Fujimi
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have reached a tie.
Oh, there will be
a player change.
Aoba pulls Shirakawa
off the court.
Shirakawa-san, volleyball
isn't only about technique and power.
Sometimes it is also
a fight against yourself.
And today, you've lost
against yourself.
With Shirakawa-san gone, we should
be able to deal with Yamamoto-san.
Listen, girls.
One last push.
Fight!
– Yeah.
It's the mammoth spike!
On it!
Great!
Fujimi
Finally, Fujimi
took the lead!
It's just like you said,
Yushima-kun.
Fujimi's power
is really something.
– Yes, but—
– "But"? Is there more?
Fujimi cannot really
take credit for this.
Aoba dug this grave
all by themselves.
Is this what you wanted
to say, Yushima-kun?
I can't tell why it is so for sure,
but it's like Inokuma-senpai says.
Aoba weren't themselves.
Aoba · Fujimi
Fujimi emerges victorious
from the second set.
We did it!
So the third set is when
the real battle begins?
Yes.
The mammoth spike
can toot it.
I'm not afraid
at all anymore.
Exactly. The third set
is just a formality.
Yeah, haha.
Don't get carried away.
Huh?
I hope you don't think you've won the last set
because you've been stronger than they are.
Your little plan has worked,
I'll admit that.
But if you now go out with such an attitude,
you'll be in for a nasty surprise.
Ayuhara, anything to say?
I'm well aware of it, sir.
I think Yamamoto-san and Shirakawa-san
will be very desperate in the third set.
Exactly. And if they're desperate,
we need to fight back desperately, too.
With Shirakawa like this,
I have no choice but to start without her.
Good luck, girls.
Coach, please wait.
It's not just Shirakawa-san's fault
that we lost the third match.
It was my fault, too.
I'm sorry, Shirakawa-san.
The truth is that the stake in this match
isn't only the first place at the Interhigh.
It's also to recruit excellent players
to join the All-Japan team.
Knowing that, I did just like
in the spring preliminaries.
I was only thinking only
about how I want to get chosen.
Yamamoto-san…
Shirakawa-san, please.
Remember what we vowed
to each other that day.
We'll fight for the victory
at the Interhigh.
That's our only goal.
Shirakawa-san
got over it.
Ayuhara.
Do you not believe
in that spike?
Ah…
When I know that Yushima-san is watching,
I can't… I just can't execute it.
I was afraid so.
But you need to know,
Ayuhara…
Huh?
The last set, which will determine the winner
of this year's tournament, is starting right now.
Know what, Coach?
Ah, never mind.
Go get them, girl.
Will Fujimi maintain their champion position
from the spring tournament?
Or will Aoba take the laurels
for the first time?
According to the information I just received,
the best player of today's match…
…will be officially invited
to the All-Japan team after the game.
Today's game is attended by President
Yamada of the Volleyball Association.
Next to him sits Inokuma Daigo,
the manager for this year's All-Japan team.
They're watching
the game like hawks.
Will they elect Ayuhara Kozue, known in the
high school volleyball world as the Attack No. 1?
Or will it be Yamamoto Misao
with her fearsome mammoth spike?
The referee blows
for the start of the set!
I'll fight with all my strength.
I'm gambling everything
on this single set.
I've got this!
What a game.
What a fury.
You can really see that both teams
are incredibly motivated!
It's the essence of the volleyball.
The people in the audience are watching
holding their breaths, forgetting to cheer.
Attack!
It's a point!
Correction! Shirakawa of Aoba deflects
Ayuhara's spike at the last moment.
Aoba · Fujimi
It's become
a really close game.
It's the mammoth spike
versus the twisting reception.
The stakes are highest than ever.
Every time Aoba scores…
…Fujimi pays back.
An hour has already passed
since the third set began.
It's safe to say that it's the greatest
battle of high school sports this year.
Makimura-san!
You can do this!
Thanks!
Hmm… This can't continue.
They're still fighting with the momentum,
but the truth is that they're absolutely exhausted.
It takes a lot of energy
to receive the mammoth spike.
The longer this match drags,
the more we're at a disadvantage.
Ah! Another one!
Watch out!
Fujimi · Aoba
Are you okay, Naka?
Chief…
They're at their limit, Professor.
One more point and they'll
start dropping like flies.
Time!
Oh? Fujimi called a time out!
What do you think
happens now, Yushima-kun?
Fujimi seems to be really tired.
That's right.
Yamamoto's spike seems to be just
a little bit above Ayuhara's, in the end.
What's wrong, Ayuhara-kun?!
Why don't you show him
your miraculous spike?!
They're putting their
whole souls into it…
What more can I ask
these girls for?
There's nothing to say.
Coach…
Hm? What?
Everyone is giving it their all.
We're on the verge
of passing out.
That's why…
I don't think… you know.
Coach… I'm going to gamble.
I'll try to repeat
that miraculous spike.
Ayuhara?
When the third set was starting,
I wanted to tell you what's at stake today.
I decided not to in the fear
that you'd lose your confidence.
But if you fail, Ayuhara…
If I fail, we will lose
in the blink of an eye.
Still…
Alright. Ayuhara, I'm with you.
Let's gamble everything on your spike.
Professor!
I have never prayed
until this day.
But now I feel like praying.
The match is resumed!
Oh? Yushima-san?
I did it!
It was the same!
Now to learn how to
get it right every single time.
Oh?
Don't mind me.
Keep going.
Okay…
Back then, Ayuhara-kun was very reluctant
to show her technique to me.
She probably didn't feel very confident
and didn't want me to see her fail.
That's what I think.
Ayuhara-kun… it's not like
I don't understand your feelings.
I also…
Go for it, Ayuhara-kun.
I want to see it so bad,
but I'm not watching anymore.
Do it, Ayuhara-kun!
Go for it!
Fujimi · Aoba
If we take back the serve now, Makimura-san
will be the server and I'll be at the front line.
It'll be the most favorable
position to try that shot.
We're getting tired,
but so do they!
Please!
Let's snatch the serve!
Okay.
Showtime.
Even if you get it right
100% of the time during practice…
…it'll be useless all the same
if you can't do it during a match.
Is your technique
some sanctum?
If you have a stage fright
in front of me…
…what will you do in front of
hundreds of people in the audience?
I'll try.
I'll do it!
This is the moment.
Fujimi · Aoba
Inokuma-kun…
What was that?
I-I apologize.
But how do I explain
what just happened?
Ayuhara used similar spike during
Fujimi's match against Shimozaki, but…
…it was widely assumed
to be just a lucky ball.
But Ayuhara's spike just now
was exactly the same as back then.
I did it…
I really did it.
Words truly cannot express
the way the ball behaved.
On top of it, Ayuhara has managed to
directly receive Yamamoto's mammoth spike.
Let's take a look at a replay.
Ayuhara-kun!
Fujimi · Aoba
Ladies and Gentlemen,
Fujimi catches up!
The game's already ended
with that one Ayuhara's play.
That play must have dealt
a huge shock to Aoba.
Yes, now it'll go down
like a snowball.
It's very difficult to stop such
chain reaction in team sports.
So, Inokuma-kun, do we invite
Ayuhara Kozue to the All-Japan team?
Absolutely.
Fujimi · Aoba
It's a match point for Fujimi!
Attack!
Ayuhara Kozue's spike
scores flawlessly.
Fujimi · Aoba
And so Fujimi
becomes the winner!
Ayuhara's spike ended up defeating
Yamamoto's mammoth spike.
Fujimi manages to defend their title
from the spring championship.
Shirakawa-san.
Yamamoto-san.
Ayuhara-san.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Both teams have fought
incredibly well.
It was truly a top-class game,
well worth of the Interhigh championships.
Coach Inokuma.
Ayuhara, your next goal is the
World Championships with the All-Japan team.
We're waiting for you
at a training camp in Hokkaidō.
Yes sir.
Champion
Perhaps it was my last
high school match.
To think it was such an amazing
experience, such a fierce fight…
I will never forget
this day of my life.
Fujimigahama
Ayuhara Kozue… hooray!
Hooray!
Thank you very much.
From today on, I'll be a part of the
National Women's Volleyball team…
…and I'm going to
a training camp in Hokkaidō.
You can count
that I'll be doing my best.
Midori…
Kozue.
Don't say anything.
If you do,
I might start crying.
We're all rooting for you, Kozue.
Thanks.
Kozue.
Kozue! Kozue…
A certain chapter of my life
is coming to an end.
But another one is opening
right in front of me.
I'll walk down wherever it takes me
and never give up.
Kozue gets chosen
for the All-Japan team.
She travels to Hokkaidō
in order to train.
There she meets other elected players,
mostly from various companies' teams.
One of them, Kiyama of Kawamoto Electric,
particularly attracts Kozue's attention.
But for some reason,
she's cold towards Kozue.
Kozue keeps on training,
biting her lips and holding back tears.
Please look forward
to the next episode!
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.