苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 092—
The training camp in Hokkaidō
Tokyo International Airport
Stay safe in Hokkaidō.
Gotou-san.
Thank you for seeing us off.
I have a feeling that they
also belong to the national team.
I appreciate your feelings,
but there's nothing we can do about it.
Don't give up so fast. You know
I always get my way if I set my mind to it.
Leave this to me, Gotou-san.
I'll get you to Hokkaidō.
I don't feel confident
without you.
Gotou-san?
They should've chosen
Gotou-san instead of me.
Nonsense.
It has to be all three of us.
Don't you think it was not a coincidence
that only Gotou-san didn't make it?
Who is that kid?
I don't know.
But she's been staring
at us for a while.
They look familiar somehow…
Passengers flying to Chitose,
please proceed to Gate 2 now.
Out! It's an out!
How silly I am.
Just like me, Shellenina also must've
come up with new techniques.
Still, the Japanese team
won't be easily defeated.
We have many players
from this year's finalist teams…
…No. 1, Mignon Couture
and No. 2, Kawamoto Electric.
We have the very best in Japan.
I won't lose to them.
Even though I was the only one
selected among the high school players…
…I'll show I can
become a regular.
Chitose Airport
If I recall, the men's team
is also starting training camp today.
I wonder if Yushima-san
is already in Hokkaidō…
Mignon Couture
Mt. Moiwa training camp
That's Sapporo!
So that must be
the Ishikari River.
And further down,
Ishikari plains.
Finally, the Ishikari Bay.
I knew it, they were
part of our team.
They're already training, at that…
Ah, Yagisawa-san!
This is the area of the
All-Japan training camp.
High school girls
have no business here.
Actually, I am part of this team.
My name is Ayuhara Kozue.
Ayuhara?
Okay, let's get going!
Long time no see,
Ayuhara-san.
Yagisawa-san! Ah, I…
The dormitory is this way.
Alright, redo!
Sure thing!
The reason why we called
Inokuma-kun all the way here…
…is that we would like him to make you win
the World Championships in Bulgaria by all means.
I firmly believe
he can do it.
We, the National Committee,
trust him blindly with our dream.
I hope you never question
his precious advice.
Now, a word from Inokuma-kun.
As far as the welcome speech is concerned,
President Yamada already summed it up well.
Our goal is the
World Championship title.
I've participated in the World Championships
as a coach of the junior national team.
Unfortunately, we were beaten
by the Soviet team.
Nevertheless, I was very satisfied with my team,
because they played to the best of their ability.
But this time I won't
be satisfied unless we win.
Because I know
you're capable of it.
Don't get cocky, though.
You're not the only ones who
have the ability to win.
Bulgaria.
Poland.
Czechoslovakia.
America.
Kenya.
Finally, the Soviet Union.
Each and every participating
team has that ability.
The champion title.
It is my only goal.
Your goal must be
to defeat all these teams, too.
By the way, Doctor Mihara-san here
will take care of team management.
Hello.
If there are troubles with Coach Inokuma,
don't hesitate and let me know.
Well then, everyone.
Introduce yourselves one by one.
Matsuyama Yuriko
of Mignon Couture.
No. 1 attacker in Japan.
Mignon Couture's captain.
Matsuyama. I appoint you
captain of the national team.
Yes sir.
Yamagami Noriko,
also of Mignon Couture.
Matsuyama-san's spike wouldn't
be possible without her toss.
Likewise,
Onozawa Masako.
Yagisawa Kaori.
Maybe Mignon Couture owes their success
to Yagisawa-san joining their ranks?
Likewise,
Hamada Ai.
Ayuhara Kozue
of Fujimi High School.
Furumoto Yumiko
of Kouyou Inc.
She's Kouyou's captain. This year they ranked third,
but they always play in the finals with Mignon.
No one can surpass
her curve ball serves.
Iwatani Kyouko,
also from Kouyou Inc.
She's famous for her
flawless receptions.
Likewise,
Seki Shiroko.
Likewise, Osada Keiko.
Shimamoto Tomiko
of Kawamoto Electric.
Kiyama Shigemi, captain
of the Kawamoto Electric team…
…who ranked second in the
national championships this year.
She's Kiyama Shigemi?
Before her time, Kawamoto
ranked 5th or 6th every year.
She lead them to runner-up finish this year.
Her time lag attack will go down in history.
Why is Kiyama-san giving me
such a menacing look?
Did I do something
to offend her?
Fight! Fight!
Moo!
Just a high school girl, after all.
All of you are first-class players that have been
thoroughly trained by first-class coaches.
I don't need to tell you
much about training.
The main priority of this camp will be
in creating a healthy team spirit.
But it doesn't mean we're going
to get buddy-buddy here!
Ayuhara, what was that?
You're embarrassing
high school students.
Y-Yes sir.
This training is already
harder in its basic techniques.
Alright, next!
Yes sir.
She looks like an acrobat.
I see how she excels at receptions
given all that agility.
The training's started for real.
I'd better stop daydreaming.
Alright, next!
Yes sir.
What's wrong?!
Too slow!
Come on!
Enough, Ayuhara.
Run twice around the camp.
Huh?
What will we do if you can't
receive such simple balls?
Alright, leave.
If you stand there forever,
you'll be a drag to other players.
Y-Yes sir!
Ayuhara is a bit overzealous.
I hope the night air
cools her head a little.
Serves her right.
What's wrong with you, Kozue?!
Something like that simply can't
happen to me as a national team player.
But still…
Why does Kiyama-san
look at me so hateful?
As if she liked to laugh
at people's failures.
Oh, if only Midori was here…
I miss her so much.
Oh, so beautiful.
Yushima-san.
Yushima-san!
No, I don't have time for this.
Now that I'm here,
I must become a regular.
We've been doing
basic exercises up till now.
That means we can go one step further
and start the special training.
That was a basic training?
The Japanese national team has always
been characterized by their perfect defense.
Our famous special receptions were as good
as the notorious attacks of the Russians.
But they say the offense
is the best defense.
I'll make your attacks as powerful
as the Soviet Union's.
We'll begin by training precision spikes,
so that you can always hit where you aim.
Divide into groups of two.
One spikes, the other one tosses.
Matsuyama!
Yamagami!
– Sir!
Alright!
Next!
– Yes sir.
As expected
from Yagisawa-san.
I wonder if I can do it?
Too far! Redo!
Where are you
aiming at, Onozawa?
Repeat!
Alright, good enough.
Practice further by yourself.
Yes sir!
You can count on it!
Okay, next!
Yes sir!
Oh…
Ayuhara, what do
you have for eyes?
Your mark is over there.
Y-Yes sir.
Kiyama-san, please toss
the ball a little better.
What?
What's your problem?
I'm sorry, but that toss was just…
Don't, Ayuhara.
You'll need to spike from any toss
you get during a real match.
Yes sir.
Exactly.
As for you, Kiyama!
Coach, I'm an attacker
first and foremost.
I'm not a setter, so I can't promise
my tosses will be very good.
Very well.
You can go home.
Huh?
Attack. Toss.
Reception. Serve.
This team doesn't need anyone
who can't do any of those.
– Continue, Ayuhara!
– Yes sir!
Is that all you've got?
Why can't I do it?
Why… Why?
Alright.
I hope that you'll get a grip
on this in a few days.
Yes sir.
Ayuhara-san!
Toss the ball higher!
Just a moment, Coach.
It's impossible for me
to hit the mark as it is.
The way Ayuhara-san
tosses the ball…
Huh?!
I won't deny that Ayuhara-san might've
been No. 1 in the high school world.
But it's not quite
the same as our level.
Even if she manages to toss it once,
she'll drag us down.
Are you sure
it's "us" and not "me"?
Coach, forgive me
if I'm too bold, but…
Why was Ayuhara-san even
chosen for the national team?
There are other players,
above Ayuhara-san's level.
As in Gotou Taeko, famous for her toss
and your partner in your duo?
Yes.
If we had Gotou-san with us, the Russians
wouldn't stand a chance against my attack.
She's that girl from Haneda…
In order for Japan to win,
we have to go with my time lag attack.
And for that, we absolutely
need Gotou-san's toss.
Do you know what
this mountain is called, girls?
That's Mt. Teine.
Yes.
The Winter Olympics take place
in January next year there.
The Munich Olympic Games
follow right after.
Munich Olympic Games…
If we can win the World Championships,
we can also win the Olympic Games.
It is the dream of the Association— no,
of everyone who has anything to do with volleyball.
The Association decided to let
one high school player take part in it.
I have no reason
to question that decision.
We're resuming.
When it was her turn,
I screwed up my tosses.
So she couldn't get
a single hit right.
Then I screwed my spikes.
But it'll be difficult to get Ayuhara-san
kicked out and bring Gotou-san in.
I won't give up, though.
Pulling Gotou-san out,
not putting me as a regular.
I'm telling you,
it's a conspiracy.
Mignon and Kouyou
are conspiring against us.
I'll bring Gotou-san to Bulgaria.
Just watch me.
And I'll grab the No. 1 Attacker
title with these two hands.
I wonder if I was chosen only
for the Olympic Games next year.
Or do they expect anything of me
for the upcoming tournament?
Doesn't matter. I should focus
on becoming a regular player.
I don't want to be
put in reverse.
I have to prove my worth
in tomorrow's mock game.
Alright. I'll show my
balloon attack then.
The balloon attack… With it
no one will deny me the regular status.
Excellent time lag attack.
I can't blame Kiyama-san
for being so proud.
A curve ball serve!
So good!
Here it is.
Matsuyama-san's bullet spike.
Now's my chance!
The balloon attack!
With this,
I'll become a regular player.
I'll nail it
with my balloon attack.
Attack!
My balloon attack…
was received?!
T-That's impossible!
The first mock game begins.
Kozue decides to use her balloon attack.
However, this doesn't work her opponents,
who play professionally in company teams.
Having worked so hard to obtain it,
Kozue is shocked.
Kiyama laughs
mercilessly at Kozue.
That cruel laughter covers up
an even more cruel scheme.
Please look forward
to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.