苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 093—
The player No. 12
White Team
Matsuyama · Yamagami · Onozawa
Hamada · Yagisawa · Ayuhara
Red Team
Kiyama · Shimamoto · Furumoto
Iwatani · Seki · Osada
Now's the chance
for my balloon attack!
The balloon attack…
was received!
Don't get distracted.
Sorry.
Although my balloon attack confused Iwatani-san
at first, the second time she defended it with ease.
Then Kiyama-san flawlessly
aimed her spike right back at me…
Ayuhara-san.
You being here is a mistake.
It should've been Gotou-san from the start.
But that won't last long. Soon everyone will
understand what a burden you are to our team.
White Team · Red Team
One point and we're in the lead!
Yeah!
Matsuyama-san is a good leader.
Her spikes are on par with western players.
The balloon attack is my only choice
to become a regular.
But it was defended the second time.
However, they do say
that accidents happen.
What are you doing?!
Ayuhara-san!
Alright. I suppose it won't hurt
to try it just one more time.
This time…
Attack!
– It's the same as before!
– Got it!
It's totally useless!
Iwatani-san is famous for her receptions,
so of course she'd get it, but Osada-san?
Now!
Ayuhara-san.
Y-Yes?
Never repeat the same technique.
Got that?
Yes.
Alright, let's get them!
– Yeah!
Fight!
"Never repeat the same technique".
I don't have any other weapon
that would be equal to them.
Maybe Kiyama-san was right when she said
it was a mistake for me to be on the national team.
In order to defeat the Russians,
we have to go with my time lag attack.
And for that, we need
Gotou-san as our setter.
I can't comprehend why they'd choose
some high school student over her.
With what I've shown so far,
they'll probably let me go to the Olympics.
But for these championships, I'm not sure if I'll even
get to sit on the bench, let alone play on the court.
Ayuhara-san!
Pay attention!
No, I can't think like that.
I've got to get a grip.
Or, at very least, I can't be a burden
to Captain and the rest of the team.
Ayuhara-san's the weak link!
We'll aim at her!
Line up!
That was the most boring
match I've seen in recent years.
There's no point to drag it any further.
I want each of you to reflect
on it until the meeting.
As for you, Ayuhara!
S-Sir.
You repeated the same technique
three times in a row and failed twice.
That was no ordinary mistake
and it won't be tolerated.
No ordinary mistake?
Your fixation on that technique
has put your team at risk.
As a punishment,
you'll clean up the court.
Yes sir.
Okay, dismissed!
– Yes sir!
Alright then, Ayuhara-san,
we'll be going ahead.
Okay.
Polishing the floor suits you.
So using a single spike
is worse than a miss…
They might be right.
Maybe I was too focused on it.
Maybe I'm too prideful?
But I've worked so hard
to obtain my balloon attack.
Still, it looks like it's only
useful in high school level games.
I don't have anything left that would
allow me to match these people.
Polishing the floor suits you.
She's right.
I'm good for nothing.
Cleaning is all I can do.
I'm a hindrance to the team.
Yeah. But she held up pretty well.
Shimamoto-san.
Can you help me practice
after the meeting's over?
Su-Sure.
Without Gotou-san, only you'll be able
to assist me with my time lag attack.
Alright.
But I sure don't like how we need to train
extra hard just because of certain someone here.
Kiyama-san…
What? I'm just saying what everyone
at the table is thinking.
Learn to keep your
opinions to yourself.
If you will excuse me, please.
A bit sensitive, aren't we?
Does she really have
to insult me so much?
Still, I can't offer them anything
besides my balloon attack.
Yushima-san…
I want to see you.
Ah! Come in!
Ayuhara-san, the meeting.
Ah, thanks.
Do you remember what I said
to you when you arrived here?
Your individual skills
are at the world level.
To make these skills usable, we need
to build a unified team through teamwork.
I thought I was clear enough.
So what was that mock game today?!
Everyone was just out for themselves.
And I noticed that especially
with Ayuhara in the Red Team.
And in the White Team…
it was you, Kiyama!
Huh?!
If you can't integrate into the team,
your techniques won't do you any good.
But, Coach!
Something to say?
Bring it on the court.
Same goes to everyone else!
Volleyball isn't played on the drawing board.
It's all about training and team spirit.
We'll intensify the training
starting tomorrow.
That's all for today.
Let's get a good sleep, girls.
Tomorrow's gonna be a hard day.
– Yes, Captain.
Ayuhara-san.
I feel like you know
the coach very well.
Am I right?
He was our coach
for the Junior Championships.
Oh?
Then you are definitely
one of his favorites.
So that's why they took you in.
Huh?
I'll warn you now that
you won't have long life here.
Ayuhara-san. Ayuhara Kozue-san.
There's a call for you.
Who in the world is calling me so late?
Hello?
This is Ayuhara.
Huh?! Midori?
It's you, Midori!
What's up? You sound
like you're about to cry.
I bet they're putting you
through hell, Kozue.
Yeah, but I'm fine.
Really? That's good to hear. Remember that
you represent our name in the national team.
So be nice but also super good.
Yeah… But to tell you the truth,
my balloon attack proved totally useless.
Huh?! For real?
Well, I guess that's not totally surprising, is it?
Every technique will eventually be defended.
Yushima-san told you that, remember?
It just means that the day has come.
You're totally right.
I'm sure you'll find
something new soon.
Say, Kozue, do you want me
to come there and cheer you up?
Oh? No, I don't want
to trouble you. I'll be fine.
Just hearing your voice
made me feel a lot better.
I see.
In any case, stay strong. Let me know
if you need anything, I'll come at any time.
Thank you, Midori.
I'll call you soon again.
Go! Go! Ayuhara!
Thank you so much…
Nothing has really changed.
But thank you anyway, Midori.
I'll do whatever I can.
Even if I'm just a substitute player.
One! Two! One! Two!
One more lap!
You look pale.
A little too rough, princess?
Say what you want.
I won't get drawn into it.
There's no point if no one's going to
acknowledge me as their team mate, anyway.
I lack the power for it.
Where's your energy?!
Alright! That's enough.
From today on, we'll be using a special
kind of ball for our reception practice.
Matsuyama, hand over that ball.
Yes sir.
I guess you already get the idea…
…but just to be formal, this special ball
is two times as heavy as a normal ball.
Two times?
If it's twice as heavy, then its power
will triple or even quadruple when hit.
From today on, we'll be doing
reception drills using this special ball.
Yagisawa!
Yes sir!
That he uses Yagisawa-san
for special training…
Let's not waste time.
We start training on the other side of the gym.
– Yes, Captain!
Yagisawa-san!
Too slow!
Arms up!
Faster!
Your opponents will
tear you apart like that.
Even children know how to hit.
The trick is to receive!
What is it?
That's all?
Is this how a national
team member plays?
Yagisawa-san!
Yagisawa-san.
I'm not giving up.
I'm not giving up…
Hang in there,
Yagisawa-san. Kaori-san!
I'm not giving up.
I'm not giving up!
That's the spirit.
Let her rest.
Yes sir.
Hold onto my arm.
Ayuhara-san.
I'm here for you. Come on.
I don't need your help.
Yagisawa-san…
You have to make the most
of every single minute.
So cold.
Even Kaori-san has changed.
The other players, too.
No one can even spare
a moment to help the others.
Such a merciless fight.
I have no business here.
Not as a regular,
nor even on the bench.
If you have the time
to daydream, hit the court!
I'm sorry, Coach!
Alright, let's take a break.
– Yes sir!
– Yes sir.
Ayuhara! Wait.
You're still up.
Yes sir!
You'd better not be
half-hearted about this.
Let's go!
It hurts like hell after just one serve!
Good. Show her.
It's worse than with Yagisawa-san.
Of course it is.
She's a high school student.
If it goes well,
I won't have to do anything.
Even Yagisawa-san didn't stand a chance.
So where does that put me?
I'm still a part of this team, though.
I have to get through this.
That's the least a reserve
player like me can do.
That's all you've got?!
Alright! That's it for today.
Practice is over!
– Yes sir.
Our levels are just too different.
I have no place in the national team.
Yushima-san…
A victory sign?
That's right.
No matter what happens,
I can't lose my heart.
I've got to stay strong.
And if Yushima-san knew I'm only polishing
the floors, he'd be disappointed in me.
I have to do something.
Anything.
It's like Midori said.
I'll discover something new.
I might not know
what spike it will be yet.
But if I don't try, I'll never know,
so I can't give up.
The surprise from the ball seeming to escape
receiver's hands only works once.
I have to change it somehow.
Oh?
That's her.
I thought she'd be in her room
packing her stuff by now.
What a stubborn girl.
Plus that strange training…
Maybe she has some talent, after all.
In any case, we have
to take the proper countermeasures.
No, that's not it.
If I hit it with all my might,
it's not a balloon attack anymore.
This is going nowhere.
I'm so ashamed to face
Midori and the others.
Yushima-san… I'm sorry.
It was a bad call to select a girl like me
for the All-Japan team.
Ayuhara-san.
Kiyama-san!?
We heard you were training.
If you want, we can give you a hand.
No, it's fine.
Excuse me.
Wait up.
You look pretty depressed.
I don't like it, either!
I hate how I have to make a team with someone
so overrated and only getting in the way.
Why don't we have a little spar?
It'll be beneficial to both of us.
A spar?
We'll spike five times each.
If you can receive even one of my spikes,
I will recognize you as a pro.
How's that sound?
Acknowledge me as a pro?
Alright then.
Fine.
Oh, and we'll be using the special ball.
Huh?! The one
from the practice?
Yes. I hope you're not
getting cold feet, now.
Playing with that heavy ball
could turn ugly.
Alright, you'll spike first.
I'll toss it to you.
It's too late to turn back.
Give me your best shot!
Okay.
Are you okay, Kiyama-san?
I'm fine. Don't mind me.
I'll get better next time.
Just like I feared, it's dangerous
to go all the way with this ball.
Above all, the goal of this training camp
is to make you into a proper team.
I'm just a spare player anyway.
If I end up hurting Kiyama-san, it'll affect
the whole team, so I have to play with less force.
Don't just stand there!
Hurry up!
I can't win here.
Even if I do, it won't make me
into a regular player.
Keep them coming!
If I lose, at least
Kiyama-san won't be hurt.
That's the best course of action
that'll benefit the team.
How much do I have to wait?
Alright, Ayuhara-san.
You'll be the receiving side now.
I'll beat you to a pulp.
You only have to lose.
It's even stronger than I thought.
Good that I chose
to give up this match.
That was the first one.
It's for the best.
I've made my decision.
But…
But…!
A fierce late night sparing
between Kiyama and Kozue.
Kozue breaks down before
Kiyama's plan.
"I won't become a regular player."
"I can't compete against professional players."
Kozue becomes a shadow of herself
and starts to work for her team.
But it doesn't take long
until Inokuma takes notice.
Kozue becomes
more and more morose.
"What will you do, Ayuhara?"
Hang in there, Kozue!
Please look forward
to the next episode!
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.