苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 094—
What will you do, Ayuhara?!
What's wrong,
Ayuhara Kozue-san?
We're not done yet.
Stand up!
I have to lose so that
I don't harm the team.
I have to lose.
I'm ready.
Toss me the ball.
Kiyama-san, maybe
we should stop.
I said, toss me that ball!
Ah, okay.
Ayuhara-san.
Even if you've won the Interhigh, you're nothing
more than an immature high school student.
Now you know the
difference in our levels.
Are you ok—
– Leave her alone.
– But…
You heard her yourself.
She agreed to my challenge
out of her own will.
There's no reason
to be sorry for her.
That should teach her
to know her place.
Let's go.
It's for the best.
It's for the best…
It's better that way.
For the sake of our national team.
It's better for everyone
if I just keep enduring it.
– Fight! – Fight!
Hello!
How about a big sip
of fresh milk, ladies?
We take a lot of pride in it.
It'll give you strength for your training.
Ah, I was just getting thirsty!
Thank you very much, mister.
One of you, come over
and I'll give you a case.
I'll be right back.
Ah, I'll go instead.
Hmph.
Now she's trying
to butter us up?
Thank you very much, mister.
I'll be going, then.
Isn't it a bit too heavy for you?
Let me help you out.
No, I'm fine.
Just be careful.
I will.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Are you okay, Ayuhara-san?
Want me to help?
No, it's fine.
Hmph. Look at her.
Ayuhara-san…
Ah, I'm terribly sorry, Captain.
I'll go fetch another one immediately.
I'm sorry.
What's the matter?
What are you doing?
All right!
Practice's over.
– Yes, Captain.
Wait a minute.
Ayuhara-san.
Yes?
You don't have to
do it by yourself.
We're all equal here.
No, it's okay.
Ayuhara-san, is something the matter?
You don't seem to have an appetite.
Oh? No, everything's fine.
It's been one week
since the camp started.
It's about time for the fatigue to come out,
so be sure to take plenty of rest, girls.
– Yes ma'am.
Matsuyama
Iwatani
Yagisawa
One, two.
Oh, here you are, Kiyama-san.
– Shh!
– Ah…
Look over there.
Oh?
She's totally crazy.
She's too busy licking
our boots during the day.
So she trains late at night.
But it's no use.
She'll last two to three
days more at best.
She'll flee the camp
all by herself soon.
Alright, Shimamoto-san.
Let's return to our rooms and sleep.
Okay…
If I show them my balloon attack,
I can become regular.
That's what I thought at first.
But they dealt with it
without breaking a sweat.
I know I have to devise
an even stronger attack.
But I don't have
any power left within me.
No matter how hard I try,
I'm still just a high school student.
There's no comparing me to the other
players chosen for the All-Japan team.
I was wrong when I thought
that I could become a regular.
I should focus on doing
whatever I can to help the team.
And if the team wins the World
Championships… then I'm plenty satisfied.
Ayuhara!
Sir?
Let me see you spike.
Yes sir!
Please toss it to me.
You call that a spike?
The jump was not high enough.
The striking power was missing, too!
I'm sorry.
I want you to make an endurance run
to the farm and back again.
Yes sir!
As for you, we'll train reception!
Let's go!
– Yes sir!
Even if I can't practice enough…
Even if I get scolded
by the coach…
It's fine.
As long as the team
gets stronger, I…
I'm happy.
I don't care what happens to me.
The team is everything.
Miss!
Miss?
Hey. Working hard, huh?
Ah, Yushima-san.
What are you doing here
all by yourself, Ayuhara-kun?
Haha. From the look on your face,
Inokuma-san's got angry with you, huh?
I guess being a sole high school player
on the team must be difficult.
But I know you've got what it takes
to be on the All-Japan team.
Good luck.
Do your best!
Inokuma-san sure is harsh.
Next!
Pay attention to when you jump up,
then play the ball right on it.
Next!
Yes sir.
Your arms are too stiff! Next!
Argh! Alright, next!
Yes sir!
Even if your shot is precise,
it's useless if it's too weak!
Next you, Matsuyama!
Good! You have to play the ball
with all your strength.
Make two groups
and continue training.
– Yes sir!
Ayuhara!
Ah! Sir!
We'll train reception.
Here we go.
Yes sir.
Heh. Serves her right.
Attention, ladies.
Tomorrow you can take a day off.
– Wow! – A day off!?
– That's terrific.
Of course you can rest here in your rooms,
but if I can give you a suggestion, I'd go for a walk.
It's okay to take it easy
every once in a while.
– Yes ma'am!
Oh? That's Ayuhara's room.
Ayuhara.
Hey. Ayuhara!
What are you doing?
Coach…
Extra training wouldn't be bad,
but what in the world is this?
Well, I washed
everyone's uniforms.
Who told you to do it?
Nobody told me to.
I did it voluntarily.
It was completely unnecessary.
We were provided a well-
functioning laundry service.
Just let them do their job.
I wanted to wash these myself.
W-What?
I think that job suits me the best.
What did you say?!
I'm the youngest
player on the team.
I'm a burden to everyone.
You fool! You're saying that your role
is to fetch balls and wash uniforms?!
That's right.
This way I save time for others,
who have the chance to train more.
Cleaning uniforms seems to be
the least I can do for the team.
You fool!
Snap out of it!
Take a moment
and mull that over.
Why…
Why did I get scolded at?
The coach…
The coach doesn't understand
my feelings at all.
Ayuhara-san.
Ayuhara-san, I asked my cousin from the
university to show us the city. Let's go together.
Hey, Ayuhara-san.
She's gone already?
It's no good.
Everything is pointless.
Shellenina!
We won't win the World Championships
unless we can win with the Soviet Union.
I'd love to play against Shellenina again…
but I'm nowhere near good enough.
I can't do anything but morally support
Matsuyama-san and the team.
Hey.
Ah, Yushima-san.
We also have a day off today.
I decided I'd go check up on you.
I'm curious about
what happened last night.
It's no big deal.
I heard everything
from Inokuma-san.
I can't blame him
for getting mad at you.
What you're doing is stupid.
Huh?
Yes. Ayuhara Kozue
these days is a big fool.
Yushima-san, I was only
thinking about my team!
Stop justifying it.
Are you planning to play
holy all way through?
You have to start to set
your own value a little higher.
You're a part of the
national team, dammit!
You made it so far as the only
high school student in the whole Japan.
Did you forget that already?
But they're so much stronger than me!
Matsuyama-san, everyone…
"I'll never become a regular."
"I'm just a spare player anyway", huh?
Ayuhara-kun, if that's what you're thinking,
then pack your bags and go home already.
Yushima-san!
If you think of yourself as a spare player,
you've already lost anyway.
Players who have lost before even stepping
on the court aren't of any use to the team.
And here you are, all like
"it's all for my team"!?
There are no regular or spare players.
Every one of you belongs to the same team.
What do you think happens
when one of you gives up, Ayuhara-kun?!
Are you still too blind
to see that, Ayuhara Kozue?
Huh?!
What will it be, Ayuhara?
What will it be?
What will you do, Ayuhara?!
Ayuhara-kun.
Here.
Yushima-san… I'll do it.
Good.
The spin…
I need to give it more spin.
Attack!
I'll do it.
I'll reinforce my ballon attack.
I'll show you.
I'll show you!
Yushima's encouragement
reignites Kozue's fighting spirit.
The words of a little girl from the farm nearby
give Kozue a valuable clue for her new spike.
Kozue goes on the court to try things out, but
a treacherous trap from Kiyama obstructs her way.
Kozue doesn't yield to it
and keeps on fighting.
Finally, a slight change in timing
in her attack produces a surprising result.
The day of departure for the World
Championships in Bulgaria is approaching fast.
What exactly
is Kozue's new spike?
Please look forward
to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.