苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 095—
The birth of the tornado strike
That's it!
It'll become a killer technique
if you manage to curve it more!
I know, but how?
Yushima-san.
I'm a member
of the national team.
I'll prove my worth
and make it success.
Just watch me!
Attack!
Coach.
What do you think of that spike?
Think it'll be good?
If she makes it curve more,
it definitely will.
I think so, too.
– Fight! – Fight!
Curve ball.
Good morning!
Hello, little girl!
Thank you for
the milk yesterday.
– Thank you.
– Thanks.
We have more today.
Thanks, but we don't want
to trouble you.
Don't be so uptight. With our milk,
you'll have a better chance to win.
Oh? I-I guess.
Did I say anything funny?
Looks like we can't refuse.
Alright, girls!
Let's drink a lot!
– Whoa!
– Yeah!
Moo…
Can't refuse, huh?
That little girl's cute. She gave even
composed Matsuyama-san a hard time.
A hard time… time?
That's it! What if I purposefully
hit the ball a moment later?
You really are a klutz.
You can't spill it this time.
Thank you.
She gave me a good idea.
Maybe that's the key
to make the ball curve more.
Thank you, little girl.
Thanks to you,
I feel really good now.
I know, right?
Our milk is the tastiest there is!
Yes, it is.
It really is delicious.
Look at her laughing
without a care in the world.
Shimamoto-san…
We don't have much time left.
The camp's end
is getting closer and closer.
Listen, I have a plan.
We'll get Gotou-san
to join us very soon.
It might get
a little violent, though.
W-What do you want to do?
When we'll practice spikes…
We'll invite Ayuhara-san
to train with us.
Then, boom. I will…
Huh?! You're serious?!
A stronger balloon attack
that always escapes receivers' hands.
Attack!
Shimamoto-san.
Now's our chance.
Eh—
Hurry up!
To hit the ball a little later…
A moment after I jump there's a short pause,
after which I begin to fall. That's the moment.
Yes. When I'm falling and the ball's above me,
what if I turn around and spike it from below?
Perhaps the ball will change its direction
in a way that the opponent can't predict.
Ayuhara-san, I'll toss it to you.
Okay. Thank you.
Time to try it.
Oh! Ayuhara-san?
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
Everything's fine.
Sorry about that.
My hand slipped.
If only the ball had hit her a little higher,
it could've broken her ribs.
But still, I didn't expect her to jump up
before the toss. Why did she do that?
Alright, go back to practice.
– Yes, Captain.
Coach, Kiyama-san's attitude towards
Ayuhara-san is inexcusable.
The "accident" just now…
As their captain, I can't tolerate it.
Doesn't matter.
Let them be.
Listen, Matsuyama.
The goal of this training camp
is to make you into a team.
But don't be mistaken.
That's doesn't equate
to rainbows and unicorns.
Just look at them.
When they receive.
When they attack.
They're not good girls.
Far from it.
Before getting into All-Japan, these were the aces
of the teams which fought with each other.
The sense of rivalry that
stems from this is important.
Here, these rivals join together for the common goal
of winning the World Championships.
That's what team spirit is about.
It has to be ruled by a strong rivalry
between each of you.
Sometimes it drives out
unexpected power.
To have a chance at the championships,
we need fighters that don't play for pleasure.
I can understand rivalry,
but malice?
Matsuyama!
You still don't understand.
My point is that if she survives harassment,
only something good can come out of it!
And I want the good stuff
to come out.
Ayuhara!
Sir!
Redo that spike from before.
Huh?
B-But I haven't grasped it fully yet.
Don't whine.
Kiyama!
You'll toss her the ball.
Yes sir.
The coach is so cruel.
I said I wasn't ready…
On top of it, he chose Kiyama-san.
But it's my chance. I'm getting
better and better. I will succeed.
Attack!
I did it!
I finally did it.
I'm not giving up.
I'm the only high school student
in all of Japan that's made it into All-Japan.
Let's start!
Attack!
Mine!
Hmph. She can't do it
even I toss it normally.
Ayuhara! Get a grip!
What the hell was that?
Here goes!
Attack!
I'm on it!
That won't cut it.
It's still too weak.
One more time.
I guess I've no choice but to
keep trying with various timings.
Attack!
Coach, that's…
I'm at my limit.
Change the defense line!
Stand up, Ayuhara!
But I have no strength left.
Ayuhara! You're in the All-Japan
team! Don't be so soft!
Attack!
Is that all you can do, Ayuhara?
We're not in a kindergarten, you know.
Such beginner spikes will make
your opponents laugh.
Go train more!
Not in kindergarten…
Kindergarten…
Kindergarten!?
All-Japan Team
Ayuhara Kozue
Good luck, Ayuhara!
Do your best!
You can do it!
Hang in there!
Kozue, do your best
in my place. You hear me?
Break a leg, Chief.
Fight, Captain!
I'm looking forward to it, Chief.
Do your best, Ayuhara Kozue.
Ah!
Yushima-san!
Good luck, Kozue!
Good luck, Chief!
– Good luck! – You can do it!
– Fight! – We believe in you!
It's hopeless. I'm hopeless.
Midori… Yushima-san.
Ayuhara-san.
Yagisawa-san.
It feels refreshing
after crying, doesn't it?
Thank you.
About that spike
you showed before.
In my opinion…
it's pretty good.
Thank you. You're the first
here who's comforted me.
Comforted?
That's not what this is about.
Huh?
Ayuhara-san.
Did you already forget
what Coach told you?
We have a big game against
the Russians ahead of us.
I think that your new spike
can become a good weapon.
Just to make things clear,
I didn't praise it out of sympathy to you.
Ayuhara-san!
Yagisawa-san.
Alright, no more sugarcoating.
Let's go train.
Yeah.
Are you ready?
Yes.
The ball accelerates there.
That's why it hit the ceiling.
Don't overdo it with the power.
Less power…
Once more!
Okay!
Attack!
It turned!
It turned.
Keep it up.
Good. I'll test it tomorrow again.
Alright, that's enough!
Break!
– Yes sir!
Coach.
Please test my spike.
Very well.
Break's over!
We'll receive Ayuhara's spike!
– Yes sir!
I'll be her tosser, Coach.
Go ahead.
Stay relaxed, Ayuhara-san.
Sure.
Here we go.
Attack!
Coach, let me receive.
Just do as before.
Okay.
Here goes.
Attack!
Iwatani-san, the receiver prodigy.
Oh!
Attack!
She still has a way to go.
I'm not going to cry anymore.
Here goes!
I'll develop it further.
No. I will make it grant me
the title of World's No. 1 Attacker.
Ayuhara-san.
Yes?
I'll twist the next toss a bit.
Pay attention to it.
Okay. I'm ready.
Ayuhara-san.
Yagisawa-san.
This time not even
Iwatani-san will receive it.
Here goes!
Okay.
Awesome!
That was a world-class reception.
But I won't give up.
I'll make my own world-class spike
with these two hands.
We've been waiting
for you, Mr. Director.
Listen up!
The training camp ends today.
But I'll hold off on thanking for your work
until you win the finals in Bulgaria.
We'll now hold a final
practice game for Yamada-san.
Don't disappoint me, girls!
– Yes sir!
The training camp is over
while my spike is still incomplete.
That'd never have happened if Gotou-san was here.
She's always distracted everyone from my deception.
Everything…
Everything is her fault.
I have an idea.
There's not much else I can do.
She jumps up just a bit before
she's tossed the ball at.
That's when I'll aim
my toss at her face.
Now's the moment!
Leave it to me!
That's it!
Ayuhara-san, this is it!
Ayuhara-san.
I'll receive your attack
for sure next time.
Alright, Ayuhara.
Let's try it one more time.
Yes sir.
Ready?
Yeah!
Attack!
A tornado!
It moves like a tornado!
Ayuhara-san.
Congratulations, Ayuhara-san.
It's an excellent technique.
It'll be a good ace in the sleeve
against the Soviet team.
Thank you very much.
It was possible
thanks to all of you.
– You did it, Ayuhara-san. Congrats.
– Congratulations. – Congratulations.
The essence of a team…
is the sense of rivalry.
And it gave a birth to an exquisite
technique: the tornado strike.
I did it, Midori.
Yushima-san, I finally did it.
The tornado strike.
That's how I'm going to name my new spike.
Oh? Shellenina!
Out of two times we've played,
I've lost both.
But the third time is the charm.
I'm looking forward
to meeting you in Bulgaria.
It'll be fine.
I have my tornado strike.
I won't lose to you.
As if I could.
Shellenina-san!
It'll be my victory!
This time it'll be my victory!
Yes. We'll win.
With your tornado strike.
Coach…
Ayuhara.
The harshness of the way to the world's top,
how it shakes your soul to the core…
There are no words
that describe it.
It's a pleasure known only to those who survive
through every single obstacle, all the way up.
Ayuhara.
Get to the world's top.
Become a worldwide star
with your world-class attack.
Yes sir.
Ayuhara Kozue will become
the world's Attack No. 1.
Chitose Airport
Yushima-san!
I heard about your tornado strike.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Let's do our best, the both of us,
on the world-scale stage.
Yes.
Finally it's that time.
My volleyball youth begins anew
on the other side of the sky.
In Bulgaria…
In Bulgaria.
World Championships
in Bulgaria begin.
On a court where youth's skill and power is brought
to a test, the first match is about to be started.
Inokuma and the All-Japan team burn with a new
fighting spirit, anticipating many fierce battles ahead.
Before tomorrow's match, the team
goes on sightseeing in the city to ease mood.
But the grudge between Kozue and Kiyama,
brought all the way from Hokkaidō, explodes brutally.
Please look forward
to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.