苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 096—
And so, the World Championships begin!
Oh, it's so dazzling.
Sofia Airport
Bulgaria is one of the southernmost
countries in Eastern Europe.
Wow, so beautiful.
The sky is so blue…
Well, of course it's blue.
Yeah, but the sky in Tōkyō
is never that clear.
That's just because we're in the sticks.
By the way, Kiyama-san, did you know that Sofia
has a population of 400,000 and two airports?
Wow, that's amazing.
Well I, for one, am disappointed that
no one greeted us at the airport.
It looks like there's
not much going on here.
I wonder what kind of hotel we'll be staying in?
Though, to be honest, I don't expect very much.
I didn't know we were here for
a sightseeing tour, Shimamoto-san.
During the Junior High Championships, it was
Coach that would scold us for goofing around.
But now he left that task
to Matsuyama-san.
I wonder where
that change came from?
Ayuhara-san.
Hm?
Look!
It's National Assembly Square.
That's the Monument
to the Tsar Liberator.
Let's check our combat strength again.
Yamagami's toss followed by
Matsuyama's spike.
That Mignon's duo is untouchable.
Furumoto's curve ball serves
are also good for the most part.
I have no complaints about Iwatani's
techniques and motivation either.
However, Kiyama's time lag attack, which was
supposed to be main pillar of our offense…
…is still no good.
It'd be relatively easy to improve her attack
if the reason for this was not enough training.
But I fear that the problem
is a mental block.
She doesn't believe in me.
If it continues like this, we'll lose one
of the fundamental pillars of the team.
We're at the hotel.
Get ready.
– Sure.
– Okay.
Whoa! It's so small!
Welcome, welcome, girls!
You're finally here!
I've been looking forward to seeing you.
Flying all the way here
from Tōkyō must've been hard.
You must be tired.
This is Sophia-san, the owner of our hotel.
She lived in Japan for 15 years.
My name is just like this city's.
Easy to remember, right?
Alright, don't just stand there.
Come in, come in!
– Thanks. – We're going.
– By all means.
– You too, sweetie.
– Ah…
Don't be shy, come in.
Good, good.
Look, girls, I've prepared
some tea for you.
– Thanks.
– Thank you.
Let me help you out.
Oh, no, sweetie, you don't have
to do anything. Let me do my thing.
Although I'm Bulgarian,
I intend to root for Japan.
But in return, I need you
to promise me that you'll win.
Do you believe you can do it?
Ah… Well, yes.
Good, then keep it up!
And how about you?
Can you win?
Y-Yes. We can win.
I… think.
Good girl!
And you? Can you win?
You can, can't you?
Kiyama-san!
Of course we can.
Why else would we come here for?
We will win.
We'll absolutely win!
That was splendid.
You're a beautiful, strong woman.
Without that firm resolution,
you'd lose even the easy games.
I'm looking forward
to seeing your games.
T-Thanks.
She was pouting so much and making scenes, but
in the end even she couldn't resist our landlady.
I must say I feel really
comfortable in this hotel.
Now all we need
is a court to practice on.
I heard we'll be able to train
only in the evenings here.
That means there will be
plenty of time for ourselves.
Let's take a stroll around the city.
The atmosphere at their games
is quite different from ours in Japan.
We can use this opportunity
to get to know them a bit better.
Come in.
We're leaving for
a sightseeing tour. Hurry up.
– Okay.
Apparently she had her own idea.
That's so like Matsuyama-san.
The best thing to see in Sofia
is the great cathedral in the center.
– Make sure you don't miss it.
– Yes ma'am. – Yes ma'am.
– Alright then, children, take care.
– Thanks.
Ah, just a moment, dearie.
Yes?
Your collar is bent.
You represent all of Japan,
so make sure you take care of yourselves.
Sorry.
It's no biggie.
It looks just like the Holy
Resurrection Cathedral in Tōkyō.
What's it called?
Just a sec.
Let's see…
Its full name is
St. Alexander Nevsky Cathedral.
It was built in honor to the Russian soldiers
who died fighting the Turks.
So it was just the Russo-Turkish War.
The bells sound beautiful.
What kind of instrument is that?
Bagpipes.
Wanna know what it's made of?
Sheep guts.
Slowly but steadily I'm starting
to get sick of Kiyama-san.
Try not to talk like that, Yagisawa-san.
Yeah, I know, but I just can't forget
what she did to you back then, Ayuhara-san.
What do you mean?
I'm talking about that time she had tossed you
the ball before you showed the tornado drop.
Now's the time!
She just hit the ball
in the wrong direction.
But I was already there
about to toss it to you myself.
Why would she cut in front of me?
Just to screw up?
Yagisawa-san didn't have to tell me
because I was thinking of it myself.
And it's not just that time.
Kiyama-san didn't like me
from the very beginning.
Before the training camp even began,
as soon as I arrived at Haneda Airport…
Where's the logic in that?
Without Gotou-san, Kiyama-san
can't execute her time lag attack.
To replace her with some random high school
student just because she won the Interhigh…
Who is that kid?
I don't know.
But she's been staring at us for a while.
Kiyama-san's partner, Gotou-san, was taken off
the team because I was chosen instead.
That's why she tried to take me down
with that crazy pass.
No! Kozue, why do you
think such things?
Yagisawa-san.
Yagisawa-san!
How do I find the others?
I don't know anything about this place.
Ah.
Kiyama-san!
Ayuhara-san.
Apparently you seem
to have gotten lost, too.
Kiyama-san, you too?
Well, I can't speak
this stupid language.
No shame in getting lost, alright?
Err… Where are you going, then?
You really are hopeless, aren't you?
Look over there.
If we use the cathedral as a point of reference,
we'll find our way back.
You're getting on my nerves.
Well, we are staying at the same hotel.
So what? You think you're one of us just because
we live under the same roof?
You've got to be kidding me.
I'll never acknowledge you.
No matter what you say, Kiyama-san,
I'm an official member of the All-Japan team.
Hmph.
What on earth were you thinking
when you aimed that ball at my face?
There. I said it.
I finally said it.
Do you have any proof?
Yes, I do.
I have it right with me.
Where is it?
Right there.
The proof… is within your heart.
You're unbelievable.
I should've known
it'd be something like that.
I don't know what you're laughing at,
but you better tell me right now.
Fine, I'll tell you.
I'm laughing at you, a special snowflake who thinks
she's being persecuted by the whole world.
– I pity you.
– Huh?!
Sneaking around, making up stupid schemes.
It's completely unsportsmanlike.
It's unlike you, Kiyama-san!
Unlike me?
If you have something against me,
then say it to my face.
No one understands Japanese here.
Don't worry about wording.
You sure are good at talking.
You could be a lawyer.
I'll bet that's how you convinced the coach
and Yamada-san to let you join the team.
Your presence
took Gotou-san from me.
If only Gotou-san was here, I would be
better than Matsuyama-san, much better.
Gotou-san's toss was supposed
to pave our road to victory.
If my time lag attack doesn't work out,
it'll be your fault and yours alone.
Is that all you have to say to me?
What, you want to add something?
Yes. I saw your spike on TV
as well as in our training.
I thought it was exceptional,
and studied it thoroughly in my own way.
Flattery won't get you anywhere.
I'm not trying to flatter you.
– Let me finish.
– I've heard enough.
Kiyama-san!
Excellent.
That was splendid.
Who are you guys?
We're a volleyball club
from the east district of Sofia.
You girls are from the Japanese
national team, is that right?
Yes, that's correct.
I thought so. As a matter of fact,
I have a favor to ask.
Come here, boys.
Let's go.
Please stop.
I'm sorry, but just one more time.
Please pardon my rudeness.
I don't think there was any other way
to convince you to play with them for a bit.
Those eyes.
How they look at me.
I've seen that look somewhere before.
Let's get going!
Yes, those eyes looked
just like Kiyama-san's back then.
These kids are most of the junior
volleyball players in Sofia.
They're comfortable with the basics, but they still
haven't grasped a proper toss nor spike yet.
So you thought to let them
train with us?
Well, the time is up.
Wait a moment.
What do you still want?
We are in a hurry.
Kiyama-san!
What are you guys doing here?
Oh, you were training with the boys?
Thank you, that's sweet of you.
No, uhm…
Nah, I just dragged them into it.
I wanted to show the boys
a real toss and spike.
You're pretty lucky.
Kiyama-san is the top fighter
on the Japanese team.
Now, show the power of
Japanese women to these Bulgarian boys.
Okay.
Ayuhara-san, was it?
Could you assist her?
Y-Yes.
Oh, then let's get to it at once.
Let me introduce her.
Ayuhara Kozue.
The youngest of our members
and the best spiker on the team.
Kiyama-san…
Ayuhara-san will show you a top-class spike
that will exceed your expectations.
Here, Ayuhara-san.
I'll toss it to you.
Assume positions!
Thank you very much.
I hope Kiyama-san doesn't hit the ball
like she did during training.
Kiyama-san… What is your plan?
Excellent!
Excellent, Ayuhara-san!
Oh, no. It was thanks to
Kiyama-san's skillful toss.
Don't be so modest.
Now it's your turn, Kiyama-san.
I think that's enough. Ayuhara-san has shown you
an excellent spike. That must be enough.
– Please!
– Please, just one more!
Looks like the youngsters want to see
your spike as well, no matter what.
Please.
I'd like to see it myself, too.
Why?
I've already shown
a good toss and reception.
I've told them a hundred times
that it's important to be good at every position.
In order to be a truly
excellent team member…
…each person must be an excellent receiver.
An excellent tosser. And an excellent attacker.
And you want to prove it to them
by showing how we play?
Kiyama-san, please, show it to them.
This old man is a former volleyball player.
He's very enthusiastic about it.
Fine.
I'll show you my spike.
My special technique: the time lag attack.
But I can't promise you anything, though.
My spike is very demanding on the tosser.
Kiyama-san, let's show it to them.
But if it goes wrong, we'll not only
embarrass ourselves, but all of Japan.
You'll be disgraced, too.
I'm ready.
Exquisite.
Hey, you're not half bad.
Right back at you, Kiyama-san.
Your spike was awesome.
I didn't want to disappoint them when it obviously
meant so much to them, so I tried really hard.
I hope you understand now what I always tell you.
Each of you must be able to do everything.
Having low ambitions
is the last thing I want for you.
They say the sky is the limit.
So never give up on hope.
You're still young.
You have so much ahead of you.
Hey, Kiyama-san…
What were you thinking about?
I found Gotou-san.
Huh?!
The second Gotou-san.
Where?
In that girl.
So now you've become her new tosser.
You never change, do you?
It was surprising, for sure.
It went smoother than I could ever hope to.
I don't think there's
anything surprising here.
The squeeze they gave us in Hokkaidō
made you much stronger.
What I'm surprised about is that you
managed to befriend Kiyama-san.
I'm not sure if you're
amazing or stupid.
Well, I still owe my tornado drop
thanks to her toss.
But she wanted to knock you
down with it, Ayuhara-san!
Don't sweat the small stuff.
The important thing was the result.
Sometimes I really don't
understand you.
That sounds good.
The courts are the same everywhere.
But their physique is a different story.
Yeah, everyone's so tall.
Do you know anyone here?
Yes, I played with some people here
during the Junior High Championships.
Virginia from the American team.
Češka from Czechoslovakia.
Manumba from Kenya.
All of my rivals from
the Junior High tournament.
All but one.
Where is Shellenina?
Where's the Russian team?
The Russian team…
Look, they're right there in front of us.
But Shellenina didn't come.
How is this possible?
Such a good player not participating
in these championships?
Shellenina,
why aren't you here in Sofia?
Playing against you was one
of my biggest goals.
Shellenina!
Where are you, Shellenina?
How many times have I dreamed
of the World Championships…
And now, I will finally be on the court.
I will do more than just my best
as a member of the national team.
Japan has to become
the world champion.
I'll work hard!
The World Championship
begins under an endless blue sky.
Old friends from the Junior World Championship
finally see each other on the court again.
With one exception: Shellenina of the
Soviet Union is nowhere to be seen.
The Japanese team plays their first match
in the preliminary round against Italy.
Contrary to the expectations, Kiyama
disturbs teamwork with her arrogance.
Japan quickly loses the first and the second set,
and now, in the third set, the team is put in a bind.
Please look forward
to the next episode!
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.