苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 097—
Backed into a corner
Češka has become
a fantastic player.
One can put her on a par with Iwatani-san,
the best defender in all of Japan.
Virginia has improved
a lot as well.
Her game may be a bit brutal,
but her spikes come down like cannonballs.
It'll be an easy game!
Let's get them!
– The Russian team's awesome.
– It's like adults taking ball from children.
Yes, compared with Soviets,
it's not just the Mexicans.
Every team we've seen
so far is like that.
Especially their captain.
She's a brilliant attacker.
She has a tremendous power
when she gets to the front line.
Brilliant attacker, my butt.
I won't lose to the Soviets.
I'll beat them up alone
with my time lag attack.
Ayuhara-san,
I'm counting on you.
Sure thing.
This time, Kiyama-san's strong
personality is very helpful.
But Shellenina still hasn't come out,
even though the match started long ago.
Now that I think of it,
she hasn't shown up on practices, either.
Shellenina…
What's going on?
Are you sick? Or maybe,
touching wood, you had an accident?
I was looking forward so much
to meeting with you on the court.
We're playing against
Italy right after.
When the first set is over,
please come down to the waiting room.
– Yes sir.
Češka from Czechoslovakia.
Virginia from America.
Manumba from Kenya.
My friends from the Junior World Championships
are here, doing their best not to lose to their seniors.
I won't lose either.
I, too, will show a beautiful play
that won't embarrass anyone in my team.
Manumba!
Get some stretchers!
Hurry up!
Manumba…
Manumba.
Manumba!
Manumba…
Doctor!
Dr. Mihara!
I'm sorry, but I need you
to come with me. Please hurry.
Manumba, the captain of the Kenyan team,
has collapsed. Another player filled for her.
The match is resumed.
You'll feel better soon.
Nchi yangu Kenya.
"Hail Kenya".
I'll bet she'll want to go back on the court.
Nchi yangu K-Ken—
Manumba, you're awake!
Thank goodness.
You're…
Yes. I'm Ayuhara Kozue.
We got to know each other in the USA.
So I have collapsed, after all.
I've given you a shot just in case,
so you'll be fine.
The climate here in Balkans is very different
from the one you're used to in Africa.
I'm glad it turned out
to be nothing serious.
Please be patient.
The syringe needs about
20-30 minutes to work.
You just feel a bit weak
from all that tension.
I'll go take a look
how your game goes.
It's bad, isn't it?
But all will play out well
when you come out.
I still vividly remember
Manumba on that day.
Nchi yangu Kenya.
Nchi yangu Kenya!
I've never met anyone
with your determination.
I can't even imagine how much
you must want to be there now.
Especially here,
at the World Championships.
Her pulse has
settled down quite a bit.
Is it okay for her to go out now?
But I can't guarantee that
she won't collapse again during the game.
I'm sure she'll go. Her team is
more important to her than anything.
I'll continue to rest here.
Manumba…
Why aren't you going to play?
We didn't have reserve players
during the Junior Championships.
I couldn't withdraw from the game
even when I was injured.
But this time it is different.
Different?
We have a lot of other players
that are more talented than I am.
But your team has lost only a few points so far.
The morale would skyrocket if you went back.
I want to go out so much that I'd be happy
even if I fell over dead on the court.
Then why?
The Kenyan team has great players.
The only thing missing from this team is harmony.
But when I fainted that time…
– Manumba…
– Manumba!
Manumba!
Manumba, hang in there!
Keep together!
Help each other!
Let's do it for Manumba.
For our motherland Kenya.
Yeah!
Everyone became really passionate
and began to try to become one team.
They actively tried to achieve harmony, whereas
I only bothered them with my sloppy play.
Then again, if I collapsed once more,
it'd mean a definite end to all of our hopes.
That's why I'm going to remain here,
even though it's killing me.
For the good of the team
and their future.
For the good of the team…
For the good of the team.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we're connected live from Bulgaria…
…to transmit the 1971 Women's
World Volleyball Championships.
The first match between Japan and Italy
will begins in a few minutes.
Just a while ago, we saw a match
between Kenya and Hungary.
Kenya put up a ferocious fight, however
Hungary ended up winning 3 to 2.
Let's go back
to our Japanese team.
How will their first match go?
It is almost time for the game to start.
Hang in there, Kozue!
These are the World Championships
I dreamed for so long about… and now I'm here.
I am a member of the
Japanese national team.
I'll do my best.
Manumba, Virginia. Be ready.
I'll give you a lot of trouble.
Out!
Another failed time lag
attack from Kiyama!
Furumoto-san!
4 to 0. Japan seems to be unable
to pick up the pace.
Yagisawa throws a feint!
A chance for Japan!
Matsuyama's in good position!
Yet another point for Italy.
They're leading us by the noses.
What's wrong, All-Japan?
Another feint from Yagisawa!
Now's your chance, Japan!
A mistake you don't often see.
Matsuyama and Kiyama
reached for the ball at the same time.
It was clearly Captain's.
Kiyama-san's played
selfishly again.
Things look not so great
for the Japanese team.
As we have seen in the last inharmonious play,
the Japanese team is obviously failing in teamwork.
We're completely losing against Italy,
who no one considered to be a very strong enemy.
The question remains:
what's going on?
Coach Inokuma has explicitly stated
his training focus was on the teamwork.
What's going on, then?
There's no sense of team at all.
Everyone seems to plays however they want.
This can seriously jeopardize
the result of the match.
Another mistake from Kiyama!
It's a set point for Italy!
Come on!
One last push!
– Yeah!
– We did it!
– Bravo!
Japan loses the first set.
Thank you.
Coach, why won't you let
Ayuhara-san on the court?
With Ayuhara-san's toss,
my time lag attack will surely work out.
Please let Ayuhara-san play
in the second set.
My time lag attack is the only thing
that will get us out of this mess.
Coach, I'm asking you as well.
Ayuhara-san has
her tornado drop.
We could make some points with it
and slowly find our way back to our rhythm.
Then we could win the second set,
and who knows, maybe even the entire game.
Is that all you have to say, girls?
Huh?
To make it very clear, I have
no intention of any player changes.
Not in the second set,
and neither in the third.
But, Coach, if by any chance
we lose this game…
Even if it means losing,
I will not change players.
The second set is about to start.
Japan falls short of the expectations again
and lets Italy take the lead in the second set as well.
The situation is completely inconceivable.
The Japanese team is playing worse and worse.
On top of it, Coach Inokuma obviously doesn't seem
to have any intention to do any player rotations.
Coach Inokuma…
Why don't you shift us?
I can assist Kiyama-san's
time lag attack with my toss.
Besides, I have my tornado drop, which
no one has been able to receive so far.
It took so long and I had to make
so much effort to invent it.
If it turns out that we lose today, I'll have to
go home without ever getting the chance to play.
Japan loses
the second set as well.
Manumba could've been
on the court, if she wanted to.
But I can not play
even if I wanted.
I don't want to suffer
like Manumba did.
These are the famous
World Championships.
I'm so close to it, just a few meters from the court,
and I have to watch it from the bench…
Why doesn't the coach
let me play?
It's the third set and it's
10 to 3 for Italy already.
If we lose also this set, we'll have
to fly home right after the first match.
Japan is backed into a corner.
Backed into a corner.
Backed into a corner…
Matsuyama feints!
Even though Kiyama collided with Matsuyama,
she managed to get a point with a powerful spike.
An emotional blow!
Kiyama-san.
Alright!
You can do this, Kiyama!
Kiyama!
– Kiyama!
– Good luck, Kiyama!
Hang in there!
Assume positions.
In volleyball, the team
is the most important.
You need to do
everything for its sake.
The teamwork is the most important
and yet I tried to play solo all along.
I trained so hard for this day,
for the World Championships.
We can't lose in the first game.
Captain, let's do this.
The time lag attack.
– You'll be my assist.
– Okay.
Matsuyama · Kiyama duo's
time lag attack scores a point!
The girls have finally started to work together
and managed to synchronize their actions.
The Italian defense is in chaos.
A service point for Japan!
Looks like they've started
to get back to their rhythm.
This time it's a point
from Kiyama · Yagisawa's duo play.
Japan slowly reduces
the difference in points.
Italy attacks.
What a powerful spike!
But Iwatani receives!
Matsuyama's brilliant feint
works out!
The Japanese team has
truly become one unit.
The Italian team
is completely powerless.
Now I understand
Coach Inokuma's plan.
Kiyama-san and I got along eventually,
but one can't say the same about the other players.
He's driven us into this hopeless situation
on purpose, to restore the unity within the team.
He wanted us to play
with all we've got under high pressure.
The unity of the team.
For the team.
I finally understand
Manumba's feelings.
She must've been in a terrible pain,
but it was all about the future of the team.
For the people in my team.
Everything for the sake of my team.
For the team!
The first match after the qualifying round.
Japan plays against German Democratic Republic.
Kozue is still worried
about Shellenina's absence.
Inokuma lets Kozue play
for the first time.
His plan is to break East Germany
in one go with Kozue's tornado drop.
However, Kozue's first game
proves disappointing.
Inokuma, unable to watch it any longer,
announces player rotation.
Please look forward
to the next episode!
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.