苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 098—
The first match
Whoa, awesome.
The Soviets' captain sure knows her business.
Tomorrow, the Russians will most likely
emerge from the elimination phase.
I wonder how
the Japanese will be doing.
It'll be difficult considering
the iron defense of the Soviet team.
Even if you ignore their block,
their defense formation is perfect.
They'll simply take the ball and
play it back with their hellish spike.
No matter how you look at it,
winning with them will be very difficult…
What strategy do you think
the Japanese will use?
Okano-san.
It was terribly boring.
Huh?
What was?
The training of the Russian team
was completely boring.
Neither their blocks nor their attacks
changed in any way.
Nothing was new at all.
What does that mean?
Uh, I can't tell that either.
Oh, that's no fun.
I'm going for a walk.
Err, but which photos
are we going to take in the end?
I don't know.
Choose some good ones.
O-Okano-san!
Tsk. The Russians' game wasn't fun?
I don't understand him at all.
Inokuma-san,
do you have a moment?
Go ahead.
To win the World Championships this year,
sooner or later you'll have to beat the Russians.
So, Inokuma-san, what is
your impression of the Russian team?
It's an outstanding team.
Is that all you have to say?
Yes. I don't know
what else to tell you.
Say, Inokuma-san. Do you know
why Shellenina hasn't appeared yet?
No. How would I know that?
Don't you think that there's
something fishy about it?
It's possible…
The Russians wouldn't
tell us anything.
There's been no news about
any accidents or illness either.
So there must be
something behind it.
Besides, there's no way they'd play in the same
lineup without any changes in their strategy.
Can we finish, now?
Huh?
It's about time
to take care of the training.
Inokuma-san.
The Soviet Union seems to be conducting
thorough research on the Japanese team.
Are you not interested in knowing
why Shellenina hasn't arrived yet?
It's no use to come up
with empty hypotheses.
– Matsuyama, I'll take over.
– Yes sir.
Is he keeping secrets from us?
Or did he see through his opponent's actions
and develops a plan on his own?
You have to be faster than that!
Ayuhara, redo!
Ah, now I see!
Inokuma-san hasn't used
Ayuhara-san in the qualifiers, either.
So that's how it is…
We still have some time
before the lunch.
Let's get some fresh air.
– Okay.
It's so peaceful.
Yeah…
When we're like this, the idea of people gathering
from all over the world to play volleyball here…
…sounds like a distant dream.
Yeah.
But that feeling
will be gone by tomorrow.
Tomorrow it's our first match out of qualifiers.
The real thing starts now.
Yes.
Ayuhara-kun.
Yes?
Do you need anything from me?
I'm Okano from
the Nippon Sports.
I would like to talk
to you for a bit.
Talk to me?
I'd like your comment as the only
high school student on the team.
I just talked to Mihara-san
and she said it's okay to ask.
I'd also like to take some pictures.
What do you say?
Sure.
When are you going
to play, Ayuhara-kun?
Huh?
It's already decided, isn't it?
No, I don't know
anything about that.
You can tell me the truth.
I promise you that I won't leak any confidential
information until you give me permission to.
W-What are you talking about?
I'm talking about when did
the coach said you'll play.
You can tell me.
He hasn't told me yet.
Really?
Really!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
It's not that I don't believe you.
I understand… So your coach so far
has been keeping you in the dark.
What is this all about?
Hmm…
Have a sit.
I heard you've developed
a new technique in Hokkaidō.
That's correct.
We've heard of its name,
the "tornado drop".
But no one has seen it.
We can only imagine
how it looks like from its name.
– Same goes for the Soviet Union.
– The Soviet Union?
The Soviet Union keeps a record
of each game of the Japanese team.
They also collect thorough information
about every one of your players.
Huh? They go that far?
It's only natural considering they're after gold
in the upcoming Olympics.
Their coach has formed
new tactics based on that.
In fact, every one of their players has
a printed copy of all the data on you…
…and actively use it
during their training.
But the Soviet Union is still not sure
what your tornado drop is, just like we are.
That's why I think you're
our secret weapon.
Come again?
Ayuhara-kun.
You're Japan's weapon
against the Soviet Union.
Me? Don't be ridiculous.
I'm pretty sure of it.
I firmly believe
that's your coach strategy.
Of course, the Soviet Union
has their own secret weapon.
The Soviet Union too?
Yes. It's Shellenina.
Shellenina?
No one has seen
Shellenina so far.
I'll bet she's in the middle
of training now.
It's already obvious from the qualifiers that the final
match will be between Japan and the Soviet Union.
That's when the secret weapons
will decide everything.
The headline on the day
before the finals will be…
The Japanese secret weapon, Ayuhara Kozue,
vs. the Soviet Union's Shellenina.
It'll be a very powerful clash.
Do your best, Ayuhara-kun.
You are Japan's secret weapon.
Well, then.
I'm Japan's secret weapon…
Tomorrow begins the real thing.
Our goal is to beat
the Russian team.
But before we reach that, we need to beat some
other teams such as Czechoslovakia, for instance.
I urge you to give your best in every match,
no matter who it's against. Is that clear?
– Yes sir.
Today's meeting is over.
Get a good rest tonight.
– Yes sir.
– Good night, sir.
Coach.
What?
Is something the matter?
No, never mind.
Good night.
I'm a secret weapon
to be used against the Soviets.
And Shellenina is also
a secret weapon.
Shellenina!
Ladies and gentlemen, we're
broadcasting live from Sofia, Bulgaria.
The games for the World Championships
will take place for the next five days.
In the first game Czechoslovakia
won 3 to 0 against Romania.
The second match is Japan vs. East Germany.
The third match is USSR against USA.
Yesterday, the Japanese men's team
made it out of the qualifiers as anticipated.
How far will our girls go, with strong opponents
such as Czechoslovakia or the Soviet Union?
The second match, Japan vs.
German Democratic Republic, is about to begin.
Matsuyama!
Sir!
Yamagami!
Sir.
Iwatani!
Sir!
Kiyama. Furumoto!
Sir.
Ayuhara!
Ayuhara, are you listening?
S-Sir.
You six will play in today's game.
– Yes sir.
Ayuhara. Try to take it easy.
Yes sir.
Alright, it's our first match
on the road of victory!
Go get them!
– Yes sir!
Oh? Wasn't Ayuhara supposed to be
saved until the game against the Soviets?
Why'd he make her
play so soon?
She was Japan's only trump card
against the best Russian player, Shellenina.
What does that mean?
Fight!
Fight, fight!
Fight, Japan!
Fight!
Let's go, Ayuhara-san.
Y-Yes, Captain.
It'll be fine, Ayuhara-san.
The Japanese team used the rookie
Ayuhara Kozue in their starting lineup.
She was No. 1 in the high school volleyball world
and it's her first appearance in the tournament.
She's a very promising player.
Why did the coach decide
to let me play?
He hasn't told me anything at all.
All of the sudden, just like that.
Calm down.
Yes.
It's completely different
than you said, Okano-san.
I don't understand.
What is Coach Inokuma thinking?
To let Ayuhara play
right off the bat…
Maybe you're
getting old, Okano-san?
Your prediction about Ayuhara Kozue
being some secret weapon seems to be way off.
Do you really have
to talk so much?
You just need to keep quiet
and take photos.
Aye, aye, boss.
What is going on?
Ayuhara-san.
They've marked you.
I have to calm down.
I see. Ayuhara is nervous.
He let her play for her to get used
to this court and the games here.
If she was nervous in the game against
the Russians, she wouldn't be of any use.
We have an advantage in speed.
We'll keep them
under continuous attack.
Ayuhara-san, you don't have
to worry about anything.
Okay.
I know it's hard in the first game,
but just try to relax.
Okay.
Alright! Let's go!
– Yeah!
I didn't think I'd get so nervous.
But it feels completely different
from the Junior Championships.
Even though it's just
our first match.
Fight!
– Yeah!
Now I understand. The coach
wants me to get used to this place.
He didn't tell me anything,
but Captain seems to be aware.
I have to calm down.
Relax all that tension.
Now's the chance!
I'm sorry.
Don't mind,
don't mind.
Ayuhara-san is still
tense, isn't she?
No, she just wanted
to let Iwatani accept the ball.
She plays more relaxed, but has
no courage to run after the ball yet.
Why do you think is that?
Geez, that Ayuhara…
She's thinking too much.
Damn, I panicked
and missed the ball.
After the coach has let me play
precisely to get me used to the game…
This isn't good.
I have to calm down.
Now!
Alright, let's finish this!
I guess Germany doesn't
pose a threat to us.
Our goal is still
the Soviet Union.
I'll show my tornado drop
when we're up against them.
But until that match,
I'll keep it a secret.
Ayuhara-san, it's yours!
Huh?
The tornado drop?
No way… It was supposed
to be our trump card.
A trump card…
Now!
Ayuhara-san!
Captain wants
my tornado drop…
But it makes no sense!
Ayuhara-san!
Ayuhara has narrowly
reflected the ball.
Another chance for Germany.
Captain wants me to play
my tornado drop.
What's going on?
I'm here to get used to the court. I was supposed
to use it only in the game against the Russians.
Player change!
Yagisawa!
Switch with Ayuhara.
Yes sir.
Ayuhara played you well.
Look, she's taken off.
That's good.
How so?
That's for the best.
Everything goes according
to Inokuma-san's plan.
Eh, I wouldn't be
so sure about that.
I wonder if the coach wanted me
to play the tornado drop as well.
No, it's not possible.
If that's the case, my technique
will no longer be a secret.
Therefore, no longer effective
against Shellenina's own techniques.
But…
But maybe the coach
has something else in mind.
The Japanese take
the first set with ease.
It appears that the second set
won't be a problem, either.
In the first match,
Czechoslovakia won 3 to 0.
In the second game, Japan won
3 to 0 against German Democratic Republic.
The third game is between USA and the Soviet Union.
So far the Russians have the upper hand.
Let's take a look
at the game.
They blocked it perfectly.
We'll have to work hard,
if we want to defeat them.
Whoa, awesome.
They don't stand a chance against
such a jumping power and powerful plays.
Oh, sports channel?
But you've seen it live
already, haven't you?
Yes.
But even if we watch it many times,
we can still learn something new.
Americans have completely lost.
Really. The Russians
are incredibly strong.
But you've won with East Germany
3 to 0 yourselves, haven't you?
I made cookies for you.
Help yourselves.
– Thanks.
– Thank you.
The Russian team
has a tremendous power.
Ah, a spike!
And it scores.
It's become a truly one-sided game.
Ayuhara!
Oh?
Coach.
You're up for the game
against Romania tomorrow as well.
Huh?
What is it, Ayuhara?
But… wasn't I…
What?
Ayuhara. Why didn't you
play the tornado drop today?
Wasn't it supposed to be our secret weapon
against the Soviet Union?
You fool!
Don't get cocky!
The World Championships
don't work like that!
The very purpose of putting you up for today
was to let you play your tornado drop!
Don't you get it?!
I want you to use it during
the entire game tomorrow. Got that?
Yes sir.
Ayuhara.
You seem to be worried about Shellenina.
Worrying won't do us any good, though.
There's no reason for us
to keep your tornado drop a secret.
Yes sir.
We have to put forth all our power
in every single game.
That's the only way to do it.
Yes, you need
to know your opponent.
But once you start sinking into fears
of what you cannot predict, you've already lost.
Fear not!
Do what you know best!
Yes sir!
I'll do my best tomorrow.
Today's opponent of the Japanese
Women's Team is Romania.
It's the youngest team
among the participants.
They've made a great progress
over the last year.
How is Japanese team planning
to fight the Romanian team?
Ayuhara-kun!
Yo.
Ah, Yushima-san.
I was watching your game
on the TV yesterday.
Yesterday I…
Just do your best today.
Forget about things from yesterday
and have confidence in yourself.
In your tornado drop.
Yes. See you later.
I'll be watching you
from the stands.
Okano-san!
What are you so excited about?
She's here. Shellenina's here.
See? Look, over there.
What?!
Shellenina.
You've finally made your appearance.
Oh? Shellenina!
Fear not.
Keep on striking.
Ayuhara-kun.
Have confidence in yourself.
In your tornado drop.
Kozue's tornado drop
bursts on the court.
The Romanian team stands
no chance against it.
Kozue's actions bring the
All-Japan team a win by a shutout.
However, one girl in the audience looks coldly
at pleased with herself Kozue.
That girl is Shellenina.
"I won't lose to Ayuhara."
The reason for her late appearance
is a secret special training.
Kozue is struck with fear.
Just what is Shellenina's
secret weapon?
Please look forward
to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.