苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 099—
The Birth of a New Heroine
It's the fifth day of the Volleyball World Championships
here in the International Sports Hall in Bulgaria.
The second day of the finals opens with
the match between Japan and the Romanian team.
But just as a reminder, our own national team
defeated East Germany yesterday.
This match, however, will begin very soon.
Ayuhara.
Sir?
Remember what I told you.
Yes sir.
Let's go!
– Yeah!
– Yeah.
As expected, Coach Inokuma is
using Ayuhara from the start today, too.
Ayuhara?
I could've sworn she was going to be
the secret weapon against the Russian team…
I don't get any of this.
Even Shellenina's finally shown up today, too.
Why even bother speculating at this point?
Ayuhara-san, before I greet you,
show me how much you've improved.
Fight!
– Yeah!
Every opponent in this group
must be taken seriously.
We can't afford to keep
the tornado drop for later.
I'll score a lot today.
With my tornado drop.
What's wrong, Japan!?
Kiyama touched the ball
with her palm.
Don't mind it,
don't mind it.
Don't let it get to you.
We can do it!
– Yeah!
Good luck!
Now it's Japan's turn to attack.
I'm looking forward to your
tornado drop, Ayuhara-kun.
That's right.
I can't disappoint Yushima-san.
Keep calm, Kozue.
Furumoto's skillful curve ball spike
scores Japan a point. Now it's tied 1 to 1.
Hopefully, the Japanese team will seize
this opportunity and take the lead.
Ayuhara-san!
Yes! The tornado drop!
Ayuhara hits the ball hard,
but it takes the wrong direction!
It's a point!
Though it seemed like a complete failure, the ball
miraculously turned back midair and hit the court.
Ladies and gentlemen, this is it!
Ayuhara Kozue's famous tornado drop!
You did it!
Y-Yeah!
I did it.
My tornado drop worked.
I knew you would succeed.
With this attack, no one
stands a chance against you.
I'll show you. I'll play
the tornado drop as often as necessary.
Romania misses the ball.
Ayuhara's astonishing technique
is wreaking havoc on their team.
We have to make sure that
they don't find their rhythm again.
Ayuhara-san!
Tornado drop!
Another tornado drop!
Good. Keep it up.
Time!
Finally, the coach of the
Romanian team asks for time.
Indeed, Ayuhara's tornado drop
is very impressive.
It might even be strong enough
to penetrate the iron wall of the Russian team.
Our block is useless
against an attack like that.
There's more.
Even the second line defense can't do much.
It's impossible to predict where the ball will land.
And on top of that,
the ball even seems to be rotating.
Don't worry.
I'm sure I can receive it.
Shellenina, we know you've trained
with the troupe in Bolshoi Circus, but…
Yes. I stayed at the training school
affiliated with the circus until yesterday.
And I've learned a lot of things.
But my training was based
on a precise plan.
I've worked hard to become
a secret weapon against Japan.
I trained with Borchinskaya,
and learned to receive her killer spikes.
I know the results of my tough training will bear fruit
during our final game against Japan.
Ayuhara-san, now I see that
my training hasn't gone to waste.
You mustn't let up yet, Ayuhara.
Keep playing your tornado drop
whenever you've got a chance to.
That way, we'll seize the game.
They won't be able to regain
their rhythm and the match will be ours.
Alright, go!
– Yes sir.
The match has resumed.
Shellenina!
Shellenina finally showed up.
It must be just like the rumors said.
A secret weapon that targets us exclusively.
Ayuhara-san!
A chance for my tornado drop!
That's right.
No need to keep it a secret.
Ayuhara!
Another tornado drop!
The game is completely
one-sided in Japan's favor.
And the Romanian team
has become totally helpless.
Iwatani receives!
Yamagami tosses! Matsuyama spikes!
And it scores.
That's a set point for Japan.
The server is Ayuhara.
Huh? Even when I serve?
Alright! Let's try it.
The tornado drop serve.
They did it!
Japan scored the set point.
Godspeed, All-Japan!
It's a truly extraordinary technique,
the tornado drop serve!
And Japan wins the second set.
Good work, Ayuhara-san.
I'm so happy that my
tornado drop is such a success.
You know, I was a bit worried,
but that service was absolutely great.
Alright!
Keep this up and beat Romania
by a shutout. Got that?
– Yes sir.
I admit, it's extraordinary.
But it takes more
than that to beat me.
Shellenina…
Japan is also in the lead
in the third set.
Ayuhara plays
yet another tornado drop.
And it went in!
The match is over.
Godspeed, All-Japan!
Japan, Japan!
Japan!
Congrats, Japan!
My compliments, Ayuhara Kozue.
Every time I see you, you play better and better.
Ladies and gentlemen, our national team
has won 3 to 0 against Romania.
We can truly say that today a new heroine
in the volleyball world was born.
That heroine is Ayuhara Kozue,
the youngest player on the team.
Her tornado drop
seems impossible.
And yet she kept spiking it,
and even served one at the end.
The player No. 12 has single-handedly
defeated the Romanian team.
Today a new star has entered
the firmament of the sport.
And she seems intent
on winning the final match.
You did a really good job,
Ayuhara-san.
But spikes and serves alone
will not work against me.
Miss Shellenina.
Oh? Are you a Japanese
newspaper reporter?
If you don't mind,
I'd like to ask for a little interview.
With me? Why not with Ayuhara-san,
the superstar of today's match?
– Miss Ayuhara.
– Yes?
We'd like to ask you
about your tornado drop.
– Please.
– Okay.
Are you planning to use it
against the Russians as well?
Y-Yes.
Do you think it can go around
their impenetrable block?
Yes. I think it can.
– Thank you, Miss Ayuhara.
– Thanks.
Yushima-san!
Yo.
Ayuhara-kun,
you played magnificently today.
Thank you.
Though I was sort of in a trance.
That's good.
Lose yourself
and keep hitting the ball.
There's a goddess of a victory
waiting for you after that.
Keep it up.
See you next time.
Yushima-san!
Hm?
I'll walk you to the bus.
Huh?
I just have to tell the coach.
I'll be right back.
That was generous of Coach Inokuma
to let you go just like that.
He said today is an exception.
He even told me to forget
about today's game.
Forget about the game?
Yes. But I'm just walking you
to the bust stop.
Coach, that sly old fox. Right?
Yushima-san,
is something wrong?
Did I make you upset?
No.
Don't you realize it?
Huh?
The meaning
of your coach's words.
"Forget about today's match."
They're harsh, fearful words.
Ah!
He's right. If you savor small victories,
you'll end up losing in the future for sure.
My tornado drop
will be defeated.
Yes.
Didn't I tell you that every attack
will be defeated some day?
My tornado drop is no exception...
And here I was, finally allowed
to demonstrate that power in practice…
Yushima-san.
Please tell me.
What… What should I do now?
I don't know, either.
To tell you the truth, I'm scared.
Don't worry too much.
Yes. My tornado drop
won't be so easy to receive.
I'll play it a lot tomorrow as well.
Yeah. That's the spirit.
If they defeat your tornado drop, you just
have to invent an even more powerful spike.
I know you can do it.
See you.
Good luck.
Thanks for walking me.
Yes. They won't receive
my tornado drop so easily.
I better go back now
and start exercising.
Ayuhara-san.
Oh?
Long time no see.
Shellenina! I would've been so disappointed
if you hadn't shown up here.
Your game today
was truly remarkable.
And that spike of yours?
It was wonderful, so powerful.
Thank you. I'm very happy
to hear praise from you.
Don't celebrate just yet.
Huh?
Ayuhara-san. This is for your ears only, but I'm
a secret weapon for the match against Japan.
I knew it!
Do you remember Borchinskaya
and her killer spikes?
Y-Yes.
A superhuman spike
that no one was able to receive.
I made her killer spike
a tool for my training.
A tool for your training?
Yes.
Also, I promise you today that
I'll definitely defeat your tornado drop.
And I'm praying for your success in your game
against Czechoslovakia tomorrow.
Let 's fight together
for the overall victory in the finals.
До свидания.
Shellenina…
You've grown so much since the last time I saw you
in the Junior High World Championships.
I know that you
don't make empty promises.
You'll receive my tornado drop.
Shellenina!
Oh, it's you, Okano-san.
Hello.
Something reached my ear
and I decided to come here.
Is it about Shellenina?
You already know it, Coach?
No. Please continue.
Well, she received special training
at the Bolshoi Circus Training Center.
It was targeted
for the match against Japan.
What did she train?
Not even the Soviets' reporters
seem to know anything about it.
Only that it wasn't a normal volleyball training,
but rather an acrobatic training.
So she'll play
like a circus acrobat.
Yes, I think so.
I'll let you know
if I discover anything new.
Thanks, Okano-san.
You're welcome.
Circus.
It might mean attacks
as well as defenses.
The tornado drop might really stay effective
only up to the game with Czechoslovakia.
All new things
have a short lifespan.
This also applies
to volleyball, unfortunately.
If it's not good enough,
create a new one.
I know you can do it.
Ah, I don't know
anything else.
But it's best not to think
for too long.
Tomorrow is the game against Czechoslovakia.
And I'll be playing tornado drops all the way through.
That's what I should focus on.
The final group.
Czechoslovakia vs. Japan.
Both of the very talented teams
are lined up in front of each other.
On one side, there's the Japanese team, whose
tornado drop literally destroyed Romania yesterday.
And on the other side, the Czechoslovakian team with their
impregnable block on par with the Russians'.
And, above all, the new addition to their team,
Češka, plays excellent, violent spikes.
It's sure to be a truly difficult game.
The Japanese team
kept Ayuhara from yesterday.
And it seems Czechoslovakia let their rookie,
Češka, play as well. The match is started.
Shellenina is watching us.
She's going to research
us thoroughly.
Fine by me.
I'll play a lot of my tornado drops today.
Even if that's
the last thing I'm going to do.
Češka!
Fantastic, Češka.
You are no worse
than Shellenina.
Ayuhara-san, you should concentrate
less on me and more on Češka.
Czechoslovakia blocks!
Thanks to Češka's fine play,
the Japanese team loses a point.
Češka!
There it is!
Češka's fearsome spike.
It's no less astonishing
than the tornado drop.
Good, Češka.
I'll respond with my tornado drop.
Ayuhara-san, here we go!
Here it is!
The tornado drop!
It didn't score?!
Sh-Shellenina and Češka
have seen through me.
At this rate, my tornado drop…
The mysterious challenge
of Shellenina worries Kozue.
In the match against Czechoslovakia, she makes
more and more mistakes in her tornado drop plays.
Finally, Kozue gets switched.
The Czech team turns out to be stronger
than expected.
Češka's flick spike, in particular, puts Japan in a crisis.
Kozue, back on the court with a new passion,
starts attacking again using her tornado drop.
But there is no more time.
Češka's direct spike aims at Kozue.
Please look forward
to the next episode!
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.