苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 100—
The tornado drop at risk
It… It didn't score?
Ayuhara-san, your
tornado drop just didn't score.
What is going on?
Sh-Shellenina and Češka
have seen through me.
At this rate, my tornado drop…
Ayuhara-san's tornado drop
doesn't work, so she gets nervous.
Češka's tried to break Ayuhara-san's rhythm
with her play, and it worked very well.
H-Hurry up and change me.
No, I have to stay strong.
But what can I do?
Ayuhara's no good.
Yeah. It's about time
they changed her.
Time!
Ayuhara.
I knew it.
He's going to change me.
We'll keep using your tornado drop.
Do you understand?
Huh?
The Czechs started
to find their way through.
If we don't do anything now,
we'll keep losing one point after another.
I don't see any better means
than your tornado drop.
Got that, Ayuhara?
But…
– Go!
– Yes sir! – Yes sir!
Ayuhara-san.
I promise you that
I'll defeat your tornado drop.
Oh? Ayuhara's going
back on the court.
What does that mean?
I don't know.
Ayuhara-san.
Y-Yes?
Good luck.
Thanks.
Ayuhara-san!
Leave it!
Tornado drop.
Oh, no.
Ayuhara, get a grip!
It's getting worse and worse.
Ayuhara's poor performance
also affects Kiyama's time lag attack.
Hang in there, Ayuhara-kun.
Ayuhara-san, chance!
Ayuhara-san.
It won't work like that.
You're not focused, Ayuhara.
Ayuhara-san, you're hesitating.
Yushima-san.
If your tornado drop turns out
not good enough, just create a new attack.
I know you can do it.
I… I don't think I can.
Ayuhara-san!
It's the set point already.
What is Coach Inokuma
thinking, really?
No! The tornado drop
won't work like that!
What's wrong, Ayuhara-san?
What a mess.
Really? 15 to 3?
Even if they manage to get over today,
the Soviets will annihilate them.
No, there's something.
There must be something.
What do you mean?
What something?
If I knew the answer,
I'd be a coach and not a reporter.
Huh?
One thing I'm pretty sure of is that they'll
give up on the tornado drop in the second set.
Listen up.
We'll keep using the tornado drop
in this set as well.
– Huh?!
C-Coach, but…
But what?
W-Well, Shellenina…
Are you afraid of Shellenina?
Yes. She terrifies me.
I can't even imagine
what techniques she'll bring to the table.
That alone makes me so scared,
it's almost paralyzing.
That's why I've been thinking of creating a new spike,
something else from the tornado drop altogether.
But I simply can't.
This is why I'm asking you
to save the tornado drop for the finals.
Ayuhara!
Stop overthinking!
I'm your coach.
Thinking up strategies is my job.
You only need
to follow my instructions.
Ayuhara-kun, keep playing
your tornado drop.
What have you worked so hard for?
What happened to your spike?
But what should I do?
I'm telling you,
I can't invent yet another technique.
If they defeated
my tornado drop now…
Are you so afraid that I'll see it?
Just because I'm watching,
you can't use your secret weapon?
I don't think I can face
Shellenina anymore.
Now, go!
– Yes sir!
Shellenina.
Oh? Ayuhara's still playing. Look.
Yeah.
Time to get serious!
– Yeah!
– Ayuhara-san, you can do it!
Yes.
Ayuhara. You have the chance to become
the star of this World Championship.
But to become a world-wide star,
I need to win against Shellenina.
Ayuhara-san!
Another failure. It doesn't work out
no matter how hard I try.
This time!
Ayuhara-san, this time!
Ready?
No! Stop! Ayuhara!
Watch out!
Ayuhara…
Time!
Coach, I think Ayuhara-san
has had enough.
Češka will go back
to attacking soon.
If we can't come up with
something quickly, we have lost.
I think Matsuyama-san's spike and Kiyama-san's
time lag attack are our greatest hope.
Calm down. I think this set
is the turning point.
The Czechs probably
think the same.
Which is why they fight
like there's no tomorrow.
It's a problem for us, but it shows that
their offense is not only limited to Češka's spike.
If it wasn't for Ayuhara's slump,
I'd probably realize it sooner.
I guess I have no choice.
Finally he switches some players.
Looks like Yagisawa and Ayuhara
are switched by Yamagami and Shimamoto.
It's for the best.
Ayuhara-san, pulling you away
is exactly what Češka wanted.
I bet that it wasn't an easy decision
for Inokuma-senpai to pull her away.
Finally they've jumped
back on their feet.
If he had replaced them earlier,
we'd be better off now.
Ayuhara-san.
Yes?
Do you know why Coach insisted on
pulling through with your tornado drop?
Isn't it because they're stronger
than we had anticipated?
Yes, there's that, too.
Yes, but wanna know
what I really think it was about?
If you use your secret weapon, the tornado drop,
in front of Shellenina, it's not so secret anymore.
The coach decision to play it fully today
means he doesn't care about that.
Huh?
You just said something about creating
something even stronger. A new spike.
I think he understands you
more than you think.
I mean, isn't it the same as our time
at the training camp in Hokkaidō?
Coach Inokuma kept pressuring you until the last
minute, then finally the tornado drop was born.
That's our coach's
way of doing things.
Attack!
Coach… I'm at my limit.
Change the defense line!
Get a grip, Ayuhara.
But it's hopeless.
Stand up!
You're in the All-Japan team!
Don't be so soft!
It's been always like that.
The moment you used
the tornado drop on the court…
…you need to start thinking of a new spike
to use against the Soviets, whether you like it or not.
I think that's his goal.
One more thing,
while we have the time.
Since Coach Inokuma thinks
we need a new spike against the Russians…
…it means he thinks
the tornado drop won't be of any use.
No way.
I promise you that
I'll defeat your tornado drop.
My tornado drop
won't work against them at all?
It won't work against Shellenina?
No… I can't believe it.
Shellenina will defeat
my tornado drop?
Keep it up, girls!
Češka's back
on offensive position.
I'm afraid the tables will turn.
What was that?
It's just a fluke.
She lucked out.
That was Češka's reception.
A lucky shot?
No. It had nothing to do with luck.
Hmm… Awesome.
The trajectory is the same
as if she spiked it.
It's like the ball's possessed.
A possessed reception.
Coach, please let me
go on the court.
Please. My tornado drop will work
this time around, I guarantee it.
Coach, please.
Look closely at Češka's reception.
Maybe you can learn something.
Ayuhara-san.
It's the third set.
Ayuhara-kun,
you need to go out and play.
I'm sorry, Coach.
Don't be sorry. Aren't you happy
that we got to know Češka's reception?
Everything remains to be seen.
Ayuhara, you're up next!
Yes sir!
I'm sure that not even Češka will be able
to respond to your tornado drop.
We can win this!
I'll do it.
What? He put Ayuhara again?
Let's hope she's recovered,
otherwise we've already lost.
Shellenina…
She's looking forward to our match.
I want to play with Shellenina.
To accomplish that goal we have to win
against Czechoslovakia, no matter what.
Very well. I'll hit the tornado drop
and make it like a rainfall.
Ayuhara-san!
Over to you!
Ayuhara! Ayuhara!
Good.
– Good!
– Looking great!
Very good, my friend.
But it won't work against me.
Ayuhara sure has recovered.
We shouldn't have
any problems now.
Češka's nervous.
She can't receive
Ayuhara-san's tornado drop.
Her spike doesn't work either.
But maybe, just maybe, Češka
might find a way to break through it.
Japan owes most of its points
to Ayuhara-kun's tornado drop.
But I'm afraid
it won't last for long.
What if Češka finds a way
to defuse the tornado drop?
Ayuhara!
Češka finally realized it.
The way to deflect
the tornado drop.
Who would've guessed they
could beat the tornado drop.
Ayuhara.
S-Sir.
Don't play any more
tornado drops in the next set.
Huh?
We're going to fool Češka. Once Ayuhara jumps,
Kiyama and Matsuyama will strike in her place.
– Yes sir!
We'll see how far
we come with this plan.
A direct spike
triumphs over my tornado drop.
My tornado drop
lost to direct spikes…
Japan won the third set 15 to 2.
Then we won also
the fourth set 15 to 4.
It's going to be an easy game.
The fifth set is already ours, with the tornado drop.
How do you like this headline?
Huh?
"The Japanese tornado sweeps away
the Czechoslovakian team".
Finally, it's the fifth set.
I knew it!
As I imagined,
he's forbidden her to play it.
The deception strategy ends here.
What are you waiting for, Ayuhara?
Play the tornado drop already!
Time!
Ayuhara, play it.
Only two points left.
Score them with your tornado drop.
Ayuhara-san.
Ayuhara-kun, you've got no choice.
Play the tornado drop.
Here we go.
Don't touch it!
One more point.
Leave it!
Ayuhara-san, we did it…
Ayuhara! Ayuhara!
If Češka noticed it a little bit faster,
we'd be in their shoes today.
Ayuhara-san!
I can't use the tornado drop
against the Soviet Union anymore.
Yushima-san,
I still haven't found the new spike…
The magical tornado drop
is no longer effective.
Kozue always knew that this day would come,
but she did not expect it so quickly.
The match with Russia
is approaching fast.
Kozue works hard,
trying to develop a new technique.
However, the more she rushes it,
the worse things get.
Yushima comforts
and encourages Kozue.
He also has to face the Soviets
without a strategy.
He understands
Kozue's stress all too well.
Please look forward
to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.