苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 102—
A Trace of the Next Miracle Ball
The 1979 Volleyball World Championships
Men's Finals is in full swing.
And the Japanese and Russian teams are fighting for the right
to bring home the title of "champion".
Hang in there, Yushima-san!
It simply isn't working.
Yushima's famous quick attack bounces off
the Soviets' impenetrable wall, yet again.
His technique is said to be
the main weapon of the Japanese team.
But seeing how even that's failing,
things aren't looking pretty for the Japanese.
We're in deep trouble
if his quick attack doesn't work.
They should change their tactic
quickly if they want to win.
Yeah, before the Russians score
even more points.
Things are looking very bad.
The Japanese team is in turmoil.
Yet the Soviet team keeps gaining
an overwhelming advantage.
It's a set point for the Russians.
14 to 3. The disadvantage
is even worse than anticipated.
The Russian team is playing fantastic. Continuing
their streak after defeating East Germany.
The interaction between Captain Kraevsky,
Sinyavsky and Belyakov is just perfect.
A curve ball from Ivanov!
Japan seizes the ball!
Now's their chance!
Will Yushima do it this time?
Hang in there, Yushima-san!
He did it!
Damn! It was a trap?
Sinyavsky's double attack
has scored another point.
The Soviet Union wins the first set
with the score of 15 to 3.
What happens when Yushima-san's
quick attack is ineffective?
It's not just a matter of points. The Russians
have completely seen through his movements.
They're reading him, for sure.
They're reading Yushima-san's
movements like an open book.
No, it goes beyond that.
At that time…
I thought Yushima-san's spike
was going to score for sure.
But…
Damn!
It was a trap all along.
Not only did they predict his moves,
but they immediately organized a counterattack.
How are you going to play
in the second set, Yushima-san?
Unfortunately it's as you feared, Yushima. Your
quick attack poses no threat to the Russians.
Coach.
What are we going to do
about the second set?
For now, let's pull Yushima.
We won't use any particular
tactic in this set.
Abandon all the patterns.
Everyone, play however you like.
Within reason, of course.
Outa, you'll enter
in Yushima's place.
Show me what you can do, guys.
Good luck.
The second set begins.
Oh? Coach Hirata
pulls Yushima from the game.
Oh!?
Outa, who entered in Yushima's place, is new
on the team, but known for his powerful long spikes.
He replaces Yushima, whose calculated attacks
earned him the name of the best attacker in Japan.
What is Coach Hirata thinking,
replacing a player like that with a rookie?
Anyway, the game continues.
and Moriyama from Japan is about to serve.
He's famous for his
excellent curve ball serves.
His serves are known worldwide.
I'm really going to be surprised if the Russian team
can handle this so easily. Don't you agree?
Yeah.
A great play from Kraevsky!
He receives that difficult ball!
Good going!
Outa's brutal direct spike
has landed the Japanese a point!
He seems happy, but I know that deep inside
he must feel left behind and sad.
But that's Yushima-san.
He won't remain on that bench for long.
I'm sure he'll go back
on the court very soon.
The Japanese team starts
the second set with a ray of hope.
Moriyama serves the ball.
Now that the Japanese seem
to stand a chance, you need to take all the photos.
Look at yourself, Okano-san,
working your pencil like a madman.
Keep it up, Japan!
Outa-san is pretty capable.
They should've used him
from the get-go.
The second set is ours.
At this rate,
we'll win the third set, too.
I wouldn't be so certain.
– Huh?
What do you mean, Coach?
We have yet to see
the Soviet's response.
Excellent reception from Japan!
A lightning fast counterattack.
Outa gets hit by an
extremely powerful spike.
The Soviet's trio
strikes back furiously.
Having discovered Outa's weakness in receptions,
they mercilessly focus their attacks on him.
The Russians have caught up to the Japanese.
Hang in there, Japan!
A set point for the Russians!
And Japan loses
the second set as well.
At this rate Japan
will lose by a shutout.
Yushima-san.
Do something.
You have to do something.
I'm sure you'll go back
on the court soon.
With a new weapon.
Yushima-san.
The Japanese team has lost the second set.
They stand with their backs against the wall.
Still the game is not over yet.
Who will be the world champion: Japan or Russia?
Yushima-san.
Listen up, guys.
I just talked with Yushima.
We've established that his quick attack
is the only chance we've got.
If it keeps on as it is,
we'll play right into their hand.
Even if we lost both sets, we at least managed
to throw them off balance in the second set.
So that's the reason why you told us
to play however we want, Coach?
Yes.
And that's why you wanted Outa,
because his style is so different from Yushima-san's.
I see.
That's how it was.
That's right.
Of course, that wasn't the only reason.
With this decision, I also hoped
to score some points…
Anyhow, we'll focus on Yushima's
quick attack again in the third set.
Show them what we're made of.
– Yes sir.
One more thing, Yushima.
Even though our plan should work,
it probably will not work until the end.
The Russians will find a way to fend off
your spikes with their block, no mistake about it.
When that happens,
abandon the quick attack immediately.
Use something else.
I'm leaving the specifics to you.
Yes sir.
If we behave completely differently from what
the Russians expect, we may have a small chance.
But let's wait and see.
Let's do this.
Yeah.
Alright, go!
Wipe the floor with them!
– Yes sir!
– Fight!
Finally, the third set begins.
How will Japan use
Yushima's reentry?
There are no more
second chances!
Yushima-san's back.
I'm sure he'll fix this.
I know he can do it.
Great! Excellent saving.
Yushima's quick attack scores!
Great! Keep it up!
Good, Yushima.
Let's continue with it.
Yes, but how long will it work?
Good luck, Yushima-san.
Japanese team takes
the lead in the third set.
All thanks to Yushima's
trademarked quick attack.
The Russian team started to lash out at the Japanese
with their extremely effective time lag attacks.
Both teams fight hard
for every single point.
The audience is going crazy.
– You're doing great!
– Show them!
– Come on!
– Yushima-san, hang in there!
Keep it up!
We believe in you, Japan!
Yushima-san seems like a different
player now. He just keeps scoring.
But how long will his
technique stay effective?
It's 6 to 6.
Yet again, we've got a tie.
Japan must absolutely
defeat Russia in this set.
But the Soviets do not let up.
Once again Yushima's quick attack
bounces off the Russians' iron block.
The Russian block developed specifically
for Yushima, works impeccably once again.
Yushima-san…
Blocking that spike
adds even more power to it.
It's as if they spiked it themselves.
An iron block spike.
The stronger you attack it,
the worse it gets.
They're not just reading his moves,
they're using them against him.
But their power is so terrible.
Yushima-san.
Don't you have other tactics?
Yushima-san…
Oh, never mind...
Look close, Kozue-kun.
Look at my misery.
How defeated I am.
Look at what happened
when I didn't have any new weapon.
Please, at least make
the women's team win.
Accomplish what we couldn't.
I didn't have the time.
But you still have
one day, Kozue-kun.
That one day will decide the fate
of your tornado drop.
Kozue-kun.
Find a new weapon!
That's as far
as my quick attack goes.
I'm going to do as our coach said
and try something they expect, at least.
Look at me, Kozue-kun!
This is my last stand!
Fantastic! Yushima spiked the ball facing away
from the net, turning only at the last moment.
The Russians were stunned with this unorthodox
play and couldn't set up any kind of defense.
Does the Japanese team
still have a chance?
Yushima tries his
reversal quick attack once more!
But this time, he fails.
It worked once, but it's not so easy
to repeat a spike like that.
But if he perfected it, it could become an excellent
way to break that impregnable wall.
He twists his arm more and more.
Not just the arm. He hits the ball using his whole
body to discharge as much energy as possible.
This gives a fantastic
trajectory to the ball.
On top of it, he's able to make it a curve ball
without giving the ball a spin.
If I could do something that
with my tornado drop…
Excellent technique.
Perhaps we could use it
to improve the tornado drop?
The Japanese men's team
ends up losing the championship.
They were simply powerless before
the Soviet Union's impenetrable block.
Tomorrow we'll watch the finals of the women's team.
And the expectations are even heavier than before.
A new attack.
I hope this at least
gave Kozue-kun a clue.
Yushima-san, I did realized
something thanks to you.
You did your best
even despite the impossible odds.
Your loss wasn't in vain.
Yushima-san,
I will create a new spike.
You still hit it
with your only your arm.
You have to strike
using your whole body.
Yes sir.
Anyway, this technique requires
a very precise pass.
Take a look at Ayuhara's position, and when she jumps
aim at the apex of a triangle she forms with the floor.
– Yes sir!
Let's go!
I can't do it. I can't find my new spike.
Even after Yushima-san gave me such a beautiful hint…
I can't do it.
Coach, please.
Okay, that's enough.
That's it for today.
– Huh?
C-Coach? I haven't
understood how to play it yet.
So… why?
Ayuhara. Are you saying
you still have energy to spend?
Of course.
Great! Keep it for tomorrow.
It will be more useful then.
For tomorrow?
We've already done
everything possible.
It's pointless to waste all our energy on this.
After all, we have an important game before us.
I want you to do your best against the Soviet Union
tomorrow, with or without novel techniques.
Forget about yesterday
and aim for tomorrow.
Clear your heads and play
to the best of your ability.
If you do that, believe me
that you will also get new power.
And most of all, have confidence in yourself. You have
this power. No one knows that better than your coach.
Coach…
We'll meet your expectations.
We'll do whatever we can.
Coach!
Good.
Yes. The game is all that's left.
Let's face tomorrow
with a new strength.
Fight!
Fight! Fight! Fight!
I still remember Manumba's refreshed look when she said
it might be the last time she'd hold a volleyball.
She left, aiming
for tomorrow as well.
Forget about yesterday.
Face tomorrow with a new strength.
I'll do it.
Yushima-san, watch me
greet a new day with a new strength.
The time to confront
Shellenina has come.
The whistle resounds among
the thousands of spectators around the field.
Kozue is anxious.
Her new spike inspired by Yushima
is not perfected yet.
But she must now face
her rival nonetheless.
The first set begins.
But something unexpected happens:
Shellenina is on the bench.
Inokuma is stunned by this
bold tactic of the Soviet Union.
Please look forward
to the next episode!
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.