苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 103—
The Final Match with the Soviet Union
This is the final match of the 1971
World Women's Volleyball Championships.
The two teams that emerged from this long series
of encounters are Japan and the Soviet Union.
And now, the confrontation between
those two great teams has finally come.
Everyone in Sophia's International Sports Hall
is waiting anxiously for the start of the game.
As you look around the hall,
it's evident that it's sold out to the very last seat.
So, the match should be starting
any time now— Ah.
Right on time.
First goes the majestic team of the Soviet Union,
which qualified for the finals with ease as expected.
Everyone's attention is naturally drawn to No. 9, Shellenina,
who's said to be a secret weapon against Japan.
Here comes the Japanese team.
The girls show signs of tension.
Even so, they're walking firmly,
making a strong impression.
Good luck!
Show them what we
didn't manage to!
The men's team
lost yesterday.
So it'd be nice if at least the women's team
could bring the world title to Japan.
The countries represented by both teams
place very high hopes on their favorites.
The final match of the Women's World
Championships Tournament is starting.
Well, I'd like to say something special,
but I can't think of anything good.
Just give this game
the best shot you have.
If you collapse on the court,
I'll personally help you up.
– Yes sir!
My tornado drop
is a thing of the past.
In the end, I was also unable to create
the new spike I promised to Yushima-san.
Yagisawa and Ayuhara!
– Sir.
You're up in the first set.
Coach?
Play the tornado drop
as much as possible.
Don't overthink things.
Yes sir.
Let's go, girls!
– Yeah!
Good luck.
There's nothing to be scared of.
Both teams are finally
on the court warming up.
Ayuhara-kun and Yagisawa-kun?
But the tornado drop
isn't working anymore?
Ah!
Shellenina isn't here.
Deflecting my tornado drop
requires her knowledge, so… why?
The Russians must feel very confident
to keep their decisive player benched.
I think it's not so much confidence,
but a well-planned strategy.
The referee's blown the whistle.
Who will win?
Who will lose?
The game starts
with the Soviets' serve.
The Soviets already gain a point
with their impenetrable block.
Normal methods will not work
against their block.
I wonder if my tornado drop
will really make any difference?
Fight!
– Yeah!
The tornado drop?
Do it. Play it!
Play the tornado drop.
Let's try it.
At worst, it'll fail.
She's going to play it!
Attack!
The tornado drop…
Oh! A direct spike!
That's right. Even if it's doable,
it doesn't mean everyone's capable of it.
Now's our chance!
Let's try it once more!
– Yeah!
Although Japan's
just lost a point…
…they've reclaimed the serve with Ayuhara's
tornado drop and now they're on the offensive.
A chance for Japan!
– Great!
– It's your chance!
Keep pushing!
Good luck, Ayuhara!
So far, so good.
But the problem is when
they let Shellenina out.
Ayuhara's supposedly retired tornado drop,
keeps scoring points, putting Japan in the lead.
But, despite everything, the Russians
don't seem particularly worried.
Fight!
On the other hand, the morale of the
Japanese team is definitely boosted.
I know this won't work forever.
So I have to score as much as possible until then.
Don't sweat it.
Yeah.
Let's keep it up.
We've got them.
The Russians probably won't
stay like that for much longer.
How will they counterattack?
Don't mind it,
don't mind it.
The Russians finally woke up.
This is not good.
They're having trouble with direct spikes,
so they went on to mark Yagisawa.
Time!
Oh? Coach Inokuma
just stood up.
There will be a player change.
Yagisawa is getting
replaced by Kiyama.
Good, nothing escapes him.
But this change means we can't squeeze
anything more from the tornado drop.
Good!
It's a point!
Kiyama's time lag attack scores!
Not even the Russians' wall
could block it.
If this keeps up, the first set
will be ours. Right?
But the Russian team
is completely calm.
Why are they so relaxed?
We have the tornado drop and the
time lag attack. We're giving them a hard time.
Hmm, maybe they don't care about
the first set. That sounds like them.
What do you think, Shellenina?
I think there's 90% chance
she won't use any new techniques.
Yes.
I think the same thing.
The only difference,
I'd say 100%.
No. With her, you can
never be sure of anything.
Japan's in the lead again!
The Soviets' attack falls behind.
The Russians simply don't stand a chance before
Ayuhara's tornado drop and Kiyama's time lag attack.
It's a set point for Japan.
Kiyama's spike scores!
Japan takes the first set.
Way to go!
Let's keep it up!
Why is Shellenina just watching?
Why won't she come out?
I know that my tornado drop
doesn't really pose a threat to you.
Ayuhara-san, in the end,
all you have is that one technique.
You didn't develop it any further.
We'll take the next three sets,
one after another.
Shellenina smiled?
Even though
she's just lost a set?
Listen. This is the part
where the real struggle begins.
They'll use Shellenina, no doubt.
But no matter who she is,
volleyball is played in teams of six.
Don't let yourself
get scared over nothing!
– Yes sir!
Now, go!
After a short break,
the game continues.
The Soviet Union finally lets Shellenina out.
What can we expect in the second set?
Maybe Shellenina was waiting
for my new spike all along?
Ayuhara-kun must feel
frightened now.
Good luck, Ayuhara!
You can do it!
I understand, Yushima-san.
I'll do my best, no matter
what happens. Look at me.
Let's get them!
Yeah!
As expected from Shellenina.
She receives a curve ball with ease.
The Soviet Union deals the first blow.
The battle starts now!
Alright! Show them
what you've got!
Tornado drop!
Ah! Shellenina intercepts
with a direct spike!
The tornado drop is done for!
That's a terrible news to Ayuhara!
It's defeated by an excellent
direct spike from Shellenina.
It's done for.
The tornado drop
is finally done for.
Ayuhara-kun.
Every technique
will get defeated one day.
It's because old things cease to work,
that new things can come to fruition.
Are you okay?
Yes, I am.
Good luck, girls!
– Yeah.
It was excellent, Shellenina.
Don't be so shocked, yet.
That deflection was just child's play.
I've yet to show you the actual technique
that makes me the secret weapon.
– Hey. – Huh?
– Weren't you supposed to take photos?
Yes, I was?
Then get ready to take some.
Of Shellenina.
Ah! The secret weapon!
Kiyama's time lag attack
earns Japan a point.
Good, but it's not a decisive
technique we can rely on.
I have a really bad feeling.
If Shellenina is up to something,
I think it'll be soon.
Shellenina!
What an awesome spike!
Truly, a superhuman technique!
She makes a somersault, then hits on the ball
midair giving it an extraordinary spin.
Things like that are
only seen in a circus.
It is a terrible play,
far exceeding the tornado drop.
If I had to name it,
I'd call that a somersault curve spike.
That's it!
That's the reason she's been
training at Bolshoi Circus.
Circus or not, I still can't believe
she can perform such technique.
Flying reception.
Shellenina grew even more
than I had imagined.
She's fearsome.
Ever since Shellenina appeared on the court,
the point gap is growing more and more.
Ah! Now, a direct spike!
Japan is truly powerless.
14 to 4. Finally, it's a set point
for the Soviet Union.
Ah! Again!
Finally, the Russians
win the second set.
Still, words can't describe Shellenina's ability to play
these excellent techniques. It's truly superhuman.
Watch out, Japan!
At this moment, we don't have
any way to counterattack.
Please keep doing your best.
That's all.
Ah, if I only had
another technique now…
But it's still not ready.
I can't do anything with it.
Compared to the gloom of the Japanese team,
the Russians are energetic and overjoyed.
The third set begins.
Shellenina plays her
sommersault curve spike again!
Damn it to hell!
Fight!
– Yeah!
– Yeah.
Show your Japanese spirit!
Do your best!
They've caught up very fast.
Good luck, Ayuhara!
Things are looking worse and worse.
Japan urgently needs to come up with something.
Hang in there, Japan!
I have to do something.
Don't get intimidated!
You've got this!
The Russian team keeps outplaying Japan,
increasing the difference in points more and more.
Please do something,
Japanese team!
Coach… We're going to lose
if this keeps up.
Let's try the spike
I tried to play the other day.
Even if it fails, it doesn't matter.
It can't be much worse.
Kiyama-san, please!
Oh?
It didn't work…
It's the same as yesterday.
I don't believe it.
It didn't work, after all.
But if there's any chance for us,
we have to rely on it.
I knew she was up to something.
Very well.
I'll take you on, Ayuhara-san.
Ayuhara has tried
what looked like a new technique.
However, the pressure is evidently
too high as she made a mistake.
I'm sorry, Yushima-san.
There's nothing else I can do.
Ayuhara-san!
She's aiming at me.
She's aiming at me…
She wants to
finish you off quickly.
Hang in there, Ayuhara-kun.
I won't lose to her.
Ayuhara makes another mistake.
It's a set point for the Russians.
The third set is conquered
by the Soviet Union.
This is so frustrating.
If only I had managed
to get that spike right…
What's that, Ayuhara-san?
We'll win the next set, too
if you don't do anything.
They've won two sets already.
One more and the game's over.
We're going to lose at this rate.
We'll lose!
The decisive moment of
the World Championship finals.
The secret technique of Shellenina
explodes on the court.
Japan loses
the second and third set.
Now everything depends
on the outcome of the fourth set.
Trying to grasp the new spike, Kozue
hits the ball from an unnatural position and falls.
Without Kozue, the Japanese national team
finds itself in a very desperate situation.
Who will earn
the glorious gold medal?
Please look forward
to the next episode!
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume o egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.