苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 104—
She's the No. 1
Women's World Volleyball
Championship Tournament
The Volleyball World Championships held in Sofia,
the capital of Bulgaria, is coming to an end.
We're watching the final match
of the women's league.
The fierce battle on the court between
Japan and the Soviet Union continues on.
While the Japanese team won the first set,
the second went to Russia.
And the Russians haven't been idle in the third set
either and now we have a set point.
The ball flies in Shellenina's direction.
Will we see it again?
Shellenina's powerful somersault
curve spike scores a point.
And the third set
goes to the Russians.
What a technique.
The only thing that can stop it
is something of a comparable caliber.
I have to stop Shellenina
somehow, no matter what.
No matter what…
No matter what!
Ayuhara-san?
What's wrong?
I just… I just slipped.
I'm fine.
I hope you got the hang
of the trajectory already.
Huh?
I'm talking about Shellenina's
spike, its trajectory.
If you understand its trajectory,
you can receive it.
Ayuhara…
Ayuhara! Come to the bench
and rest up for a bit.
B-But I'm okay, really.
Okay, girls, sit down with me.
It's a strong spike,
no doubt about it.
It has the speed and the power.
But speed and power
aren't the problem here.
All of you know
how to deal with that.
It all boils down to the trajectory.
You have to know it.
– Yes sir.
Unlike in the quick attack, the ball spins
for a while in one place, giving you some time.
That moment is enough
to predict the trajectory change.
And when you know the trajectory,
you only have to cut it.
Don't be afraid.
There's no way
you can't receive it!
Can you do it?
– Yes sir!
Good!
It's the fourth set.
Show them what you've got.
– Yes sir!
Let's go!
– Yeah!
Good luck, Ayuhara.
All people in Japan can follow this encounter
as its broadcast via satellite television.
Although Japan has won the first set,
the second and the third went to the Soviet Union.
To stay in the game, Japan has
to win the fourth set at all costs.
Only after we get to the final set,
we'll stand a chance.
I can't bear it anymore.
Hang in there, Chief!
Ayuhara-san, you can do it!
Kozue…
Inokuma must've given them clues
for how to receive Shellenina's spike.
But Ayuhara's…
Finally, the fourth set
has just begun!
Ayuhara's tired.
She's getting sloppy.
I hope she recovers soon.
Inokuma must be
well aware of it, but still…
If we lose this set,
everything is over.
We have to make
a breakthrough.
But to make that breakthrough,
I have to come up with a new technique.
Ayuhara-kun.
I hope this at least
gives you a clue.
I have to find a way to play Yushima-san's
spike and make it stronger.
What to do?
What do I do?
Ayuhara-san!
Ayuhara, that technique just now
wasn't the tornado drop.
Which one is better,
yours or mine?
This set will resolve everything.
Don't mind it,
don't mind it.
Don't let it get to you.
Yeah.
Fight!
– Yeah!
A successful reception!
Captain Matsuyama received
Shellenina's spike!
Yamagami saves the ball
with a skillful toss!
What skill!
Kiyama's feint scores a point!
The Matsuyama · Yagamami duo
makes a comeback for the Japanese team!
Alright. I'll play with
everything I have, too.
Furumoto's curve ball serve!
It flies up high!
A chance for Japan!
– Ayuhara-san!
– Got it!
Oh! Don't do this!
Oh, Kozue!
Ayuhara's excellent spike scores, but she's
lost her balance and fell unluckily on the court.
She seems to be fine, though!
She already stood up.
Thank goodness.
That's our Chief!
But that landing looked terrible.
She'll be fine, that's Chief we're
talking about! She's made of steel!
I'm sorry. I'm fine.
Coach, are you sure about keeping
Ayuhara-san on the court?
Was that your new
miracle ball, Ayuhara?
Well, I won't lose to you.
I won't lose to you, Ayuhara.
Oh! Ayuhara-san?!
Ayuhara-san!
Coach…
Are you okay?
I'm sorry. I'll receive it
next time for sure.
Ayuhara-san, you…
I'm okay, Captain.
It's nothing, really.
Very well. Let's go!
– Fight!
Ayuhara stands up again.
But still, what a play it was!
No, this is not good.
Don't over-exert yourself.
You need all of your energy
for the new spike.
Kozue…
Ayuhara-san!
Chief…
Kozue!
Kozue?
Stop it, Chief!
What are we going to do without
our captain? Come on, Chief!
Hey, don't panic.
Time!
Ayuhara-san?
Ayuhara-san,
are you alright?
Yagisawa! Switch her.
Yes sir!
Ayuhara-san…
How is she, Mihara-san?
I'm not sure yet.
Either way, she has to rest.
The Japanese team has greatly mobilized
in the fourth set, pressuring their opponents.
A good back feint
from Yamagami.
The Japanese team
plays like they're born anew.
They've managed
to regain the lead.
With a little luck,
we'll qualify for the final set.
She's not hurt.
But she's exhausted, so…
I think we should let her rest up
for a while, then she'll be fine.
Fight!
– Yeah!
Tsutomu-kun!
When things get too bad or too painful, I always
think of you constantly challenging yourself, Kozue-kun.
Let's do our best
together, Kozue-kun.
Keep walking your own path
and become the world's Attack No. 1.
The world's Attack No. 1…
Ah! Tsutomu-kun!
Japan seizes the fourth set!
Ayuhara…
– Ayuhara-san?!
– Ayuhara-san?
Coach.
It's the final set.
Are you up to it, Ayuhara?
Yes sir.
Japan vs. the Soviet Union.
The fifth set.
This is the final set
that decides everything.
Both teams are
entering the court.
Kozue!
It wouldn't be the same
without Chief. Show them!
Good luck, Ayuhara-san.
Kozue.
Kozue, do your best.
Do your best!
Ayuhara.
Ayuhara! Good going!
Great! Ayuhara!
Yes. That's how you play. Just thinking
about hitting the ball and nothing else.
That's right.
Ayuhara-kun, that's enough.
Don't think about
new techniques.
What's wrong, Chief?
Ayuhara-san, hang in there!
Ayuhara-san!
Show them, Chief!
The Russians gain the lead
by one point.
Come on, Chief.
Pull yourself together,
Ayuhara-san!
Hold on, Chief!
You can see that this is the final match.
Both teams are playing passionately.
Each time the Japanese score a point,
the Russians catch up. It's like a game of tag.
Both teams desperately fight
for the right to serve.
Fight, Japan!
Fight, Russia!
It's a match point for Japan!
Attack!
We win!
Japan won the match!
The Japanese women's team
won the World Championships!
Ayuhara's final spike
has defeated the Soviet Union!
Ayuhara! Ayuhara!
Ayuhara…
Shellenina.
The Japanese team wins the
Women's Volleyball World Championship.
Every player gets rewarded
with a gold medal.
It took a lot of hardship and a lot of sacrifices
to achieve what these girls just have.
They have worked hard for a long time
for this very moment.
The gold medals shine beautifully
on the girls' chests.
Congratulations, Japan.
There's no stopping of the tremendous
applause from the audience.
Captain Matsuyama and each of her players have
demonstrated thorough training and fought like lions.
Especially No. 12, Ayuhara Kozue,
who deserves special attention.
She was the decisive player
despite being the youngest on the team.
Kozue…
It won't be an exaggeration to say that today was birth
of a new star who will lead Japanese volleyball.
Kozue, I'm so happy.
Your mom is so happy right now…
Everyone has tears in their eyes.
The tension of the game has finally vanished,
leaving room for emotions.
And now we come to the next highlight
of this year's World Volleyball Championships.
In just a moment, the name of this year's
best player will be announced. Who will it be?
I see the chairman of the commission
stepping up to the microphone.
Best one: Ayuhara Kozue, Japan.
It's Ayuhara! Ayuhara was voted
as the best player in the world!
The players all over the world
send applause to Ayuhara.
Ayuhara-kun, you did it!
You became the world's star!
M-Me? The best player?
Ayuhara Kozue, Japan.
Ayuhara, you're
the best in the world.
Shellenina, Ayuhara's great rival since
the Junior World Championships…
…applauds Ayuhara and
congratulates her wholeheartedly.
You did it, Chief!
Attack No. 1!
Even though it hurts…
…even though I feel sad…
Ayuhara Kozue oficially becomes
the world's Attack No. 1.
…on the court I feel just fine.
I cannot even fathom
how she is feeling right now.
When I hear the ball flying,
my heart races.
Receive. Toss. Spike.
One-two, one-two! Attack!
Through the tears and sweat,
putting up a youthful fight…
…under the blue sky,
I just want to scream:
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
Even though it hurts…
…even though I feel sad…
…I have my team mates.
I find myself whistling
and my heart races.
Receive. Toss. Spike.
One-two, one-two! Attack!
Showing fighting spirit
through the tears…
…looking at billowing clouds,
I just want to scream:
The game isn't over yet.
I'm going to aim for the Olympic Games in Munich.
Then for the next World Championship.
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
The road ahead of me is still long
and bumpy, like it's always been.
I've merely took the first step
down that road.
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
I'll see how far it takes me.
Together with my volleyball.
The End