苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 009—
Torn resignation letters
Midori-san.
At last it's time for our turn.
Yep.
Your turn?
What do you mean?
We want to repay you for the last time.
What's that?
Drop the act.
The results won't change.
Or maybe you've spent your spring break on some special training?
As if, hahaha.
That's exactly right.
Hey, April Fools is long over.
Just to make it clear: we've already proved our skill before.
Got it?
That's why we want to repay you with skill.
We won't let you keep that boastful attitude forever. Got it?
We get it.
Looks like the last time wasn't enough for you after all.
Hmph.
That's ridiculous. Our Big Four is too good to accept such a request.
No trash talk. We'll play with them all right.
Huh?
We'll play with the same people.
You've got your game.
Happy?
– Let's do this.
– What's with her.
Damn.
Are we really doing this?
Ah, it's professor Hongou.
Professor!
– Professor!
Professor, did you come to be Fujimi students' good charm?
What?
You've taken place of our professor Kajioka as the new coach to promote yourself, no?
Whoa.
What are you saying?
Professor Hongou is not like that.
Then why did he push to become our coach?
Izumi-san.
Hmph. Shut up.
I wonder what's with Izumi-san.
She's acting strange.
I won't forgive it.
As the club members, for you to cast us out…
What do you intend to do?
Professor!
How about you say something?
That's right. Professor Hongou.
She's yelling so much.
You two stay out of this!
What it'll be, professor!
What's with your way of talking.
Students these days have no respect at all.
Never mind that.
Even if you say this, you come here as you please.
I will say just this.
In the volleyball, the skill is the most important.
By the way, I believe you said you want a grudge match.
That's correct.
We did.
– Chief…
– We're no good.
Interesting.
Well then, you girls.
Ket's see your skills before your beloved professor Hongou.
What do we do?
It doesn't matter.
The teacher nailed it. We'll just kick their butts.
Hurry.
Let's do this.
"Repay with skill." I'll believe those words.
I'm counting on you, Ayuhara.
Ayuhara-san, take your time.
– Do your best!
– Captain!
I got it!
– Ah!
– Oh!
The curve ball.
"Leaf Fall".
Hehe.
Fufufu.
Why are you spacing out?
It's a point for us.
We scored one point.
Y-Yes ma'am! Right away.
《Izumi group: 0》
《Ayuhara group: 0》
《Ayuhara group: 1》
Here I go.
Here goes!
Ah…
Ahh.
Ahh…
It hurts.
It hurts!
My hand got numb again.
What to do?
Ah, Izumi-san!
Ah!
Waii, captain! Nice, nice!
Ayuhara-san, maybe we should go easy on them?
Waii, good going, good going!
Waai!
Here I go.
Look out!
Ah!!
Ho?
Besides Ayuhara, Hayakawa can serve that curve ball too.
If you thought I'd lose to Ayuhara-san, big mistake.
How do you like it?
Hayakawa-san, awesome!
I can't believe it.
It feels so strange when we're leading this easily.
I didn't think the camp would be this effective.
But looks like our surprise can't compare with theirs.
Hmm.
Ayuhara-san.
I don't want to lose.
I can't lose.
Never.
No way we'll lose!…
No way we'll lose!
No way we'll lose!!
Izumi became unreasonable and lost her rhythm.
Ah!
Aaa!
All right! We won this set!
Waai, you did well!
Ah, it hurts…
Chief, that was terrific.
The way you served with your left hand…
And that strength. That spike could dent the court.
How did you like current Ayuhara-san's skills?
Hmph.
Uh…
We lost.
Wh-What are you saying? The match starts now.
It's ridiculous to decide it with a single set.
Stay strong, Izumi-san.
– Ah, Izumi-san.
– Izumi-san.
Izumi-kun!
What's wrong, Izumi?
It's no use.
This hand just won't react.
– Izumi-san!
– Izumi-san.
– Izumi-san, hey.
Izumi-san.
Why did we give up midway? That's not like you, Izumi-san.
Any more sets wouldn't change the outcome.
– Eh?
But why?
That's ridiculous.
Don't argue with me. I know what I'm talking about.
It's regrettable. I'll be going home first.
Hm…
That was crazy.
Ah, it's so unlike Izumi-san.
I see.
So it was university training camp.
That explains it.
But it must've been tough, no?
Correct.
But we won with the Big Four.
I feel refreshed.
Chief, you were like Superman.
Hayakawa-san's curve ball was awesome, too.
Yeah. It was super cool!
It finally feels like volleyball club again.
Yeah. I don't want to hear their boasting ever again.
They couldn't see past the end of their noses.
In the end they had to bump into a wall.
Hahahaha.
Heheheh.
Aah.
The Big Four is over.
However, Ayuhara.
What do you want to do now?
Eh?
Don't you want to fix your relationship with them?
With the exception of Ayuhara's group, when compared to other members, they are stronger.
I'm sure you understand that too.
But professor.
It's futile for us to try joining forces with such uncooperative people.
Hehehe.
Futile or not, I'm entrusting it to you.
God it? Ayuhara. Hayakawa.
Katori-san, what will it be?
Hmm.
If you feel this way, it can't be helped.
It's decided then.
After telling Izumi-san, let's put our resignation together tomorrow.
Roger.
Who'd want to be in that club anyway.
Keep it straight!
Fight, fight!
Don't space out!
Watch the ball closely!
No matter what professor said…
It's no use.
What is?
The Big Four are sure to quit the club now.
We can't let them do that.
Our power will fall considerably.
That's weak, Ayuhara-san.
Even without the Big Four we're plenty capable on our own.
Ah, I wonder about that.
Izumi-san acted strange today.
I can't believe she gave it all she had.
At any rate, I'll try talking to them tomorrow again.
It's useless.
I'm positive they'll drop out.
I absolutely won't let them do that.
– You're so stubborn.
– Same goes to you.
Hehe.
I'm trying to be a realist.
I'll leave it to you, captain.
I'll take my chances.
I'll show you that I can persuade the Big Four.
Ah.
Well then, now that we have our letters ready…
Where's Izumi-san?
Seems like she's absent today.
I thought we'd deliver the letters with all four of us.
I wonder what happened to Izumi-san.
Yesterdays game must've gotten to her.
Surely.
《Izumi family》
No.
Yuri.
By "no" I mean "no".
I don't want to go to the hospital again.
But it looks very painful.
Playing more with that arm is reckless.
Right?
Let's go.
I'll go with you, okay?
If you want to go that much, then go without me.
I'm not going there.
Yuri!
Hold on!
So, do you think you'll be able to persuade them?
Hm. To be honest, I'm not really sure.
Hey, maybe you can think of something?
I said that in the heat of the moment yesterday, but I honestly don't think I can make friends with these girls.
But both you and the Big Four share the love for the volleyball, don't you.
Of course we do.
Why can't you join forces then?
I can't help but think you've misunderstood each other.
In this world there are things that even bugs won't touch.
Hehe.
You can be harsh at times, you know.
Hm.
I just remembered how you almost got in a fight with Hayakawa-san in the past.
Ah, you knew it?
That's a newspaper club member for you.
Ah!
Ah, you girls.
Huh.
Ayuhara-san.
– Sorry for all the trouble.
– Eh?
– We're quitting the volleyball club.
– Oh, my.
See for yourself.
It's a resignation letter. We're on the way to professor Hongou.
That's too bad.
You girls, haven't you staked everything on the volleyball so far? And yet…
"Staked everything"? Don't be absurd.
It's just a stupid ball game.
You're not serious!
I understand it more than you think.
There's no way you're thinking that seriously.
I'm a fool for volleyball too, so I get it.
Training half for fun, unlike you, I can't get better.
Isn't that right?
Fufufu. In other words, you're telling us we're geniuses?
What are you saying?
All right, let's go.
Hold on!
Don't be stubborn. Please?
– Please think it ove—
– We've had enough.
Let's go, let's go.
Is it okay to let them go like that?
Wait, wait!
What now?
Wh—!
What are you doing!
Hey, give it back!
Give it back!
Get over here!
Oh, I didn't know Ayuhara-san can handle paperwork well.
《Class 3C》
What a way to make a person look like a fool.
We can't let her off the hook like that.
If you don't do something, I will.
Yeah. I won't be staying silent.
Katori-san. What about you?
W-Well, same goes for me.
All right.
Let's notify someone.
How about the principal?
Sounds good. I'll go.
Ah, it's you.
Good timing.
Kudou-san. I want to talk to you.
– Talk?
– Yep.
Come to see me by the riverbank after classes.
I'll be waiting. It's a promise!
Ayuhara-san!
Damn it, she left me no choice.
We're here.
Be prepared for a company.
It's awfully quiet.
How many people will be there?
There's no way we can know it!
Never mind the others and focus on Ayuhara.
Got it?
Hello.
Ah!
You're late.
Are you alone?
Yes. Why are you asking?
Then why have you called us here?
There's something I wanted to ask you.
It's about this.
Wh-What is it.
Let's hear whatever it is.
Do you really want to quit the volleyball club?
Of course we do. Isn't that obvious?
I may have fought with you until now.
But I have always respected your talent.
Hmph.
I respect your serve and spike too, Ayuhara-san.
Right?
If me and you join our forces, we might make an excellent team together.
Eh?
Are you serious about that?
Certainly.
We're in the same club and I want to win matches.
Don't you want to make a strong team even a little bit?
We're in the same club?
Hmph.
Too bad.
We don't want to see a volleyball ever again.
So you're dropping out no matter what?
Yeah.
Hand over the letters.
No matter how much you disturb us, I'm quitting.
To hell with volleyball.
Give it back!
Give it back.
Ah!
Wh-What are you doing!
Ah…
If you hate volleyball that much, let's see you cut up that ball.
Let's see you tear that ball you don't want to see ever again.
If you can do it, I'll give it up and give you the letters back.
Hmph.
Who needs volleyball.
Who needs volleyball!
Such a thing…
Who needs that thing…
Who needs it!
Who needs this ball!
The ball is crying.
It's crying.
Until yesterday, that ball was your true friend.
Now you're trying to cut that friend to pieces!
Shut up!
Stop!
Look out!
Uh…
I…
I couldn't do it.
Didn't we promise after entering Hamaki?
Kudou-san, Ozawa-san… we promised we'll continue with volleyball till high school…
Sniff.
It's like Katori-san says.
You can't quit volleyball.
Since your love for volleyball is true…
Why do we even fight?
Why aren't we united?
Ozawa-san. Kudou-san, Katori-san…
Please!
Please make a team with us.
For the sake of that friendship.
Ayuhara-san.
Whoa. One more time.
Keep at it!
Strange.
I wonder what chief's doing.
All right, let's take a break.
Ayuhara-san intends to get the Big Four back.
Ah, is that so.
I see.
Shouldn't they come to us bowing their heads by now?
It won't be this simple. They have their pride, you know.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
– Hey.
– Wow.
Here she goes again.
You've got something to say, no?
Well?
From the start we were thinking too much.
When we came here, we thought we'd be marginalized.
To avoid it, we decided to seize the initiative first.
That's what we were thinking.
In other words, you were a little nervous just like us.
We apologize.
We've been rude to you.
Hehehe.
Don't sweat it. We're over that.
What's with you, sportsgirl. March with pride.
– Yes sir.
What about Izumi though?
– Ah, she…
– Well that's…
Looks like she's absent from school today.
We're worried about her as well.
She's been acting strange since a few days ago.
Strange?
Now that you mention it, it feels like she was hiding something.
You're great friends. It must be for a reason.
She's surprisingly secretive though.
Hmm.
I can't blame her. Izumi-san's mom is actually her stepmother after all.
A stepmother…
We'll tell her later. I'm sure she'll understand.
I wonder if it goes well. She can be scary at times.
Hmm.
Without Izumi-san, the name of Big Four loses its sense.
That's right.
Professor. I'll go check on her and visit her home.
All right, professor?
Hm.
Ah. Let us go too then.
You should focus on practice.
I'll be fine by myself.
Very well. Let's leave it to Ayuhara.
Yes sir.
《Izumi family》
What a mansion.
Excuse me.
I wonder if they're out.
Who might you be?
Ah. I beg your pardon, is Izumi Yuri-san home?
Ah, you're Yuri's friend?
Yes ma'am. My name's Ayuhara Kozue.
Ah, nice to meet you. Welcome.
Yuri will be home soon. Make yourself comfortable.
Excuse me.
However…
Hm?
You're not a member of the volleyball club, are you?
Spot on. I am its member.
I am very sorry.
But I'm afraid I can't let you meet with Yuri.
Eh?
I'm sorry for troubling you with this request only now, but could you please go home?
Ah… why's that? I came here out of the blue but I'd rather not go home until I meet with Yuri.
Why?
Shut up and go home.
Ah, Izumi-san.
Yuri.
Go home.
You're not welcome here.
Hurry.
Get out!
Why?
What's going on?
Kozue went alone to Izumi's home, but…
…when it became evident she's with the volleyball club, Izumi's stepmother coldens.
After Izumi Yuri gets home, she grabs Kozue's arm and drags her out…
…shouting bitter words to her stepmother.
Kozue can't shake off the feeling that there's something deeper going on.
But seeing Yuri's attitude, her hand reacts instinctively.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.