苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 013—
Strategy without strategy
All-Japan Middle School Girls Volleyball Championships
In the All-Japan Volleyball Championships…
…out of 32 participant teams only 8 are still in.
The quarter finals are finally here.
Who will emerge victorious?
Let's ask a
sports
commentator, Yamaguchi-san.
How is it, Yamaguchi-san?
What teams do you think are likely to win?
Hmm.
Well, things seem to have taken a weird turn this year.
Unprecedentedly, out of the eight teams that made it here…
…except Meihou Academy and Okuyama Middle School…
…the other six schools all come from outside Tokyo.
It's not easy to pick someone.
Especially considering how the favorite…
…Iwai Middle School has lost in the qualifiers.
Fukuoka Middle School, who hasn't lost a single set yet, seems very powerful.
What about the debuting team, Fujimi Academy?
Yeah. They are famous for their beautiful attack duo.
I wonder about their overall skill though.
Meihou is bound to give us a fine game.
However, Fukuoka is a curious case.
Kakinouchi might be a one man team, however…
…except for her revolving receive, their team has nothing special.
They're pretty mysterious.
Fukuoka Middle School
What's the final decision?
Right now I'd say Meihou, Fukuoka, Fujimi.
I'd place these three in that order.
Nice, attack duo!
Shikoku ・ Fujimi
Good luck, Fujimi!
Do your best!
Shikoku ・ Fujimi
Ayuhara-san, it's a match point.
We've got this game.
Yep.
But the problem is Fukuoka.
Give us a good serve.
Leave it to me.
Here I go.
Special technique.
"Leaf Fall".
I'm glad.
Today we won as well.
Tomorrow is the semi-final.
Then, the final!
But I'm worried about Fukuoka.
I feel as if they're hiding some special weapon.
I want to see it.
I want to see Fukuoka's game!
Professor, we're going to stay and see Fukuoka's games, no?
We can't form a strategy without seeing the real thing.
Am I right, professor?
Hm?
Nah. There's no need to see it.
Let's go back to the hotel.
I-It can't be.
Professor, let us stay.
I'm worried about various press reports in the newspapers and on the TV.
Professor, if we're to form a strategy…
…we have to stay and see their game.
Please let us stay!
There's no need to.
Eh?
But why?
I don't understand, professor.
After all, if Meihou loses tomorrow, we'll be facing Fukuoka.
I know.
By the way…
…unlike Sapporo and Meihou,
you don't think you can win with Fukuoka.
Is that right?
Ayuhara, how is it?
That's not true.
Good. Hayakawa?
I absolutely believe in us.
Absolutely?
Whatever.
What about the rest?
We feel the same as captain and Hayakawa-san.
So you're saying you all believe in yourselves?
– Yes sir!
Very well.
That's good then.
There's no point in watching them.
With your confidence, there's nothing to fear about Fukuoka.
We're leaving.
B-But, professor!
Come on already.
Hotel "Yamato"
Ayuhara, Hayakawa and the girls…
…are disturbed. I understand them.
But it's not the same as having no confidence.
What Fujimi needs to win right now is…
…an absolute belief that they can win.
We need to do it at our pace.
If I showed them the Fukuoka's tactic now…
…they'd be no longer serious and let their guard down.
Then again I can't have them think they can't win no matter what they do.
The path to victory will close this way.
In order to win…
…we need a strategy without strategy.
That's our only choice.
First match: Fujimi vs. Sapporo
Good luck!
Sapporo ・ Fujimi
Having emerged from the qualifiers with no major mistakes, Sapporo Middle School from Hokkaidou…
…has evident trouble with defending against the Fujimi Academy's beautiful attack duo.
Good, good!
Sapporo ・ Fujimi
Fujimi achieves a crushing victory.
It is an excellent outcome after all the Fukuoka's victories.
Good!
Ah, it's the Fukuoka.
Hey, it's the Fukuoka.
They were watching us all the time.
Even before the match.
I felt Kakinouchi Yoshiko's eyes on me during the entire match.
It feels creepy.
Yeah. She had such a dirty look.
They must've come to research our game.
It probably was for the nth time.
I know it must've been several times.
I feel frozen right now.
We also should watch their game.
Hey.
Ayuhara. Hayakawa.
– We're going to the waiting room.
– P-Professor!
What is it?
Please let us stay for the next game.
Eh? Here we go again.
Yep.
The Fukuoka's team saw our entire game.
Eh?
I know.
Then it's okay to watch, no?
Hold on.
You girls…
…keep pleading "let us stay, let us stay", but…
…why do you want to see it so much?
We've explained it already!
It's to research our opponent.
You know your opponents plenty already.
Haven't you read Izumi's memo earlier?
That's not enough, professor.
Indeed, we've learned a lot from that memo.
But it can't replace seeing the opponent in a real match.
That's weird.
Why are you so worried about Fukuoka?
Eh?
You might be playing the finals with Meihou.
I know Meihou very well.
I can come up with a strategy too.
Ayuhara, when did you become a coach?
Are you planning to form a strategy in my stead?
Eh?
Th-That's not it…
Then leave it to me.
We're leaving.
Meihou ・ Fukuoka
Semi-finals
No smoking
Hey, Ayuhara-kun! Congrats!
Good going.
What a crushing victory.
It's still early for this.
Yeah, Tsutomu-san. Save it for later.
Nope. You've already won.
Even though Fukuoka watched your game…
…they were so shocked they haven't said a word.
Tsutomu-san's overjoyed, but…
…that silence is what I fear.
It must be nice to not know it.
They came here to learn about our weak points. They were silent because they were focused.
Captain!
I'm listening!
Professor is calling us out.
He wants us to go to the next
building via the south entrance.
He said he wants to talk to us.
Eh?
We can discuss strategy here in the waiting room.
Hmm. I don't understand him very well either.
All right. Let's go.
I'm sure we'll hear more
"when did you become a coach?".
Professor, what is it?
You called us out.
All right, take a seat.
We'll be listening to a record now, so stay quiet.
Wh-What?
We didn't come all the way to Tokyo to listen to music.
– Right?
– Yeah.
Why are we doing this?
Now, now.
Don't be so loud.
This room has perfect acoustics.
I can hear you very well.
It's this song.
Do-Don't joke around.
I'm going to see the game.
– Let's go.
Hold it.
Listen to what I'm saying.
Even if you don't understand what I'm doing,
I won't allow doing as you please.
That's cruel
That's just awful.
Look, a feudal lord.
What a tyrant.
Yeah.
Something's wrong with professor.
I won't listen to anything.
Say what you want.
I will say just this.
Fukuoka will surely defeat Meihou and play against you.
And no matter if you watch their games or
not, you won't understand their strength.
I don't understand what you mean.
I don't get it either.
Yeah.
We'll surely understand them when we see their game.
You won't.
There's no way you'd get it from mere watching.
Why?
I don't buy it, professor.
You're giving me a hard time.
How's this:
Tell me, why is Fukuoka so strong?
The stronger your opponent's team is,
the easier their victories are.
In other words, the fewer opportunities for them to demonstrate their true power.
That is Fukuoka's strength.
Eh?
That's right.
That's why it's no use trying to research them.
The problem is with you.
Your confidence.
How proficient can you get in the match?
That's all.
That's all there is to it.
Then what do we do? What's our strategy?
The most important in playing against Fukuoka is to believe in yourself.
Do not doubt your own strength.
It's not the strategy.
If I had to name it, it's a "strategy without strategy".
A "strategy without strategy".
Yes.
That is all.
That is what we can do.
What's left is not to lose your confidence before Fukuoka.
So nothing ventured, nothing gained?
Yep.
Thinking of a strategy is a waste.
We need to impose our pace on the opponent.
We should stay calm and play as usual.
Is that right, professor?
Correct.
Easier said than done.
All right, let's play it.
We still have the time.
– Yes.
– Yes sir.
It's something everyone knows: Beethoven's Symphony No. 5.
It helps find a way those who have lost it.
Nothing can be done except
the "strategy without strategy"…?
I guess it's no use dwelling on it.
Meihou, the volleyball queen, is in trouble.
They've already lost the first set.
They haven't recovered in this set
and Fukuoka keeps the lead.
It's 13 to 9 already.
Again, Kakinouchi's has landed another spike just grazing the line.
Fukuoka ・ Meihou
It's now 14 to 9. Finally, the match point goes to Fukuoka.
This match is completely unlike Meihou.
Back to you, Yamaguchi-san.
It's not even a half of the energy I expected to see.
I'm really surprised.
I don't know if it's a good or a bad thing for a team such as Fukuoka…
…but at any rate, they managed to
greatly shake their enemy's team…
…and deal shock that might be never recovered from.
Oh? What makes you say that?
Err, I approached the coach of last year's winners, Iwai Middle School.
And he said this:
I'm ashamed we were defeated in the qualifiers.
Hm. I'd like to ask you about that Fukuoka Middle School.
For such a strong team I have very little commentary on it.
It's a bad story.
Every one of our Iwai's club regular players said they want to quit volleyball after that match.
Oh?
They said they've lost interest in it.
They lost their confidence too.
That said, I think it's absurd.
Oh?
It's a curious story.
This is why I think Meihou Academy and Yoshimura's team might turn out similar.
Chinko, it's yours!
Don't hit it! It's out!
Yamaguchi-san.
The last spike would be an out, wouldn't it.
That's right.
Looks like the players' mental
composure is in pieces.
Meihou might have a history of achievements, but today…
…I feel like I do not want to see Yoshimura-san struggle any longer.
Oh! It went through!
Meihou players' receive a ball that was completely out of the court.
The players seem extremely confused.
It's out again!
At last, the sixth match point. The server hits the ball.
All right, let's finish this!
Splendid!
Finally, Fukuoka Middle School wins. The prestigious Meihou Academy is defeated.
As expected from Meihou.
They were the strongest since Iwai.
At last, the final with Fujimi.
And the Ayuhara-Hayakawa duo.
Let's put them through the same as Yoshimura-san.
The captain Yoshimura of Meihou Academy, due to the fierce match, has lost consciousness…
…and is under medical care right now.
The next game between Fukuoka Middle School and Fujimi Academy…
…will commence in 30 minutes.
Both teams are to gather on the court 10 minutes before the match.
I quit…
I'm quitting volleyball.
No matter what happens…
Looks like Fujimi Academy didn't watch the previous match.
That is correct.
We got an information I'll
be
relaying to our listeners.
When the game started, all Fujimi members gathered in a building next door.
They shut the doors and didn't step out thus far.
A building?
Where exactly?
I think it's an auditorium.
S-Say what?
One can't help but wonder why they shut themselves in such a room.
I'd understand if they came to research the game. Right, Yamaguchi-san?
Maybe they're abstaining from the match.
N-Nah, it can't be the case.
Maybe there is another point to their actions.
Eh?
Ah, no.
Never mind.
When you lose confidence, it's all over.
We need to take Fukuoka head-on.
One more!
Let's keep the high spirits.
Kozue, good luck.
I wish papa, who is of a stronger heart,
would watch it with me today.
Five minutes until the match.
Both teams are to step off the court.
Practice stop.
What are you doing?
Oh, I'm sorry it hit you.
It wasn't on purpose, Ayuhara-san.
What was that?
Oh? Wanna fight?
Hey!
Nakazawa!
Cut it out!
Yeah.
It's important not to get taken in.
Both captains, choose who serves first.
Rock, paper!
Rock paper!
I don't know what you're scheming, but it won't work on me.
Whatever. It's our win anyway.
Rock, paper, scissors!
Fufu.
I have a bad feeling about this.
At last, spring All-Japan Middle School Women's Volleyball Championships are reaching climax.
Both teams are in high spirits.
We're about to see a splendid match.
Fukuoka's captain Kakinouchi is
famous for her revolving receive.
Meanwhile, Fujimi's captain Ayuhara is known as an ambidextrous attacker.
It's an interesting fight between an attacker and a receiver.
Which one will emerge victorious?
Bring it on!
Here we go, Kakinouchi-san.
Good luck Fujimi
Do your best!
– Godspeed, Fujimi!
– Good luck!
Amazing. Her aim at line is perfect.
Attack!
Ayuhara-san, let's try feinting.
Damn! I can't penetrate it at all!
Fujimi ・ Fukuoka
What do I do?
Looks like Fukuoka completely controls this match as well.
Oh, Fujimi got a serve.
Server will be captain Ayuhara Kozue.
I guess I have to use "Leaf Fall".
Excellent receive!
As expected from Kakinouchi.
She perfectly warded off the famous "Leaf Fall".
Ayuhara-san. Your struggle is futile.
Good luck, Fukuoka!
Fukuoka wins the first set.
Fukuoka ・ Fujimi
Do you understand?
This is Fukuoka's strength.
It's something you can only see by yourself in the court.
There's no way to learn it just from watching the game.
All right. The real match begins now.
Do your thing. That is all. Go!
– Yes sir!
The second set begins.
Each team assumed positions.
The Kantou's representative, Meihou Academy, due to captain Yoshimura's and four players'…
…worsening state from the match with Fukuoka, will abstain from the third place play-off.
Eh?
Therefore the third place goes by walkover to the Hokkaidou's representative, Sapporo.
Yoshimura-san's state worsened?
What did they mean?
Kakinouchi-san. What happened to Yoshimura-san?
Hahahaha.
It's not like we did anything to her.
Plus I think they referred to the mental state.
Whoa.
She went crazy on her own.
I can't be held responsible
if you end up that way as well.
Hahahaha.
Eh?
Went crazy on her own?
Fukuoka wins the first match against Fujimi.
"Remember the music."
—says coach Hongou. Kozue, keeping these words in mind, wins the second set.
Finally, the decisive set.
Fukuoka starts with a fierce attack…
…and Fujimi Academy faces a
pinch with the score of 15 to 14.
Just then, Kozue, who reclaimed the
right to serve, has a wonderful idea.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.