苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 010—
Creeping conspiracy
Ayuhara-san, leave.
Get out.
Can't you hear?
Yuri-san.
You're being rude to her.
You shut up.
What do you know.
Izumi-san, that's no way to speak to your mother.
"Mother", you say?
Hmph.
What a thing to say.
For this woman to be my mother…
Thanks but no.
She's nice before others.
But there's no telling what she thinks.
She must hate me.
Izumi-san!
Ah!
What are you doing!
I've misjudged you, Izumi-san.
Even if she's your step mom, a parent is a parent.
You, however…
Huh? I've heard enough.
What can you possibly know?
Hurry up and go home.
Don't you understand what's said to you?
Doesn't look so.
Fine, do whatever.
Hmph.
Izumi-san.
Uhm…
Please, let's call it a day.
I understand.
Well then, excuse me.
My…
So you really went to Izumi's home yesterday.
Yep. But it was no use.
See?
That's why I told you to give it up.
Isn't it better this way? We don't have to care about her anymore.
I'm not giving up yet.
I'll persuade her until I succeed.
I really admire that side of you.
But her aside, don't you think the others are doing pretty well?
They do and I appreciate it. But still…
I'd really like to have Izumi-san on our side in the future matches.
Don't you overrate her?
Didn't we win with her the other day?
It'll be okay.
With you and me, it's certain.
There are no certainties in sports.
Letting her go will be a mistake.
Ayuhara-san, Izumi-san joined the track and field club.
Eh?
Track and field club?
That's right.
– She's practicing on the track.
– Whoa.
Told you.
That's why we're better off letting her go.
That's awful.
What the heck were you thinking, Izumi-san?
But Izumi-san sure is cold.
She left behind everyone's back.
I'll see professor Hongou for an advice.
I already know she switched clubs.
Eh?
Just a while ago, she gave me this.
Letter of resignation
Izumi Yuri
Professor, did you accept her resignation then?
Well…
I didn't want to accept it either.
But no matter what you say, you
can't go against one's free will.
Ready?
Ah.
Izumi-san, we need to talk to you.
What about?
Why did you keep it from us and leave the club on your own?
That wasn't cool, Izumi-san.
Big Four or not, we did everything together until now.
Why didn't you talk to us about quitting the volleyball club?
It wouldn't change anything.
Besides what about you?
After flocking to Ayuhara-san…
You have some nerve saying that.
Just a second, Izumi-san.
At first we wanted to quit the club too, and wrote our own resignation letters.
But in the end we couldn't quit.
We love volleyball after all.
Besides volleyball, we don't have anything special.
Doesn't it apply to you too, Izumi-san?
Even so.
I don't want to be under that girl's thumb.
If you want to be her lackeys so much, I won't stop you.
How worthless.
"Lackeys", you say?
Don't be rude.
What about you?
You used to fret over silliest things.
But now you think cynicism is cool?
Yeah. Do whatever.
We're through.
This might be the end of it.
So Izumi-san didn't tell professor Hongou why she resigned?
That's harsh. She ought to do at least this much, no?
Hmm. But Izumi-san, who likes volleyball this much…
She must have had a good reason to join the track and field club.
Don't you think so too?
Why don't we forget about her already?
Instead let's think about the nearing matches.
Yeah.
Oh?
Hey, look, isn't it Izumi-san?
Eh?
Ah.
Whoa, she's with Tsutomu-san.
I wonder what's the meaning of this.
Why Tsutomu-kun and Izumi-san are together?
Oh?
Tsutomu-kun.
What, it's just you.
What's up?
I've been waiting for you.
For me?
Yep.
There's something I want to ask you.
What do you want to ask?
It's about Izumi-san.
Tsutomu-kun, for how long are you going out with Izumi-san?
How long I…
Her home is in the same direction as mine, so we go home together.
Something wrong with that?
I don't think I can understand Izumi-san any longer.
Ah, it's about her quitting the club, huh.
I'm worried about that too, actually.
It seems you two just can't get along.
I tried to.
But she has no intention of
listening to what I'm saying…
…and quit the club just like that.
But Izumi-san's situation is very tough.
You can't blame her.
Wow, you sympathize with her a lot, don't you.
Why's that?
Why shouldn't I be sympathetic?
It's weird. Suspicious!
Wait, hold on! What do you mean by "suspicious"!
What was that?
Tsutomu-kun, when I'm in trouble, you don't move the slightest…
…but for Izumi-san, you grab her shoulders right away.
Don't say stupid things.
It's not like you!
Excuse me for being stupid!
– Kozue-chan!
– Leave me alone!
The Toukai district qualifiers for the spring All-Japan Middle School Volleyball Tournament are near!
Hey, girls!
Stop and come here for a second.
– Yes sir!
Okay, you're gathered.
Listen, everyone.
At last, the district qualifiers for the
All-Japan Tournament start tomorrow.
It's a tournament, so one loss and we're out.
You get what it means.
Whether we can win or not…
…depends on the skills you gathered in the training…
…and if you use them at 100% in the matches.
If you go all out…
…the qualifications…
…and, of course, the tournament, are within our reach.
Girls.
Give it your all!
– Yes sir!
Got it?
Let's prove our Fujimi's prestige…
…and win through at any cost.
– Yeah!
– Yes, we'll work hard!
Good.
Final drill! Resume the training!
Yes, sir!
So strong!
What's that, what's that!
Get a grip, Kashiwagi!
You won't have time in the tournament!
– I'm sorry!
– Take this!
Sir!
Next!
Here it goes!
Take this!
More!
Okay, next!
Attack duo!
Sir!
Mark my words.
I won't let you win at any rate!
Ah, Izumi-san!
What are you doing here?
We're practicing now.
Eh?
Ah.
I took a day off today.
A day off?
Out of the blue like that?
You can't. When you're in our club, you need to be serious.
You see…
I feel ill today. I'm going home now.
Izumi-san! You can't!
Ah, that felt good.
Yes, just a little bit.
Hey.
The qualifiers start tomorrow. I'm excited!
Our first opponent is Kawakita Middle School.
Let's win, win, win all the way through!
Yeah.
Let's work hard!
Ah, I want to see Toukai already.
I'm surprised though
– Fujimi's been losing all this time and now we enter district qualifiers.
Teachers room
Then…
We'll win for sure, right?
…I think so, yes.
Thinking won't get us far, professor Hongou.
Yeah.
However…
…a match is like water.
You can't know the outcome.
It's no good. The coach having no confidence is a bad thing.
That's right, professor Hongou.
Furthermore…
Who promised a dazzling victory if they became a coach, hm? Wasn't that you?
Correct.
My intention didn't change.
Then give us a dazzling victory you promised.
Although I think you'll be hard pressed…
…to find an excellent warrior such as Izumi.
But professor.
Players like Izumi are in it for themselves.
Well, I wonder about that.
While you were preaching about teamwork and whatnot, she quit your club nonetheless.
Am I not right?
No.
It'll be fine.
You don't need to worry.
Is that so?
Very well, then.
But don't come to me crying and begging to get her back in your club, professor Hongou.
I won't.
Watch us in the matches from tomorrow on.
How nostalgic.
We used to fight so much, didn't we.
Yeah.
But we became friends thanks to it, didn't we?
Now that you say it, I wonder.
Why I rebelled so much back then.
Not unlike Izumi-san, no?
My, hehe.
Ah.
Check it out!
Ah, Tsutomu-kun and Izumi-san!
Sniffle.
Izumi-kun.
Whoa!
What a shock!
They're acting weird.
They're too bold!
It's unbecoming for middle schoolers.
Tsutomu-san's Tsutomu-san, too.
What is he doing with Izumi-san? How filthy!
If the school finds out, they'll be in trouble.
Come on, stop crying.
If people saw us, they'd jump to conclusions.
I don't care.
I just can't take it any more.
Don't feel down.
Stay calm, okay, Izumi-kun?
Okay?
Hey, Izumi-kun.
Wow. I can't stay out of this any more.
Yeah. Let's give them a warning.
Wipe your tears.
You two.
Oh.
Kozue-chan.
Tsutomu-kun, what are you two doing here?
It'd be okay if only us saw you, but what if you were seen by other people?
They'll disdain you, Tsutomu-san.
You got it all wrong! Don't say weird things!
Whoa, how cold.
It's too late to call it a misunderstanding.
What were you doing here?
What a thing to say.
It's none of your business.
Keep your mouths shut.
Hmph.
What was that?
What about you?
Gawking at us like that.
Hey, listen for a bit, Ayuhara-kun, Hayakawa-kun.
Actually, Izumi-kun…
Don't.
But…
It's no use.
There's no talking to these girls. There's no way they'd understand.
How rude.
Izumi-san, what are you doing?
Quitting the club after losing to us is just cowardice!
Lost, you say?
Hmph.
Don't make me laugh.
Do you really think I've lost to you?
What was it then?
If you think you won, feel free to take us on!
Say what you want.
The club I parted with…
…in my eyes, didn't win at all.
Whoa.
Izumi-kun.
Do you really think you can win the qualifiers without me?
Yeah.
We'll win all right.
Izumi-san. Don't make a big mistake.
We're saying this precisely because we want you back in our club.
Don't lie!
At heart, you're happy that I'm no longer there! I understand that much!
Calm down, Izumi-kun.
Kozue-chan.
Izumi-kun was, see…
I told you not to.
But…
It's okay. At any rate…
I'm looking forward to the upcoming matches.
And how will you do.
I'll be watching you very closely.
Bye.
Oh!
Wait, Izumi-kun.
Tsutomu-kun, say it.
What have you two talked about?
That's… err… see…
Nah. I really can't.
If you really need to know, get Izumi-san to say it herself.
Oh?
All right then.
I won't force you if it's too personal.
But at this rate…
…I won't be able to get over it.
Anyway.
I can say this much:
There's nothing between me and Izumi-kun.
Rather than worrying about such things…
…better focus on the upcoming matches.
Eh?
I'll come and cheer you on.
Really?
Yep. Really.
I'm looking forward to seeing your "Leaf Fall" serving technique.
Do your best.
Thanks. We will.
But…
I can't help but think about you and Izumi-san.
I'm really concerned.
You'll understand eventually.
Please have faith in me.
Well, I want to, I do.
But, right?
Let's drop it, Midori-san.
More importantly, district qualifiers start tomorrow.
We came this far. Let's forget
it
all and focus on the games.
Toukai district middle school volleyball qualifying venue
Good luck, Kawakita Middle School
Certain victory, Fujimi Academy
Do your best!
Good!
Ah!
Ahh!
Leave it to me!
Okay!
Please!
Got it!
Good, good!
Ah!
We won't lose!
Heave ho!
Fujimi
Kawakita
Matsu
Hama
Sone
Yama
Good.
Let's keep this pace.
Next time it won't be this easy.
Fujimi ・ Sone
Come on!
Keep it together!
Good luck!
Let's end this fast.
Full focus!
Don't mind, don't mind!
All right, one more! Come on come on come on!
Ahh.
– Here I go!
– Fast, fast!
Fujimi ・ Sone
Ah!
Come on.
Fujimi ・ Sone
It's strange.
Why do we struggle so much today?
Time!
What's wrong, girls.
Pull yourself together.
It's incomparable to yesterday
That's right.
But we don't understand why.
We just can't get through.
Listen.
It'll be bad if we lose the second set.
Calm down and strike carefully.
Receive precisely.
Got it?
– Yes.
– Yes sir.
Let's do this.
Get it together!
It's our come back!
Fujimi ・ Sone
Good.
But it's strange.
Suddenly we can't get anywhere.
At the same time, they put up a fierce fight exploiting our weak points.
Strange.
Something's up.
You can do it!
Good going, good going!
We made it after all.
Good we managed to stay focused.
Oh?
Izumi-san came after all?
Although we had such a fight…
In the end she stayed true to her words.
By the way, something weird happened.
Hm? Weird how?
Well, it's about Izumi-san.
Eh?
Something's up with her?
Yeah. Wait till you hear.
Yesterday, in the coffee shop near the station…
…I saw Izumi-san with the
girls from Sone Middle School.
– Strange, don't you think?
– Eh?
Very!
It's the school we're playing against now!
Well, I don't know why she did this.
But meeting with your match opponents is bizarre, no?
It truly is.
What they talked about, I wonder?
It can't be.
Even Izumi-san wouldn't do such thing.
I hope I'm wrong about Izumi-san and Sone Middle School.
But I can't shake it off.
– What the heck was that?
– Ah!
No good, no good!
With today's performance…
…we won't be able to win the qualifiers.
Tomorrow's the decisive match.
The opponent is Toukai Middle School.
They're different from the others.
If you don't improve greatly, you'll lose.
All right. Two hours of intensive training.
Got it?
Understood!
How depressing.
I'm exhausted.
What?
Kudou! Katori!
Step out.
Leave immediately.
– Eh?
– Professor!
Tomorrow, Ikezaki and Nakazawa will go.
Got it?
Yes sir.
Good.
Let's begin.
Dismissed!
Yes sir!
Sir!
All right, go!
But we sure don't need a hard fight in the qualifiers.
I wonder how it'll go.
Weird.
Something's up.
The club I parted with in my eyes didn't win at all.
Do you really think you can win the qualifiers without me?
I'll be watching you very closely.
That's it. That must be it!
Volleyball club's room
I'm off.
Bye bye!
Ah, Ozawa-san, hold on.
Ah?
What?
Hey, Ozawa-san.
Can you take me to the coffee shop where you saw Izumi-san?
Eh? That shop?
How is it?
No biggie. But I know better coffee shops.
Nah. It's all right.
I'm curious about this one.
Ayuhara-san! I want to go too.
Hey, Midori-san.
Ehehe!
You won't fool me. I figured it out fair and square.
Coffee Shop "Alice"
Eh? What was that about figuring it out?
You'll see it in a sec.
See what?
You'll see for yourself.
I'm sure they'll show up.
Who will?
Izumi-san.
Eh?!
Just as expected.
Well, that's only if my hunch is correct.
So she'll bring in Toukai girls?
Yes.
Even though it was Sone's first match today…
…they knew our weak points very well. Especially Katori-san and Kudou-san.
Wow.
So Izumi-san was spying for the enemy?
Ssh.
They're here.
She really did contact with Toukai girls.
Izumi Yuri brings in the Toukai Middle School volleyball team scheduled for the final game.
Was Izumi really a spy all along?
Kozue and Midori tremble with anger.
The match with Toukai begins.
Fujimi Academy has changed completely since yesterday.
Patience snaps and a fierce attack unleashes.
Kozue's attack shines brightly.
Meanwhile, Izumi, sitting alone in the audience chair…
…watches the girls with a glaring hatred.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.