苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかでは平気なの
Kooto no naka dewa heiki nano
…in the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ　トス　スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー　ワン・ツー　アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
だけど涙がでちゃう
Dakedo namida ga dechau
But sometimes I cry.
女の子だもん
Onna no ko damon
I'm a girl, after all.
涙も汗も若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く叫びたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック　アタック　ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
—Episode 015—
After victory
I still can't believe we won.
Me too.
Fujimigahama. Fujimigahama.
Wow, what a crowd.
Ayuhara-san!
Fujimi Academy… hooray!
Hooray!
Professor Hongou… hooray!
Ah, I'm flattered.
Ayuhara Kozue-kun… hooray!
Hooray!
Ayuhara-san!
– Ayuhara-san!
– Congratulations.
Ah, it's Ayuhara-san.
She's with Hayakawa-san.
How dreamy.
I really admire them.
Let's get an autograph.
Err…
Hm? What is it?
Please sign this.
Eh?
S-Sign? What are you saying?
Please.
She's signing it.
I'll ask them too.
Hmm.
Hayakawa Midori
Your turn, Kozue-san.
A-All right.
Excuse me…
Please sign for me too.
Me too, please.
Eh?
So cool.
Whoa, our popularity is skyrocketing now.
I don't feel like celebrating.
I don't count how many times I had to tell about our games anymore.
My mouth is all sore now.
But you're happy, aren't you.
Okay, girls. Assume positions.
Yes sir.
All right. Here we go.
Next!
Here I go!
Receive!
Come on.
What's that?
Take this.
Professor Hongou.
Hm?
Principal asked for you.
Fujimi Academy's success increased the school's prestige.
I see.
I think I'd like to keep our focus on the volleyball club.
That's fine.
Fujimi Academy's pride is our Fujimigahama's pride.
Excuse me.
Ah, professor Hongou.
This is mr. Ooyama, a member of the city council.
Thank you for your hard work.
Thank you.
Actually, mr. Ooyama invited our volleyball club for a celebration party.
We'd like to conduct it in the city hall and not only for the volleyball club - invite your friends too.
The more people the merrier.
Hehehe.
Please, take a seat. Make yourself comfortable.
All right.
Don't hesitate to ask for anything.
I will help you out as much as I can.
Thank you very much.
There's also the matter of the party time. Should I go and tell the club members?
Hm.
I guess we can cut the club activities short today.
Professor Hongou?
Ah, yes.
I'll be going then.
It's her. What are you going to do?
What am I going to do? Huh?
You have to tell her.
What do I tell her?
"Wanna be friends?" or something.
Uh…
But we're not even in the same class.
What a lost case.
You tell it because you're not in the same class.
– Come on, come on!
– Hey, don't push me.
Newspaper club
Tsutomu-kun.
Ah, just a second.
All right.
Get going already.
Hurry up and be done with it!
Good luck.
Err.
A-A-Ayuhara-san.
Hm?
Good morning.
Ah…
A-Actually, well…
Uhm…
I-I— nah, err…
Friends are nice… uh, that's not it…
I got it wrong. Well…
You see…
Looks like… I can't express myself very well… don't you think?
Err…
Oh. Ooki.
What is it?
Ah! Ichinose! It's nothing.
Excuse me. Good bye.
What was that?
Nothing important.
Never mind that, Tsutomu-kun.
Are you going to today's party?
Party?
Heh. How pathetic.
Well, you saw it, didn't you? Ichinose came along.
It was a bad timing.
Ichinose is what's bad.
You don't stand a chance with him.
Eh, we can't ever land a girl. What a disappointment.
Youth has lots of problems. It's painful.
The city's throwing a party?
Yes.
Being suddenly famous is no easy thing.
Just this morning some girls asked me for an autograph.
Autograph?
Autograph, huh?
Hey, why don't we go together?
Our practice was cut short today. Come on.
The practice was cut short?
For some party?
Yep.
Besides we're a bit tired lately.
Is that so? Too bad, I have to attend an editorial meeting.
It can't be helped then.
Ready?
Ah, it's Izumi-san.
All right, I'll invite Izumi-san instead.
– Izumi-sa—
– Don't.
Eh?
Izumi-san giving her all in the practice…
…while you're walking on air.
Oh? I'm not walking on air.
You're giving off that vibe, though.
People treat champions like stars.
Looks like it makes you feel good.
You're unkind. Besides, Tsutomu-kun, what about you?
You act like you know it all, while in reality you never did any sports.
Wh-What was that?
Am I not right? At any rate, we won the championships.
What's wrong with being treated like stars?
Eh?
Why…
What the heck are you playing volleyball for?
Was it to win contests, get capes and pennants and bask in the glory?
What's wrong with winning?
Sports exist precisely so that people can win.
Y-You're—
Ichinose-san.
Ichinose-san, what's wrong?
An, it's nothing.
Let me introduce you.
She's Nozawa Yukiko-kun, a third-year from class 2.
You're Ayuhara-san of the volleyball club, no?
Congratulations on winning.
Your success was very wonderful.
Thank you.
I'm Nozawa Yukiko of the newspaper club.
Nice to meet you.
My pleasure.
Ah, I forgot.
You wanted to sort out the notes before the editorial meeting.
Let's get going.
Please keep doing your best, Ayuhara-san.
Hold on, Ichinose-san.
I bask in the glory after winning the championship?
That's not true at all.
One. Two. One. Two.
All right.
Keep at it.
Let's see more vigor.
What's with you?
Cheer up.
Kozue-san.
Kozue-san, why are you spacing out?
We need to hurry up and change, or we'll be late to the party.
Ah, let's invite Izumi-san and the girls too.
They won't be going.
Why?
Say, what are you going to wear?
There will be lots of city people, right?
What would be good, I wonder?
It can't be too flashy, I guess.
I can't really decide what to put on…
Yeah.
Fujimi Academy girls volleyball club All-Japan championships celebration venue
Well then, I'd like to say a word before we open the celebration party.
The victory the Fujimi Academy's volleyball club girls have seized…
…doesn't bring glory only to the Fujimi Academy.
It also promotes our Fujimigahama city across the whole Japan.
It can be said they made a great contribution to the city development.
Seeing how much Fujimi Academy's volleyball club girls have accomplished…
…no matter how much one praises them, one can't praise too much.
That's right.
We achieved this glory with our own hands.
All right, let's begin.
Okay. Next!
Next!
– I wonder if I can pass it?
– I'm anxious.
Ah, damn.
Oh dear.
I heard there will be lots of people wanting to join our club, but I never imagined this many.
It's only natural. We're the best in Japan.
But this selection is a lot of work.
It can't be helped.
It's the price for our fame.
Hehe.
Okay, two-two-three, three-two-three.
Put all your heart into it.
Good.
Good. It's enough.
Sorry for the bother, professor Nakajima.
We're using the gym again.
Ah, it's okay.
But today is gymnastics club's practice.
We're in the same sports section. I'll gladly cooperate with you.
How is the selection going?
It's quite a chore.
But it's a wonderful thing.
I'm not sure.
What's wrong?
It feels like school festival.
Hm?
I'd rather the students stayed more focused.
Be patient. There's not much we can do.
I don't want to be too much of a nag to them.
But I also want to raise them as well as possible.
Volleyball club's room
Ah, it's over.
Finally.
I'm tired like after practice.
By welcoming the new club members, our Fujimi Academy's volleyball club…
…manages to struggle through yet another crisis.
Hehe.
Hey, captain.
With all the new members this room will get cramped.
You're right.
Besides, there's the issue of practice time.
There wasn't enough time even just for us.
Really.
Yeah.
We have to use the gym in turns with the table tennis and gymnastics clubs.
Yeah…
Accepting all the new members will be meaningless if we don't even have the time to practice.
– Yeah.
– Captain, we need to do something.
Yep.
Captain, we're counting on you.
All for our newly expanded club.
– We're counting on you.
– Please.
Is that everyone's conclusion?
Let's ask the principal and the
vice-principal about a new club room.
Who knows what they will say.
However, Ayuhara, what about the gym practices?
You say you need it no matter what, but what about the table tennis and the gymnastics clubs?
That's…
What will we do, Ayuhara?
That's… that can't be helped.
Hm?
Even if the table tennis and gymnastics clubs' practice time gets cut, it can't be helped.
Our volleyball club has won in the All-Japan championships.
We also want to protect our title in the future.
I don't want to say I don't care what happens to the other clubs.
But even if we cause some inconvenience, it can't be helped.
Can't be helped, huh.
I see. Very well.
Professor Hongou wants to talk about the volleyball club.
Creating a new club room should fit in the club budget.
I see. That's good.
Even as an academic institution, it's natural to emphasize the volleyball club.
Since the expenses will come out not only in the new club room, but also in the future…
…I think that I will review this club's budget.
Hm. However, it might turn out it's not possible to increase the budget.
We're supposed to receive grant money from the city, aren't we?
The aid money is to be used only in an emergency case where we deplete our current budget.
Of course, with the focus on the volleyball club.
Because of this, we might be forced to examine the clubs themselves.
Hmm.
Watch out!
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
I only slipped.
We're getting really hurt now that we practice outdoors.
If we can't do it in the gym, we shouldn't practice at all in my opinion.
She gave our gym to the Japan's best volleyball club.
Prof. Nakajima has a weak spot for prof. Hongou, no?
What is it, girls?
Hm?
Let's hear it.
We were talking about how the gymnastics club should practice in a gym.
No?
We're practicing at the gym too.
We're only doing it outdoors when we're out of time.
Until now, we were practicing inside.
That's right.
But volleyball club's practice time was lengthened.
Are you saying that because they're the Japan's best, it can't be helped, prof. Nakajima?
No one says such things.
They got many freshmen recently.
It's only natural to lengthen their practice time.
Do you understand?
Those who can only practice in the gym can stop coming to the practices outdoors.
Sports should be done only by people capable of it.
All right. Next.
Good.
Next!
See? You join your hands like this.
Ayuhara-san.
What is it?
I'm Takahashi of the table tennis club.
I came here to ask you about the practice time.
The new practice times are a little short for our club.
Because of that…
I don't know what to say to you.
We asked professor Hongou and it was decided as a result of the staff meeting.
I understand it well, but…
I can't speak for the others.
Hey, you can practice outdoors, can't you?
Even the gymnastics club can do it.
In that case, the same goes to your volleyball club, no?
Oh? An attack already?
Don't get cocky just because you're champions.
Nobody's getting cocky.
But us being champions is just a sign of our skill.
We don't even have a coach.
We're lacking club members, too.
Don't take us lightly just because of that.
Kobayashi-san.
I'm fine.
We absolutely need that much of the practice time.
Hmph. We're going.
Excuse us.
They only came to make us nervous. What a jealous bunch.
All right, practice, practice.
Ayuhara. Something's wrong?
Eh? Nah.
Professor, actually…
I'm going to Tokyo Volleyball Association tomorrow.
I should be back in two-three days.
Volleyball Association?
Why are you going?
To discuss about your game schedule and some other things.
Who are we playing against next?
It's not fully decided yet.
Come on. Practice time.
Yes sir.
Here I go.
Looks like the table tennis club gets disbanded, Ayuhara-kun.
Huh?
The cause seems to be the low member count and their poor results in the contests.
I see.
So?
"So?" I came here to get your opinion.
I don't have anything to say.
Really?
What do you want me to say?
That the table tennis club fell victim to us?
I don't mean that.
Hm. Very well then.
Bye.
H-Hey.
Even if they fell victim to us, it can't be helped.
Let's do it again.
Ready?
Go!
Huh.
Good, good.
One more lapse.
We'll aim for a new contest record.
Got it? Don't lose to the volleyball club.
Okay, here I go!
Good going. Pass it to me.
What's wrong?
Here goes.
Shoot!
Idiot!
Think we can win in the game like this?
Lose and you'll be like the table tennis club.
We need to win. Real games are all about winning!
Got it.
It's nice that our victory has given people a motivation.
But for the table tennis club to get disbanded?
Ayuhara-san.
Is something the matter?
Ah, professor Nakajima.
Everything is fine. Thank you.
I see.
Do you not know if professor Hongou is back yet?
He's still out.
I understand.
Ayuhara-san.
You're thinking of something, aren't you?
Why don't you do as your heart tells you to?
Professor Hongou cannot coach your own thoughts.
When the game starts and you enter the court, you, the captain, is the judge. You direct everyone.
Tennis table club
Kozue-kun.
I want to show you something.
Please come with me.
This is the place.
Huh?
It's the end of the table tennis club.
Right in this cottage.
Just like a piece of junk.
Takahashi, even after his club got disbanded, continues to play as it's his favorite activity.
Ichinose-san.
Ah, Nozawa-kun. What is it?
Uhm…
It's okay. You can speak before Ayuhara-kun.
It's about the sports section budgets.
No matter how much they spend on the volleyball club, they shouldn't disband the table tennis club.
Here is the budget for each club.
People like Takahashi…
…just do what they love the most. Isn't it a true sportsmanship?
I think it's the essence of the sports.
What is considered true sports?
I think I'll get involved with the table tennis club and cover their story in our newspaper.
Why don't you help us out, Ayuhara-san?
There's no way you wouldn't know sports true nature.
Sports is not a theory.
You don't understand sports at all.
Coach Hongou, after announcing a practice game with the Soviet team…
…challenges the club with the question: "why are you playing?".
"I won't coach you until you're able to answer this question."
Meanwhile, the club, unable to hold enough practice…
…asks the school for a dedicated gym.
Tsutomu strongly criticizes the club's actions in the school newspaper.
Kozue finds an ally in Mitamura of the football club, who hits Tsutomu.
Please look forward to the next episode.
青い青い空に
Aoi aoi sora ni
Up in the blue, blue sky…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
はずむボールが
Hazumu booru ga
The bouncing ball is up there…
夢をえがく
Yume wo egaku
…painting my dreams.
明日の太陽
Ashita no taiyou
The sun tomorrow goes…
バンボンボボン
Ban bonbobon
…bounce-bounce-bounce.
サーブ　レシーブ　トス
Saabu reshiibu tosu
Serve. Receive. Toss.
ジャンプ　スパイク　アタック
Janpu supaiku atakku
Jump. Spike. Attack.
六つのハートが一つに燃える
Muttsu no haato ga hitotsu ni moeru
The six hearts burn as one.