Attack No. 1
Fujimi Academy's New Star
苦しくたって
Kurushiku tatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashiku tatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかではへいきなの
Kooto no naka de wa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ  トス  スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・トゥー  ワン・トゥー  アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
涙も汗も 若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く さけびたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック  アタック  No.1
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック  アタック  No.1
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
苦しくたって
Kurushiku tatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashiku tatte
…even though I feel sad…
チームの仲間が いるんだもん
Chiimu no nakama ga irundamon
…I have my team mates.
ホイッスルがなると 心がはずむわ
Hoissuru ga naru to kokoro ga hazumu wa
I find myself whistling and my heart races.
レシーブ  トス  スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー  ワン・ツー  アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
涙の中に若い心で
Namida no naka ni wakai kokoro de
Showing fighting spirit through the tears…
ながれゆく雲にさけびたい
Nagareyuku kumo ni sakebitai
…looking at billowing clouds, I just want to scream:
アタック  アタック  No.1
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック  アタック  No.1
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
Fujimi Academy
Math
Ayuhara-kun.
Hey.
Ayuhara-kun?
Ayuhara-san, get it together.
What is it, Ikezaki-san?
Sir.
I know you just transferred here, but what's with your attitude?
Huh? What do you mean?
If my class bores you so much, go sleep in the infirmary.
Yes sir.
Ayuhara-kun!
She surprised me.
She has some nerve acting like this.
Infirmary
By Meihou Academy you mean that prestigious institute in Tōkyō?
Yes.
That's why I've had high expectations for having Ayuhara-san transfer here.
Bad call. She doesn't even come to class.
What do you think, professor Hongou?
Well, simply put, she does whatever she wants.
But I don't think we should chase every student and tell them what to do.
Ah.
Ayuhara-san, we've been waiting for you.
Make yourself comfortable. Take a seat.
Err…
Do you need anything from me?
You did well, Ayuhara-san.
What did I do?
The way you stuck it to His Majesty.
We couldn't believe our ears. Right, Ofuku?
Yep.
Say, why don't we become friends?
What kind of friends?
People call us the useless and delinquents.
In reality, we're just a free and cheerful group.
We want to be friends.
We could achieve something together.
It's decided.
– Let's go!
– Yahoo!
Come on, dance!
Kakko!
Someone's here.
This is bad. Party's over.
Ayuhara-kun, I presume?
You're well informed.
Well, you're pretty famous.
And you are…?
I'm Ichinose.
Kashiwagi-kun was here just a moment ago, wasn't she?
I'm not going to say anything bad, but don't hang out with such people.
It's none of your business.
You are the Vice Chairman of the Student Council, right?
Let me make myself clear: I hate Fujimi Academy.
Some school I've transferred into.
Ayuhara-kun!
Same goes to Fujimi Academy. You trouble us with your behavior.
– Ken?
– Ken!
– How do you know Ken?
Tsutomu-san is my nephew.
Kozue is my niece, on my husband's side.
Is it clear?
What? This means—
…we're actually related.
Wah, so cold.
Of course it is.
But I love the waves so much.
Taking a long, long time, they eventually wear down their obstacles.
Waves are remarkable.
So wonderful.
Let me change the topic… say, why do you skip classes?
I don't really want to skip them, but…
Motivation just doesn't seem to come.
When I don't have a goal, I
don't feel like doing anything.
Come on, you can do better.
– Do your best.
– Okay.
– All right, here goes the serve.
– I'm ready.
Good luck!
She's here again.
Your jump is not high enough. Let's try once again.
Got it.
Here goes!
– Ah!
– Look out!
Hold on.
You're Ayuhara-san, right?
Yes.
You come every here since you've transferred.
You're here to watch our practices, right?
Yes…
Why don't you join our club?
I think I'll pass.
I want her to join us so much…
What's with her?
So cheeky.
But I need to admit it was pretty good receive.
It seems your go-go dancing was discussed at today's staff meeting.
It will be a problem if you don't behave.
I refuse, Vice Chairman.
Why?
Both teachers and you look at Kashiwagi-san's group with prejudice.
You assume everything they don't understand must be bad.
If they tried it, they might have fun.
See for yourself.
Naka, radio!
All right!
Yahoo!
How was it, Tsutomu-san?
Wanna try it?
Awesome!
Ayuhara-san, you're made to be our chief!
Ayuhara-san.
Oh?
Katsuragi-san asked me to find you.
Find me?
Katsuragi-san says she really wants you to join our club.
After seeing your receive yesterday, she's sure you've got what it takes.
It's your chance. You should take it.
I'm sorry, but I'd rather hang out with these girls rather than play volleyball with you.
Besides, that club is, well…
Huh?
Hm, how should I put it?
What do you mean, Ayuhara-san?
Nothing particular. Only that I'm disappointed with your practice.
Excuse me.
Let's go, girls.
Ayuhara-san.
Hase-san and Hara-san told me.
You insulted our volleyball club.
I don't think I've ever insulted you.
Ayuhara-san, don't lie to us.
I am not lying to anyone.
I've only spoken the truth.
Ah, you seem to be pretty confident about volleyball.
Why don't we test you?
Test me?
Yeah. It's going to be rough, though.
Are you ready?
Yes!
– Hara-san!
– Here!
Whoa.
Keep going. Don't stop now.
What a girl.
All right…
That was low!
Attack!
Hey, what are you doing to our captain?
Captain was st—
Hey! Right back at you, what were you doing to Ayuhara-san?
What now? Your delinquent bunch isn't welcome here.
Now you've said it.
Am I mistaken?
Aren't you the trash of Fujimi Academy?
– What the hell?
– You know I'm right!
Calm down, Naka.
His Majesty is watching.
If you've got a problem, I'm listening.
But we're not delinquents. We won't fight with you.
Of course we can always compete in sports, though.
We'll do this.
Do… what?
We'll win with you in a match.
We, the "delinquents", the "useless group"!
Hmph. Don't make me laugh.
Volleyball can't be played alone.
I know. We'll hold the match one month from now.
Interesting. Truly interesting.
Wanna do this?
Yeah!
Chief, what's gotten into you?
It's reckless. We don't even know the rules.
We can do it. We can do it!
Keep it together.
One-two! One-two!
I can't take it anymore.
This is nothing yet.
Come on, stand up.
– It hurts.
– I've had enough too.
This won't get you anywhere. Come on, stand up.
Hey, how about we run somewhere else without sand?
While it'd feel easier, running on sand is the best for training your legs.
Now, one more lapse to the lighthouse.
Eh!? That far…?
Shock…
Get it together. Our opponents are volleyball club's regulars.
If we admit defeat here, we'll never win.
Yeah.
It's just as the chief says. Let's keep at it until we pass out.
Well then, let's go!
Ah… wait…
It's no good.
Let's go.
Okay.
Keep at it.
Come on.
I see.
By the way, volleyball club's practice seems to be more intense lately.
That's because they don't want to lose to the Kashiwagi-Nakazawa's group.
But why is Ayuhara Kozue staying with these delinquents, I wonder.
One-two! One-two!
All right. From today we'll focus on handling the ball.
There's only one rule to winning.
It's practice. Practice. Practice!
Yep.
Okay then, here we go.
Ah, ow-ow-ow.
That's no good.
Listen.
No matter the circumstances,
if you lift the ball, it's a foul play.
Always play with your fingertips.
Yep.
Okay, Ofuku, let's pair up.
Okay.
– Debu, let's go!
– Okay!
It hurts.
Today we'll focus on serving and receiving.
In 6-player system, you only get one serve,
so aim to hit the ball into the opponents court.
– Got it?
– Yeah.
Keep it up, keep it up!
Stand up, stand up!
One more!
It doesn't look all that dangerous.
Ah. It's the volleyball club.
They came to spy on us for sure.
Don't pay attention to them.
All right, let's begin.
– Professor Hongou.
– Hm?
They're really giving their best, don't you think?
Yes. Ever since Ayuhara-kun started coaching volleyball…
…their diligence in the classroom and their grades have improved.
Perhaps the volleyball will get those girls back on the right track.
I'm looking forward to it.
Professor.
As her homeroom teacher, I'm
taking my hat off to Ayuhara-san.
Let's not engage yet and keep watching over her.
They seem to be set on winning with the volleyball club.
Right, professor Nakajima?
Keep going.
Yeah!
We won't lose!
Their spirit is what lets them learn so quickly.
We'll win.
We'll win for sure!
Teachers room
I am secretly looking forward to the today's match.
Me too, actually.
Today we'll see how far can
the bad-performing students go.
The game is about to start.
Shall we go?
All right, Ayuhara-san.
– Are you ready?
– Yes, we are.
Ayuhara-san, even if we didn't do this match,
the result is obvious. Let's make it a one-set game.
The match hasn't even started.
But fine, if that's how you want to play.
Begin the match.
Good luck, everyone!
Yeah!
I'm sorry!
Don't mind, don't mind!
Here they go!
Attack!
Keep it together.
This is bad. Without Kashiwagi-san, we'll lose the match.
Let's kick their butts!
Keep the serve!
Catch!
How is it, "chief" Ayuhara?
Listen, girls. It'll be fine. Calm down.
Left!
What is it, useless team?
You're here to play, right?
But you didn't show us anything yet.
What's wrong?
I guess Ayuhara-kun hadn't any chances.
You can't blame her.
We'll lose at this rate.
We need a comeback.
Time!
Girls, listen closely.
What's wrong?
This isn't even 10% of the energy you showed at practice.
Chief, this is unfamiliar.
Isn't it all in your heads?
We haven't even started the struggle.
Your strength is plenty enough.
What's left is the willpower.
The willpower?
I have a strategy. Come closer.
Hurry up, what are we waiting for?
Let's go!
What are you doing? It's shameful for our club to be scared with this.
Resume the match.
Let's stop them.
Okay!
Right!
Attack!
Pretty cool!
Keep it up!
One more!
You can do it!
Captain, watch out!
Kashiwagi-san!
Leave it to me!
Here I go!
Good, good!
Do your best!
Out!
Ofuku!
Nice, nice, useless team! Keep it up!
Hmm, they seem to go at it.
It's frustrating.
All right, one last push.
You're mine!
Damn!
Hara-san!
Ah, damn!
It's our chance! Toss it to me!
Attack!
The match ends. Ayuhara team wins.
– Nice, nice!
– Awesome!
Great!
We won.
I'm so happy.
We actually won.
You did well, girls.
They were amazing.
Truly amazing…
Chief…
Ayuhara-san, thank you.
This is the first time I get to feel like this.
Same goes for me.
I never seriously considered sports, and now look at me…
Everyone did their best.
I'm so glad.
– Ayuhara-san.
– Eh?
Oh?
What's this?
We've completely lost.
You're not useless at all. You were splendid.
We're embarrassed that we made fun of you until now.
We apologize.
My.
We've also got a favor to ask.
We want all of you to join the volleyball club.
Huh?
The volleyball club has only seniors now.
If we had second year students
too, we would grow stronger.
Yeah. Us seniors have many things around the
corner, so we can't give the practice our all.
Ayuhara-san, what are we going to do?
Isn't it all right?
Let's join the volleyball club together.
This is a chance for us.
Yeah. I'll do it.
Yep. Me too.
I'll join too.
I'm joining too.
I'll be hungry all the time, I bet.
Just make up your mind.
Do you join? Do you not?
I'll join, I'll join with you.
My figure will improve for sure.
Moreover we want you, Ayuhara-san, to be our captain.
Huh? Me, a captain?
Does anybody oppose?
Of course we agree!
It's decided then.
Ayuhara-san.
Since a long time, this jersey was used by the captain of the volleyball club.
Let us see you in it.
It suits you well.
New captain.
So cool!
Thank you. Let's all work together.
New captain.
– Katsuragi-san.
– Ayuhara-san.
How wonderful.
I'm so glad I'm able to play volleyball.
I also met new friends.
Together with everyone, dreaming of sparkling future not unlike the stars in that night sky.
Volleyball club's room
Ah, you're here so early?
Ayuhara-san, there's a letter to our club.
Here.
Oh? Katsuragi-san, why do you not open it?
The club's matters are resolved by the captain.
My.
What do you think it is?
Listen, everyone.
It's an invitation to Toukai district middle school volleyball championship.
It's a chance for our new members to shine.
Good, now we have a goal. Let's do it.
Practice, practice!
Let's not waste time and go to the court.
Yeah!
Oh?
What are they doing?
It's strange. Let's check it out.
Such an accurate spike…
Almost like a machine.
Are you the new captain,
Ayuhara Kozue-san?
– Midori! Midori, is it you?
– Kakko!
I've transferred today.
My dad's company moved him here, to Fujimi.
Ah. Long time no see.
How many years has it been?
Hayakawa Midori-san and I were in the same class in the grade school.
We were in the fifth class, I think.
If I remember, she then moved to Kyōtō.
But who would've think Kakko and Naka would enter a volleyball club.
I've just started, so I'm not any good yet.
But you're something else, Midori. We just saw you.
Really. It's my first time seeing someone this good.
I've been playing ever since I went to Kyōtō.
But…
…this much should be easy for Ayuhara-san.
Well, I'd have to try.
There's no way you couldn't do it.
After all, Ayuhara-san, you're the captain, right?
Huh?
If you don't mind, I'd like to join the volleyball club.
Hey, captain!
Volleyball club's new captain!
Ah, Tsutomu-san.
Did something happen?
You seem down.
No, it's nothing.
Tired from the practice?
The tournament's schedule was decided, wasn't it?
It'd be troublesome if the new captain wasn't into it.
You have to do your best to win the championship.
– Hey, Tsutomu-san.
– Hm?
What is it?
Tsutomu-san!
Ah, it's Midori-san.
Let me introduce you.
Oh. Ayuhara-san.
What, you know yourselves already?
Yes. I entered the volleyball club today.
I've already greeted captain Ayuhara-san.
That's how it was.
Tsutomu-san, you're not in Ayuhara-san's class, but I feel that you get along well.
Yeah. To tell you the truth, we're related.
My aunt, which is my mom's younger sister,
is married to Ayuhara-kun's father's younger brother.
In other words, her uncle.
Understand? It's a little roundabout, but we're certainly related.
Oh, that was it?
Hey, Ayuhara-san, I've known Tsutomu-san ever since kindergarten.
We had reputation of being good friends at elementary school.
Teachers room
Thank you very much.
Nah, don't mention it.
I thought we should put an effort into the sport clubs as well.
The school is mostly about academic achievements.
But yes, putting some effort into club victories should be good.
If they do win, it might increase the school's prestige.
I will do my best.
We will certainly win the tournament.
There's no way we'll lose.
Thank you, Hayakawa-san.
It's wonderful that we can practice here.
Ah, for being able to practice here?
It's only natural.
It's all for the victory in the tournament.
Now, let's practice.
You better do you best too.
I heard about your reputation of the "useless group".
Don't say that, it makes my ears hurt.
That's an old story. We're different now.
Exactly! We're serious now.
That's because of volleyball, right?
Yep. It's thanks to volleyball.
That's not it, isn't it?
Huh?
Then what is it?
If it wasn't for Ayuhara-san, you'd get expelled from the school, no?
Eh!? Who said that?
I heard that from Ayuhara-san.
– Captain did?
– I never said such thing.
Ayuhara-san, it's okay to be open about this.
Haven't you told me it earlier?
But…
I… I really didn't.
We do owe Ayuhara-san.
– But expulsion…?
– That's cruel.
Yes, it's just heartless.
What's the meaning of this?
Everyone, let it be.
If we win the tournament, let's just forget it.
Let's practice.
Hmph! Stick it.
Everyone, be serious. Toss the ball.
Hayakawa-san, here goes.
Here!
That's… that's terrible.
I don't think you're such a person.
Yeah, me neither.
Midori was like that since elementary school.
She's wealthy, alone and selfish.
Huh…
Listen, everyone.
The Fujimi Academy hasn't won a match even once.
I want a team that is a capable of winning the upcoming tournament.
I also think that we need a resolute captain.
Hayakawa-san would be good.
We'd get far with under Midori, don't you think?
Yeah.
What are you saying?
You have some nerve saying that.
Who do you think gathered us here?
Have you forgotten already!?
Even so, Ayuhara-san said all those thing—
Do you really think our captain would do that?
Midori, what on earth are you scheming?
Stop being so egocentric.
If you only think about yourself, you'll trip soon enough, Midori.
Hey, it's about time you said something!
Kashiwagi-san.
It's okay already.
But she…
Hayakawa-san.
I'm giving up my captain title.
Ayuhara-san!
Ayuhara-san, don't get me wrong.
I wanted to be the captain, but that's not what I've asked the vice principal for.
I'm only thinking of the volleyball club.
Also it's not up to oneself to become or quit being a captain.
It's a decision of everyone.
Ayuhara-kun.
Here you are.
I came all the way from home.
Do you need anything?
I heard you resigned.
Everyone heard.
Kashiwagi-san is really worried about you.
People like Midori-san are restless since their childhoods until they're treated like a queen.
That's the truth of it.
I see.
But why does she want to become a captain so much?
I'd be fine if I wasn't captain.
Don't talk like that. It's not like you.
I could probably talk her out of it.
However, it'd be better if
you resolved it by yourself.
With the tournament around the corner, it's the most important time for your club.
What's wrong, new captain?
Get a grip!
Haven't you found your purpose in the volleyball club?
Or did you lose your motivation already?
Quit volleyball!
Quit!?
Well, with the way you're now…
I still have the patience for this.
What would happen if we had a fight now?
Volleyball club will end.
I love volleyball.
That's why even if Hayakawa-san did become a captain, I'd still be okay with it.
I'm home.
To Ayuhara Kozue-sama
Who left it here?
There's no stamp. It must have been delivered directly.
"Ayuhara-san."
"I want to talk with you alone."
"Please meet me at 7 AM at the volleyball club's room."
Hayakawa-san, huh?
I wonder what she wants to talk to me about this time?
Hayakawa-san!
Why are we here so early?
I forgot to lock the door yesterday.
I realized only this morning.
It'd be bad if our equipment was stolen, and this is why I've asked you to come.
Volleyball club's room
It is unlocked all right.
Ah.
Ayuhara-san!
Ayuhara-san, what are you doing here so early?
You come at the right moment. Look at this.
How terrible!
The net is torn too.
Who would do such a thing?
Someone who hates volleyball club.
Ayuhara-san, what is this?
Eh?
This? It was lying here. They probably used this.
Ayuhara-san, you're pretty dreadful person.
Huh? What are you talking about?
Ayuhara-san, you're holding a
grudge against me.
Is that right?
Eh?
Ha-Ha-Hayakawa-san, are you saying it was me?
No matter how big I hold the grudge against you,
I'd never destroy important equipment.
What?
I'm finished listening to our captain.
Aren't you, everyone?
Don't you think the title of captain doesn't fit Ayuhara-san?
Hey, girls.
I'm disappointed in you.
I didn't think you're such a person.
What's so funny?
Hayakawa-san, do you want to
become the captain this bad?
If that's the case, just say so openly!
Don't resort to writing some roundabout letters.
What's with that look?
Are you trying to weasel your way out of this by framing me?
Ayuhara-san, I think it's clear that you don't deserve the title of captain.
Let's go, everyone.
Yep.
Let's go, let's go.
Hayakawa-san really should be our captain.
Look at me, trying to do my best for the club…
Okay, throw me a lot!
Hayakawa-san's practicing all by herself.
What about us?
We want to practice too.
Well then, let us begin too.
I've been waiting for this!
All right, don't hold back.
Yeah, let's go.
Wait, I'm not through my own practice yet.
Eh?
I think you've practiced enough already.
But the match is just the day after tomorrow.
That's precisely why – it's meaningless if you get good only by yourself.
Do you have a problem with my methods?
I do.
Me too.
I am the captain here.
I've been chosen by everyone's free will.
That's why we're going to have it my way.
Toukai district middle school volleyball championship
City Gym
As expected from a strong candidate.
It sure is lively.
Go! Go! Mikawa!
Of course, the strength is the most important, but at such times I'd want better cheering party.
You can't blame them, we're very weak compared to Mikawa.
What do you know? Our Fujimi Academy has Ayuhara-san and Hayakawa-san.
Nah, we have no chance of winning.
What did you say?
Ah, professor Hongou.
It's futile. It doesn't matter if their opponent is Mikawa or whoever. They won't win.
Here I go!
Hayakawa-san, calm down.
I know.
S-Strange.
She's been always so good.
Hayakawa-san, what's your experience in actual matches?
Matches? Today is my first match.
Eh? Th-The first?
Yeah. Everyone was too scared to become my partner.
I see. After you've pulled that one man show in the
gym, it didn't occur to you to ask anyone for help.
Shut it. My volleyball won't be defeated.
No one will defeat me.
Mikawa ・ Fujimi
Hayakawa-san!
Ayuhara-san!
Damn it. It got completely one-sided.
I can't watch it.
They're gonna lose.
Keep the serve! Let's go!
She did it!
Attack!
Saw that, Hayakawa-san?
This is the real game. This is how we fight.
After all, we only got three
points thanks to Ayuhara-san. Too bad.
We have been losing until now,
but I
thought we stood a chance just this once.
Hey. Are you saying this is my fault?
Eh?
You're trying to drive me out, no?
No… that's not true…
This is your first game. No one blames you.
What are you saying? That's not the problem here.
If only… If only you did better, we could have easily won this.
Knock it off, Hayakawa-san.
What do you think volleyball is?
It's a team sport.
Oh my, Ayuhara-san. Are you really going to start preaching here?
It seems you don't know much about volleyball.
A strong volleyball team must have outstanding players.
I agree. But outstanding means doing what it
takes in the critical moments.
And that is not you.
You're just looking for attention.
Hey, take it easy.
We're on the bus.
Principal's room
Oh?
You want to be a volleyball coach?
Yes, sir.
But do you have any experience with volleyball?
No, sir.
But I have played baseball in the college.
Principal, even without experience,
I am confident I can be a good coach.
The volleyball club as of now is certainly divided.
But under my coaching, they're sure to get back on the right track.
Hmm, I can't help but wonder about that.
Ah, never mind, if you say so then I guess it's okay.
Which means that you agree, right?
Thank you very much, sir.
But please let it me do things my way.
All right.
The remaining problem is Ayuhara and Hayakawa.
I'll certainly reconcile them.
Ah, I'm done with the cleaning.
– Ayuhara-san.
– Yes?
– Have you heard?
– Eh? About what?
They've decided on our coach.
It's professor Hongou.
Reall— ah…
Are you sure?
Let's see for ourselves.
Yep, let's go!
Hey!
What were you doing?
S-Sir. We've been cleaning.
Too slow!
You get 30 minutes tops.
No exceptions.
That goes to you too.
Listen. Volleyball isn't kids' play.
As long as I'm your coach, I
don't intend to go easy on you.
Those who have a problem with that, quit the club at once!
Huh? I didn't knew him from that side.
I get it, I get it.
It's the "look, I'm serious" part.
Furthermore I'll be deciding the captain.
Until my decision, there's no captain.
I won't lose.
I'll win. I have to.
Ah, it's no use…
I'm not done yet…
Hey, who said you can rest?
Stand up! Stand up at once!
I'm sorry, sir.
Heave-ho.
I've had enough.
No matter what happens, I can not lose to Hayakawa-san.
I can't lose to Ayuhara-san.
No way I'll lose!
All right, here we go.
Come on, come on!
You're defeated from this much?
Once more, be ready!
Okay, next!
More!
Come on!
Get it together!
Hey!
What's with that?
Next!
Let's go!
All right, everyone's fired up.
Principal's room
We received a complaint from
the Parent-Teacher Association, too.
They're saying that your training is too harsh.
I'd like to have you put your excessive energy into something more useful.
Is that so?
But for the students, club activities are a way to
learn things about life that textbooks don't offer.
Hmm.
That's a naive point of view.
As expected from a young teacher.
At any rate, the PTA complaint is a huge problem.
I'd like to resolve this by all m—
But you agreed for me to use my methods.
That's the problem, you see.
It's those "methods" of yours.
The students are backing away, aren't they?
Am I not correct?
Please think it over, professor Hongou.
All right. Understood.
Really?
Is that so.
It's fine then.
If the students definitely oppose to my coaching…
…I'll step down.
Next!
Fool!
If you can't do even such a simple receive,
you'll need special training.
We'll fix this right now!
Eh?
Here we go!
Ikezaki-san!
We've not even started!
More, more!
What's wrong?
– Ah!
– Ikezaki-san!
Hey!
Please stop it!
What is it?
Do you disagree with my coaching so much?
We're not your dolls, professor.
– Yeah!
– Let's go home.
Wait a moment.
Actually, it was decided you'll play a
practice match tomorrow.
If you can win that game, I can step down as your coach.
But your opponent is Matsushima Middle School.
How's that? Can you win?
If you win, good. If you lose,
you'll acknowledge the need for more training.
Expect it to be stricter than now.
You'll step down, coach?
That's correct.
You finally have a chance to get back at me.
How will it be?
We accept.
Okay then, do your best.
We'll do it.
City Gym
Here goes!
Got it!
Me!
You did it.
Katsuragi-san, give us a good serve.
Leave it to me.
Someone!
I'll get it!
Me!
Fujimi ・ Matsushima
Time!
Nice spike, Hayakawa-san.
Hayakawa-san's showing her bad habit again.
However, it seems to work.
Looks like we can pull it off.
Listen, keep close to the ball.
That last toss was a close call.
Keep tossing to me.
Eh? That was for Ayuhara-san.
Hm.
The problem starts here.
They're getting better and that's a fact.
This will probably drive them to start taking Matsushima lightly.
That strategy time can cost them everything.
Ayuhara-san!
Me!
Good, good! Keep it up!
Great!
Hayakawa-san, you're marked.
What now? Just one more point. It'll be all right.
Kakko!
Got it!
Leave it to me!
Fujimi ・ Matsushima
Keep it up!
We had a lead just a second ago.
Too bad, but this set goes to you.
At this rate we might lose the second set as well.
We have to do something.
This is where the coach should come up with an advice.
But with our coach…
It's a pinch.
But you can survive this.
If you do, your enemies will respect your power.
You did well.
Marking Hayakawa was a success. Now they'll surely switch to Ayuhara.
Yeah.
Mark these two thoroughly until the end.
Got it?
– Yes sir.
This is embarrassing, but I'm thoroughly marked.
I'd like to try to attack in turns with Ayuhara-san.
What do you think?
Yeah. It's not like we have other options.
Yeah. Sounds like it's going to work.
Don't you think?
All right. Let's try alternating our attacks.
After all, if we lose this set, we lose the match.
Good luck!
Okay!
Midori!
Ah, I'm sorry!
Referee, time!
Ayuhara-kun asked for time.
I wonder what strategy she comes up with.
Hayakawa-san, listen carefully.
Me and you are completely marked.
I know that already.
Plus their block is impenetrable.
Their form is at its best, too.
Finally their coach knows our weak points very well.
The question is who attacks next.
They already know from the toss alone whether it's Hayakawa-san or me who hits the ball.
Right?
A-And…?
Now, if we destroy their focus, we destroy their defense.
We need to break that focus.
Yes but how?
First, me and Hayakawa-san move away from the ball, then we swiftly attack.
Come closer, everyone.
Looks like Ayuhara-san's plan is settled.
All right, let's go.
Attack!
There it is!
The attack duo!
Huh?
Here I go!
Nice, nice!
Attack!
Fujimi ・ Matsushima
Professor, the tables have turned. It's the set point.
Ayuhara-san, awesome!
We got to the final set.
They're amazing, don't you think, professor?
Ayuhara and Hayakawa managed to form a duo.
With this, their team should be safe.
I don't need to see the last set to know the outcome.
They'll win for sure.
But no matter how strong we are, if we aren't united, we won't accomplish anything.
I'll keep my promise. I'll withdraw from coaching.
Fujimi ・ Matsushima
All right, match point. Do your best.
Okay!
– Good luck, girls!
– Yeah!
Chance!
Attack!
We won. It's our victory.
Don't be sad about this loss.
Let's do our best to defeat Fujimi Academy in the future.
Got it?
– Yes sir.
– Yeah.
We'll do our best.
We'll get back at them for sure.
That's the spirit. That's our Matsushima's volleyball club.
– Yes sir.
From now, let's do our best!
Fight!
– Yeah!
Hey, we won.
What is it, everyone?
It's nothing.
But seeing them united with their coach so well… I'm a little jealous.
That's all there is to it.
What is it, Hayakawa-san?
– What?
– Huh?
Ayuhara-san.
I need to settle this with you.
In front of the others, too.
Eh? Do you still intend to fight?
Girls, you too listen.
For a while, I've been thinking about
the importance of the teamwork to volleyball.
Hayakawa-san…
This time I finally saw it clearly and it clicked.
Ayuhara-san.
I was completely mistaken.
I won't ask for your pardon, because I don't think I can be forgiven…
Let's end this.
Make yourself feel better. Slap me all you want.
I'm sorry. I lost my cool.
Thank you, Ayuhara-san.
I'm relieved.
With this we finally become proper team mates.
I'm really happy you're saying this.
But there's another thing I want to settle here.
There's more?
Yeah. It's just my opinion.
I think that our Fujimi Academy volleyball club's captain can be no one other than you, Ayuhara-san.
What do you think, girls?
I agree. I completely agree.
I think it's for the best too.
– Agreed.
Will you do it?
I will. Let's aim for the Japan's top.
Hayakawa-san.
Everyone. Thank you.
Long live captain Ayuhara!
Ayuhara-san. From today, they're yours.
My goal and my dreams.
Hayakawa-san, you understand now.
Yo. Congratulations.
I'm surprised. You've become this strong…
Tsutomu-kun, where's prof. Hongou?
Hm?
He said he'll withdraw as promised and left when the final set started.
He did, huh…
What do we do?
Do we get him to give up like he promised?
– Hm…
– Hmm…
I got it!
You're probably thinking the same. In the end, our club needs professor Hongou.
Volleyball club's room
Oh? What's that?
Oh?
As promised, I've withdrew from coaching.
Rejoice, weaklings.
If you don't want me to laugh at you,
do your best from now on.
Hongou.
It can't be. It can't be!
He doesn't really want to withdraw.
That's why he came here alone.
That's right. "Quit the club"… "weaklings"…
Nothing changes the fact he gave his best with us.
Let's try his home.
We need to convey our feelings to him.
– Yep!
He's said to have gone to the beach.
All right, let's go.
Ah, isn't that him?
– Yeah. – Yeah!
– He is!
All right, let's call out to him.
Professor Hongou!
– Professor Hongou!
– Professor! – Professor!
Looks like we've finally united.
It's the first step for the Japan's best volleyball club.
You weaklings!
What did you come for?
– Professor!
– Please coach us!
Don't quit!
It's the birth of a wonderful team.
Professor!
Professor Hongou!
All right.
I will…
I will make you into the Japan's best team!
– Professor!