Attack No. 1
Revolving receive arc
苦しくたって
Kurushiku tatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashiku tatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかではへいきなの
Kooto no naka de wa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ  トス  スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・トゥー  ワン・トゥー  アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
涙も汗も 若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く さけびたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック  アタック  No.1
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック  アタック  No.1
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
苦しくたって
Kurushiku tatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashiku tatte
…even though I feel sad…
チームの仲間が いるんだもん
Chiimu no nakama ga irundamon
…I have my team mates.
ホイッスルがなると 心がはずむわ
Hoissuru ga naru to kokoro ga hazumu wa
I find myself whistling and my heart races.
レシーブ  トス  スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー  ワン・ツー  アタック
Wan tsu wan tsu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
涙の中に若い心で
Namida no naka ni wakai kokoro de
Showing fighting spirit through the tears…
ながれゆく雲にさけびたい
Nagareyuku kumo ni sakebitai
…looking at billowing clouds, I just want to scream:
アタック  アタック  No.1
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック  アタック  No.1
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
I can't reach it!
Leave it to me!
Okay, girls, come over here.
It is about time for the staff meeting to end.
Professor Hongou should be back.
Let's go to the club room.
– Okay.
– Let's go.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Ah, it's you, Tsutomu-san. Why are you in such a hurry?
My club has an emergency meeting.
Calm down. It doesn't suit such an upstanding newspaper club member.
We're merging. We're merging!
Merging?
– Eh?
– Who's merging with what?
You know how our academy deals with various problems these times, don't you?
They decided to merge with another school.
It was announced at the staff meeting just now.
– Eh?
– Who will be merging with?
I don't know that yet. Excuse me, I'm in a hurry.
Ah. What will happens to our club if the school we merge with has its own volleyball club?
I don't feel like going to practices… right, Cap—
Captain…!
Captain!
– Ah, finally I see you. Trouble!
– What trouble?
They decided who we're merging with.
Hamaki Middle School will come here.
Eh? Hamaki Middle School?
The one who won second place in the last tournaments.
Then what about our club?
Their famous Big Four will come over to us.
The Big Four…
Hurry up and set up the net.
Okay Midori, I'm pulling it.
Heave-ho.
OK. Ready.
Let's go!
Let's not lose to Hamaki's Big Four!
That's right! We can't lose to some Big Four!
What are you doing?
C-Captain!
The Big Four.
Pretty good, if you ask me.
– Equipment looks new too.
– Those are the Big Four?
You've got a better gym that I expected.
We should be able to practice here.
I'm Fujimi Academy volleyball club's captain, Ayuhara Kozue.
I'm Hamaki Middle School's captain, Izumi Yuri.
I'm Kudou Keiko.
Ozawa Yukie.
Katori Yoshiko.
Some people apparently call us The Big Four of Hamaki.
Eh, Big Four, my foot.
They creep me out.
Who are they?
It's the volleyball club of Fujimi Women's University.
Awesome practice.
Their team once won the All-Japan tournament.
– Wanna try?
– Yeah.
– Watch out, sweetie!
– Got it!
Hey, kiddos.
You're pretty good. Fujimi Academy?
Yes. I'm Ayuhara Kozue of volleyball club.
I'm Hayakawa Midori.
I'm their captain, Oohara Mari.
Both of you have good talent.
How about a sparring?
Ah?
Thank you!
Listen, I won't go easy on you.
– Yes ma'am.
The spring break starts the day after tomorrow. Do you have plans?
Hmm, I haven't thought of anything yet.
Captain! Trouble! Serious trouble in the club!
What's the fuss?
It's about the Big Four practice! They seized the court!
– Eh?
– Ah, Captain!
– Captain!
Captain, look at that.
Ready?
– Yeah!
It's our court…
Go with full power!
Ready?
These Big Four need a lesson!
Wait, Naka.
Okay, once more!
Izumi-san, let's practice together.
We're still in the middle of our training.
Just wait there for a bit.
This is everyone's court.
We should use it together, don't you think?
You're getting in our way.
You just don't get it, do you?
If we practice with you, you'll only hinder us.
Wow.
If you're free, go fetch a ball or something. That's fitting for you.
You're all good girls after all.
Hahaha.
Midori!
Now you did it!
If you wanna fight, we'll fight.
Bring it!
Fine!
Midori, what have you done…
Do you want to stay silent when they make fun of us?
I don't intend to.
So you do want to fight us.
All right. It can't be helped.
No.
We'll settle it with this ball.
Heh, how interesting.
We'll finally figure who's stronger, no buts.
Let's hold a four players match.
I'll be your referee.
– Professor!
– Professor Kajioka.
I'm Hamaki volleyball club's coach, Kajioka.
After the merge, looks like I'll take care of you too.
Eh? B-But…
– When was that decided?
– Eh?
Ah, Professor!
– I'm Hongou.
– Kajioka.
Heh. It wasn't technically decided.
But that's not to say it won't happen, so I'll decided to be their referee.
Be my guest.
Begin match.
Here goes!
– Yeah!
Watch out!
I'm sorry.
Don't worry.
Don't mind, don't mind!
I haven't seen such a curve ball before.
Ah, don't worry.
Hahaha.
Don't strain yourself, now.
Really, what are you doing?
They're on a different level.
Good luck, Ayuhara.
You know how to work until the end.
Me and you girls started it together.
Fight with all you have.
Receive!
Too weak.
Let's win and get the gym already.
Don't mind, Captain!
Good!
Here she goes!
Damn!
We lost. We completely lost.
But we can start again.
Move on to the next goal, acquire new strength.
Ayuhara. I will be coaching you.
It's vexing. It's vexing, but we lost through and through.
Kozue.
We lost it… For our power to be so different…
I won't step back.
I'll surely show them.
How annoying.
I won't lose to The Big Four.
I'll participate in the university volleyball club's training camp and acquire new strength.
– Is this seat free?
– Go ahead.
It's you, Midori!
I'm going with you to the training camp.
How did you know?
I figured it roughly when you told me you had no plans for the spring break.
I called Captain Oohara too.
Midori.
Ayuhara-san, let's fight together.
No matter how tough it'll be.
I'll fight. I'll show them how to play.
Fujimi Women's University volleyball club's training camp site
It's tough…
I feel weak in mornings.
The little one's has it together!
Come on, come on!
You've got something to say, don't you?
Well?
We were overthinking it right from the start.
When we came here,
we thought we'd be marginalized.
To avoid it, we decided to seize the initiative first.
Don't sweat it. We're over that.
What's with you, sports-girl.
March with pride.
– Yes sir.
What about Izumi though?
We're worried about her as well.
Stop and come here for a second.
– Yes sir!
Listen, girls. At last, the district qualifiers for the All-Japan Tournament start tomorrow.
Make Fujimi Academy proud and give your all.
– Yes sir!
Let's prove our Fujimi's prestige and win through!
– Yeah!
– Yes sir!
I'll work hard.
Okay, next!
Next!
Good!
More!
Okay, next!
Attack duo!
Mark my words.
I won't let you win, no matter what.
Somehow I can't relax when I think about tomorrow's match.
Fujimi ・ Sone
Fujimi ・ Tōkai