What is your impression of entering
the World Championship for the first time?
Do you think you can win?
I-I do.
How do you plan to win
against the Soviet Union?
And the United States?
Well, we'll do our best.
How far do you think
you can go?
Can we hope for the semifinals?
We will simply do our best.
You girls are the Japan
representatives, after all.
We will win.
We will win, for sure!
Wow, that's a strong statement.
So your goal is to win the whole thing, right?
Of course.
Ayuhara-san?
I agree. We promise a victory.
Ayuhara-san!
Good luck, Ayuhara!
Attack No. 1
World Junior High Championships Arc
– Take a look at that!
– Huh?
We're finally here.
In America, in New York…
…and at the World Junior High
Volleyball Championship.
That long and painful training camp…
It was all for this day.
Ayuhara! Hayakawa!
Sir?
A letter from the Volleyball
Association just came in.
Ayuhara and Hayakawa were chosen for the
Junior High Girls Volleyball All-Japan Best Twelve.
All-Japan Best Twelve?
Yes, those twelve will represent Japan
and for the first time participate…
…in the World Junior Volleyball
Championship held in the United States.
– Huh? World Championship?
– World Championship?
There will be a training camp held for one month
in Miyazaki, Kyūshū to strengthen the participants.
You'll hone your teamwork
and condition there.
And then fly to America.
Congratulations.
– Thank you, sir.
World Junior Volleyball Championship
Ayuhara Kozue · Hayakawa Midori farewell party
The fact that two of our students
were chosen as Japan's representatives…
…makes not only the volleyball team,
but everyone here at Fujimi Academy proud.
We pray for Fujimi Academy's
stars to keep on shining.
Your hard work has greatly contributed
to the academy's growth.
We wish you the best results.
Kyūshū Nichinan Coast
Look, Midori, we're finally here.
Right before Miyazaki
Academy's gym.
So this is where we'll be
staying for the whole month?
Yeah.
Let's go.
Look, Midori.
The others are here already.
Ayuhara-san!
Ah, Kakinouchi-san.
And you too, Yoshimura-san.
So you were chosen as well?
I never doubted
that I'd see you here.
I was afraid we wouldn't
get to play together again.
I'm so happy.
Everyone, line up!
Don't you understand what
"everyone, line up" means?
– Yes sir!
I am your new coach.
My name's Inokuma Daigo.
You were chosen among the best
to be Japan's representatives.
On top of that, you're aiming
to be the world's best.
This camp will train
you for a month.
Hopefully you're aware
that it won't be a normal training.
After you unpack your luggage,
change into your uniforms.
Then get back here at once.
We'll begin training immediately!
He seems kind of strict…
Listen up.
I'll say this just once.
I'm not here to teach
a bunch of princesses.
I don't care if you're girls.
The only thing that matters to me
is making you the world's best.
The best in the world!
Therefore, people who can't keep up and people
who are useless will be sent straight home.
Got it?
Where's your response!?
– Yes sir!
All right!
Then let's get down to training.
Which one of you want be first?
Sir!
Let's go!
Ah!
Throwing her a spike
with all he's got…
The opponent is a man.
And a famous attacker
on top of that.
There's no way for us
to accept such a ball.
Arai-san, hang in there.
T-That's not enough
to break me.
Arai-san!
Don't go near her!
Where do you think you are?
This is the court you've
gambled your life on.
This is where you need to do
your utmost, even if it's practice.
Those defeated by the game
shouldn't rely on help from the others.
If you can't practice without getting
help from others, you're not fit for this game.
The playing field is not a bed.
If you want to sleep,
then get back to your room!
– Next!
– Yes sir!
What!? Is that ball
too difficult to you?
Is this all you've got?
Would you like to go home?
I'm sorry!
Next!
苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかではへいきなの
Kooto no naka de wa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ  トス  スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・トゥー  ワン・トゥー  アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
涙も汗も 若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く さけびたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック  アタック  ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック  アタック  ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
チームの仲間が いるんだもん
Chiimu no nakama ga irundamon
…I have my team mates.
ホイッスルがなると 心がはずむわ
Hoissuru ga naru to kokoro ga hazumu wa
When I hear the whistle, my heart races.
レシーブ  トス  スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー  ワン・ツー  アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
涙の中に若い心で
Namida no naka ni wakai kokoro de
Showing fighting spirit through the tears…
ながれゆく雲にさけびたい
Nagareyuku kumo ni sakebitai
…looking at billowing clouds, I just want to scream:
アタック  アタック  ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック  アタック  ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
Our first opponent
is the United States.
Midori's serve starts the battle
we've bet our youth on.
She did it!
Here goes.
Attack!
Something's up.
This is going too well.
Here it is, my chance ball!
They're good.
An ordinary team would break under
such a score difference in the first set.
But they continue to play
at their own pace.
It's just as I feared.
Now they're going to show us
what they can really do.
Damn!
Midori must be tired badly
if she made a foul play.
And not just Midori,
everyone's tired.
This isn't good.
They tired us out.
We're getting tired
more and more.
Cassie's still smiling.
Such a simple ball?! Ah!
Kozue!
Attack!
Beaten again.
If we lose this set, it's all over!
As long as Cassie's smiling,
we have no chance of winning.
One more point.
That's all we need.
If we lose here, it's game over.
We did it. We won!
It was splendid, Kozue.
In the end, all it took
was just a little feint.
I still can't believe that we defeated
the favorites in our very first match.
But I don't understand
the American team.
They were smiling
until the very end.
Hello!
Oh!
Congratulations, Ayuhara-san.
Eh? Ah, err…
Thank you.
We may have lost,
but it was a lot of fun.
Oh? Fun?
Yes. Volleyball is wonderful.
We are very happy to have played
such a fun game with you all.
Thank you.
Arigatou. Thank you.
Cassie…
I guess I forgot how
volleyball ought to be fun.
Yeah, but we'd better not
become like Cassie's team.
They're way too lax.
But their game
was wonderful nonetheless.
We weren't able to break
their rhythm the entire game.
Cassie has taught me
something important.
She reminded me how volleyball can be fun,
something that the special training had made me forget.
I will not forget Cassie's words
in the games from tomorrow on.
Our opponent for the second round
is the Korean team.
Their captain, Sai,
has a sharp look in her eyes.
How will they attack?
Machine gun attack.
Sanjou-san pretends to hit the ball,
but it's Kakinouchi-san who actually hits.
But Captain Sai doesn't
seem to be concerned.
We can't let our guard down.
She looks like
she's up to something.
Got it!
The match is close
at the moment.
We need to destroy
that balance somehow.
That was it!
That was Sai's bullet spike.
She accepts the tossed ball keeping
its momentum and sends it just above the net.
It's unlike Sanjou-san's
machine gun-like attack.
It's like a rapid-fire gun.
What a spike.
It's pretty strong.
The first set is a complete defeat.
Sai-san is the central figure
of the Korean team.
We have to throw
her off somehow.
Hey, Midori.
Aim at their captain.
Okay. Got it.
Good.
Hayakawa's curve ball serve
works well against Sai.
It's just like I thought.
Sai-san is tired
and starting to lose control.
She can't use her
bullet spike anymore.
Now's our chance!
Attack!
Looks like we've won
against Korea, too.
Finally, tomorrow
is the final game.
Hey, the coach called us over.
The Soviet team is playing now.
He wants us to study their style.
They're playing against…
Czechoslovakia.
Their revolving reception
is awesome.
I wonder how much it'll work
against the Russians.
I think the Soviet Union
will go through them like butter.
I wouldn't be so fast, the Czechs
seem to be very formidable.
Apparently it'll be a close game.
A close game?
Czechoslovakia is doing
better than expected.
Every time the Soviets serve, Češka
instructs the receiver where the ball will land.
Her lead seems
to be working well.
Yes, but the Soviets haven't
shown their true power yet.
Huh?
The proof's right in Borchinskaya
still being on the bench.
But I know what's going on
in their coach's head.
He doesn't want to use
Borchinskaya in today's game.
He's saving her
for tomorrow's finals.
But he'll need to have her
come out sooner or later.
Wow, she tied the score!
Ah! Borchinskaya!
Pay close attention to her.
Borcha!
Saw that, Ayuhara?
Češka's revolving reception
is superior in every way to mine.
And yet, she let it slam the court.
Who knows if we're going to be just as
powerless tomorrow as Czechoslovakia is today?
We've got to think of a way
to receive that killer spike.
– Ayuhara.
– Sir?
Once we're back, we begin training right away.
We'll figure out how to receive Borchinskaya's killer spike.
When the match is over,
bring everyone back to the hotel.
Yes sir.
Sir, do you have any ideas?
Unfortunately not.
I'm not sure how to receive it yet.
Anyway, we're going to train.
We'll see how it goes.
See you at the hotel.
Yes sir.
We can not win the Soviet Union unless
we can receive Borchinskaya's spike.
But I still don't know
how to do that.
We'll practice
and see how it goes.
If we don't learn it here,
we'll do it during the match.
– Yes sir!
Alright, begin!
Let's go!
What's with you, girls?
Get a grip!
I can't believe this.
Kakinouchi.
Let me see you spike.
Yes sir!
– Sanjou, you're next!
– Sir!
Everyone is shaking.
They're all thinking of the finals
with the Soviet Union tomorrow.
Alright, that's enough!
Let's take a short break.
Yoshimura-san, are you okay?
It hurts…
What amazing power.
Kakinouchi-san.
Oh, Captain. Wanna join?
What are we going to do?
Practice receiving killer spikes.
Killer spikes? But how?
Easy. We'll start with spikes
from only three meters away.
We try to receive that.
Then we'll gradually
shorten the distance.
That way we can produce power
and speed similar to the killer spike.
That's the gist of it.
I see. It's a good opportunity
for me to try something.
Captain, what are you
thinking about?
Huh? Ah, no, it's nothing.
I'll try receiving.
Kakinouchi-san, please.
I'm ready.
Got it.
Okay.
Captain?
It's all right! Let's continue!
Kozue's acting strange.
It's like she's losing the ball on purpose.
Looks like we can pull it off.
I'll go talk with Coach about this.
What did you want to talk
to me about, Ayuhara?
Coach, please listen.
I've thought of a way
to receive Borchinskaya's killer spike.
Hm? Let's hear it.
It's still rough
around the edges, sir.
But I thought it might be possible to cut the power
of the strike in half by relaying it once.
So, you're saying you can receive Borchinskaya's
killer spike if you divide reception into two stages.
T-That's correct.
To accomplish it, rather than bumping it
to the front, you'd send it back.
Exactly. A two-stage reception.
Perhaps Coach noticed me
during our training?
You've got us a good strategy.
You're growing well as a player.
We were in trouble because we
couldn't use Central Gymnasium.
When Cassie heard of it, she arranged
a gym with the help of the Rotary Club.
Thank you, Cassie.
Cassie let us borrow this court and even
gathered her team to get us proper training.
Sai-kun from the Korean team
has also offered us her help.
Sai's and Borchinskaya's spikes
have similar intensity and speed.
Today's training will be the decisive factor
in our match against the Russians.
Give your best!
– Yes sir!
The basis of the
two-stage reception is this…
Oh, he's using chess?
Let's say Borchinskaya
performs her spike from here.
The receiver repels
her spike backwards.
At the same time the player here
runs out of the court and sends it back.
Out of the court?
Next is this player.
She spikes the ball
returned from behind.
You've got to be
faster than that!
Yes sir.
– Next!
– Sir.
One more lapse.
Keep working these legs.
Y-Yes sir.
The All-Japan team
isn't here yet.
I see. Thanks.
They haven't returned
to the hotel yet.
– Really?
– Huh?
The Russians returned from their training long ago
and are holding a team meeting in their hotel.
I really don't have the slightest idea
where our volleyball girls could have gone.
You don't think they'd go sightseeing
before such an important game, do you?
Well, Coach Inokuma surely doesn't make
reporting any easier for us, either way.
Next!
Use your lower body more!
Make sure to stay calm
at the moment of receiving.
Yes sir.
Next!
How many times
do I need to repeat myself!?
When you toss, aim at the ribbon!
It's not just for elegance!
Yes sir!
No good. Ayuhara.
What were you doing
at the camp in Miyazaki?
What happens if you
can't even do this much?
I'm sorry, sir.
The remaining problem
is the Soviets' iron block.
But I don't think there is
that much to be afraid of.
When Shellenina turns
to Borchinskaya, she can no longer block you.
We can earn points
by targeting that opening.
This is the end of the meeting tonight,
but one last word.
Thanks to everyone's efforts we managed
to figure out the two-stage reception.
Ayuhara.
Kakinouchi.
Sanjou.
Hayakawa.
Yoshimura.
Arai.
Noda.
Ootsuki.
Miyatsu.
Mishima.
Every one of you held out well so far.
You have my gratitude.
Give everything you have in tomorrow's
finals and play without regrets.
That's all I want
from you right now.
Here, in the Central Gymnasium in New York,
the final match between the Soviet Union and Japan…
…is about to begin
in a few moments.
The final match: Japan vs. the Soviet Union
Although our team is here for the first time, its active
participation makes these championships very exciting.
The Soviet team, holding the world
champion title, was unbeatable so far.
Will the victory of the World Junior Volleyball Championship
go to the Soviet Union, or to the debuting Japanese team?
Finally, the match is started.
The server is
Kakinouchi from Japan.
A good reception
from the Russians!
Shellenina hits the ball!
Hayakawa spikes!
The Russians block!
The famous Soviet block
works well yet again.
It is truly like
an impenetrable wall.
The Soviets serve.
The ball flies!
Kakinouchi – revolving reception!
Ayuhara tosses! Sanjou spikes!
Will it be a point?
Nope! Yet again it bounces off
the Russians' iron block.
The Soviets regain
the right to serve.
We need to break through that block.
Coach gave us the sign.
Yeah.
Stay calm! We panic, we lose!
Okay!
We haven't even started!
– Yeah!
Ayuhara and Sanjou
play a time lag attack!
It goes in!
Great! Keep it up!
Midori.
Good going, Japan!
Good luck!
We're leading, but…
I wonder what's wrong?
They're only focusing on their defense now.
What happened to going at us with their full power?
Borchinskaya hasn't come out either.
It's a set point for Japan.
Will they seize the first set?
We have a serve!
The Russians repel!
The ball's on Japan's side!
What kind of attack will we see?
Ayuhara spikes!
Will it work this time?
Ayuhara's spike scores a point!
It hits the court of the Soviet Union!
Japan wins the first set.
Great, Japan! Keep it up!
The All-Japan team is now one step closer
to the title of world's best.
The Soviet team went into defense
to measure our attack power.
They'll start attacking in the next set.
This is where the real game starts.
They lost the first set,
but they don't seem to be upset at all.
On the contrary,
they're very calm.
You've been carefully analyzing our power.
When will you show your cross toss, Shellenina?
It's time to start the second set.
Will things go in Japan's favor
in the second set as well?
We let them control the pace
of the game before we knew it.
No. We can't afford
getting impatient.
But everyone is rushing it…
We've totally lost our rhythm.
Time.
Oh? Looks like the Soviet coach
asked for strategy time.
Oh? Borchinskaya has
stopped exercising just now.
The Soviets make a change
in their lineup.
Borchinskaya…
The cross toss!
Now show them
our two-stage reception!
An excellent reception from Japan!
They've just received Shellenina's and
Borchinskaya's serve, which no one could ever do!
It hurts…
Yoshimura-san, what's wrong?
Her spike… got my fingers.
I was afraid of that.
Borchinskaya's spike turned out even stronger
than Sai's bullet spike we had used in training.
Ootsuki! You're up!
Yes sir.
Player change!
Good job.
Thanks. Good luck.
Good work. You did well.
I'm sorry.
As expected, they're strong.
I'd like to make the two-stage
reception even more reliable.
But how can we do that?
I see. I see!
Alright!
As expected from the Soviet team,
the holder of the world's best title.
Their tenacity has turned the tables
and won them the second set.
Listen close.
The moment Borchinskaya spikes,
the receiver faces away from the net.
This is different
from our practice yesterday.
With this you should be able to receive
and pass it to the back reliably.
But Coach…
It sounds good in theory…
But we didn't practice it at all.
You can do it! It's not that hard.
It's volleyball basics.
That's true, but still…
The important thing is to try first.
You won't know
if you can until you try.
Admit it. Isn't this the reason everyone
started playing volleyball in the first place?
Okay, go!
– Yes sir!
Ladies and gentlemen,
it's the final set.
This is the set where
everything will get resolved.
Good. Keep it up.
All boils down
to decisions and timing.
13 to 12.
The Russians lead by one point.
The World Junior
Volleyball Championships.
The Soviet Union vs. Japan's final game
has entered its final stage.
Will it be the Soviet team, or the All-Japan team
that seizes the title of world's best?
The Soviets serve the ball.
The server calmly looks around
and hits the ball!
Japan receives!
Toss! Spike!
A reception!
Ah, a mistake.
Japan gets to serve.
Attack!
Match point for the Russians!
Yahoo!
14 to 14! It's a tie!
A vivid combination play
of Kakinouchi and Ayuhara!
All-Japan continues
to attack fiercely.
Can the debuting Japanese team
win against the current champion?
15 to 15! A tie again!
A surprise from the Russians!
They score a point with a skillful feint.
An intense spike from Japan!
They reclaim the right to serve.
The Russians cannot
score a point now.
For the fourth time,
it's a match point.
What a fierce exchange.
Forty seconds passed already.
It's a record-breaking exchange
in women's volleyball!
The play is truly ferocious.
The players are at limits of
what's physically possible.
Will the Soviets beat Japan,
or will Japan hold out?
Someone!
The Soviet Union
wins the championships.
It's Japan's defeat.
The fight for glory has ended
with that single serve.
Borchinskaya's spike
beautifully ended the game.
The Soviet Union's power won against
Japan's technique and speed.
The Soviet team continues its streak
from last year and emerges victorious again.
Arai-san.
You did well, too,
Japanese team.
Captain Shellenina of the Soviet team reaches out
her hand to the Japanese team's captain.
Ayuhara, thank you.
It was a wonderful match.
Although defeated, each one of the middle
school girls fought with all they had.
Well done, Japan.
We must applaud them
for their hard work.
Each and every country.
The World Women's Junior Volleyball Championship
that lasted this entire last week finally draws its curtain.
All the sweat
that sprinkled this court.
All the force that hit it.
I can't forgive them.
I can't. Not ever.
At the very end, when I used up all my power,
I just thought that it's not over yet.
That it's just the beginning
to another chapter in my life.
It'll be tough,
but I'll keep looking forward.
Wrong, wrong.
You got it completely wrong.
Ayuhara's spike
isn't anything like that.
She aims the ball
at about this point.
And your receive
isn't good either.
Ayuhara's revolving receive
is way more amazing than you can imagine.
Look at this.
Damn, it's nothing like Ayuhara's.
Alright, let's go.
– Ayuhara-san.
– Kakinouchi-san.
Ayuhara-san.
Fin