Attack No. 1
The Phoenix Arc
苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
コートのなかではへいきなの
Kooto no naka de wa heiki nano
…on the court I feel just fine.
ボールがうなると胸がはずむわ
Booru ga unaru to mune ga hazumu wa
When I hear the ball flying, my heart races.
レシーブ  トス  スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・トゥー  ワン・トゥー  アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
涙も汗も 若いファイトで
Namida mo ase mo wakai faito de
Through the tears and sweat, putting up a youthful fight…
青空に遠く さけびたい
Aozora ni tooku sakebitai
…under the blue sky, I just want to scream:
アタック  アタック  ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック  アタック  ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
苦しくたって
Kurushikutatte
Even though it hurts…
悲しくたって
Kanashikutatte
…even though I feel sad…
チームの仲間が いるんだもん
Chiimu no nakama ga irundamon
…I have my team mates.
ホイッスルがなると 心がはずむわ
Hoissuru ga naru to kokoro ga hazumu wa
When I hear the whistle, my heart races.
レシーブ  トス  スパイク
Reshiibu tosu supaiku
Receive. Toss. Spike.
ワン・ツー  ワン・ツー  アタック
Wan tsuu wan tsuu atakku
One-two, one-two! Attack!
涙の中に若い心で
Namida no naka ni wakai kokoro de
Showing fighting spirit through the tears…
ながれゆく雲にさけびたい
Nagareyuku kumo ni sakebitai
…looking at billowing clouds, I just want to scream:
アタック  アタック  ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
アタック  アタック  ナンバーワン
Atakku atakku nanbaa wan
Attack! Attack! Number 1!
Alright, then let the practice match begin.
We'll play one set, three-on-three.
Our opponents this time were the Yagisawa sisters from
Jidōin High School in Ōsaka, known as the Interhigh queens.
Our Fujimi team was to play
a practice match against them.
– Good luck.
We're playing against
such a scary rival this time.
I wonder what their
"trinity attack" is like.
Jidōin High School.
They're calm just like
queens should be.
Yeah.
If they beat us here, we won't
stand a chance at the Interhigh.
We can't lose, no matter what!
Incredible.
So that was the "trinity attack".
The Yagisawa sisters…
You're a fearsome opponent.
Captain, last one!
Once they jump, I can't tell
which one strikes the ball.
I don't have the slightest idea
how to get past it.
If we lose sight of their movement
for even a second, it's over.
We have to throw them
off balance somehow!
Attack!
Oopsie!
Great! She did it!
They're too strong.
The gap between them is too much.
We've completely lost.
Ayuhara-san.
– Thank you.
We lost. We lost
through and through.
We couldn't do anything
against your "trinity attack".
Let's meet again at the Interhigh.
But…
See you at the Interhigh.
– Let's go.
– Yeah.
"Let's meet at the Interhigh".
Here you are.
Yeah, we just wanted
to wash our faces.
It's a little refreshing.
How about you, Captain?
I guess I'll join you.
Oh? The practice's over already?
Huh…
Naka, what about training?
Well, Professor Shimizu…
Huh? Professor Shimizu what?
Professor Shimizu!
Professor Shimizu…
I shouldn't have agreed
to that three-player match after all.
It was too much of a shock to them.
I don't have what it takes
to support them.
There's only one way left.
I'm sorry, Professor Shimizu.
I'm afraid I can't help you.
We have many outstanding players such as
Ayuhara-san, yet I don't know what to do at all.
I'm a novice at coaching.
I understand your
situation all too well.
But I still have to refuse.
Professor Hongou…
I'm busy, Professor Shimizu.
Excuse me, please.
Everyone's so depressed.
None of us can prepare for a game
that we've already lost anyway.
No matter how much
we love volleyball…
Stop it, everyone!
Oonuma-san!
Why can't you just give
practice your all?
If you really like volleyball, if you love it,
snap out of it already!
And yet here you are, getting depressed
over nothing. You're better off quitting.
Even if we can't win the Interhigh,
we have to do our best!
Ayuhara!
Yes!
Next!
Midori!
Stand up, Hayakawa! Stand up!
What's with you?
I've had it!
Midori…
I'm fed with this nonsense practice!
What did you just say?!
I don't see the point in practicing when
we know that we're going to lose anyway!
– Huh?
Midori, what are you saying?
Just what you heard.
This training is completely pointless
and you know it! Just stop pretending!
I'm not going to keep up
with this charade anymore!
Professor!
Captain…
P-Professor Hongou!
Professor!
You girls!
Why are you sitting on the court?!
We're going to fix this team
right away! Line up!
This kind of practice
gets us nowhere.
I'll arrange a training camp
at a university for you.
Professor Hongou!
What's wrong, Kozue?
You still want to practice?
I just thought of something.
I feel like I realized
a weak point in my spike.
Ah, it's no use…
There's a big difference between
thinking of something and doing it.
A weak point?
Did Professor Hongou point something out?
No. It's just my intuition.
You're thinking too much.
You're too young to develop a neurosis.
Go to bed already.
Come on, Kozue.
Yeah…
Kozue, you're still up?
Just a second.
That's it, Forehead.
That's the Fujimi High's trademark,
the machine gun attack.
Hmm. Machine gun attack, huh?
It certainly is a unique technique.
But it won't be of much use.
But why, Professor?!
We learned it specifically
to use against the Yagisawa sisters.
Oh, you did.
But it's only worked once so far.
Huh?
Fine, I'll explain it thoroughly.
The opponent we'll meet at the Interhigh
are nothing like the ones we played with so far.
A technique that worked once
won't work second time against them.
For example,
let's take you, Ayuhara.
Sir.
You certainly were an excellent
attacker in middle school.
However, it's dubious how far you can go
at the Interhigh. It's on whole another level.
The game with the Yagisawa sisters
the other day has proved that very well.
Ayuhara's spike, no matter
how you look at it, has no weak points.
But it's just a textbook spike.
Because of that, a professional player
will immediately see right through it.
If Ayuhara-san's spike isn't enough,
what about the team?
Forget Jidōin, we might
not even be able to beat Misawa.
We can't rely solely on Ayuhara-san.
All of us have shared responsibility
on the match score.
Offense is said
to be the greatest defense.
We should focus on that.
– Alright, Captain!
– Roger that!
Let's hurry up and go to sleep.
Yeah, not a word.
I'm gonna sleep like a log.
Oh? Where's Ayuhara-san?
She's stayed behind with Professor.
I expected to see you here, Ayuhara.
Please tell me, Professor!
I gave my all
to obtain my current attack.
But what should I do if we need even more power?
I just don't know what to do anymore.
So you want me
to solve that problem for you.
Yes sir.
You're asking too much, Ayuhara.
Huh?
You can destroy this wall
that's blocking you with your own power.
But trying to overcome that wall
with a ladder is not the way to go.
I can say only one thing.
Get rid of your pride
as attack number one.
But I'm just thinking
about our customers.
That may be true, but if you keep doing this
we might go out of business in this town!
That's nonsense!
Please don't yell, Tsutomu.
You'll inherit this shop either way.
You can do whatever you want with it.
But please, Tsutomu,
everything but that.
Have it your way, Dad!
Tsutomu…
Tsutomu-kun.
Oh… K-Kozue-kun?
Whenever you try something new,
a bump or two along the road should be expected.
Our business is no exception.
If we buy directly from the production area, there's no place
for the middleman, so we can sell our vegetables cheaply.
But my dad says that's not possible
and just forbids me.
Why?
Because apparently no one
has done it before.
If we were to try it,
we'd get resistance from the other stores.
Dad's afraid of the backlash.
But I still want to try it, Kozue-kun.
There never will be any progress unless we can
overcome the boundaries set by common sense.
You're right.
In order to have progress,
we must keep an open mind to possibilities.
I feel encouraged
after hearing your words.
Good. That's the spirit, Kozue-kun.
Do not hesitate. Go for it!
I will.
Good luck, Kozue-kun.
Thanks.
I'll go cheer you on
during the prefectural qualifiers.
Thank you.
Here's our strategy for the preliminaries.
Oonuma will give us a chance.
To accomplish that, we'll leave both reception
and toss completely up to Oonuma.
Are you okay with that, Oonuma?
Yes sir!
Then Hayakawa relays that toss with her long spike
either to the right or left end of the net.
Yes sir.
The enemy will naturally think
the ball will be an out.
Then at the last moment Ayuhara slams
Hayakawa's spike to the corner of the enemy's court.
Just like I thought!
Yes. Spiked balls are flying
at 30 to 40 km/h.
You need to catch up with that ball,
jump and spike rather than cutting it.
I named this technique
a "double attack".
Double attack?
Tenryū is pretty good.
They're a dark horse.
They have no distinct technique,
but they have an outstanding team work.
I think they might get
to the semifinals.
So they'll play against…
Either Misawa or us.
Maybe we'll have to play with
Misawa first, then Tenryū?
We should be thinking about
how to play against Tenryū, too.
Kozue?
Kozue!
Ah, huh?
Kozue. What are you doing?
People are talking to you, you know.
I'm sorry.
It's just I can't see
Tsutomu-kun anywhere.
Don't worry, he must be busy.
Midori…
Alright, girls, prepare yourselves.
We're playing against Matsubara High next.
– Yes sir.
– Kozue.
– Y-Yeah.
He's still not here…
Maybe something's wrong?
Maybe something happen—
Kozue, chance ball!
What are you doing?
What are you doing…?
What are you doing!?
Do not hesitate, Ayuhara!
Ah, what a close call.
Who'd think Matsubara would give us problems.
Kozue, come here for a bit.
What was with you today?
We might've won,
but you've played like a novice!
I'm sorry.
Tomorrow we're playing against Numazu.
Get a grip!
Hayakawa-san, that's enough.
But Captain!
Good luck tomorrow, Ayuhara-san.
Sure.
I'm sure Tsutomu-san
will come see you tomorrow.
Yeah…
It's the greengrocer man!
Cheap fruits! Very cheap!
Fresh fruits, very cheap!
Oh, Toko-chan?
Is what they're offering really that special?
It is! You can get a radish for 80 yen.
Second one will be for half price!
Aren't you just playing house?
Nope! The store is real!
Hurry up or it's all gonna sold out!
Oh dear.
Welcome, welcome!
Ichinose's mobile supermarket!
We got great discounts!
Welcome, welcome!
Very cheap prices!
– I'd like these. – Yes ma'am.
– And this one.
Sure thing. Let's see…
That'll be 350 yen total.
– Here.
– Thank you.
Hey, pretty eyes.
Do you have some potatoes?
Well, that'll be 150 yen.
Wow, it really is cheap.
Tsutomu-kun.
Oh, what's up?
– You look overwhelmed. Let me help you.
– I'm fine.
Hey, I'd like to buy
these tomatoes.
– Yes ma'am.
One kilogram, right? Let's see…
That'll be 100 yen.
How much for these?
Thank you. Ah, let's see…
Please serve me too.
Of course. Just a second.
Aren't you glad that
Miss came to help us out?
Oh.
How can you be making a profit
with such prices?
Oh, I can sell them fresh and so cheap
because I contracted the producers directly.
Well, then, good luck
with your business.
Is she your girlfriend?
N-No, that's not how it is.
Huh! You're both blushing!
Hey!
What? I'm just telling the truth.
Sorry I didn't come
to cheer for you today, Kozue-kun.
It's alright.
You just started a new job.
It must be tough,
doing it all by yourself.
Haha, not at all.
On the contrary, I'm very excited.
You saw the sales
yourself, didn't you?
It was a bold decision,
but it ended up great.
But Tsutomu-kun,
can you really do all this alone?
There were a lot of customers
to deal with today.
Tsk. I'm not that frail.
If you have so much time to worry about me,
think about your volleyball.
That reminds me of
Professor Hongou's double attack.
I'd love to see it once.
It's still incomplete.
Listen. No matter what happens,
I'll go cheer you on during the final game.
Show me your double attack then.
Believe in yourself.
I know for sure
Ayuhara Kozue can do it.
Tsutomu-kun…
It's a promise.
If I lie, I'll eat a thousand needles.
Go! Go! Ayuhara!
Numazu · Fujimi
Good going, Kozue!
It's the sign!
Good luck.
Captain!
It seems it's still out of their reach.
Numazu · Fujimi
Five points left. Hold out, girls!
– Yeah!
It's the sign for
the double attack again.
Professor!
They just recovered
from the previous mistake.
We shouldn't press them so hard
in such important game.
I press them because
it's an important game.
But we can't afford
any more failures.
They'll lose confidence
and it'll be all for nothing.
If we were to lose now, we might as well give up.
We'd have no chance with Misawa nor Tenryū anyway.
This time…!
Dammit!
Believe in yourself.
I know for sure
Ayuhara Kozue can do it!
If we lose heart here, it's all over.
Believe in yourself
and win this through!
Everything sold out!
Yeah. It's all thanks
to your advertising, Toko-chan.
Thank you.
Alright, I'm going for another round.
This time, it's to the other side of the river.
– Come see us again!
– Sure thing.
Hey you, clown.
You sure do some flashy stuff.
Those crazy low prices of yours
are causing trouble for our business.
Why do you want to destroy us?
Do you have something to say?
Destroy? No way. I just…
Spare us that rubbish, punk.
Let's have compensation
for our damage.
Let go of me.
I'm only selling cheap and fresh
vegetables to my customers.
What…? You're asking for it!
Please don't use violence.
Screw you.
Think you're such a big shot?
Give us half of the sales!
If you do, we'll let you
off the hook for today.
No way in hell.
I have no reason
to give money to you!
What…?
Here they are, Mr. Policeman!
Mr. Policeman!
Let's get the hell out of here.
Are you okay, mister?
I'm fine. Where's that policeman?
There isn't one.
I tried to save you.
I just came up with it.
Thank you.
You saved me, Toko-chan.
Mister!
– Once again!
– Yes sir!
What's with you?
This is nothing like during the match!
Do it like it was the actual thing!
Miss!
Toko-chan, what's wrong?
Miss, big trouble!
Greengrocer Mister
was badly hurt!
Huh?! Tsutomu-kun?!
Tsutomu-kun, how's your injury?
Does it hurt?
Oh, this? It's nothing serious.
Are you really okay?
I am. See?
That's what I meant…
I'm fine, really. The doctor said it's going to hurt
for today, but I can go to work tomorrow.
Tsutomu-kun, I'm begging you
to stop this dangerous work.
Huh?
Hahaha.
Kozue-kun, you've got
a surprisingly weak heart.
I'm not going to stop
with my direct sales, no matter what.
Have you seen how happy those housewives
were when taking cheap and fresh vegetables?
I intend to put all I have
into this work, Kozue-kun.
An injury like that is nothing.
It'll take much more
than that to stop me.
Tsutomu-kun.
You've changed.
You've grown up
so much more than me.
It's a race with that sun!
The High School Women's
Volleyball Tournament semifinals.
A three-set match of Fujimi High School
vs. Misawa Academy will begin shortly.
Good luck, Ayuhara-kun.
I'll watch your game on Ichinose's behalf.
It's the falling leaf!
Attack!
Machine gun attack!
Misawa · Fujimi
I'll receive the next one,
no matter what!
Here comes another.
That's the last one.
Ah, thanks.
It must be tough for you, too.
Having to drive
such a long way to my farm.
Well, I did decide to purchase goods without the middleman.
This way of operating might be tough, but I still want to keep at it.
So you'll come tomorrow, too?
I decided for myself that I'll try as far as I can.
Anyway, it's a pleasure to do business with you.
Yeah, likewise.
I'll do what I can.
– Bye for now.
– Yeah.
See you.
Be careful on your way home.
Misawa · Fujimi
Attack!
They did it!
Good.
Ayuhara-san.
Keep it up in the second set.
We'll do what we can.
Alright, finally it got out.
Gotta hurry.
One last push.
Fight!
– Fight!
You can do it, Fujimi!
All yours, Captain!
On it!
She did it!
An easy victory
with the double attack!
Fujimi High School wins in the semi-finals of
High School Women's Volleyball Prefectural Tournament.
Tomorrow's gonna be the final match
with Tenryū High School.
Yeah. I want us to become the prefecture
representatives and go to Interhigh.
Well, we did just beat Misawa Academy, and we
considered them to be our most powerful enemy.
Who knows? Maybe we'll keeping winning
for the whole Interhigh and become the champions?
There you go again, Midori.
It won't be that easy.
I guess.
Our goal is still miles away.
Fight, fight!
Tomorrow is the final game, right?
Yeah.
You don't sound enthusiastic.
Don't you believe you'll win?
No, that's not it. I always feel this way
the day before an important match.
That's not like you, Kozue-kun. Get a grip!
Where's your usual fighting spirit?
I'll be fine.
That aside, you look somewhat
tired yourself, Tsutomu-kun.
How's your work?
Actually, it's pretty tough.
There are some painful things
I need to deal with.
But I'll work hard.
I'll work hard, too.
I won't lose to you, Tsutomu-kun.
Hey, Kozue-kun.
Wanna climb Mt. Fuji with me?
Huh?
Yeah.
Of course, after you're done
with tomorrow's finals.
But Tsutomu-kun,
what about your job?
Don't sweat it.
One day won't make a difference.
Let's climb it together.
Yeah. I have to win tomorrow's
finals no matter what.
But this will be the first time
I'll have climbed Mt. Fuji.
I've wanted to climb it at least once
ever since I was a little girl.
The final qualifying match for High School
Women's Volleyball Tournament is about to begin.
Fujimi's explosive double attack
gains them another point!
It truly seems like nothing can be done
to break their offense.
8 to 2. It's the first set and Fujimi has
already gained a tremendous advantage.
Alright, this will be the last one.
Here you go!
Will your truck be okay?
It's loaded down pretty good.
It'll be fine.
Anyway, I'll be back tomorrow.
Sure, you know I don't mind.
But isn't it a bit much for you to make such a long trip
from Fujimi just to buy a bunch of vegetables?
I'll travel anywhere if it lets me
cut my costs and sell them cheaper.
I see… You're one impressive youngster.
Not at all.
Alright then,
thank you very much.
Sure. See you tomorrow.
The road is dangerous.
Be careful on your way home.
I will.
Alright then, till tomorrow!
Ayuhara's feint does its job
and earns her team another point.
At a score of 14 to 4,
it's now a set point for Fujimi!
We just need one more point!
We have to make it!
– Yeah!
No problem.
We just have to stay with the double attack.
But we can't let our guard down.
Tenryū's captain Suga for the first time
succeeds at receiving the double attack!
– Kozue!
– Got it!
Tenryū finally puts up resistance.
They've started to fight back against Fujimi's double attack.
A time lag attack from Fujimi!
Fujimi finally wins the first set.
It's so late already.
I hope I can make it in time.
Hang in there.
The Tenryū team
earns another point.
In the first set we thought Fujimi's double attack
to be invincible, but Tenryū proved that wrong.
They pick up every serve. I'm sure
impatience plays a big role in that, too.
Kozue-kun!
Kozue-kun.
My shoelace snapped like a stick. It's too unnatural.
What if something happened to Tsutomu-kun?
Tenryū gains a set point!
Finally, Tenryū wins the second set.
They showed a lot of strength and tenacity.
In the third set feel free to use any attack,
not limited to the double attack!
– Yes sir!
And when using the double attack,
aim not only at the edges, but also at the center.
At the center, too?
To do that Hayakawa will make her long pass
along the net from a greater distance.
Yes sir.
We're bound to defeat them.
We will win for sure.
– Yes sir!
Finally the third set
is about to begin.
The serve goes to Ayuhara Kozue,
captain of the All-Japan middle school team.
She's a wonderful player,
despite being a first year student.
We're counting on you, Ayuhara!
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Go! Go! Ayuhara!
Tsutomu-kun!
Tsutomu-kun… I'm such a fool.
I bet that shoelace was hit by a spike.
What am I thinking?
After nothing but the double attack from left and right, another Fujimi's
famous technique, the machine gun attack, firmly hits the court.
I'll aim at the center!
Got it!
That's unexpected.
A double attack from the center!
Fujimi gains another point!
It seems Tenryū has lost their
resolve in this set.
They're desperately
trying to catch up.
Again, they demonstrate
an incredible stamina and perseverance.
Tenryū catches up,
point by point!
Fujimi desperately
tries to stop them!
Another point for Tenryū!
A tie! Tenryū finally caught up
and finally achieved a draw.
This is truly a match at an Interhigh-worthy level.
Both teams are going head to head.
At this rate,
it's a battle of sheer willpower.
If we lose here,
I won't be able to face Tsutomu-kun.
I have to think of something!
It's a tie, again!
Miss!
Tsutomu's in trouble!
Time!
Miss! We have to hurry!
Wh-What did happen
to Tsutomu-kun?
Go to the hospital immediately.
He's fatally injured…
Tsutomu-kun?
Tsutomu-kun!
This is an emergency.
Go see him at once!
– Ayuhara-san.
– Ayuhara-san!
I can't go until this
important game is over.
Kozue?
That's right.
Let's resume the game immediately!
Then let's win it
as soon as possible!
To get Kozue to the hospital
Thank you, Midori.
B-But…
Tsutomu-kun won't die.
He can't die, no matter what.
Ayuhara!
Miss, you're an idiot!
Miss, you idiot!
Don't be sorry if Tsutomu dies!
Time to finish this.
Now's our chance!
Ah! Double attack!
Tsutomu-kun!
It disappeared!
She did it!
We won. The double attack's
worked surprisingly well.
Tsutomu-kun!
Kozue.
You fool!
Are you going there or not!?
Hurry up and go!
I ordered a taxi for you.
It's already waiting.
Go!
I hope she makes it in time.
She will. I'm sure of it.
– Kozue.
Tsutomu-kun!
Tsutomu… kun.
It happened just a moment ago.
What on earth were you doing?!
Tsutomu-kun kept on calling your name,
struggling to breathe!
Stop! I don't want to hear this!
Kozue, please compose yourself.
Now, go and look
at Tsutomu-kun.
Tsutomu… Kozue-chan's here.
She came here for you.
No! No! No!
What's wrong, Kozue?
No! I don't want to look!
I don't believe it!
Tsutomu-kun's not dead!
I just don't believe it!
Kozue!
Idiot! Idiot! Idiot!
Even though he called
your name so much…
Even though I told you!
If you just came with me right away,
you could've seen him!
Idiot, idiot, idiot!
Idiot!
Miss, you big idiot!
If you went with me right away,
you could've seen him!
Miss, you idiot!
I'm sorry, Tsutomu-kun.
I…
I just…
I wanted to climb Mt. Fuji
with you, Tsutomu-kun.
I had something
I wanted to confess.
Kozue-kun. What is it
that you wanted to tell me?
I'll tell you in a moment.
Just please close your eyes.
Close them? Like this?
Kozue-kun.
Can I hold your hand?
When I close my eyes,
I feel like you're going to go somewhere.
Tsutomu-kun.
Time to get brave
and finally say it.
For quite some time,
Tsutomu-kun…
I've been in love with you.
Kozue-kun.
When will you come back, Kozue?
I cannot receive your attack.
I feel so sad.
It feels so lonely without you.
Hayakawa-san!
Hayakawa-san is trying to replace
Ayuhara-san, isn't she?
She has good intentions,
but it's not going to work.
Why?
She's too annoyed.
Look at her.
Look at all that useless movement.
She's giving it too much power.
As a result, she's already tired.
She must be thinking
about Ayuhara-san.
Of course.
She's the one who asked Ayuhara
not to quit volleyball and come back to the team.
Tsutomu-kun's diary?
Thank you, Auntie.
We're distributing mementos from his life.
I think you should have it.
I want you to get better
again, Kozue-san.
Thank you.
I'm sure Tsutomu
would've liked it this way.
Tsutomu-kun's diary…
I'm pressing to my chest everything
he didn't show to anyone until now.
This book holds all
the memories of Tsutomu-kun.
With this, I can meet with
Tsutomu-kun one more time.
"I'm in love with Ayuhara Kozue."
"In love"!?
"Ayuhara Kozue"?
But I'm not going to tell it to her
until she becomes the best attacker in the world.
The best attacker in the world!
World's Attack No. 1.
T-Tsutomu-kun…
These pictures and data
are all about me!
He went this far?!
Through all of this, just for me?
I came to understanding that we have to devote
ourselves to our talents for the sake of our futures.
Right now, my biggest wish is for Kozue-kun
to become the best attacker in the world.
Tsutomu-kun.
But even so, Professor,
I still believe in Ayuhara.
I'm confident she'll return to us.
But we have to go
to Tōkyō in a few days.
I hope she comes back
before we leave.
Ah! Kozue!
– Huh?!
– Oh!
She's here?!
Ayuhara-san!
I'm sorry for being late.
Kozue!
I've been waiting for you.
I've been waiting for you…
I'm sorry, Midori.
I'm so glad, Ayuhara-san.
Yo! Welcome back!
We've been waiting for you!
– Alright, come on.
– Yeah.
I'm sorry for all
the trouble, Professor.
Alright! Save formalities for later.
We don't have much time.
Ayuhara. Hayakawa. Oonuma.
Get down to double attack
practice immediately.
– Yes sir!
Y-Yes sir!
Let's start with
the center double attack!
Yes sir!
It's the revival
of the double attack!
Good, Ayuhara.
You have recovered well.
Go! Go! Fujimi!
Come on!
Win the Interhigh!
– Good luck!
– If you win, I'll date you!
Hayakawa-kun! Ayuhara-san!
Do your best!
You can count on us,
Mitamura-kun.
Great! Good to see
you've cheered up!
Mitamura-kun, it's alright already.
It's dangerous to run!
I'll be fine, Hayakawa-kun!
Don't lose to Kozue-san.
Don't mind it,
don't mind it!
Ah! I told you!
I'm fine! Ah—
I knew it.
I'm so happy.
About what?
You need to ask?
You look so much better.
Seems like Mitamura-kun's
energy got to you.
Looks like you
got over Tsutomu-san.
Yes. Weeping won't
do me any good.
I'll give my best in the matches.
That's the spirit. Keep it up!
Keep your head high, Attack No. 1.
Tsutomu-kun, I'll grant your wish.
Please watch over me.
Become strong, Ayuhara.
You will never get over by just
trying to forget Ichinose Tsutomu.
Only once you accept that life and death
are inseparable, can you move on.
Fin