The Cursed One Piece
Michiyo
Togashi, don't forget us, okay?
Take care of yourself, okay?
Yeah.
You're all so lively.
Do your best over there too!
Thank you, I'll write to all of you.
I'll write too!
Come by now and then!
Don't go finding yourself a girlfriend, Togashi!
And just like that, the person who I loved was transferring schools.
I wish we made more memories...
even though we didn't talk very much.
I'm back!
Ah, Michiyo, welcome home.
Look, your aunt is here to see you.
Oh, welcome.
Oh, my, Michiyo, as lively as ever.
What were you doing again? Basketball?
Oh, no, nothing like that.
No, no, she does
But she's so tall, what a waste.
No, that's just for show. She's just unsteady when she plays sports.
I wonder who she got that from...
Masako, you can't say things like that.
It's fine.
That's just how I am. A plain old bean pole.
See, she got mad at you.
It's fine, she'll get over it soon enough.
So, how did Togashi's goodbye party go?
Akiko and Yuuko stated to cry.
What about you?
I didn't.
Why? You always really liked Togashi, didn't you?
I didn't hear that, why don't you say it again?
That hurts! I'm sorry, just let go of me!
What's this?
It's it cute? Auntie handed it down to me.
Again?
Well... it would be too short for you, right?
Anyway, it wouldn't suit me, would it?
It's a shame you're that tall, isn't it?
Chinatsu!
Sorry!
I'd be cuter if I was more ladylike.
Then I'd be able to get on better with Togashi.
I'm sure he'll forget all about me.
My head hurts...
Your fever isn't going down at all.
You'll have to stay in bed today.
I'll speak to the school.
She must've been really shocked.
Chinatsu!
It's nothing, it's nothing.
Well, you should try and get some sleep.
What? The boy she likes has transferred schools?
Oh, my! I didn't think she had someone like that!
I see...
But if she wanted him to notice her
she should have been more lady like.
What? It's always you who buys me boyish clothes...
It's your fault!
Michiyo, we're going shopping, so stay in bed.
Oh, that's right, nobody's home.
A delivery?
I have to change.
Oh, the stamp.
They were just here.
"From Togashi to Kakimoto Michiyo."
It's from Togashi?!
No way...
"How are you, Kakimoto?"
"I'm sure you'll be surprised that this turned up out of the blue."
"I've moved in with my grandma in the countryside,
but my grandma is ill, and before she
passes she wants to see the girl I'll marry."
"It's too soon for me to get married and I
keep telling her that, but she doesn't listen."
"So, my grandma has sent this
one piece. It's very special to her."
"Sorry if this is late notice,
but can you wear this and meet me at the Usakuracho bus station at 2 p.m. this Sunday?"
This Sunday?
That's tomorrow!
"You're the only person I can count on."
I can't believe it. It suits me.
I'm so happy!
You sure picked up quickly.
It's because I'm young.
Are you sure that's all?
That's all.
So, we can all go shopping tomorrow.
I've made a promise with a friend.
Oh, really?
Sorry.
Seems suspicious...
What was that?
Nothing!
See ya!
Bring me something back.
Now then.
That's right, I could be late getting back.
I'll write Chinatsu a letter.
"To Chinatsu, I've actually gone to see Togashi. - Michiyo"
Kakimoto!
Togashi!
She still isn't back.
She's late, it's getting dark too.
I'll try phoning one of her friends.
Yes, if you could.
The address book...
What? What's this...
What is she doing?!
She's going to get told off like this.
Oh, hello, Akiko? This is
Kakimoto Michiyo's sister.
Do you have Togashi's phone number?
Togashi?
Oh, that's right. Kakimoto was off yesterday so she wouldn't know.
He was really unlucky, he was caught up in a big crash when he was moving house.
His whole family died.
Hello? Kakimoto, are you there?
Was it something about Togashi?
Hello? Hello? Hello?!
That was when I knew she wasn't coming back.
The police have been searching for her,
but they've made the public know
that there aren't any leads on it yet.
But there was one story I heard.
There was a pretty girl wearing a one piece around Usakuracho.
She was holding hands with a scruffy looking man, and having lots of fun.
But those are just rumors, I know they aren't true.
I know she'll come back.
Coming!