The Cursed One Piece
Kaori
It's lovely...
This... is for me?
Kaori, are you ready yet?
Sorry, I'll be right there.
Kaori will be thrilled.
I'm sure it will look good on her.
Takayuki is my mother's younger brother.
It came as a shock when he got married last year.
It's made him much more gentle.
I just know that Takayuki has to be my prince.
That sounds serious.
I'm ready.
What's wrong?
Women sure are scary, huh? I didn't know they could change this much.
You're over exaggerating.
No, I mean it. You look really cute.
It really suits you.
Takayuki...
If I wore that, I could dance with Takayuki.
Oh, no...
I must have fallen asleep.
There must have been a power cut.
Oh, no. What have I...
I must have put this on last night when thinking of Takayuki.
That's ridiculous.
What a relief that it didn't get creased.
Was that me?
Or was it mama...
That's right, it must be papa coming back.
Darling, it's late, why are you going to that woman's place?
Don't you care about Kaori?
Darling...
Kaori.
Kaori, it's time to get up.
What are you doing, Kaori?
I know you're happy, but it's childish to go to sleep in it.
I was...
That's right!
I changed! I really did!
What are you talking about?
Hurry up and wash your face.
Mama, where's papa?
He's working, like he usually is.
I feel so sorry for her...
Is there anything I can do about
my mother's mental breakdown?
Mental breakdown?
Has something happened?
It's just... what do I do about last night?
When I woke up, I was wearing the one piece. I'm sure I took it off.
One piece?
You sure you weren't just tired?
I wonder about that...
All rise!
What's wrong?
Oh... it's nothing.
I'm sorry.
How... did it get like this?
It's all because of that.
But, it's so pretty...
Takayuki, please save me...
Kaori.
Kaori!
You have to stop this, it's strange.
What is?
Kaori! Kaori! Kaori, get a hold of yourself!
Yes?
I'm thankful that you came all this way, but...
It's better if you just look from here.
If she notices you, she'll get excited.
No matter how many times she changes, it's no good.
It's that one piece.
It keeps coming back?
At the start I tried to take the one piece off.
Then my brother and I tried to do tear it, but it wouldn't come off.
It wouldn't work, you know?
But the other day, after touching it, I finally understood.
It's just her skin.
That's just what it has become.
It hurts her when you touch it or look at it.
You can even see its veins, it's strange, isn't it?