I want to be pretty...
I want to wear nice clothes and be more beautiful than anyone else.
If I do, that person will turn around and look at me.
Uchida Shungicu's
The Cursed One Piece
He'll turn around because I'm pretty.
Yuuko
Doi...
Hey!
Oh, Mayumi! You're here!
Oh, you look so cute!
You look really pretty!
My papa just came back and brought lots of western clothes with him.
Must be nice having a father like that...
He brought accessories with him too, right?
That's so cool!
It's nothing special really, when he
comes back he never stops talking.
What's wrong with that?
I'm so jealous!
I guess you're right, I should be happy that he's back.
He got back in time for my birthday, after all.
So, you're coming to my party, right?
- Yeah!
- Of course!
You're coming too, Yuuko?
Well... I... of course...
Are there boys coming too?
There are, Doi already said he is coming but...
Mayumi! Are you going out with Doi?!
Of course not...
No way! You're going out, aren't you?
No, it's nothing like that.
I knew it!
I said that's not it.
We just talk at school all the time and he's helped me a few times.
What? You've cleaned the blackboard for me?
I completely forgot, sorry about that.
He has such a kind voice...
After that I became curious about Doi.
Whenever I looked at him,
he was already looking at me.
Was that a coincidence?
I have nothing to wear...
Coming!
Oh, what is this?
It's so pretty...
You can't, we don't even know who it's from.
It might have been delivered to the wrong house.
That's not all, that one piece makes me uncomfortable...
It fits perfectly.
It's almost like it was made for me.
I'm sorry.
Hey, Mama, is it okay for me to wear that to Mayumi's birthday party?
No, you can't.
Why? Do you want them all to laugh at me for wearing my own weird clothes?
You've already got lots of clothes.
You just bought some more the other day.
That's not fair! Please, Mama!
You're just going to your friends house, why do you need to get all dressed up?
Stop being selfish.
I have to go... I have to...
Hashimoto.
But...
Hashimoto!
Doi!
Hey, you're going to the party today too, right?
Y-Yes...
What a relief! I was invited too.
This'll be the first time I see you in your own clothes.
Well... I guess you're right.
I don't want to go...
I don't want to go!
It would've been nice if I could go wearing that one piece.
Wh-What could that be?
No way! Mama said she closed it properly!
It's Mama's fault... all her fault...
All hers...
Yuuko sure is late, isn't she?
She even said she was coming.
Hashimoto...
Hey, Doi, let's go and play a game.
It's my birthday today, you know?
Hey...
Yeah, okay. We'll bring Hashimoto too.
Only I have to die...
Only me...
Only I have to die.
Doi...
Doi.
Doi!
Doi...
Doi... look at me...
I was discharged a few days later and
found out that Doi had transferred schools.
After talking to otther boys,
they told me that he like me.
If I hadn't worn that dress,
that wouldn't have happened.
But, I still can't get rid of the regret I feel.
After yesterday's dance, the one piece that
should have disappeared was back in there.
I still haven't checked properly.
I'm too scared to look.
Because I'm still scared of that eerie
one piece, everyday is filled with fear.