What if…
You were replaced with another child when you were born?
This is a story about a young lady born into a luxurious life…
…while being raised in a poor family.
Fighting against her fate…
…she strives to one day become a singer.
Wandering Sun
Dareka ni fumareta no no kusa mo
The grass on the field is stepped on by someone
Itsuka sora wo furiaogu
Someday we'll look up to the sky
Namida de nanimo mienai toki ni mo
Even when we can't see from the tears
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Shiawase no uta tooi toki ni mo
Even when we can't see from the tears
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Tonan General Hospital
Everyone is naked when they're born.
Everyone has a similar face…
…and cries in a similar voice.
But the moment they leave this room…
…each of these newborns will meet their own fate.
And the only thing to decide that fate…
…is a small bracelet attached to their foot.
Mine ・ Kōda
But what if someone were to replace those bracelets?
—Episode 01—
The Exchange
That's exactly how two girls had their fates exchanged without knowing it.
Tōkyō Metropolitan High School
This is one of them, Mine Nozomi, 17 years later.
And that concludes classes for this semester.
Mine!
Sir?
This is definitely a surprise.
You didn't fall asleep until the end today.
That's not like you at all.
Well, it is my last class, after all.
Something happened?
What did you say?
What do you mean?
Yeah, Nozomi.
Well, Mine-kun has been studying with you for two years.
It's truly unfortunate, but as of today—
That's awful!
It's too much!
Nozomi-chan quits school? That's a load of bull, Professor!
Just wait a second, Yumemaro-kun.
Mine isn't quitting.
She's just transferring.
S-So where are you going?
Which school?
Mine wants to study during the day.
So she decided to shift to a daytime school.
Really?
You should've told us earlier!
Thanks for putting up with me all this time.
Thank you.
Hey, Nozomi.
Do you think we'll let you off the hook like that?
Huh?
Just make sure to show up at the gym later.
Why are we here?
Come on, get inside.
But it's late and creepy.
Come on, step in.
Hehe.
Oh!
Why are you all here?
Ah!?
Why didn't you tell us that you were transferring?
Because…
Keeping something that important to yourself was pretty cold!
You could've told at least one of us.
Now, now, guys.
Even me, her closest friend, didn't know about thi—
Closest friend? You?
Don't get ahead of yourself, bean pole.
Yumemaro-kun?
Okay, let's do this!
Get her!
Heave-ho!
Stop it!
Stop!
Knock it off!
Stop it, it's embarrassing!
Stop already…
Mine Nozomi.
Good luck.
Don't forget us!
Come visit us some time.
Good luck.
Good luck!
Please remember us even at your new school.
I'll show it.
I didn't want to show it to anyone until now.
But I'll show it!
Huh?!
You idiot. Don't cry.
I'm not crying.
Nozomi-chan.
When you know where you're seated,
let us know, too.
We'll polish your desk till it shines.
Thank you, Yumemaro-kun.
Idiot, idiot, idiot!
Nozomi, you idiot!
Mine Nozomi, you idiot!
Good luck.
Take care.
Be safe!
– Come see us again!
– Stay healthy, Nozomi!
You can come back any time!
Stay safe!
Then, a mysterious woman, Nohara Michiko…
…goes to visit the other girl that she swapped, Kōda Miki.
What could she possibly want after all this time?
Yes?
Miki-san, right?
And you are…?
You don't know me.
A new semester starts tomorrow.
School's boring.
But tomorrow won't be boring.
The real you will transfer in.
The real me?
What do you mean?
You'll understand it in time.
Until next time.
Hello?
Hello.
Hello!
The real me will come to school?
What on earth does that mean?
Tōkyō Metropolitan High School
Good morning, Kōda-san!
Big news, big news!
You don't say.
Let me guess, a transfer student?
How'd you know?
What kind of girl is she?
What kind…?
She's in the classroom.
She works at an oden stand.
Mine Nozomi
1954-12-07
Nice!
The best transfer student we've had!
Please take a seat, ma'am!
Welcome, Miss Waitress!
Mine Nozomi
1954-12-07
A girl
Bust: 85 Waist: 60 Hips: 88
We were waiting for you, Miss Waitress!
I can't see her apron anywhere.
Her…?
She's supposed to be the real me?
Don't make me laugh.
Silence!
From today on, we'll have
a new student in our class—
It seems the introduction is already done.
There's just one mistake, though.
April 12th.?
That's the same as me.
It must be a coincidence.
Things like this happens all the time.
B-But…
The real you will transfer in.
I'm Kōda Miki.
I was born on April 12th.
Really?
The same as me?
Well then, let's be friends.
You did speak to me before, though.
Over the phone, that is.
Phone…?
I'll say this once.
Do not make weird phone calls again.
Kōda-san!?
What a weirdo.
What did she even mean…?
Huh?
So she was born on the same day as you?
Yes, but she's totally stuck-up.
I couldn't even get along with her.
Just remember that her father is the president of a big company and yours just has a small business.
She might not want to be your friend.
Yeah.
I'll bet when she laughs, she goes like, "fufufu".
But Sis goes like "bwahaha"!
Hey!
"Keiko's dream blooms at night".
The one that blooms red…
Poppy.
The one that blooms white…
Oh, Nozomi? It's about time you went to see your father.
Lily.
Oh, you're right.
I completely forgot.
How should I bloom?
Gotta hurry!
My dream…
I'll be back soon!
…blooms at night.
Sixty five.
Sixty six.
Sixty seven…
My life's getting dark…
So, no problems on your first day at school?
No matter how dark the past…
Now that you finally have the chance to attend the daytime classes…
Work hard and study with all you've got.
My dream blooms at night.
Thanks.
And then you will have to thank that lady.
You owe her a lot. She worked hard to get you into that school.
Yeah. I hope I have the opportunity
to thank her one day.
It's weird that she's not here yet.
She told me she'd drop by for sure after work.
Working overtime, maybe?
She's such a nice person, that Nohara-san.
Yeah, she has this "nice auntie" aura.
You can tell her anything.
A "nice auntie"?
Me?
Perfect. Everything's going exactly as I had planned.
Sis!
Whatcha doing here, you two?
Someone asked for you a little while ago, Sis.
He said he's with president's water.
You dummy.
It was "president's daughter".
Oh. Right!
Someone named Miki-san?
He left it here saying it's your birthday present.
A present for me?
Oh!
How beautiful…
It's a diamond!
No way. Nozomi's not here.
I cannot accept gifts in her place.
Come on, it's no big deal.
Nozomi's going to be back soon.
Once she returns…
How was it, ma'am? Was is the same?
That's not it. The voice I heard on the phone was different.
Strange…
The only other woman left
at their house was her little sister.
M`lady, a friend of yours named Mine has come to see you.
Her?
She's pretty bold to come all the way here.
Let her into the living room.
Of course, M`lady.
Are we going to teach her a lesson, ma'am?
Yes. Leave it to me.
Thanks for coming, Miki-san.
Please, make yourself comfortable.
But why did you bring your school bag?
Oh, this?
I'm returning this.
I put it in my school bag to keep it safe.
If I took it and chipped or scratched it,
I wouldn't be able to study.
So I came here to return it to you.
I really can't accept something this valuable.
Would you have preferred
a diamond bigger than this?
Not at all!
I think this gift is way too expensive for someone like me.
Your sense of value is strange.
What's 500 yen for you is 50,000 yen for me.
Huh?
Would you prefer if I just gave you money?
Money?
Miki-san, why would I accept your money?
Why? Well, I guess it's time to explain.
Who told you to come to this school?
Told me?
Why are you asking a question like that?
It wasn't your father, was it?
I know someone else is paying for your studies.
Miki-san…?
Fine, I'll say it clearly.
It's a woman around 35 years old.
That's enough.
Excuse me! I have to go.
What on earth was that?
If she's rich, fine,
but I never asked for her charity.
But why is she so concerned about my transfer?
Plus that question about who sponsored me… what business does Miki-san have with that?
When I was 17 years old…
…you considered me a slave in this mansion.
I never went anywhere and stayed crying in a tiny room without sun.
Kōda
This time it's your turn to cry.
Good morning, M`lady. There is a package for you.
A secret admirer who couldn't wait for my birthday?
Miki-sama
Strange. I wonder who could've sent this?
How boring.
My initials?
But it should be an "M", not an "N".
"N"?
Her first name starts with "N".
Mine Nozomi…
Don't screw with me.
"From the real lady to the fake lady."
I won't forgive this.
Calling me a fake?
Bye!
Till tomorrow.
Mine-san.
Oh?
I'd like to discuss something with you.
Fine.
I wanted to talk to you, too.
Is that so?
Then let's find a quiet place.
Where are we going?
Are you scared?
We can talk just fine here in the car,
so where are you taking me?
Miki-san!
Miki-san, wait!
Slow down.
Miki-san.
What did you want to talk…
Who are these people?
You know them?
Who knows?
I don't know what's going on but this is pretty underhanded.
Underhanded?
You've got some nerve saying that!
Since you're playing dumb, I'll be frank.
Unless you're stupid, you should remember this little present you just gave me.
A handkerchief suits you well.
Girls should be honest.
It was from you, wasn't it?
That's fine.
I just want you to explain to me,
what these initials mean?
I don't even know what you're talking about.
I get angry when people try to keep things from me.
What the heck?
Wait, you hussy!
Get back here!
Now, tell the lady what she wants.
It's better for you that way.
What… what's that?
It's Nozomi!
Damn. Hold tight.
Wait what?!
Whatcha gonna do?
Hey, tough guy!
– Hotta-kun!
– Company!
Damn! Get them!
All right! You're on, you piece of trash!
Take this! And this! And this!
Crap! Let's run!
Get lost!
And don't ever come back!
What scumbags.
Thank you, Hotta-kun.
Are you all right, Nozomi?
Yes.
D-Did he kiss you or anything?
As if I'd let him.
Who are they?
Can you tell me who these two are?
They're my friends from the night school.
Wow, she's got class.
Is she one of your new friends, Nozomi?
Let's introduce ourselves.
So they're your accomplices who sent me this ridiculous handkerchief…
…and threatened me with weird phone calls?
If you wanted money, you should've said so from the beginning.
Eh?
Miki-san…
You don't have to push yourself.
I can give you 100,000 yen like it's nothing.
People like you…
I heard part time school systems are poor,
but I never thought this much—
You idiot!
Now you've done it!
For me, the daughter
of a president a big company…
…to be hit like this.
On top of that it was from some oden stand-girl.
Mark my words.
I'm not going to let it end like this.
Yes… hate each other more.
Be troubled more and more.
I want you to feel the most miserable.
Just like I felt when I was your age.
The black seeds sown 17 years ago…
…have finally started to open up.
The fateful encounter between Nozomi and Miki finally takes place.
Miki who harbors hostility towards Nozomi, reaches out to her…
…and invites her to a birthday party as a chance of reconciliation.
Please look forward to the next episode:
"Double Birthday Party".
Uta wa watashi no tomodachi dakara
Music is my friend
Kurushii toki mo watashi no mikata
When things get hard, it stays with me
Tatta hitori de sabishii keredo
Heard alone it's lonely, but
Kokoro no uta wo minna no uta ni
Heard together it resonates with everyone
Minna no uta ga bachi ippai ni
I hope the people downtown can hear it
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow that will spread someday