What if…
You were replaced with another child when you were born?
This is a story about a young lady born into a luxurious life…
…while being raised in a poor family.
Fighting against her fate…
…she strives to one day become a singer.
Wandering Sun
Dareka ni fumareta no no kusa mo
The grass on the field is stepped on by someone
Itsuka sora wo furiaogu
Someday we'll look up to the sky
Namida de nanimo mienai toki ni mo
Even when we can't see from the tears
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Shiawase no uta tooi toki ni mo
Even when we can't see from the tears
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Two girls who were replaced
by a mysterious woman named Nohara Michiko…
…Mine Nozomi and Kōda Miki.
17 years later, they met again.
However, the day Nozomi moved to Miki's class…
…Miki received a mysterious phone call hinting towards a secret behind her birth…
…and was given a mysterious gift.
—Episode 02—
Double Birthday Party
You've reached Kōda.
Kōda speaking.
Kōda Miki-san?
That voice…! You called me before, didn't you?
That's right. I warned you that
the real you was going to appear soon.
I'm that kind woman from before.
"Kind"? Don't be ridiculous.
Although your birthday is in three days…
…I went ahead and sent you a birthday gift.
Did you like it?
Like it? How could I when you didn't even get the initials right?
But that "NK" is correct.
Those are your initials.
The "K" in "NK" stands for "Kōda".
"N" is your other real name.
How about you stop beating around the bush and just be direct?
The "N" stands for "Nozomi", doesn't it?
Mrs. Mine-Nozomi's-Sponsor.
Hehe.
At any rate, you're not the star
of the birthday party in three days.
Just keep those words in mind.
Hello?
Hello!?
Kōda-kun, you're very late.
Good morning.
It couldn't be helped.
The ward office opens
at 9 o'clock in the morning.
Father: Kōda Daijirō
Mother: Kōda Sumiyo
Kōda Miki (eldest daughter)
Eldest daughter: Kōda Miki.
Hey, where ya goin'!?
What, you can't keep up?
– Wait, wait!
– Finally!
Why did you give me a copy of your family register? What does this have to do with me?
I told you already. It's a gift.
But I don't need it.
Why would I want your birth certificate?
It just talks about you and your parents…?
That's why I'm giving it to you.
Huh?
If you hang it over your bed and see it every day…
…you'll remember to not be jealous of others' happiness and not meddle with their lives.
What do you mean?
Why don't you ask yourself?
By the way, you're coming to my birthday party tomorrow, aren't you?
It's in the Hotel Enpara, Diamond Room, 5 o'clock sharp!
And with a deluxe meal and a band!
We're totally going!
You can count on us!
Mommy bought me a new foreign car before my birthday.
How about we drive to Haneda after the party?
– Wow!
– So cool!
Hey, wait a moment…
How rude.
Why is Miki-san acting so strange towards me?
Drive in a new foreign car, huh?
I hope it rusts to the core. Hah!
♪ A pauper on the outside, a princess on the inside. ♪
♪ Prettier than any flower. ♪
Be more careful.
Don't jump out so suddenly next time.
I need to be more careful?!
You have some nerve saying that!
You're out of your mind, driving that big car so fast on a cramped road!
Heh. I see I don't need to worry.
If you're healthy enough to get mad, you're fine.
Wow, how cold.
Is that all you have to say after you almost killed a person?
You're right, I'm sorry.
There. Satisfied now?
As if. My body is priceless until marriage.
Take me to the hospital.
Huh?
Ah.
Better do what the lady says.
You punk.
Is that you, Kuma-san!?
Where have you been?
It's been three years already!
Let's save that talk for later.
Just leave this to Kuma-san.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
You, buddy.
I don't know where you're from, rich fella, but you're in trouble.
And how about you take off those fancy sunglasses when somebody's talking to you, huh?
"Rich fella"?
Oh wow…!
Tsk.
Hmph.
You scum! You just took those shades off a second ago and you're already hitting on Nozomi-chan!
I won't forgive it.
Take this!
Kuma-san!
Kuma-san, hang in there.
I'll leave him under your care.
Here's some money for a bicycle repair.
See ya.
And then I knocked that pompous bastard down with just one punch!
Awesome!
What happened next?
That's cool and everything, but Kuma-san.
What is it, Pops?
You're not young anymore.
Why don't you quit drifting and settle down already? A nice bride would suit you.
Whatcha saying?
You forgot how old Kumagorō here is known as the "Divorcee Kuma".
I'm a master at finding gold. So what does age matter?
Eh!
One day I'll find an enormous gold nugget in some mountain! Enormous, I say!
Hey, Uncle!
Yeah?
What is it, Kazuo?
The day after tomorrow is Nozomi's birthday.
Right?
Yep.
Eh? I see.
Then I've got a question for you, Pops.
How old is Nozomi-chan?
She should be about 17, right?
She grew up to be very pretty.
I guess even ordinary parents can make great kids!
She doesn't resemble you at all, Pops.
Your Uncle will give her a great present the day after tomorrow.
Okay!
What will you give her, Dad?
I-I haven't decided yet, uh…
Yuki, follow me!
Don't be stupid.
You can't ask Dad about that!
Why?
He let Nozomi go to daytime school even though it meant she couldn't help him anymore.
Dad has to work a lot harder.
That's why he had to quit smoking and needs to save money.
Save money?
Yeah. Even though he wants to give Nozomi a good present, he can't, because he has no money.
That sounds tough.
It's super tough.
Then I'll save too!
Eh!?
You're pretty mature for kids!
How sweet of you to think of your older sister.
I'm sure she'll pay you back tenfold—
No, hundredfold, no, thousandfold for it some day!
Tsk.
What are you saying?
I don't want any such repayment.
Yeah, yeah!
We don't need any compensation!
Eh?!
They're so mature.
I can't believe they're saying that.
I'm not sure who's the older sister here…
What's wrong, Miki-san?
Mama! This piano is acting up!
It just doesn't sound good!
Miki. You went to the ward office
today, didn't you?
Oh, Daddy, I'm surprised you know about it.
I heard you went to see the family register. Why?
Huh, you know a lot, don't you, Daddy?
How did you figure it out?
Miki-san, what did you need your birth certificate for?
Well, it was like this…
Father: Kōda Daijirō
Mother: Kōda Sumiyo
Kōda Miki (eldest daughter)
No, there is no mistake.
The signatures are authentic.
But is there any chance I was adopted?
Don't be absurd. It's a birth certificate.
You're right.
Hahaha.
I see.
So that's how it was?
But…
Why did you go to investigate it again?
Actually I got a bad prank call a while ago.
The woman over the phone…
…was suggesting that I'm not really your child.
Nonsense. Who's spreading such slander and from where?
What a bad joke.
Do you have any idea who's behind this?
Mine Nozomi.
She's my classmate who recently joined our school.
She's the most suspicious.
Do you have any evidence?
Her family is poor and runs an oden stand.
I'm sure she's really jealous of my lifestyle.
Don't judge people based on that.
But you always trust Miki's words…
How can you say that?
First of all, you're spoiling Miki too much.
You throw her a birthday party at a hotel.
You buy her a ridiculously expensive sports car.
It's time for you to stop giving in to all her whims.
Daddy!?
Dear!?
Why was I the one who got scolded?
The person behind those prank calls is the bad guy here!
I have to do something about this.
I know.
I'll peel off Mine Nozomi's mask in front of Daddy.
I'll make her lose face.
Apologize…?
Yes.
I will apologize as many times as it takes.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
What happened?
It's okay already.
Thank you, Nozomi-san.
But tell me, what did you have against me?
I will not mention a name but I will explain everything.
One of my friends had told me all kinds of horrible things about you and me.
Huh?
How come you have stopped believing this girl?
I learned that she was a liar the hard way.
After that, we parted ways.
So I'd like to be friends with you.
But please, don't say anything. Just accept my apology.
Kōda-san!
Can I trust her…?
What is it this time?
"April 12th. Invitation to a birthday party".
"Hotel Enpara, Diamond Room".
Ignorance is bliss.
That's how it works for many people.
But what about you?
I know everything.
I know how somebody else should be the star of today's birthday party.
And I know whose real parents are the organizers of this party.
Happy birthday to you.
Happy birthday, Miki-san.
Here.
I am very happy to see so many
of you gathered for my birthday today.
And to have so many nice birthday gifts.
Thank you very much.
With all my heart
Nozomi
Ah, Mine-san.
What's wrong? Don't you dance?
I can dance.
I see. That's good.
You should dance with us!
But…
Ah, I see.
You don't have a partner, right?
Pretty much.
I'm sorry we're the only ones having fun.
I'm terribly sorry!
I'll clean it up right away.
It's okay. Don't sweat it.
Wow, you've got your hands full of work.
I'm free, so let me help you.
Ah, M`lady, you don't have to do this…
T-Thank you…
Miki.
Get ready to get bullied even more.
Ah!
Daddy, dance is something to do,
not something to see.
Come on, let's dance. I'll lead if you want.
Forget the dancing, Miki, what's the meaning of that?
Huh?
Oh, her?
Yes.
It's very rude to let an important guest do maid's job.
But Daddy, she has…
…no one to dance with, huh?
It's my classmate, Mine Nozomi-san, who was born on the same day as me.
I got a wonderful gift from her.
As a token of my gratitude,
I thought of giving her something as well.
Miki's pretty mean.
I pity her. She's already embarrassed in front of all these people without even knowing it.
You think she's going to cry and run away?
Why don't we make a bet?
I bet she's not the type of girl to cry so easily.
I propose that we open the box to see what's in it.
You go first.
Miki-san, that's…
Amazing! I've never seen such expensive birthday gift in my entire life!
As expected!
It's truly a Kōda family gesture.
Don't be like that. It's nothing serious.
Now let's see what Nozomi-san has offered me.
What's this?
It's a good luck charm.
It's popular among young girls.
I'm sorry but you can have this back.
Our family has been catholic since long ago.
But the amulet has nothing to do with religion.
It's just a little fun.
It's a pity.
On one hand, a gorgeous necklace.
On the other, a funny good luck charm.
Is she crazy?
An expensive necklace versus some shrine gadget.
– What was she thinking?
– I'd say that's rather miserable.
I'm sorry for ruining your mood, Miki-san.
At any rate, I'm giving this back to you.
But I'd like you to know one thing.
I can't afford expensive gifts,
because my family is pretty poor.
That's why yesterday, when I was walking around, I went to visit a temple.
I knew I wouldn't have much to offer,
so I prayed for you and your parents to be happy.
Thank you.
Huh?
You gave a wonderful gift that doesn't lose to anything.
I'll accept it as Miki's father
if she doesn't want it.
Thank you for your kindness.
Mister…
Dear…?
Miki said she didn't want it.
We're not giving it back.
Listen closely. This is a gift you can never return.
By the way, that too.
Of course.
Daddy, you don't have to do this.
No, Miki.
Kindness should be repaid with kindness, not money.
Nozomi-san.
Would you please accept my gift in my daughter's place?
Of course, but, uhm…
Can you dance?
Yes, I can.
I know the basics, at least.
Play us some waltz.
May I have this dance?
With pleasure.
She can dance the waltz…?
Mama…!
It's a little late, but I brought you the keys to the car you ordered.
She really is a good child.
He's really kind.
It feels like I've met him somewhere before.
As if I'd known him for a long, long time.
Why is that?
Why do I feel this way?
The loving touch between a parent and child.
Daijirō and Nozomi just danced
while getting familiar with that warmth.
♪ Found the first star! ♪
♪ Found the second star. ♪
♪ Found the third, fourth, fifth, sixth star! ♪
Don't worry, your sister will be back soon.
She wouldn't forget about her own birthday.
Here you go.
Even I dropped by to celebrate.
She'll be back soon.
Now I understand everything.
I thought this car was yours,
but you were in charge of delivering it.
That was the day before yesterday.
I only remember some hottie jumping under my wheels.
Is that how you speak to a lady?
A lady?
Well, you have lady-like vibe, I'll give you that.
Thank you for your cooperation tonight.
Mr. Roadhog.
Which reminds me I haven't gotten your name yet.
My name, huh?
I forgot it a long ago.
You said weird things.
Yep. It's funny.
That's my name.
They call me "Funny".
"Funny"?
And you're Nozomi-san, right?
I feel like we've met before.
I'm off.
Nozomi-san!
I'll give you a gift, too.
It's your favorite kindness.
Best wishes for your birthday.
See you!
Funny…
I hope we meet again.
I hope so…
The Spring Composition Competition is approaching.
Nozomi and Miki are going to participate.
Full of emotions, Nozomi pours her heart into a certain song.
However, on the day of the announcement,
the song they choose…
…turns out to be the same melody.
Please look forward to the next episode:
"The Stolen Melody".
Uta wa watashi no tomodachi dakara
Music is my friend
Kurushii toki mo watashi no mikata
When things get hard, it stays with me
Tatta hitori de sabishii keredo
Heard alone it's lonely, but
Kokoro no uta wo minna no uta ni
Heard together it resonates with everyone
Minna no uta ga bachi ippai ni
I hope the people downtown can hear it
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow that will spread someday