What if…
…you were replaced with
another child when you were born?
This is a story about a young lady
born into a luxurious life
while being raised in a poor family.
Fighting against her fate,
she strives to one day
become a singer.
Wandering Sun
Dareka ni fumareta no no kusa mo
The grass on the field
is stepped on by someone
Itsuka sora wo furiaogu
Someday we'll look up to the sky
Namida de nanimo mienai toki ni mo
Even when we can't see from the tears
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Shiawase no uta tooi toki ni mo
Even when we can't see from the tears
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
—Episode 05—
The First Encore
Uta wa anata no tomodachi dakara
Music is your friend
Kanashii toki mo anata no mikata
When things get sad, it stays with you
Watashi to anata ga te o toriatte
You and I hold hands together
Kibou no uta wo minna no uta ni
The song of hope belongs to everyone
Minna no uta ga sora ippai ni
Everyone's song fills the sky
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday