Wandering Sun
Dareka ni fumareta no no kusa mo
A blade of grass,
stepped on by someone,
Itsuka sora wo furiaogu
Someday will grow high again
Namida de nanimo mienai toki ni mo
Even when we can't see from the tears
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Shiawase no uta tooi toki ni mo
Even if we are unable to sing in joy
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
In order to pay the debt for her father's
hospitalization, Nozomi took part in a talent show.
Ironically, she ran into
Egawa Isao there again.
Nozomi singed desperately
trying forget that Egawa is in the jury.
Seeing that like a dog with a bone
Nozomi doesn't lose her passion for singing,
Egawa reconsidered his
decision to drive her out.
— Episode 16 —
Singing In The Sunset
♪  I feel dead  ♪
♪  I feel dead on the inside    ♪
Miki-san's so lucky
that she can take lessons.
♪  It's beyond words  ♪
I wish Mr. Egawa started
teaching me soon…
♪  My wings are broken  ♪
♪  I'm like a wounded bird  ♪
♪  The memory of you  ♪
Let's repeat the last part.
Yes sir.
♪  The memory of you  ♪
♪  comes back to haunt me  ♪
– ♪  It slowly decays—
– Redo.
Huh?
Sir…
Sir, what is wrong
with the way I sing?
I firmly believe that my skills don't lose
to any professional vocalist on the scene.
Exactly.
Miki was excellent today.
Especially the last part,
her technique was so good.
She singed so well that
it gave me goosebumps.
When it comes to your technique,
I admit there is nothing to complain about.
You can make a few successful discs
the way you are now.
But this is not enough
if you want to become a true singer.
The essence of the song
comes from the singer's soul.
And that soul is something
I can't feel in your singing.
I'm sorry.
I'm being foolish.
This is the sort of thing
that can't be taught with just words.
Forget it. Let's continue.
– Sir…
– Miki.
Think about your career.
Your debut is too important.
If you keep going, you'll make him angry,
and that's not something you want.
You're right.
He's hard on her, don't you think?
She sings so beautifully for once,
and he doesn't acknowledge it at all.
She will soon make her debut,
so she cannot afford to fail now.
I'm so jealous of her. She'll debut soon
and Mr. Egawa is working so hard, too.
It's your turn right after.
There's no way I'm not right. I mean,
why else would he take you in again?
You think?
You bet I do!
Well, just wait and see.
He'll call you over right after
Miki-san's lesson is over, trust me.
That'd be terrific.
Good luck.
Thanks.
It's over. Hear?
What are you doing?
Ah!
I have an appointment regarding my debut
and you're going to accompany me.
We're going to Uchida Productions.
And change those clothes.
This is nonsense.
Let's go, Nozomi-chan.
Master, what about
Nozomi-chan's lessons?
My lessons for today are over.
What?
Did I hear you talking about lessons?
I hope you're kidding.
Do you know what you should be
focused on the most at the moment?
Did you forget
that you're my assistant?
I'm about to make my debut soon.
It's a critical time for me.
Is it really okay for you
to be so carefree?
But I just wanted
to take a few lessons…
Get it out of your head.
Collect our things and we're going.
Soul this, soul that. He makes me feel
like I'm some kind of thoughtless animal.
Now, now.
Don't be so mad at him.
I know he's hard to deal with,
but you can't act like that in public.
Hey, Mom, will you help me
with the advertising campaign?
Of course I will and you know that.
Thank you, Mom.
I can always count on you.
Our family will do everything in its power
to make sure your career is a success.
This practically guarantees my path
to stardom. I can't tell you how good it feels.
You should be happy
as well, Nozomi-san.
You won't be an assistant to just a singer,
you'll be an assistant to a star.
Okay, smile.
Good.
Lower your chin a bit.
There, that's it.
Right leg a little bit to the back.
Okay, good.
We'll take a few more.
Don't move from this spot.
Raise your right arm a little bit more.
Chin a bit lower.
There.
Alright, here we go.
Inoue-san is now considered
to be number one photographer.
Whoever is photographed by Inoue-san
becomes the talk of the town.
What about the illustrator?
We've arranged a contract
with Okizu Kōji.
Okizu-san's illustrations.
Inoue-san's photographs.
We could even make artistic posters
and sell them for high prices.
Sounds perfect to me.
Alright, let's change the position.
Come under this spotlight.
A moment, please.
I'm sweating a lot.
Omine-san!
Where is she?
I can't believe her.
What kind of assistant is she?
Omine!
Omine?
Hey, can't you hear
she's calling you?
Go!
What are you doing? You're my assistant.
You should come immediately when called.
I can put up with a lot,
but calling me "Omine"…
W-What's with that look?
Wipe my sweat at once.
Yes ma'am.
You're so slow.
How long are you going to do this?
I'm sorry.
Miki-kun, are you ready?
Let's continue.
Sure!
A new star, Kōda Miki
What do you think, Maestro?
She looks gorgeous, doesn't she?
Here, take a look.
Egawa Isao's treasured student,
the master of the song world
"Egawa Isao's treasured student"?
Yes. It has your name on it.
I'm only Kōda Miki's teacher.
I don't remember agreeing to advertise her.
Please don't be so modest.
It's only to thank you for your guidance.
How about dropping this attitude
just once, for crying out loud?
Listen close, Miki-kun.
I will say this just once.
When you're my student, my responsibilities
go beyond just giving you lessons.
I'm also fully responsible
for your career.
If your debut turns to be a fiasco,
it's not just you who will get ridiculed.
I become a laughingstock as well.
But a man like me cannot afford this.
You're taking this
too serious, Maestro…
Now that you put me in this position,
get ready for my lessons to get even harder.
Even harder?
I'm ready to respond
to your expectations, sir.
I'll become a singer
that's worthy of your praise.
My talent plus your tough lessons.
We have all the conditions
necessary for me to become a star, right?
Alright then, no more idle talk.
Let's begin with today's lesson.
Y-Yes sir!
My responsibilities go beyond giving lessons.
I'm also fully responsible for your career.
♪  I feel dead  ♪
♪  I feel dead on the inside    ♪
I'll become a singer
that's worthy of your praise.
I'll become a singer.
♪  It's beyond words  ♪
♪  My wings are broken  ♪
I've been thinking, you grew a lot.
You have so much patience now.
Do I?
Yes. You know how to hold out
when things go all wrong.
You have every right to take singing lessons.
You should go talk to Mr. Egawa.
Sune-chan.
I just can't believe him.
How can he be so excited
about a debut of a girl like Miki?
If he dedicates his time to her,
he must have good reasons.
But it makes me sick when I think about it.
It's just so unfair to you, if you want my opinion.
Alright, I'll go and tell him
what I think of that hooey.
Wait!
Are you okay, Sune-chan?
What on earth is going on in here?
Master!
W-Why can't you take Nozomi-chan—
Sune-chan, don't.
But…
Mine. Come with me to my room.
Sure.
It must be tough for you, Mine.
No, not really.
I'll be even stricter from now on.
Huh?
First of all, I want you
to understand one thing.
I have no intention to give you
any lessons for time being.
Sir…
I have no intention to give you
any lessons for time being.
He didn't even want to explain
to me the reason for his decision.
I wonder why?
I looked forward to this so much.
Sune-chan was right. Why did he
bother to take me in again?
I don't understand him at all.
Alright, cut!
It was perfect.
Good work. Thanks.
Ah, I'm beat up.
Let's take a short break, Miki.
Mom, where's Omine?
I thought to get something
cool for everyone,
so I sent her off to buy
some ice creams.
But she's so slow, as usual.
You sure took your time.
What took you so long?
I'm sorry.
Distribute these
to everyone at once.
Yes ma'am.
Here.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Thanks for treating us, Miki-chan!
Omine, when you're done,
go clean the edge of the pool.
Yes ma'am.
Great, that's what I'm
talking about. Nice pose.
Alright, here goes.
Okay.
Alright, time for the next pose, but we need
something to get her up higher…
Nozomi-san.
Yes?
Come here now, get on all fours.
What?
Why are you so surprised?
A good assistant must be ready
to do whatever it takes to help her boss.
But don't you think
this is a little too much?
It's fine.
Here, go ahead and
use me as your stool.
H-Hey, now…
Wait, I'll get something.
Don't worry about me.
That's my job, I'm ready to do
everything for my mistress.
Good. Looks like you're slowly
learning your place.
Okay, here we go. Smile!
Put your arms higher.
Like this?
Yes, perfect.
Oh. Nohara-san.
Miki-chan, look over here.
Alright, now laugh.
Excellent.
Great. You look super cute. Good!
Can you look over here?
Yes, exactly like that. Great!
– That's it. Pleasure working with you.
– Thanks.
Oh, Mr. Nohara!
I'm so glad that you came here.
I'm here as the lyricist
for your debut song.
That's still very kind of you.
Don't you think that
you're crossing the line?
Huh? Ah, you're talking about Omine.
She did it of her own accord.
Oh? But in the end, wasn't it you
who ordered her to do it?
There's no way she could refuse you.
Admit that you have
a soft spot for her.
I still remember
what happened at the airport.
That's none of your business.
Oh, is that so?
Look at this, it has your pictures
from the other day.
Wow, they look so good!
For Pete's sake. The photographers went along,
but what would Egawa-san say?
There's also the matter
of accepting Mine Nozomi back
but then ignoring her altogether
for Kōda Miki's debut.
What's going on in his head?
Where are you going, Mine-kun?
I have to go to Mr. Egawa's place
and get a tape for Miki-san.
Can you spare a moment?
There's something I'd like
to talk to you about.
To me?
This is for me?
Yes. It's a song I have
composed for your debut.
Now let's talk a little bit
about the contract.
A contract?
What are you talking about?
This time it'll be with my own studio,
which I have just founded.
I'd like to offer you to become our first
singer ever. What do you say?
No. I can't leave here.
What makes you think so?
Huh?
If you stay at Egawa-san's place, there's
no knowing when you get to make your debut.
He's the Egawa Isao, I get it.
But I'm the number one lyricist, Nohara Jun.
We'll get you your debut right away
and make you into a star.
My condition is that I'd like you to stop
working as Miki's assistant at once.
I hated to see you
the way you were today.
Debut…
Debut.
I could debut.
I'm sorry, but the answer is no.
W-Why?!
Why?
You could make your debut
as a professional singer right away.
It's your chance!
I don't understand
your decision at all.
I think that I'd accept it happily
if I didn't meet Mr. Egawa sooner.
Egawa-san?
Yes.
I don't know why, but I have a feeling
that he's trying to help me.
Aren't you overestimating him, though?
Possibly.
But I believe in Mr. Egawa.
And that's why…
At any rate, I have
to turn down your offer.
Excuse me.
Hey! Mine-kun!
Egawa-san…
You're a formidable foe.
Looks like you're in a bad mood.
Miki-san called to find out if Nozomi-chan's
arrived to get the tapes, saying she's so slow.
I was so furious that I told her that she and you
just had a very long and fun discussion.
You should be teaching her, after all.
Why do you give lessons
to Miki-san only?
And watch out for smoking,
It's bad for your health!
Nozomi. You want to sing, don't you?
I'm sure you can do it.
No. I can't imagine
your future any other way.
But true music
must be a cry of the soul.
You must express what you had
experienced, what you had felt inside.
I know you're capable of it.
I'm sorry, Dad.
Forgive me, Mom.
If I only had accepted that proposal…
But I couldn't do it.
Because if I did, I would never be able
to look straight in Mr. Egawa's eyes.
If you stay at Egawa-san's place, there's
no knowing when you get to make your debut.
That's not true.
He has his reasons as well.
But I don't want to make
my family suffer over this.
How long do I have to wait?
Fanni.
Fanni… You told me once that
I'm like a canary that forgot its song.
I am now like a bird in a cage
that's craving to sing, but can not.
Tell me, Fanni.
How long do I have to endure?
How much longer?
Fanni. Tell me, for how long?
Fanni.
Fanni!
♪  Music is my friend  ♪
♪  When things get hard,  ♪
♪  it stays with me  ♪
♪  Heard alone it's lonely, but  ♪
Nozomi. To become a real singer,
you must be able to convey your feelings.
You still need to
refine your technique.
♪  Heard together,  ♪
♪  it resonates with everyone  ♪
That's why you need training that's even more
severe than what you've been through.
Nozomi.
Endure it!
♪  I hope the people  ♪
♪  downtown can hear it  ♪
♪  Let's believe in the tomorrow  ♪
♪  that will spread someday  ♪
Kōda Miki's debut party is to be held
in summer on a luxury cruise ship.
Miki is steadily climbing the stairs
to stardom. Compared to her, Nozomi,
who is still unable to take any lessons,
feels pathetic and powerless.
Egawa Isao took Nozomi for a walk by the ocean.
Suddenly, he tells something strange.
He orders Nozomi to join
clam diggers and dive into the sea.
Please look forward to the next episode:
"Training By The Sea".
Uta wa watashi no tomodachi dakara
Music is my friend
Kurushii toki mo watashi no mikata
When things get hard, it stays with me
Tatta hitori de sabishii keredo
Heard alone it's lonely, but
Kokoro no uta wo minna no uta ni
Heard together it resonates with everyone
Minna no uta ga bachi ippai ni
I hope the people downtown can hear it
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday