Wandering Sun
Dareka ni fumareta no no kusa mo
A blade of grass,
stepped on by someone,
Itsuka sora wo furiaogu
Someday will grow high again
Namida de nanimo mienai toki ni mo
Even when we can't see from the tears
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Shiawase no uta tooi toki ni mo
Even if we are unable to sing in joy
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
"Why did he accept me back to his house
if doesn't he want to teach me?"
Nozomi can't understand
Egawa Isao's actions.
In contrast to anxious
and impatient Nozomi,
Miki is working hard taking
demanding lessons for her debut.
New star Kōda Miki
♪  I'm dead on the inside  ♪
♪  It's beyond words  ♪
♪  My wings are broken  ♪
♪  I'm like a wounded bird  ♪
Miki-san's voice got so clear.
Maybe it's because her debut is approaching.
♪  The memory of you  ♪
And just look at me…
— Episode 17 —
Training By The Sea
♪  comes back to haunt me  ♪
♪  It slowly decays in my mind  ♪
All right, that's all for today.
We still have a lot of time.
Hmm, actually…
Miki, Mr. Egawa
is just pleased with you.
That's why he let you off
earlier than usual.
No, I never said that.
It's because the song isn't yet finished.
I need to make a few corrections.
Oh, I see.
Mom.
I'm the one who's
responsible for my success.
Mr. Egawa's melody, Mr. Nohara's lyrics.
Uchida Productions, Orion Records.
Everything is first class.
But none of this matters
if I don't give my absolute best.
That's why I have to take
my lessons very seriously.
That's well put.
I'll be working on your song all night.
It'll get even tougher
from tomorrow on.
Yes sir.
I wonder how long he's going to keep
you waiting like this, Nozomi-chan.
I don't mind it.
I've grown used to it, actually.
Maybe it's a part of something deeper and
he has a plan for you that we don't see…
That'd be terrific.
I've brought you some snacks.
We don't need them.
Don't interrupt us.
Yes sir.
That's Shimamaru Mk II.
Take a close look.
Shimamaru Mk II
It's used by pearl divers.
The ship has a tonnage of 1500 tons.
Using this aft passenger area,
we'll arrange a party for around 300 people.
It's gorgeous.
You'll have a beautiful view of
Shima Peninsula from the board.
The slides don't do the justice.
Pearl divers…
There is no way that a debut party
in such conditions turns out to be a failure.
But let's hear opinion of your mom.
It exceeds my wildest expectations.
I'm very satisfied, to say the least.
It's nice to hear your praise, especially
that it was my idea for the most part.
How does the schedule look like?
Let's see…
We'll open the party
next week, on August 5th.
Next week…
That's rather quick.
I just finished the song last night.
Oh, Mr. Egawa, your strict
guidance is unparalleled.
There's nothing to worry about.
I just have to do my best.
Good.
In that case, I would like us to go
to Shima Peninsula as early as tomorrow
and begin practicing already.
We'll practice by the sea?
Yes.
It sounds really good to me.
I could even rent a hotel room
for you two to make things easier.
Perfect.
He's fully dedicated to my debut.
Nozomi will become a shadow.
See you tomorrow.
Thank you for everything, sir.
Welcome home.
Good afternoon.
Sir, there was a call for you
from Nohara-san.
Thanks, I'll call him back later.
By the way, do you think
you could take a trip for a week?
A trip?
We decided to hold Kōda-kun's
debut party in Shima Peninsula.
Huh?
We're going there tomorrow.
I'll teach her in the hotel.
Will you come with us?
Yes sir.
Take care of the baggage.
Yes ma'am.
Sir, could you open the trunk?
I'll take care of your baggage.
Actually, it's part of my job.
Yes, of course, sir.
Why did he insist
to take Nozomi with us?
She's your assistant, after all.
She has her uses.
I guess you're right.
But I don't like how he brought her
without my permission.
Keep her close and make her work hard.
I can't always stay with you, it'd look bad.
I have my lessons.
Of course I won't let her fool around.
This room has the best view
in the entire hotel.
Hurry up, Nozomi-san!
Right away.
Nozomi, let's take a walk
when things calm down.
Yes sir.
A walk?
I thought we didn't
have time for this?
Nozomi.
Sir.
I want you to become a diver.
A diver?
What?
You mean, like those
people over there?
Yes, just like them.
You'd be bored to stay in the hotel
with nothing to do all day long.
Instead, you could bring us
a basket of tasty abalone every day.
Think you can do that?
Yes… but…
With all I have to do,
I can't go around fishing for abalone.
What do you say?
Do we have a deal?
Yeah…
Good girl.
I'll talk to the divers.
Is this why he brought me here?
To collect shellfish for him?
Good morning.
Oh, you must be the girl
from yesterday.
That's me.
Let's work together.
Finally, a pretty girl joined in.
Wouldn't you be better off
taking a stroll or something?
She has small butt,
so she won't sink easily.
Alright, let's get to work.
I'm their boss.
Stay close to me.
Yes ma'am.
Don't just stand there. Jump in.
Right. Sorry.
No one's surfaced yet.
Alright, one more time.
♪  It slowly decays in my mind  ♪
♪  Ahh  ♪
No! You're butchering it!
Listen, it's all about control!
Raise your voice!
"Ahh", "ahh", "ahh"!
Pay attention to the notes!
Yes sir.
Let's try the intro again.
♪  Ahh, where have you gone?  ♪
Are you okay?
You've just started.
Don't overdo it.
You got two, huh?
Oh, why the long face?
It's pretty good for a first-timer.
You'll get better eventually.
Huh?
Actually, I made a bet
that you won't get a single one.
One more and you can cook a dinner.
If you keep at it,
you can become a pro.
Do you really think so?
I don't think I have enough lung capacity.
No, sweetie. The longer you stay under,
the longer you'll be able to hold your breath.
But…
If you don't believe me,
see for yourself next time we dive.
Nozomi!
Sir.
How was your first day?
Let me see.
Oh, it's just two…
Huh?
That won't cut it.
But, sir!
Even two were just fine.
I did great.
How could you just
throw them back to sea?
Nozomi.
You should not use expressions
such as "I did great" so easily.
If you had really done great, you should've
collected more than the other divers.
But I just started today.
That's my whole point. If you engage them
thinking like a beginner, you'll never succeed.
Those women endured rigorous training,
one that you and I can't probably even fathom.
"Doing great" means you should
put forth at least as much effort.
I told you to become a diver.
I meant a professional.
That's ridiculous. I can't.
If you don't understand
what I want to say,
go back to Tōkyō at once.
Ah… Sir!
If you have nothing more to say,
focus on collecting more clams.
Kōda-kun is clenching her teeth
and studying like never before.
Why on earth does
he want me to become a diver?
Don't be so discouraged.
You won't live long
if you worry too much.
I…
You'll forget everything in the sea.
One more round, ladies!
'Aight, break's over.
Let's get to it.
I don't understand
Mr. Egawa anymore at all.
Why is he doing all this?
I had two goals
in coming to this island.
The first one was to train
Kōda Miki for her debut. The other one…
Well, I can't help but wonder how she'd react
if she learned that I absolutely hate abalone.
Nozomi kept diving and every day
she picked up more and more shellfish.
She was gradually
retaking her confidence.
Today was my best day yet.
Here, look.
Yeah.
Wow, I like what I'm seeing.
I've got to say, mister,
Nozomi-chan's spirit impressed me a lot.
She has the potential
to become a mermaid.
Oh, please.
A mermaid?
It's a master diver.
Do you think you could
train her to become one?
Oh, with pleasure.
Now you're just teasing me.
All right, then. How about
we eat one of these tonight?
Tomorrow is Kōda's debut party.
Yes.
The cruise ship is getting decorated.
There's a lot of commotion around it.
It will be a big day.
Yes, a very big day for all of us.
I hope for a full basket
tomorrow as well.
Sure.
Sir!
Do not forget that you too will become
a great singer. Make sure not to catch a cold.
Yes sir.
It's all part of your preparation.
So it's part of preparing me
to become a singer…
But is it really?
How is this supposed to work?
You look fantastic, Miki.
It fits you perfectly.
What do you think?
It's very nice.
It's so gorgeous and dazzling.
You've become good at flattery.
And the back?
Looks good.
I heard that you became a diver.
That's right.
Nice.
Huh?
Evidently, you've realized you can't succeed
as a singer and found something else.
I, on the other hand, can't picture
myself doing anything else.
I'd better get going.
It's time for my last lesson.
Will I be fine, sir?
So even you can get nervous.
I guess it's natural.
Don't worry, it will go well.
The guests are beginning to arrive.
How about one last
inspection of your stage?
Sure. I'll go at once.
I can already see how presumptuous
she becomes in a few weeks.
I caught so many,
no wonder I'm so exhausted.
Look at you, you cutie.
Mom, where is my score?
The score?
It was on the table at the hotel.
What? It wasn't in the bag?
I thought you took it.
So it's still there?
I can't sing without it!
But you remember the lyrics, right?
No, Mr. Egawa left me lots of important notes
on the score that tell me exactly how to sing.
It took me a week to learn it,
and that's with the notes.
I understand.
So it's just indispensable.
I can't sing without the score.
We still have some time.
Let's get someone to bring it over.
No, we can't do that.
What would people say?
What kind of musician
forgets their score?
I suppose you're right.
We have to get it in a way
that won't get noticed.
Mom…
Leave it to me.
There are a lot of people
who know how to swim in these parts.
There would be nothing strange
if someone boarded the ship to rest for a bit.
I guess…
Mine-san!
This is for you.
We got a call from Kōda-san. She's asked
you to carry this envelope to the ship at once.
She's asked for me?
You must swim up to the ship and deliver it
without getting noticed by anybody.
Wait, what? Swim?
Yes. The score is protected
by three plastic casings.
I see…
You're tired. Are you sure
you can make it within half an hour?
I'll be fine.
It's just about 2 kilometers, right?
That's right.
Good, the waves are small.
She's late…
How are the preparations going?
We're almost finished.
We're starting in 30 minutes.
See you on stage.
Where is she?
What is she doing?!
Miki!
What is she doing!?
She's been diving for a week.
She's slow as always!
Hurry up!
Miki-san.
Thank you.
Alright, now please excuse me.
Wait.
What is this?
Oh!
You're trying to sabotage
my debut, aren't you?
Not at all!
There's a hole in the package.
Anyone would've noticed it.
Why didn't you check it before?
I did! But it must've
been too small to notice.
I won't forgive it.
You ruined my life!
You're a terrible person.
Why did you do this to me? Why?!
Don't even try to apologize.
Nothing can be done now.
Calm down, Miki-san.
I'll replace your score.
What?
I listened to your lessons and
learned your song for the most part.
I'll sing it for you
and you'll remember it.
B-But…
We don't have time for games.
You care about your debut, right?
It's sink or swim.
We'll do it one step at a time.
T-That'd be terrific.
I'll join in when it comes back.
♪  I'm dead  ♪
♪  I'm dead on the inside  ♪
Look at her. I didn't even teach her,
and she's completely mastered the song.
♪  It's beyond words  ♪
And looks like training
with the divers didn't go to waste.
♪  My wings are broken  ♪
Her breath is deeper,
and makes the song resonate better.
♪  I'm like a wounded bird  ♪
♪  The memory of you  ♪
♪  burns hot in my heart  ♪
♪  Ahh, where have you gone?  ♪
♪  I'm dead  ♪
♪  I'm dead on the inside  ♪
Mine Nozomi.
Mine Nozomi, the diver!
♪  It's beyond words  ♪
I have but one thing to say.
You are one amazing girl.
♪  My wings are broken  ♪
♪  I'm like a wounded bird  ♪
♪  The memory of you  ♪
♪  burns hot in my heart  ♪
♪  Ahh, where have you gone?  ♪
Looks like the debut is a success.
♪  The memory of you  ♪
♪  comes back to haunt me  ♪
♪  It slowly decays in my mind  ♪
After returning to Tōkyō, Nozomi is overjoyed
to finally have the chance to sing in front of Egawa.
However, Egawa, upon hearing Nozomi sing,
tells her to sing in a club in Yokohama.
That club turns out to be an uncanny
gathering place for local black people.
Nozomi is terrified.
Please look forward to the next episode:
"The Song Of The Port".
Uta wa watashi no tomodachi dakara
Music is my friend
Kurushii toki mo watashi no mikata
When things get hard, it stays with me
Tatta hitori de sabishii keredo
Heard alone it's lonely, but
Kokoro no uta wo minna no uta ni
Heard together it resonates with everyone
Minna no uta ga bachi ippai ni
I hope the people downtown can hear it
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday