Wandering Sun
Dareka ni fumareta no no kusa mo
A blade of grass,
stepped on by someone,
Itsuka sora wo furiaogu
Someday will grow high again
Namida de nanimo mienai toki ni mo
Even when we can't see from the tears
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Shiawase no uta tooi toki ni mo
Even if we are unable to sing in joy
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
The voice is what matters
the most to a singer.
One can dream of a professional career
only if they're able to sing from the diaphragm.
Egawa, who saw Nozomi's qualities,
made her dive into the sea
in order to put pressure on her lungs
and enhance their capacity.
Egawa is now thinking of resuming
Nozomi's training to further develop her talent.
Here's a small gift.
Wow, what a delight!
— Episode 18 —
The Song Of The Port
I've never seen shells as big as these.
Thank you, Nozomi-chan.
I caught them with
a group of divers I met.
You're kidding! How did you learn to dive
so well? Tell me everything, Nozomi-chan.
Well, at first it was a disaster.
But by the end of our trip, I was told that
I could become a professional diver if I wanted.
No way! For real?
But what was Mr. Egawa thinking?
Why would he want you to join the divers?
Sometimes I just don't understand him.
Maybe he's getting senile…
Who is?
Ah, Master!
Ah, I meant…
the mailman!
Welcome home, sir.
I was just going to your office
to express my thanks for our trip.
Nozomi, follow me to
the study room for a bit.
Yes sir.
Study room?
Does that mean?…
Nozomi.
Sir.
I want you to sing something to me.
What?
Let's see…
Which one would be good…
There. Try singing this.
"The Wounded Bird"?
This is Miki-san's song…
Why does he want me
to sing this one in particular?
What's wrong?
Right.
♪  I'm dead   ♪
♪  I'm dead on the inside  ♪
♪  It's beyond words  ♪
Oww…
But… you did it, Nozomi-chan!
♪  My wings are broken  ♪
♪  I'm like a wounded bird  ♪
♪  The memory of you  ♪
♪  burns hot in my heart  ♪
Wait, this is my debut song.
♪  where have you gone?  ♪
You're right. It is.
Who's singing it?
♪  The memory of you  ♪
♪  comes back to haunt me  ♪
Sounds like Nozomi…
But there's no way she's that good.
♪  It slowly decays in my mind  ♪
The idea to let her play
with the divers was a good call.
Nozomi wasn't capable
of this volume before.
And above all, you can hear
that she puts heart into it.
♪  Up in the sky  ♪
♪  Up in that deep blue sky  ♪
What's going on?
You're such a thief.
What?
You were singing my debut song
to promote yourself to Mr. Egawa.
You want to belittle me in his eyes.
I can't believe how low you've sunk.
That's not true.
Why did you steal my song, then?
Steal?…
I knew you were born in a poor house,
but I didn't know you were so rotten.
What did you say?
Why are you giving me that look?
What do you have to defend yourself?
I asked her to sing it.
Why did you do that?
I had no particular reason.
I just wanted to hear her sing it.
By the way, what brings
you here at such hour?
We still have a week until recording.
It was decided that we'll hold
a press conference before that.
It'd be an honor if you were
to participate in it.
If it was only this,
you could've just called.
See, Mom? I told you.
Mr. Egawa didn't hesitate for a moment
to accept our invitation.
A good teacher is always happy to look after
his student's career beyond their debut.
I never said I'd agree.
My response is no.
I am only committed to giving
you singing lessons.
I don't remember agreeing to do your
advertising or go to your press conferences.
Furthermore, I no longer want to hear
about moral obligations towards my students.
– Maestro…
– Sir…
Back to you, Nozomi.
Sir?
Starting tomorrow, you'll sing in
the evening at a night club in Yokohama.
A night club in Yokohama?
Is it really okay?
Here's your score.
"Lady Tady"…
"Lady Tady".
I'm sorry, do you know which way
is the club named "Lady Tady"?
"Lady Tady"?
Can't say it rings a bell.
Here, it's marked on the map.
Ah, looks like it's in Chinatown,
in a side street to the left.
Thank you very much.
There's Chinatown…
A side street to the left.
I think this is it.
Maybe I heard him wrong?
That's not it…
Not there either.
Looks like this is the place.
Good evening.
I'm Mine Nozomi.
Mr. Egawa has sent me here.
This way, please.
So you're Mine Nozomi-san, right?
Yes. Pleased to meet you.
Have a sit.
Sure.
So young…
Excuse me?
Oh, nothing. A member of the band will
be here soon. Could you wait for him here?
Naturally.
Nitta-san!
Nozomi-chan?
I heard we'll have a new singer.
So it was you, huh?
Yes.
But frankly I feel bad seeing a cute girl
like you in a place like this.
What do you mean?
You'll see for yourself soon.
But I'm so glad that I get to sing
accompanied by your trumpet again.
I'm looking forward to it.
Nicchan, it's your turn.
My name is Mine Nozomi.
I'm the new singer here and I'll do my best.
I hope you'll like my songs.
Nozomi meets Nitta Akira again, a trumpeter
she first met during her Tōhoku tour.
The ability to sing to her old friend's trumpet
makes Nozomi feel joy and a bit of nostalgia.
Keep singing.
They want to intimidate you.
You can't lose to them.
Continue, Nozomi-chan.
Keep singing.
Nitta-san…
Outta my way.
Get away from that thing.
Come back when you learn
to play the piano.
What's your problem?
How about you play it yourself?
Ha. That's all you can do?
Get lost!
Something's changed in his eyes
as he was about to press a key.
What was that about?
Anyway, that's a nice mess
I've gotten myself into, indeed.
Time for a break.
Let's get some ramen. It's my treat.
For real?
Thanks.
Do you know who
that foreigner was?
Nope, not at all.
He's Bill Jones.
Bill Jones?
He was once a famous Dixieland pianist
in New Orleans. He was an absolute legend.
How did he end up like that?
I heard he had lost his lover
while he was on a concert tour.
He was given the news while on stage.
He's been unable to play ever since.
He drifted for a long, long time
before arriving to Japan.
Now no one remembers him.
I learned he was the Bill Jones
only by accident, too.
One night, when he was dead drunk, I had
to drive him home. That's how I met him.
At first, I just couldn't
believe he was the man.
Welcome.
Surprising, huh? That club.
Yeah.
This audience has the most fun
when it teases the band.
We had many singers like you.
But eventually none of them
lasted more than a week.
Now, don't get it wrong.
The guests' sense of music is wonderful.
Take for example the guy who played
the piano. He's actually pretty good.
Bill Jones stopped him because
he thought he was not good enough.
In any case, I had never
seen such thing.
This is why, even if they whistle
at me, I don't mean to give in.
It's a good learning experience.
What do you mean?
You have to be really very good
to please that kind of audience.
After all, don't forget that they are
the ones who created the jazz.
If they whistle at me, there can be only one
explanation: that I'm not good enough.
But I am sure that one day I will be able to
make them respect and listen to me in quiet.
Until that day comes,
I won't give up, no matter what.
That's what I had decided.
Nitta-san.
I'm not going to leave, either.
But I'm afraid you can't do much with the songs
you sing. They're all Japanese love ballads.
No matter how hard you try,
you won't change your style overnight.
I agree, but I've been
sent here by Mr. Egawa.
They come here to listen to jazz.
Anything else will get whistled.
At any rate, I'm not going anywhere.
Nozomi felt encouraged
after talking to Nitta.
Day after day, she continued to sing.
But the audience still
refused to listen to her.
Days passed by as exhausted Nozomi
was going home by the last train.
Excuse me, it's the end of the line.
Ah.
Ah! I overslept!
I missed my stop again!
What do you say?
She's not bad at all.
I'd never tell she's still
basically an amateur.
Good morning, gentlemen.
We will hold the press conference
in the room we reserved.
I'm sorry, but please
wait for a few more minutes.
Oh, where's Mr. Egawa?
Oh? He was here just moments ago.
Nozomi-san, look for
Mr. Egawa and call him here.
Oh, if you're looking for him,
he's just gone home.
Then hurry up and bring him back.
I'm not sure if it's such a good idea.
What did you say?! Why?
Well, he did say earlier that he didn't
want to go to your press conference.
Besides, he's busy today.
Silence!
How dare you talk that way?
You're her assistant.
How can you lecture your mistress?
My mistress?
Yes.
You're Miki's assistant.
She's a mistress to you.
Don't be so harsh to her, Mom. Mine-san
needs to deal with all sorts of hardships.
Ah, I still didn't give you
the salary for this month.
You worked a lot this month.
Here, you've earned this.
Here, let me give it to you.
Thank you.
All right, Mom.
Let's go to the conference room.
This way, gentlemen.
Oh, how's your singing at the night club
in Yokohama for the black people going?
I heard they didn't take well to it.
Excuse us.
"How insulting."
Nozomi trembled with anger.
However, as she continued to sing in vain
with words that no one could understand,
Kōda Miki was steadily
climbing the stairs towards stardom.
As time went by, Nozomi was
getting more anxious and nervous.
How long do I have to wait before
I can become a real singer?
What am I even doing now? I sing in Japanese
for people who don't understand it at all.
It's like singing to mannequins.
Some rowdy mannequins.
What was Mr. Egawa thinking,
sending me to a place like that?
Ah! Fanni!
Fanni…
I didn't forget my song.
I can still sing.
I can sing more than enough!
Fanni… I… I…
Fanni.
I know!
If nobody listens to me
either way, I'll sing for you, Fanni.
For you only.
What are you doing?!
Stop it! Give it back!
Hold up!
I have to sing.
No matter what happens.
Nobody is listening to me.
It's the perfect moment.
Fanni…
♪  I want a chain of love to capture you  ♪
♪  I want to tie you and not let you go  ♪
♪  For you to always stay by me  ♪
♪  Morning, evening, all night long  ♪
♪  For us to live together  ♪
Nozomi-chan…
♪  You're going to leave me someday  ♪
♪  You're going to go someplace else  ♪
♪  I know everything about you  ♪
♪  But what good will it do to me  ♪
♪  That's the one thing  ♪
♪  I'm afraid the most  ♪
Bill Jones played the piano.
Bill Jones…
– Bill Jones!?
– Bill Jones…
Oh! It's Bill Jones!
It's him! The one who had
disappeared long ago!
♪  You're going to leave me someday  ♪
♪  You're going to go someplace else  ♪
♪  I know everything about you  ♪
♪  But what good will it do to me  ♪
♪  That's the one thing  ♪
♪  I'm afraid the most  ♪
Everyone is listening to my song.
Even though they
don't understand the words.
♪  There's no such thing as a chain of love  ♪
♪  I've looked for one about everywhere  ♪
It's so mysterious.
We never exchanged
a single word before,
but Bill Jones' piano is perfectly
matched with my breathing.
♪  If somebody was to sell one now  ♪
♪  I would buy it no matter the cost  ♪
I'm following the rhythm of these people
even though I don't have it in my blood.
♪  So please, pretty please,  ♪
♪  someone make it already  ♪
♪  Crying into a pillow is of no use  ♪
♪  So is thinking about my beloved one  ♪
What an extraordinary day. Today Bill Jones
returned to play the piano in front of everyone.
The reason for his comeback
is Mine Nozomi's song.
♪  It's completely useless, I'll tell you that  ♪
♪  I mean, just take a look at the big picture  ♪
He's using his wonderful technique
to capture the crowd with her,
despite literally no one in this room
can understand the words.
♪  My dream won't come  ♪
♪  true either way  ♪
Mine Nozomi obtained a technique that
can unite people across various cultures.
She's all I had hoped for.
She's a real singer.
♪  I want a chain of love to capture you  ♪
♪  I want to tie you and not let you go  ♪
Mine Nozomi.
You are a real singer!
♪  For you to always stay by me  ♪
♪  Morning, evening, all night long  ♪
♪  For us to live together  ♪
Mine Nozomi.
You are a real singer!
Even if one doesn't understand the words,
if the singer shows great passion,
their music can cross oceans and borders
unifying people around the globe.
The reason why Egawa
had sent Nozomi to Yokohama
was to teach her
that if one sings right,
they can capture the hearts
of any kind of audience.
Now that Nozomi has understood this,
there is only one thing left to do.
It's to make her debut as a singer.
When Nozomi learns that Egawa wants
to prepare her debut, she is overjoyed.
But as she ponders her past with Kōda Miki,
who had already debuted as a singer,
Nozomi suddenly gets anxious.
She realizes that there's
a lot more to debut than just singing:
things such as photo shoots, interviews
and being chased by fashion model magazines.
In fact, because of all that, Kōda Miki
has started to skip some of her lessons.
Nozomi wonders if she becomes
the same after her debut.
Troubled Nozomi asks Nitta for advice,
aware how well he knows the show business world.
She's told to find
her own way forward.
Nozomi makes a certain pledge to herself.
She goes to Egawa Isao to convey her feelings.
Please look forward to the next episode:"
"A Long Way Up".
Uta wa watashi no tomodachi dakara
Music is my friend
Kurushii toki mo watashi no mikata
When things get hard, it stays with me
Tatta hitori de sabishii keredo
Heard alone it's lonely, but
Kokoro no uta wo minna no uta ni
Heard together it resonates with everyone
Minna no uta ga bachi ippai ni
I hope the people downtown can hear it
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday