Wandering Sun
Dareka ni fumareta no no kusa mo
A blade of grass,
stepped on by someone,
Itsuka sora wo furiaogu
Someday will grow high again
Namida de nanimo mienai toki ni mo
Even when we can't see from the tears
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Shiawase no uta tooi toki ni mo
Even when we can't see from the tears
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Who's the man on the piano?
That's Bill Jones. He's back.
You're right, it's Bill.
That's Bill! It's really him!
♪  I want a chain of love to capture you  ♪
♪  I want to tie you and not let you go  ♪
♪  For you to always stay by me  ♪
♪  Morning, evening, all night long  ♪
♪  For us to live together  ♪
Nozomi.
♪  You're going to leave me someday  ♪
♪  You're going to go someplace else  ♪
Yes. That's the essence of music.
It's not about the words you use.
It's not even about the technique.
It's in the way you let your
own emotions flow through it.
♪  I know everything about you  ♪
♪  But what good will it do to me  ♪
That's precisely what has moved
the forgotten jazz pianist, Bill Jones.
♪  That's the one thing  ♪
♪  I'm afraid the most  ♪
Finally, Nozomi.
They finally recognized you
as a real singer.
— Episode 19 —
A Long Way Up
Good morning, sir.
You called for me.
Yes.
You sang until very late last night.
You must be really tired.
No, not at all. Anyhow, I'd like to thank you
for coming all the way to listen to my song.
In fact, that is precisely what
I wanted to talk to you about.
Nozomi.
Yes, sir?
You did very well last night.
Huh?
Maybe I'm not formal enough.
But you have to understand,
compliments have never been my forte.
Compliments?
Yes.
You've reached as my student
the level I had always hoped for.
No, it's even higher than that.
Sir…
I think you're ready to make
your debut if you wish.
Debut?
I can make my debut?
Yes.
We'll make your debut.
Sir…
Nozomi, you silly girl… as soon as you heard
about the debut, you cried with happiness.
You have endured far too much
suffering for a seventeen-year-old girl.
However, age does not count
towards becoming a good singer.
All the misfortune you've experienced
thus far doesn't matter either.
What matters is that
you've chosen the way of singing.
What kind of singer
will you become?
The answer to that question
will shape your life.
From now on, everything
is in your hands.
And that's what I wanted you
to think about through my teaching.
You see, the debut in itself
is not a big deal.
People all over the world
make their debuts every day.
You're just another one in the crowd.
Sir…
Sir… Thank you so much.
However, Nozomi.
This is where things
will get really difficult.
It doesn't take much effort
to make a living as a professional.
But it's a different thing altogether
if you want to become a star.
The real battle begins now.
I'm betting a lot on you.
Do your best.
Do you understand?
Yes.
I have to let my family know.
I can't wait to see their reactions.
Anyway, congratulations.
Pops got discharged safe and sound and
you're becoming a star. It's really amazing!
It was possible only
thanks to everyone's support.
Nozomi, you better not disappoint Mr. Egawa
after he's supported you for so long. Do your best.
Here's to No. 1 singer in Japan!
What? With my support, you'll become the greatest
singer in the whole nation, no doubt about it.
It's your support that
worries me, to be honest.
Hah, now you're just teasing me.
Anyway, make sure to eat a lot today.
You've deserved it.
We'll support you, too.
Good luck, Sis!
Thanks.
Don't strain yourself, Dad.
Oh, I'm fine, now.
I'll do my best, too. I don't want
to lose to my beautiful daughter.
That's the spirit!
Time for another round… oh?
That's not right.
Dad still needs to rest.
Oh, don't be so stiff.
Just one round.
No!
I had it coming, I guess.
Wow, the moon is so big.
It's full moon tonight.
So big!
It really is!
Soon I too will join the ranks
of professional singers.
I can't believe it.
I finally made it.
How did it go?
That's still not it. How many times
do I need to repeat myself?
I told you, spread your arms.
Move your head,
make your hair move like waves.
Move your legs lightly,
like a ballerina. Now, let's repeat.
She's ran for like half a kilometer
just for a few photos in some magazine.
Alright, stay in that spot!
Imagine you're like a balloon,
flying up to the sky.
Start!
That's all wrong!
Go back to the start.
No, no. Once more!
What are you doing?
Get up and run!
But all this has nothing to do
with the profession of a singer.
I spent the entire morning running around.
Anything more and I'd have fainted.
You didn't have to go that far.
No. I can't afford to be so capricious.
I'm a commercial product.
I have to make sure I sell well.
To take advantage of every
opportunity that comes my way.
Otherwise, I can't even dream
of becoming a star.
Oh, by the way. I heard that you're going
to make your debut soon as well.
That's right.
Congratulations.
But since I've been already there,
let me give you some advice.
Forget all that sweet talk about the essence
of music. You need to sell first and foremost.
Because if you don't, you can't
call yourself a professional.
Music that sells…
Is that how professionals think?
Here, look. It's Mori Shin'ichi
and Ishida Ayumi.
You were great yesterday,
Ayumi-chan.
Make up room
Good morning.
On-air
I'm a commercial product.
But I feel that since her debut
Miki-san's been too busy to actually sing.
Kōda Miki Autograph Session
Kōda Miki's First Single
"The Wounded Bird"
Okay, good!
Good job. Thanks.
Good job.
See you later.
Miki was already a budding singer.
Upon hearing her words,
Nozomi felt great uneasiness and
anxiety creeping into her heart.
The anxiety was slowly, but steadily
spreading, like a rain cloud.
Miki-san has her own fans already.
She's quickly climbing
the ladder of success.
But…
Step on it.
Ah, what a pain in the butt.
They have wrinkled my new dress.
Nozomi-san, what's next
on the schedule?
Just a moment.
Oh no, we have a problem.
You have a lesson with Mr. Egawa,
but at the same time an autograph session
in a newly opened record store.
It was my agent who scheduled it so.
Alright. Drive me to that store.
What about the lesson?
I'll just have to catch up
before my new song comes out.
But the autograph session gets priority as it'll
boost my sales. That's how you become famous.
You'd like to see
Mr. Egawa, wouldn't you?
That's fine. You can go and tell on me as you
always do, if that's what you want, Nozomi-san.
I've never badmouthed you.
Alright, alright.
Anyway, I need a little space now.
Your work is done for today.
I understand.
It's obvious that Miki-san chose
the quickest way to get to famous.
But because of that, she must devote all
her time to her promotion and public relations.
Egawa
She will certainly become a star,
but can she call herself a real singer?
Is this how it works?
Kōda decided to miss her lesson?
Did you come here
just to tell me that?
You could've just called.
Yes, but…
It's fine.
In any event,
I don't intend to criticize Kōda.
Her packed schedule only proves
that she is selling well.
But sir, don't you think her technique
will worsen if she keeps skipping lessons?
Of course it will.
But if she manages to hold for a year or two,
it will already be quite good.
Do not forget that new singers
arrive on the market every day.
This means that…
Yes. If you're not very careful, you'll end up
like every other consumable good.
There is only one way to avoid that.
You have to plan ahead
on how you're going to sell.
You can't lose sight of yourself.
Can't lose sight of yourself?
In other words, keep singing
with all your heart.
It's difficult in the long run, though.
I understand.
Instead of wasting time here with me, I think you'd
be better off going back to the club in Yokohama.
Yes sir.
That's the girl from yesterday.
Did she come to sing again?
Looks like it.
Hey, Bill! She's here again!
Play us something good!
Hey, miss! Sing for us once more!
Everyone remembers me.
I was sure you'd come back.
Here, get on the stage.
Nitta-san, I'm very happy,
but today I'd prefer not to.
What are you talking about?
Everyone's looking forward to it.
Especially Bill.
He's been coming here every day.
♪  I want a chain of love to capture you  ♪
♪  I want to tie you and not let you go  ♪
♪  For you to always stay by me  ♪
♪  Morning, evening, all night long  ♪
♪  For us to live together  ♪
♪  If somebody was to sell one now  ♪
♪  I would buy it no matter the cost  ♪
It's no good.
I've lost all my confidence.
I can't sing naturally.
The words don't flow.
What's going on?
What are you doing?
What's wrong, Nozomi-chan?
It's all wrong!
No, no, no!
I'm sorry, but I can't.
I'm not good enough.
– What's wrong?
– Hey! Mine-kun!
Nozomi-chan…
What in the world has happened?
It was a complete disaster.
What a resounding failure.
I disappointed all those people.
They were looking forward to it so much…
Nozomi-chan.
Nitta-san.
I…
Wait a moment. If you want to ask for an advice
about life, I'm afraid I'm not the best person.
That's not it.
I just don't understand
things anymore.
What is music all about?
Why do I want to sing?
Hmm.
Mr. Egawa told me that
I'm ready to make my debut.
Oh, that's a good news.
But I wonder, if I become a professional now,
is that enough to call myself a real singer?
I don't know all the answers, either.
This is actually the reason
why I'm going on a journey again.
What?
Another journey?
I met you again in Yokohama and I saw how
you brought about the great Bill Jones' comeback.
It was a huge shock.
My biggest dream would be to play
the trumpet the way he can play the piano.
That's why I feel depressed.
Nitta-san…
So far I have continued to play the trumpet
without having a clear purpose in my mind.
I've been looking for one for years.
But now I feel that I'm on the right track.
I hope that someday we will meet again.
But I have a hunch you'll be a big star by then.
Farewell.
Despite so much experience,
he went on a journey to find his purpose.
I understand.
Now I know what I'm singing for.
Nitta-san, you taught me that.
Thank you, Nitta-san.
You want to quit?
Are you serious?
Yes. I know it's short notice.
I won't hide it's a hassle for me.
Oh, well, I guess I don't mind, since there
are countless people willing to be my assistant.
That means you'll finally get
to focus on studying. Am I right?
Actually, no. After our discussion here,
I'm going to say goodbye to Mr. Egawa as well.
What? Are you serious?
What about your dream
of becoming a singer?
I'm going to look
for my own way of achieving it.
Oh? I see.
I don't think the show business world is so nice
that you can become a singer all by herself.
Oh, well. Good luck, anyway.
Good bye.
What is she thinking?
At any rate this means
one less rival to worry about.
You want to leave?
Nozomi. Before I say anything,
I want to know the reason for this decision.
I'm not so sure if I have what it takes
to be a professional singer.
That's not a good reason!
Tell me what's really on your mind.
What is the actual reason?
Sir… There's something
I want to ask you.
What is music?
That's… something
you can't explain with words.
At the beginning, I envied Miki-san for
how fast she was climbing the career ladder.
But as time passes, I'm under the impression
that she has less and less to do with actual music.
Even if I debut and become a star,
I don't want to end up being like Miki-san.
So are you saying that
you don't want to become a star?
No. Far from it.
But I don't want to become someone
who is blinded by money and fame.
My dad told me once that
as a singer, my is job to comfort
people who are in low spirits.
Before becoming a star,
I'd like to become such singer.
I understand.
If that's what you want,
you're free leave.
Thank you.
But know that you have chosen a much harder path
than the one that leads you to become a star.
Master!
Nozomi-chan!
Are you really sure about this?
You were so close
of achieving your dream.
Thank you for worrying
about me, Sune-chan.
But as long as we have something to eat,
I think my family will get by somehow.
Good bye, Sune-chan.
Nozomi-chan…
Nozomi-chan!
Nozomi has grown even more
than I had realized.
She's finally understood
what music is all about.
Nozomi, you're going to be
all alone from now on.
You don't need me anymore.
You figured everything out all by yourself.
You really are something, you know that?
That's for the best.
I'm a singer.
This is what I'm going to do in life.
I have to sing
from the bottom of my heart.
Station Store
I don't know what
mom and dad will say.
But I'm determined and
nothing will change my mind now.
Fanni comes back from America.
Nozomi wonders whether rejecting
the opportunity for a debut was a good idea.
She goes to ask Fanni for guidance.
But for some reason,
Fanni doesn't want to meet her.
Shortly thereafter, she learns from Miki
that Fanni is actually her older brother.
It turns out to be a fatal blow
and Nozomi disappears.
Please look forward to the next episode:
"Welcome Back, Fanni".
Uta wa watashi no tomodachi dakara
Music is my friend
Kurushii toki mo watashi no mikata
When things get hard, it stays with me
Tatta hitori de sabishii keredo
Heard alone it's lonely, but
Kokoro no uta wo minna no uta ni
Heard together it resonates with everyone
Minna no uta ga bachi ippai ni
I hope the people downtown can hear it
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday