Wandering Sun
Dareka ni fumareta no no kusa mo
A blade of grass,
stepped on by someone,
Itsuka sora wo furiaogu
Someday will grow high again
Namida de nanimo mienai toki ni mo
Even when we can't see from the tears
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Shiawase no uta tooi toki ni mo
Even when we can't see from the tears
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Egawa had offered Nozomi a chance to debut,
but she turned it down. Was that a wise decision?
Nozomi had been eagerly awaiting
the day when she could make her debut.
What changed her feelings was
seeing Kōda Miki's lifestyle
and how it makes her move away
from the world of music more and more.
Good luck, Nozomi!
Congratulations!
However, the most difficult thing for Nozomi
was facing her family, who did not know anything.
— Episode 20 —
Welcome Back, Fanni
I really don't think
I can understand you.
You have come this far
and you want to stop?
You did everything for nothing.
What do you say, Nozomi?
I could go with you.
How about talking
to Mr. Egawa again?
I thought you of all people
would understand my decision.
Hey, Nozomi-chan…
Actually, never mind.
What does it mean to be a singer?
What and whom do I sing for?
Until I can answer these questions,
I can't make my debut.
But you know, Nozomi, such a chance
doesn't come your way every day.
I'm well aware of it.
So why do you behave this way?
What's more, keep in mind that Mr. Egawa
has gone out of his way to help you.
And here I was telling all my friends
that you would go on television soon.
Sis won't be a singer anymore?
Looks like it.
Well, if you're so sure of yourself,
I won't say anything more.
Just don't regret it later.
One doesn't make a living
with ideals alone.
You're right.
Kazuo-chan, Yuki-chan.
Thank you.
It really means a lot to me.
– Look, it's Fanni!
– What?
The boxer Fanni Moriyama
returns home today.
Welcome Home, Fanni Moriyama
After mysterious disappearance
he comes back with a world ranking.
Fanni's back?
Fanni… That's my Fanni!
When he first arrived to New York, he started
working odd jobs to ensure his livelihood.
But he never stopped training as a boxer
and soon joined a local gym.
And last month, he defeated the legendary
Terry Wilson in a light weight title match.
Fanni's back… with world ranking.
How does it feel to be a star?
"Star"? I don't like
the sound of it, to be honest.
Fanni's a star. I, on the other hand,
have destroyed my chance.
Did I make the right call?
Or was that a grave mistake?
Fanni… What would you say to me?
Fanni.
No, no! Stop pushing, for crying
out loud! He won't see anyone!
Sir, I am…
Go home. Fanni doesn't—
I am friends with him.
Tell him that Mine Nozomi
would like to see him.
Sorry, but no. He doesn't want
to see anyone now.
No way. Just tell him
my name, Nozomi.
No means no!
Chairman's Office
Huh? Mine Nozomi?
What's wrong?
I told you before.
I don't want to see anybody.
Gotcha.
Is something the matter?
No, everything's fine.
I see.
No one's heard of him before,
and now he's a legendary star.
There's no way
he'd want to meet you now.
Did Fanni change?
The Fanni I remember
was kind and gentle.
Did I really make the right decision?
Tell me, please.
Sir, you have a guest.
Good morning.
So, did you finish the lyrics
I asked you for the other day?
I will be happy with anything,
as long as it is written by you.
But if it's possible, I'd like it
to be a beautiful love song.
Oh, is this my song?
You are really rude.
Rude?
What and who I am writing for
does not concern you at all.
This one is for Mine Nozomi.
What did you say?
Sometimes, you see, I write songs…
…to hear them,
rather than sell them.
I wonder if Mine will ever agree
to sing this piece, though.
You are unreasonably spiteful.
Apparently you like Nozomi a lot.
Did you know that her boyfriend,
Fanni Moriyama, has returned home?
What?
Fanni Moriyama.
He's became a star and now he's back.
You know what they organized?
What?
A welcome party for him.
A welcome party?
Fanni Moriyama…
It's at Hotel United.
Fanni Moriyama.
What kind of man is he? Who could
possibly make her fall head over heels?
Here, the elevator to the 39th floor,
the Sky Hall is this way.
Fanni Moriyama is a big deal.
I bet he'll become big.
I completely agree.
I only saw him on TV,
but he's handsome, like an actor.
Fanni Moriyama Welcome Party
I am not a fan.
I know Fanni personally.
"Fanni"…?
I kindly ask you to let me see
Fanni Moriyama-san in person.
Sorry, but this party
is invitation only.
– Excuse me…
– Oh, welcome, welcome.
Fanni… Why did you become a star?
Oh, I forgot my invitation.
Let's do the formalities later.
Ah, Mr. Nohara!
Please enjoy the party.
Here is Saeki Yumi-san, No. 1 among beautiful
actresses. She wanted to meet Fanni by all means.
Ladies and gentlemen,
let's have a round of applause.
Thanks, thanks.
Thank you very much.
Well then, ladies and gentlemen,
the drinks and meals are over there.
We hope you enjoy this party and celebrate
Fanni Moriyama's return with everyone.
Pleased to meet you.
My name is Nohara Jun. I'm a song writer.
I'm Fanni Moriyama.
Let's talk over there.
Actually, I came to talk to you
about Mine Nozomi-san.
Huh?
About… Nozomi?
I have a genuine feelings for her song, or her
passion for it. You could say I'm in love with her.
How… does that concern me?
She's smitten with you.
She loves you!
I'm here to ask about
your feelings for her.
I want to know how you
genuinely feel about her.
I'd rather not talk about it.
So are you saying that you do not
have any feelings for Nozomi?
That's not what I said.
Nozomi has been
waiting for your return.
Look, what do you expect me to say?
Even as a boxer, you ought to know how important
it is for her as a singer to maintain that purity.
She's very talented and I think it's your job
as her lover to protect her innocence.
I can't.
What do you mean?
It's not my concern if Nozomi
is too weak to face reality.
I don't care whether
she sings your songs, either.
Hold on! She's still just a girl.
What about it?
Are you just going
to throw her out like that?
Don't be stupid.
How could I abandon
my little sister?
Little sister?…
Little sister?
Come on out.
If you were to get lyrics from Nohara-san,
wouldn't you be so kind to sell them to me?
What?
Is this what you
wanted to talk about?
I'd be very grateful.
Is Nohara-san composing
a song for me?
Could you sell them to me?
I have to refuse.
It's not out of any malice.
If he wrote a song for me,
wouldn't it be rude to him to peddle it?
Get off your high horse!
I only offered it because I thought
it would be a waste on you.
Don't you get that a good song should
be sold in stores all over the country?
But…
But you always preach about the essence
of music or whatever. What a load of garbage!
What have you accomplished so far?
It is not garbage.
I do want to become a real singer. I am just
still figuring out what that means to me.
Look, there are no real singers
or fake singers.
Professionals have to produce as many hits
as possible. That is all there is to it.
But it doesn't mean
the end justifies the means.
Fine, whatever.
I get so irritated whenever I talk to you.
Will you sell it to me or not?
I will not.
I'm sorry.
I guess that was out of line.
Did you see Fanni already?
Fanni?
I suppose you weren't able to.
Such a shame.
Huh? How do you know?
Miki-san, if you know
something, please tell me.
Oh, I do happen to know something.
Something truly unfortunate.
What is it? Please tell me.
Fanni and you
are brother and sister.
If you think I'm lying,
try asking him about it.
Fanni and you
are brother and sister.
Fanni is my older brother?
The hell?! You have a death wish?
Fanni is my brother.
Fanni!
Open up, Fanni!
Please open the door.
Fanni!
Open the door.
I'm begging you.
Please open the door.
Fanni, you're there,
aren't you? Open it!
Go away, Nozomi.
We can't see each other.
Is it true?
Are you my…
Don't say it out loud, Nozomi!
Are you really…
Are you my brother?
Calm down, Nozomi.
So what if I am?
What do you say, Nozomi?
Forget about it as soon as possible
and dedicate yourself to singing.
Fanni…
Brother!
The Fanni I loved was my brother…
It can't be. It can't be!
Now I remember, back then
I had been looking for Hisashi.
I couldn't see him anywhere.
I didn't even know how he looked like.
But I found Fanni instead…
Fanni was my brother
Hisashi all along.
The man I had loved
was my older brother.
Fanni Moriyama speaking.
This is Nohara.
Sorry about the other day.
To cut things short,
I'm looking for Nozomi-san.
What? Did something
happen to her?
Yes. As far as I know,
she went to see you, but…
she didn't come back yet.
What?
I'm doing what I can to find her.
I understand.
I'll go look for her as well.
You're so infatuated with Nozomi
that you get angry when it comes to her.
How can you go around hurting people
without feeling any sort of remorse?
Hurting each other
is the destiny of all rivals.
How is Nozomi your rival when she
gave up her chance to make a debut?
Heh.
You do not believe in yourself,
and that's why you're afraid of Nozomi.
Fanni… So that's how
you must've felt.
That's why you'd taken off without a word
and had lost that Rookie of the Year match.
Now it all makes sense.
After your return, you only wanted to
avoid me and spare me this sick truth.
Mom, Dad… Why did you have
to give my brother up for adoption?
You left for America and got back
on your feet without anyone's help.
But for me it's just too hard.
♪  It's already autumn  ♪
♪  There's no one on the seashore  ♪
♪  Even though one of my dreams  ♪
♪  has just shattered  ♪
♪  I will never forget  ♪
♪  I promised the sand  ♪
♪  Even if it's lonely, if it's so lonely  ♪
♪  I'm not going to die  ♪
Nozomi!
Fanni!
I looked for you all over, Nozomi.
Why were you crying?
I didn't know
you were such a crybaby.
We'll get through this.
I believe in you, Nozomi.
Thanks.
I think I'll go on a journey.
I need to get back on my feet.
But it'll be tough to do it all alone.
I'll be fine… Brother.
Good. Good luck, Nozomi.
Thanks.
Fanni and Nozomi
are not related by blood.
As the two don't know about the birth switch,
they have now reunited as siblings.
Suffering through love, they are determined
to welcome tomorrow with joy.
Nozomi learns that
Fanni is her brother.
Leaving everything behind, she goes on a journey
to find the true meaning of her song.
Her first stop is at a poor
fishing village with few young people.
As she tries to cheer the locals up,
she's only met with cold glares.
Please look forward to the next episode:
"A Cry To The Sea".
Uta wa watashi no tomodachi dakara
Music is my friend
Kurushii toki mo watashi no mikata
When things get hard, it stays with me
Tatta hitori de sabishii keredo
Heard alone it's lonely, but
Kokoro no uta wo minna no uta ni
Heard together it resonates with everyone
Minna no uta ga bachi ippai ni
I hope the people downtown can hear it
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday