Wandering Sun
Dareka ni fumareta no no kusa mo
A blade of grass,
stepped on by someone,
Itsuka sora wo furiaogu
Someday will grow high again
Namida de nanimo mienai toki ni mo
Even when we can't see from the tears
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Shiawase no uta tooi toki ni mo
Even if we are unable to sing in joy
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Mine Nozomi went on a journey
to discover the true meaning of music.
At some point she started to cry
in despair, but continued to sing still.
To sing is to feel.
A single drop of water
soon becomes a small stream.
It flows endlessly like a river
through the mountains.
Nozomi's "Song of Heart" moved
one person, then another and another.
Before long she captured
hearts of many, many people.
But in the middle of her journey Nozomi learns
that her father's health problems have recurred.
— Episode 23 —
The Phantom Singer
Sun TV chief producer, Yoshii Yoshi.
I listened to your song, young lady.
I must admit, it was fantastic.
I've been doing this job for 15 years
and I've heard thousands of songs,
but it is the first time I listened
to one that was so touching.
Thank you, but I do not
deserve this compliment.
Lately, the switchboard of our station receives
nothing but requests for the "Song of Heart".
We were surprised, because no one seemed
to know the song, let alone the singer.
So I set off to look for both.
My investigation brought me to the festival
in Arashiyama, where I stumbled upon you.
I'm going to be serious.
I want you to go on my show. I'd like us to discuss
the contract when we get back to Tōkyō.
But sir, I…
If you have something to do,
we can have the meeting tomorrow.
Please wait a moment.
I'm very thankful for your offer
to appear on your TV show.
But please let me think about it.
Huh?
Think about it?
I had never met a newcomer
who'd have refused to appear on TV.
On the contrary, they all
were dying to sign the contract.
I'm sorry to disappoint you, but I really
prefer to think it through first. I'm sorry.
It doesn't look like she's trying
to get her value up, at least not yet.
Sis!
Kazuo! Yuki!
– Sis!
– Welcome home!
I'm so glad you're back.
How's Dad?
How's he feeling?
He's fine. Why?
Really?
Yes. Don't worry.
Oh, thank goodness.
But how did you know I'd be here?
We got a telegram.
Telegram?
It was from someone
with a funny name, like…
The Gorillas?
Whoa! The Geriras?
Hige-san is very thoughtful.
I have to thank them.
Okay, let's go home.
Hehe, hold your horses.
There's one thing
we'd like to talk about first.
What do you mean?
Why don't I explain it to you?
Sir!
Welcome back, Mine.
He'll tell you everything.
What's going on, sir?
Did something happen?
You don't have to worry
about your family anymore.
Your brother, Fanni Moriyama,
has returned to live with your family.
Really? Fanni did?
He's living at our house now?
Exactly. Your brother came back to the family
and offered to take care of all of you.
Too bad you didn't get to see
the day of his arrival.
Mom and Dad cried so much.
Kuma-san was like always,
then he whacked his back.
I see.
Ah, come on, don't do it.
You know I hate
to see you in this state.
Sorry, Kazuo.
I'm just so happy.
You better do your best,
for your brother's sake, too.
I will.
Don't cry anymore. Let's go.
Here, Sis.
Thank you.
– For me, french fries.
– For me, okonomiyaki.
For me…
Oh? Yoshii-san.
Sorry to disturb you, Maestro.
Please forgive me for this indiscretion,
but I let myself follow you.
What brings you here?
Looks like Mine Nozomi is your
apprentice, or am I mistaken?
You shouldn't hide her
from the public like that.
I never meant to hide her.
Quite on the contrary.
I'll negotiate your contract with
Mr. Egawa. Is this alright with you?
Yes.
I'm leaving everything
to my teacher.
The fact that Yoshii-san himself wants you
is the best proof that you're a real singer.
Thank you, sir.
Huh, things are going well.
I always knew you're very good.
Too bad you're a little big, Sis.
Yoshii-san is recognized as one
of the best producers around.
There are few famous singers today
who have made it big without his help.
Besides, the music festivals he organizes are of
remarkable quality, one the best in the country.
Are you sure you want
to turn down his offer?
He will surely make you a star,
even bigger than I ever could.
I'm scared of becoming a star.
When you were on a journey, you gradually
grew to dislike the idea of becoming a star.
I understand it better than you think.
But what you sing is a real song,
in its truest form.
More people should hear it.
The only way to let people learn of it and love it,
is to appear on mass media in one form or another.
Just take your time to think it over.
I will.
Mr. Egawa has made
some great points.
But if I appear on mass media,
won't I soon lose sight of myself?
Won't I get blinded by stardom?
Before long, I could get too busy
to even take any lessons.
Become a mass media's puppet.
I don't want that.
I still remember
my promise to Nitta-san.
That in 10, 20 years…
No, that throughout my whole life
I won't betray my ideals and stay true to myself.
Sune-chan!
Want me to turn it off?
Nah.
It used to upset me,
but I don't mind it anymore.
Then you'll be fine.
I'm glad to hear it.
You've got it together now.
This means you can face the world of television
without worrying that you'll change in a bad way.
I wonder about that.
There are many singers who become famous
without betraying their ideals.
At first it'll be a bit difficult
not to get carried away.
But I believe you have enough integrity
to remain the true singer that you have become.
Why don't you even try?
You have what it takes.
Yet you look like
you want to run away.
That's not true.
I never said I want to run away.
I'm sorry, but that's just
how it looks to me.
That you're just afraid
of any challenge.
You've got it wrong! I just…
The next request is
for the "Song of Heart".
However, it's a mysterious piece,
to which we don't even know the lyrics very well.
From the students in Kanazawa
to 60 years-old elderly people,
the requests for this song come
from rural areas all around the country.
It is unprecedented in the history of our station
for such a phantom song to have so big demand.
Who in the world is the vocalist?
Where is she now?
Finally, when will her fans
get to see her in public?
These questions remain
unanswered for now.
I have my own fans?
Nozomi-chan, is it really alright for you
to let your fans down like this?
I'm an egoist, I know. But still…
If this becomes my full time job and I become
a mass media's puppet, I'll betray what I stand for.
Nozomi-chan…
But I'll do it.
Sune-chan, I made my decision.
I'll give it a try.
I might get crushed
by the world of television.
But that doesn't matter.
I have to think about the people
who are waiting for me.
Nozomi-chan.
I'll sing.
I'll sing for the people
who want to hear it.
But the most important thing is that I will sing
to improve myself. I can't ever forget that.
Good luck.
Thank you. I'll need it.
Hello? This is Yoshii.
Ah, Mr. Egawa.
Oh? Are you serious?
Do you really give consent for Mine Nozomi's
appearance on public television?
I'm so thankful.
Oh, yes, of course.
Oh? A condition?
She was thinking about it all night long
and seems resolved to go along with this.
But I think it would be better if you discussed
the conditions with her in person.
Oh, you see, actually
it's a bit of a problem.
I'm flying to the United States
shortly after tonight's broadcast.
I'll be away for entire two weeks.
That's fine, we can wait
until you get back.
As a matter of fact, tomorrow
I'm leaving for Europe myself.
Let's meet in two weeks.
I wonder if they'll agree to my terms.
All right, everything went okay.
But I'd like to know
what her conditions are.
Your request may be quite difficult for him,
but I think he should agree.
I see.
You must think only of singing.
Yes. I understand.
Good work.
Good work!
Today it took you longer than usual.
I didn't feel well today.
It was difficult for me to sing it the right way.
Are you all right?
Yes, just a little tired.
Miki…
You can't afford to relax.
You have next performance right after.
Five minutes of rest
won't kill anyone.
We still don't know who the singer for the
"Song of Heart" is. What are we going to do?
There's nothing we can do, to be honest.
The other companies are looking for her as well.
We don't anything about her
except that she's a cute young girl.
Really, a phantom singer,
for lack of a better name. What a pain.
Yes. A phantom singer.
"Song of Heart"? Surely not the one
Mine Nozomi had written?
The one behind the "Song of Heart"
is truly a phantom singer.
Yes.
It's Nozomi.
There's no mistake.
Only she could sing the "Song of Heart".
This means…
At some point some recording company
is going to find her and she'll sing a contract.
"A phantom singer"? That name
is going to give her even more reputation.
Who is it?
– It's me.
– It's open.
Miki, you're awake, too?
What are you doing here
in the middle of the night?
About the phantom singer
they discussed about today…
You mean Mine Nozomi?
I knew it.
Well, of course it's her.
You see, Mine…
There's more?
The chief producer Yoshii of Sun TV is planning
to put her on his next music festival.
Mr. Yoshii's music festivals invite
only the first-class musicians.
And Mine Nozomi is making her debut
on one of these festivals.
Are you sure?
Yes, I'm sure.
She didn't release a single disc,
yet she's ahead of you.
But listen to me, Miki.
The negotiations for her
contract are postponed
until Yoshii-san comes back
from the United States.
From what I know, Mine Nozomi
has a condition on her own.
A condition?
It means that we have some space.
Some space?
Yes. Space to take
our own measures.
Mom! I can always count on you.
Can you really do something about it?
Yes. You know that it is out of the question for
the Kōda family to be left behind by the poor.
Mom…
The singer behind the
"Song of Heart": Mine Nozomi
It's Mine Nozomi, no mistake!
Why were you in the shadows so far?
Where you have been all this time?
Can you sing for us?
We'd love to sign
a contract with you.
Oh, please consider our offer first.
We can guarantee exclusive
late-night broadcasts.
And we can put you
on our morning show.
I really don't know what to say.
Hello? This is Everything Sport.
Oh, it's you, ma'am.
Thank you again for the scoop
you gave us the other day.
Mine Nozomi's conditions?
She has her terms
regarding her debut?
What? It's about contract money?
Yes, yes it is. As a proof, the president
of the company promoting my daughter
prepared a contract for a heavenly sum
and sent the offer to Egawa Isao.
Oh, you mean Uchida Productions?
That's another big scoop. Thank you
for your information and for choosing us.
Even if they find out it's all fake,
it'll hurt her image nevertheless.
The future of Mine Nozomi's contract
with Sun TV depends on her conditions?
Uchida Productions
begins to move aggressively
"A contract between
Uchida Productions and Mine Nozomi"?
"The more money, the better,
says the singer".
This is terrible.
I didn't talk to anyone about it,
yet they wrote all of this.
Yes, exactly. And even though there were people
from Uchida Productions, I never let anyone in.
And here they wrote that you
have already signed the contract.
Once Yoshii-san learns of it,
he will be furious.
Money's got nothing
to do with my terms.
I'm back. Here's the paperwork
for her contract.
Thanks.
I'd like to know who are you
planning to broadcast this week?
Oh? I thought we talked about this
before I went to the United States.
I wanted to hold a special show
for the singer behind the "Song of Heart".
Looks like you're not aware
that Mine has turned on us.
What? "Mine Nozomi signs
a contract with Uchida Productions."
"The more money, the better"?
So her terms were about the money.
We no longer have the rights to use her, unless
we sign our own contract with Uchida Productions.
But it'll be a cold day in hell
before they sell her.
I… I can't believe that girl.
Was the singer behind the "Song of Heart"
someone of such a low moral character?
I'm sorry, sir.
Could you pass us the ball?
For me, the great Yoshii Yoshi,
to be deceived by some girl from the streets…
Wait. If Mine Nozomi
was really like that…
What was that in Arashiyama?
It wasn't fake.
My ears can't be fooled.
I'll talk to her directly.
That's the most important right now.
Thank you for arranging a meeting.
I've been waiting for your return.
You don't have to care about the trash
they write in the magazines, Mine-kun.
Thank you, sir.
It was a mistake on my part that I went
to America without listening to your terms.
So what are they?
Please name your terms now.
I just want you not to force me to become
a star at all costs for you to sell.
I see. What else?
I will do everything to be
a true singer and not an instrument.
Anything more specific?
Huh? More specific?
I just listed my conditions.
That's all, actually.
That's all?
Is it not good?
W-What?
Y-Your only condition…
is just to not make you
into a star at all costs?
Yes.
I understand.
So that's all.
That's how it was. Ha!
Excuse me, but I don't think
I had the right to be so upfront right away.
Very well.
I agree to your condition.
However…
I hope you'll appear
on our music festivals.
Naturally.
I'll participate with great pleasure.
Mine Nozomi wants to become a singer,
but hasn't yet made her official debut.
For you, it must be intoxicating
to feel so superior to Nozomi.
But your style is
not so good, you know.
Nozomi…
Mine Nozomi's on television!
That's not possible.
What is she doing here? How?
She seems so happy
when she's singing.
Damn you. Why do you always win?
Why?
Very well. I won't let it end like this.
Mine Nozomi.
You are a true singer.
My ears were right.
But know this, Mine.
I'm not confident I'll be able
to meet the condition you set for me.
You told me not to
make you into a star…
But would the world forgive me?
Nozomi sang.
She kept on singing.
To be heard by
as many people as possible.
Nozomi's song echoed
in the sky all over Japan.
Yes.
I have very sensitive information about the
"Song of Heart" artist and I want to make it public.
Yes. I'm waiting at Princess Hotel.
I have informed
other companies as well.
Hm?
Who am I?
I'm the older sister
of Nohara Jun, the lyricist.
Mine Nozomi.
This time you'll get to taste
the world of suffering I had to go through.
This time you will.
There's no mistake.
A lone woman, Nohara Michiko,
who wishes for Mine Nozomi's misfortune.
What is she planning?
Not knowing about
the cursed fate lurking over her,
Mine Nozomi kept on
singing innocently.
Mine Nozomi appears on television
and her popularity begins to rapidly grow.
There is one woman, however,
who is not pleased to see her success.
Nohara Michiko continues
her scheming to see Nozomi's fall.
Michiko gathers press
and speaks out surprising facts.
What does she tell them?
Please look forward to the next episode:
"The Secret Is Out".
Uta wa watashi no tomodachi dakara
Music is my friend
Kurushii toki mo watashi no mikata
When things get hard, it stays with me
Tatta hitori de sabishii keredo
Heard alone it's lonely, but
Kokoro no uta wo minna no uta ni
Heard together it resonates with everyone
Minna no uta ga bachi ippai ni
I hope the people downtown can hear it
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday