Wandering Sun
Dareka ni fumareta no no kusa mo
A blade of grass,
stepped on by someone,
Itsuka sora wo furiaogu
Someday will grow high again
Namida de nanimo mienai toki ni mo
Even when we can't see from the tears
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Shiawase no uta tooi toki ni mo
Even if we are unable to sing in joy
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Raised in a poor family which she has to support,
not discouraged by the constant hardships of life,
a girl who loves to sing
and decided to live by singing,
Mine Nozomi.
On the other hand, grown up in a wealthy family,
enjoying a facilitated path to stardom,
a girl who takes the most
effective route to reach her goals,
Kōda Miki.
— Episode 24 —
The Secret Is Out
Thank you all for coming here.
I'd like to release a certain information about
two singers who are now gaining popularity.
Something that will turn the lives of
Mine Nozomi and Kōda Miki upside down.
There is a secret behind
the birth of these two.
What kind of secret?
Are they siblings?
No way!
I'll tell you everything,
but I have to start from the beginning.
Let me start with Kōda Miki.
She's not the daughter
of the great industrialist we all know.
In reality, she is a daughter of an
oden stand owner who lives in the slums.
As for the other girl, Mine Nozomi.
She's the rightful heiress to the Kōda Family.
The girls were swapped at their birth.
Swapped?
Are you serious?
That's absurd.
But if it's true…
I'm sorry, but I can't
give you any more details.
But I want to introduce myself. I am the sister
of the famous songwriter, Nohara Jun.
Now that you know who I am,
I think you can believe my words.
Hold still for the camera, ma'am!
The secret of the births of
Kōda Miki and Mine Nozomi
Nohara Jun's sister's astonishing confession
T-That's absurd.
Try to calm down, Miki.
They're saying
I'm not your daughter.
What are you talking about?
No one knows better than me who my daughter is.
You must not listen to their lies.
But…
The exchange took place in the hospital
and babies are all alike. It's plausible.
No, it's not. Think about it.
You were born in the Tonan Hospital.
It's the best hospital in the city and certainly
not a place where the poor can set foot.
It's evident that it's the work of someone
who is envious of your popularity.
Someone who can't bear to see
you succeed and getting famous.
Do you seriously think it's someone
who wants to hinder me?
I don't know.
What else could it be?
People who appear on TV once or twice
and realize they can't succeed
often resort to such games.
You know who this reminds me of?
Mine Nozomi.
Mine Nozomi?
Miss, there are people who want
to have an interview with you.
They're from press.
Oh, we'll be right there.
Do you understand?
You are a star.
You can't let it get to you.
For now, let your mom
handle the interview.
It's true. If you want to become a star,
you have to eliminate your enemies.
It's not so strange for Mine Nozomi
to try to create a scandal.
But this is just too low.
I won't forgive her.
You won't believe what I heard—
Watch out!
Excuse me, where can I find
Mine Nozomi-san's house?
We live there.
Oh, you're her siblings?
I'd like to talk to your older sister.
She's not home right now.
She went to the hospital
to get medicine for Dad.
I see. Where is that hospital?
It's the one just beyond the river.
Gotcha. Thanks.
What's your name, mister?
Thank you!
Sis is totally a star now.
Yeah. Let's go.
Here, the secret
of Nozomi-chan's birth.
That must be it, right?
Let's see… hmm.
Whoa! Kōda's family empire?!
Hey, Kazuo-chan.
No gossiping about
Nozomi-chan, you hear me?
Let's go, Yuki.
Okay.
Tonan General Hospital
What… Where it'd come from?
Me and Miki-san
exchanged in the cradles?
I can't believe it.
Why would Nohara-san's sister wait for 17 years
before going public with something like this?
This is… This is such nonsense.
I can't believe it.
I can't believe it!
Mine-san.
Here's your medicine, Mine-san.
Ah, right.
Sorry for spacing out.
The doctor advises him to rest as much
as possible and avoid any stress.
I understand. Thank you, ma'am.
Take care.
It's Mine Nozomi.
Mine-kun, we have
a few questions for you.
We're with the Weekly Punch.
How do you feel about recent
articles about you in the newspapers?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Hey, hey, Mine-kun!
Just a sec!
Do you have anything to say?
Even single word will do.
It's all slander.
How so?
Let me ask you, do you have
any proof to prove your story?
Hmm, that's true,
we don't exactly have anything.
But there's at least one person
who claims that's the truth.
I only know that I am the daughter
of Mine Shinsuke and Shizuko.
Oh, in that case, one more thing.
I understand your side.
But the matter of Kōda Miki still remains.
Miki-san?
Yes. She thinks you created this scandal yourself
as a plan to bring down her popularity.
Me, bring Miki-san down?
That's absurd.
But to tell you the truth,
we thought so, too.
Never in my life I'd do such thing.
Show some evidence before you
write such things in the newspapers.
We don't have any evidence, but you're in
a close relationship with Nohara Jun, aren't you?
A close relationship?
I'd never asked Mr. Nohara to do anything for me.
I don't have that sort of relationship with him.
If what you say is true,
who came up with it, then?
That's what I'd like to know myself.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
my dad's waiting for me.
Do you think she's honest?
Please. Do you really believe those
crocodile tears? We see them every day.
In any case, we'll need some facts
to get to the bottom of this.
I'll just write about
Mine Nozomi's tears.
Yes. I am Mine Nozomi.
The one who's lived in this town forever,
born to Mine Shinsuke and Shizuko.
This is my truth,
even if people tell me otherwise.
It's me, Jun.
Jun? What brings you here?
Don't play stupid.
It's all written here.
Do not shout at me in the hall.
What will the neighbors think?
Come inside.
What were you thinking, sister?
Organizing a press conference?…
Want a cup of tea?
Are you even listening to me?
Yes, I'm not deaf.
Listen, it's not the first time that
the newspapers openly attack me.
But this time you also expose yourself
through this foolishness.
I asked if you want some tea.
Sister!
You may not be fully aware of this, but you can
end up in serious trouble because of this.
You can even end up in jail.
I guess you have a point.
What are you trying to accomplish?
Jun. I don't intend to cause
you any more inconvenience.
Let me worry about my life myself.
But you know, sister…
I'm done listening to this lecture.
Go away if you have
nothing more to say.
Very well. I will.
Jun! From now on, you can also
forget that we're siblings.
It'd be a hindrance
to your shining career, after all.
What, you forgot something?
For all these years, you haven't
married anyone, you haven't eaten well,
you've been living
this nasty lifestyle.
Who the hell are you
trying to get revenge on?
Revenge?
When a woman sacrifices her life in this way,
it can't be out of anything but vengeance.
Don't concern yourself with this.
In the end, it's got nothing to do with you.
Go away!
I'm going.
Don't come here again.
However, you can't cut the blood ties so easily.
The two of us forever remain brother and sister.
Jun. I have nothing against you.
But you could never possibly
understand my feelings.
Sister. I hate you,
but I still feel sorry for you.
But I am really curious as to
how this will affect their lives.
Just when one of them is about
to become a great professional singer.
Nozomi. Nozomi? Where's Nozomi?
She went to get you medicine.
She'll be right back.
You really can't do anything
without Nozomi, can you?
Hey, Mom…
Is what they write here true?
Shh.
What if your father hears you?
But do reporters tell lies, Mom?
No. Nozomi is my daughter.
She's your sister,
like she's always been.
Yeah, it's just I don't know why,
but it feels really complicated.
I'm home.
Just treat her the same way
you always do.
Welcome home.
I'm sorry I'm late.
How's Dad?
He just fell asleep.
We'll give him pills later.
I see.
Is something wrong?
N-No, all's perfect.
Right, Yuki?
Y-Yeah.
All perfect!
I know everything.
There were reporters here, right, Mom?
No, not here, but they talked
with Kazuo-chan and Yuki-chan.
Ah, thank goodness.
Thank goodness?
What do you mean?
The last thing Dad needs now
is to deal with such crappy rumors.
Thank you, Nozomi.
Come on, Mom, you too?
No matter what anyone says,
I was raised in this house.
I'm your and Dad's daughter.
Nozomi…
Thank you.
Thank you, Nozomi.
What's there to thank me for?
You're acting strange.
She's our big sister, after all!
Sis!
I can't believe you guys.
Nozomi. Nozomi!
It's me, Dad.
Nozomi…
Dad, no matter what,
I am your daughter.
I'm my Dad's daughter.
Camera, action!
It's false rumor. She's my own
daughter, my flesh and blood.
A mother can recognize her child.
You tarnish my daughter's reputation.
If you don't stop, I'll sue you.
I can't believe them.
That's not it yet.
She still has a lot to learn…
No wonder, given that she's
just started her career.
Good work, Miki.
Ohh, Miki-chan,
if it isn't my favorite singer!
Every day, you look more
and more like a real celebrity.
But what is this story
that you were swapped at birth—
Shh. Let's talk outside, Mr. President.
This isn't the best place
to discuss that topic.
You might be right.
Coffee, three times, please.
Now, let's go back to the topic.
It's a real blow to the business.
It's nothing but a bunch of lies.
Even so, such media attention
is not good at all.
It may reflect bad
on Miki-chan's career.
Yes. Miki-chan is our goose that lays
the golden eggs. We have to protect her.
Exactly.
I'm not opposed to tacky gossip,
as long as it increases sales.
But suggesting that your daughter
comes from a poor family is a little too much.
This is an attack on Miki.
An attack?
Yes.
She's referring to Mine Nozomi.
If I'm not mistaken, Mine Nozomi
was an employee of yours?
Yes, that's right.
She's jealous that Miki's made her debut earlier,
which is why she has resorted to such petty tricks.
She's willing to do
anything to succeed.
In that case, why it was Nohara-kun's
sister that put the word out?
It's money.
It's all about the money.
That's why I am going
to file a lawsuit for defamation.
But you would only add fuel to the fire,
causing even more gossip.
I have all the intention
to go all-out on this.
Mr. President, please do your best
to suppress weekly magazines and media.
All right.
Our conglomerate will prepare as much money
as it takes to get this issue sorted out.
I understand.
Miki-chan has finally started
getting her recognition as a star.
We should eliminate all obstacles.
Good evening.
I'm from the National Police.
Are you Nohara Michiko-san?
Yes.
I must ask you to accompany me
to the police station.
I understand.
Take a sit.
Let me get straight to the point.
You're detained on charges of
defaming Kōda Miki at a press conference
you organized some time ago.
I'd like to ask you
a few questions about this.
First of all, what was the purpose
of that press conference?
You also claimed that Kōda Miki
wasn't born to the Kōda family
and it is Mine Nozomi who is
the rightful heiress instead.
Is it the truth?
If it isn't, it's a very serious crime.
Is it the truth,
or is it just worthless slander?!
It's not slander.
So you're claiming that
what you said was true?
I can't hear you!
That's the truth.
The exchange is a fact.
And how could you
possibly know about it?
How do you know about it?
Because I'm the one
who'd swapped them.
The day Kōda Miki and Mine Nozomi were born,
I swapped their name tags, right in the hospital.
Tell me more details.
When I was born,
Japan was torn by war.
Right after my younger brother Jun
was born, our father had to go to the front.
After his departure, our life
became more and more difficult.
Once the war is over, our weak mother had
to go around selling soap door to door.
I was going to school while singing
lullabies to my younger brother.
It wasn't a merry life.
As I was about to graduate, I started to work
as an apprentice nurse at Tonan Hospital.
My wish was to be able to help ill people, to ease
their suffering, as any good nurse should do.
It was such a nice feeling,
I thought I'd stay a nurse forever.
One day I met a young patient
who broke his legs on skis.
That man came from a wealthy family
that could afford such luxuries.
He was from a world entirely
different from the one I lived in.
Yet before I knew it, we started
to have fun taking long, long walks together.
My first love.
A world of fables that I should
never have ventured to.
But I didn't know it back then.
I was just a plain, timid girl.
And above all,
I really believed in love.
Then he whispered
the magic word: marriage.
He studied at a top university and
was about to work for a top company.
But above all, he was going
to be my husband. I was crazy with joy.
But no dream lasts forever.
Suddenly, one day he came to see me
to ask to break the engagement.
He told me that if he want to keep his career,
he must ask to marry his boss' rich daughter,
and he couldn't take
a poor girl like me as his bride.
For a short period of my life,
I had the chance to live the dream.
But it didn't take long for life
to come and kick me again.
It was just too cruel. I had realized
I would never find happiness.
That day, I was on duty in the delivery room
where two girls were born.
Newborns do not have
the opportunity to decide their destiny.
They cannot change the family
where they come to the world.
These two girls were born
on the same day.
They hadn't had the power to decide
anything for themselves.
Only a small tag attached to their feet decides
whether their life will be hell or paradise.
Then I got a great idea.
If God decides destiny,
I will take my revenge by changing it.
It was the only way I could laugh at God,
who's been making fun of me my entire life.
The same night I had disappeared.
At that time I was only 17 years old.
Nozomi-chan, I'm so sorry.
You're so much stronger than I am.
Yes, this is Miki.
Uchida-san?
What?!
Hello? Hello?
Nohara Michiko
switched the babies?
Are you serious?
The police?…
It's the truth…
Miki is not my daughter.
She's… not my daughter.
Sumiyo!
Miki! Miki!
Get a hold of yourself.
She's not my daughter!
My real daughter is Mine Nozomi!
Ah!
Sumiyo! Pull yourself together!
Mine Nozomi… is my child.
Mine Nozomi…
Mine-kun is rehearsing right now.
Please wait a moment.
Dad… I'm your child.
My earliest memories are of you.
When you got home drunk,
you always sang me the song about apples.
It was terrible,
but also very nice at once.
I kept asking you again and again,
"sing it another time",
and you had
this big smile on your face.
Get well soon, Dad.
And let me hear the song
about the apples again.
I'm your child, after all.
Really good, I liked it.
Mine-kun, you got a phone call.
Yes?
This is Mine Nozomi.
What?! Dad's in critical condition?!
Dad…
Dad!
Now that Michiko revealed the secret of their birth,
Nozomi and Miki's hearts are deeply hurt.
The shock is so deep
that Miki goes missing.
At the same time, Nozomi is informed that
her beloved father Shinsuke is fighting for his life.
Please look forward to the next episode:
"Goodbye, Dad".
Uta wa watashi no tomodachi dakara
Music is my friend
Kurushii toki mo watashi no mikata
When things get hard, it stays with me
Tatta hitori de sabishii keredo
Heard alone it's lonely, but
Kokoro no uta wo minna no uta ni
Heard together it resonates with everyone
Minna no uta ga bachi ippai ni
I hope the people downtown can hear it
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday