Wandering Sun
Dareka ni fumareta no no kusa mo
A blade of grass,
stepped on by someone,
Itsuka sora wo furiaogu
Someday will grow high again
Namida de nanimo mienai toki ni mo
Even when we can't see from the tears
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Shiawase no uta tooi toki ni mo
Even if we are unable to sing in joy
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
17 years ago, Kōda Miki and Mine Nozomi,
who were born in the same hospital,
had been swapped by Nohara Michiko,
who held a grudge against the upper class.
Learning that Mine Nozomi was the rightful heiress
to the Kōda family was a huge shock for everyone.
Nozomi, to whom
it hasn't fully sunk in yet,
now also learns that her father
is in a critical condition.
Hello? Hello?
Mom?
So he's in hospital now?
Yes, I asked Kuma-san to carry him
to the hospital. It looked very serious.
The doctors have told me that
he was suffering this whole time.
Had he said anything before,
maybe we could do something about it.
But you know how stubborn he is.
He's been suffering through this all alone.
Don't lose hope, Mom.
He's in the hospital now,
they're going to save him.
You're right.
Are you still working?
Yes. We're going live in a minute.
Try to focus only on that.
I'll do what I can to make Dad
hold on until you can see him.
Okay.
All right, I'm hanging up.
Ah! Mom…
— Episode 25 —
Goodbye, Dad
Dad…
You can't die on us.
Don't die!
Mine-san. Mine-san?
Yes?
We're going live in a minute.
Please get ready.
Oh? You look pale.
Is something the matter?
No, not really.
Put a bit more make-up
and you should be good to go.
Ah, Hara-san, wait up!
Dad, hang in there.
I'll see you soon.
Rehearsal  ·  Live
Ten seconds to go.
Eight.
Five.
Three.
Ready…
Start!
Ladies and gentlemen, good evening and
welcome to the Star Parade you all waited for.
Last week we introduced you to a girl who aroused
a wave of admiration all over the country.
We received a mountain of letters from her
numerous admirers and we're very pleased
to present Nozomi-san
today to you as well.
Well then, let's hear her sing.
Mine-san, the screen's all yours.
She'll sing us the "Song of Heart".
Dad. Dad!
Hang in there!
– Say…
– Yeah?
About that girl on TV.
Isn't she Mine Nozomi?
She's the daughter
of the patient from 203.
But looks like she's actually not.
Huh?
– You know Kōda Miki, right?
– Of course.
In reality, she's the real daughter
of Mine-san, rather than Mine Nozomi.
Rumor has it that the two of them
were swapped at birth.
Anyway, don't you think it's heartless to sing
on television while your father's dying?
This kind of attitude is typical
among artists, to be honest.
Parents of famous people often
die alone without anyone by their bedside.
You think?
That's the way it is.
Yes?
Please come to the room 203.
There's something wrong.
Right away.
Dad…
Did anything happen?
No, it's nothing.
But let's go faster, if possible.
Please.
Sure thing.
Where can I find
Mine Shinsuke's room?
Second floor, room 203.
Dad!
Dad…
Nozomi.
He kept calling your name
until the very end.
Damn it.
Look, that's Mine Nozomi.
The artists never arrive in time.
They never remember about their family…
Nozomi?
Are you okay?
Yes, I am.
And? Are they still up?
Yeah, the light's still on.
Looks like the family meeting's still on.
Maybe we might even take a nice photo of Kōda
Miki with the saddest expression in the world.
Yeah. Let's go.
All right.
Is someone there?
Weird…
What's the matter, Hiroko?
Oh, it's you, Master?
I thought I heard someone.
Make sure every door stays locked.
Naturally.
It must be recognized that you are
partly responsible for all this, my dear.
What do you mean by that?
You were so worried about bad rumors,
that you tried to buy all the journalists.
But money doesn't solve everything.
But what else could I have done?
Realistically speaking,
I hardly had any alternatives.
Why don't you put yourself
in our place, for once?
Staying all day long locked in the house,
unable to go out. What an insistent bunch.
Well, you can't deny that you yourself
tried to corrupt the press.
Watch how you talk to me.
Master, someone named
Kumagorō is calling.
Kumagorō?
Hmm. I wonder who he is.
Hello? This is Kōda. Yes.
What?
Well, just now, err…
Nozomi-chan's father…
I mean, the father of
Miki-san from your house…
Actually I don't know how you're related,
but someone just has to tell you about it.
Yes.
Oh, I see.
Thank you for letting us know.
Thank you. Yes.
We'll definitely come
for the incense offering.
What was that about?
A man called Kuma-san
said over the phone…
…that Nozomi-san's father
has passed away.
Of course, he was also
Miki's biological father.
Hey, now…
Miki.
No! I'm not going anywhere!
I'm not going to his funeral!
He's not my real dad.
It's all wrong.
Miki.
I understand how you're feeling.
It isn't easy for me, either.
For 17 years, you have been my daughter,
and now suddenly you're a child of a stranger.
But listen to me, Miki.
There are things that we cannot change.
We must face bravely whatever life has in store.
It is the only thing
us humans can do to survive.
I would say that is more
than enough for today.
Tomorrow we'll pay tribute
to Nozomi-san's father.
This means we'll also meet
your biological mother, Miki.
We'll all have to think about
how to make the best of this situation.
Of course, without neglecting
your brilliant career.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Okay?
Dear…
Good night.
They're all trying to deceive me.
Even Mom and Daddy.
Now that Daddy knows that I'm
not his daughter, he'll hate me.
He'll just take Nozomi in
and drive me out.
My life is destroyed.
Ma'am, your father has asked me
to come to wake you up.
You're going out together, right?
Ma'am?
Ma—
Master!
Something horrible happened!
"I'm leaving this house".
"Miki".
What should we do, dear?
There's nothing we can do.
Let's call the police.
Police?
Yes. The sooner, the better.
But isn't it a bit too much?
If we involve the police…
This is the only way we can find Miki.
Who would've thought that
we'd have reached this point.
This is the end of our family.
Now people will come to believe
what all the newspapers write about us.
Hello? Hello?
Our daughter has gone—
Mine
I prepared you something to eat, Nozomi.
It's not good for your health
if you continue like that.
You didn't eat anything
since yesterday.
Please, just eat something.
Please.
I decided to stop singing.
Starting today,
I'll find something else to do.
What are you talking about?
Why?
Mom.
Because I was singing on television,
I arrived too late at Dad's bedside.
I didn't have the chance to say goodbye
to the most important person in the world.
I'll never forgive myself.
I'll never forget.
I'm sorry, Dad.
Dad… I'm so sorry.
Nozomi, you got it all wrong.
In all your life, you had never
disappointed your dad.
On the contrary,
he's been very proud of you.
He'd been telling everyone about how his
daughter was going to become a great singer.
That's not the only reason, Mom.
What good are my songs
that I sing on television
if I fail as a human being
at the most important things?
My songs can't save anyone's life.
They're just empty,
meaningless words.
I'm sorry, Mom, but I have
no intention of continuing to sing.
Forgive me, Dad.
I don't want to lose Mom
the way I lost you.
Nozomi…
Nozomi!
I'm going to get rid of this guitar.
Hold on, Nozomi! Wait!
Gotcha.
This is the one thing
I can't let you do.
Please, let go of me, Kuma-san.
No can do.
I can't let you do this.
I'm here to stop you,
as your number one fan.
Kuma-san, I decided that I'll never
sing or use this guitar again.
How could I, after I've betrayed my father,
not even keeping him company on his deathbed?
You're looking at this from the wrong side.
Think about it this way.
Listen close, Nozomi-chan.
Everyone knows I'm not very smart
and I don't understand the difficult stuff.
But one thing I know for sure is that I love your
music and I'd like to continue to hear you sing.
You see, when I hear you sing,
I kinda forget about all the problems.
It's like, I feel I can do anything
and things will be fine.
And it's not just me, you know.
Your dad was like that, too.
Everyone loves your songs,
Nozomi-chan.
Your dad once told me:
"Nozomi is going
to become a great singer.
You know why? Because I have a tin ear,
yet when she sings, it does something to me."
I don't think he had tin ear, after all.
Nozomi-chan, I'm sure your dad went
up to heaven hearing your music.
You sing so well, with so much love!
It's impossible he didn't hear you.
It's not possible. It's just not.
That's right, Nozomi.
Your dad's heard you.
I'm sure of it.
Do you see, Nozomi-chan? You gotta cheer up
and keep singing, for your dad's sake.
Of course, for me, too.
Oh, I almost forgot.
You can bring these to the funeral.
The florist didn't make it in time.
Thank you, Kuma-san.
Nozomi, you should put these for him.
He'd be happy that way.
Okay.
Hey, it's Fanni!
Hisashi!
I came as soon as I knew the news.
Let me see him.
I'm so glad that you came.
Fanni…
Father.
Father…
I…
It's hot, isn't it?
I brought you beer.
Here's to you, Father.
I always wanted to have a drink
with you while you still were alive.
Alright, Father.
Cheers!
I have nowhere to go.
What should I do?
Watch it, kid!
You have a death wish?!
Drive-in
What can I do for you?
Anything will do.
Bring me something to eat.
S-Sure.
Hey, where are you from, little girl?
You're soaking wet.
Don't you have
anything to dry yourself?
Here, you can use this.
Huh? You don't want it?
Look at yourself, man.
It's way too dirty, hah.
You think? But it's not
as dirty as it seems.
By the way, if you look at her,
she looks so much like that new singer.
I think her name was Kōda Miki?
She's super popular now.
Now that you mention it, yeah.
Like two peas in a pod.
But she can't be the real thing, can she?
Kōda Miki was the daughter of
Kōda Conglomerate's president, wasn't she?
What possibly would
she be doing here?
Yeah, you're right.
Hey, wait up!
I have your food!
Nozomi-chan, you can go home now.
I'll walk you
to that bridge over there.
Fanni.
Hm?
We're not really related, right?
Yes, that's right.
In that case…
Do you think…
I could become your girlfriend?
Yes.
Daddy, Mom… I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Nozomi's father Shinsuke had left
the world without seeing her on stage.
Nozomi is going through
a very sad period in her life.
Meanwhile Miki is looking for her own path,
while wandering on the edge of life and death.
The two of them try to sort out their lives
while fighting against their destiny.
Mine Nozomi.
Kōda Miki.
Please look forward to the last episode:
"Song of Heart: My Dearest Friend".
Uta wa watashi no tomodachi dakara
Music is my friend
Kurushii toki mo watashi no mikata
When things get hard, it stays with me
Tatta hitori de sabishii keredo
Heard alone it's lonely, but
Kokoro no uta wo minna no uta ni
Heard together it resonates with everyone
Minna no uta ga bachi ippai ni
I hope the people downtown can hear it
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday