Wandering Sun
Dareka ni fumareta no no kusa mo
A blade of grass,
stepped on by someone,
Itsuka sora wo furiaogu
Someday will grow high again
Namida de nanimo mienai toki ni mo
Even when we can't see from the tears
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Shiawase no uta tooi toki ni mo
Even if we are unable to sing in joy
Watashitachi wa ikiteiru no yo
We are alive!
Sasurai nagara kizutsuki nagara
While wandering, while wounded
Ashita no taiyou wo sagashiteiru no
We are looking for the sun of tomorrow
Nozomi is blaming herself after she could not see
her dying father due to her work as a singer.
Wiping tears, she concludes that
the only chance to redeem herself
is to become a good professional
vocalist as soon as possible.
On the other hand, Miki, after learning
the secret of her birth, flees her home.
— Episode 26 —
Song Of Heart: My Dearest Friend
– Sis!
– Wait for us!
Hurry up or you'll fall behind!
Sis…
You always go to bed late at night.
Why did you get up so early this morning?
Well, everything is so beautiful at this time.
The air is so fresh and clean.
What now?
Ah, there he is!
The guy you were waiting for
is coming this way.
Fanni! Fanni!
Fanni!
Now I understand. So that's why you were
so eager for the roadwork today, huh?
More or less.
You're so cool, Fanni!
Good job.
Good job!
Thank you, everyone!
Good work.
Your "Song of Heart" is great.
Thank you very much, sir.
I heard that your dad
has passed away?
That's right.
My condolences.
Don't let it break you down.
Yes, sir.
See you.
Pleasure to work with you.
Mine-san, can I ask
for an autograph?
My little girl really wants one.
Oh? An autograph?
I didn't expect this.
– I'd like one, too.
– Please.
Good night!
Good night.
This girl is somehow different
from the others.
She's so honest and cheerful.
The secret behind
the birth of Kōda Miki
Kōda Miki's inconvenient past
The secret behind the birth is out
The secret behind Miki-san's birth?
Mass media are looking
for sensations everywhere.
When I think about it, I don't know
what's going on with Miki-san now.
I wonder…
Hello? This is Kōda.
Ah! The police.
No, not really.
I see.
Y-Yes, by all means, please.
The police?
Yes.
What did they tell you?
Well, they haven't had
any news about Miki yet.
It seems they're completely clueless
about her whereabouts.
It's all because I had
too high expectations for her.
That's why… she…
Yes, yes, coming.
Good morning.
How is Miki-san?
Oh, about that…
Did anything happen?
Actually, she's gone missing
two days ago.
What? She's gone missing?!
I didn't know about it at all, sir.
Oh, Mine-kun.
Miki-san…
Yes, unfortunately.
In fact, this is why we weren't able to attend
your father's funeral. I'm very sorry.
There is no need to apologize, sir.
Do you have any idea where
Miki-san might have gone to?
No.
Dear…
Yes?
Someone is calling again.
Ah… Nozomi-san!
Y-Yes?
That's correct.
I can barely hear you.
Shimoda Police Department?
Miki was found?!
So, is she safe?
I see. All right.
Looks like everything
will be fine, ma'am.
Yes. Thank you.
Yes. Tashiro Clinic in Shimoda, right?
Yes, I understand.
We're going there immediately.
Thank you very much, sir.
Did she have an accident?
They told me that a local fisherman
found her unconscious on the seashore.
Seashore?…
Ma'am!
What was she doing there?
Don't worry, honey.
The police said
she didn't have any injuries.
Really?
Thank goodness.
I'm going to the hospital in Shimoda.
You look very pale, so it might
be better for you to stay at home.
No, I'm… I'm fine.
No, you can't do it in this state.
Let me take care of this.
All right, honey?
Dear…
Sir, maybe I could go with you?
You want to go, too?
Miki-san is like a sister to me.
Please take me with you, sir.
Thank you for your offer.
I'm sure that Miki will be
happy to see you as well.
In that case,
let's go visit her together.
I don't know how to thank you.
You don't have to thank me, ma'am, but
I'm very moved to hear you say these words.
She's been unconscious all the time since
she came here, but it should be all right now.
Both pulse and breathing are normal.
The electrocardiogram readings
don't show anything out of ordinary, either.
Why the bandages?
Well, she's slightly injured in the head,
but it's nothing serious.
I see. So she's basically fine?
Yes. Now all that's left
is for her to wake up.
So you're the boy
who's rescued that lady?
Thank you.
Nah, I just saw her when I played
on the beach and ran to my dad.
By the way, miss, you're that singer,
Mine Nozomi, right?
Yes, I am.
I knew it! Your "Song of Heart"
is something else, you know.
Really? Thank you.
I love that song.
Why don't we sing it together?
What?
But I'm terrible at singing.
It'll be fine. I'll lead.
Okay.
M-Miki? Miki!
It's me, your dad!
Miki! It's your dad.
C-Can you recognize me?
Miki. It's me, dad.
Daddy?…
Miki! Yes, that's right.
It's your dad.
Nozomi-san…
Thank goodness, Miki-san.
Hello!
Oh, I wondered who it was,
and it was you, Nozomi-chan.
Long time no see.
Really.
It maestro at home?
Yes. He's pacing back and forth
in the study room.
Great, I'll go talk to him.
What? A solo show?
You heard me right.
That's fantastic,
but isn't that a bit…
…"too early for me",
is what you wanted to say?
Yes…
I think the same.
It is a bit early for you.
However, it's not something
out of your reach.
There are two categories
of these shows.
The first is when you have worked
in the industry for many, many years,
and you make such show to, in a way,
commemorate your long career.
The other one is when you're
an ambitious novice who makes up for
your lack of experience by willing
to risk everything to win fast popularity.
Having said that,
I'm not interested in either of them.
My goal is to make a show
with an artist at the peak of their career.
I'd like to introduce the public to a singer who
applies herself thoroughly at each and every stage.
In a way, it's no longer about
Mine Nozomi, the singer,
but the passion, the emotions, the music itself,
like in your "Song of Heart".
I understand.
Actually, I was inspired with
this concept by my own master,
Mr. Yasuoka, one of the greatest music minds.
His ambition was to one day make such show.
Mr. Yasuoka?!
Oh, you know about him?
Of course I do!
His name, at least.
In that case, you'll be happy to hear
that Mr. Yasuoka spoke highly of your song.
He really did?
He said that if you agreed
to make a solo show,
you could come to influence the direction
of music development in this country.
I can't ignore an advice from my old master,
even though it's a great test of my own ability.
What do you say, Mine? Would you like to work
with me together to pull off the impossible?
By all means, sir!
How could I refuse?
The show is in October.
The stage is Kokusai Hall.
We have a lot of work to do.
Yes sir!
Good, good.
My first catch!
Hello? Is this Mine Nozomi's
fanclub headquarters?
Nozomi-chan!
Over here. Here, look up.
Welcome home.
Kuma-san.
When did you start
to fix people's roofs?
The matmaker fella let me borrow it
for a while and all's great, but…
The damn thing
was leaking like a sieve.
What do you mean, borrow?
Come and take a look.
How do you like it?
I'm pretty proud of it.
An office?
Hehe. We even have
our own landline.
What business are you starting?
This says everything.
Kuma-san…
"Mine Nozomi's
Fanclub Management Office".
How do you like it?
Kuma-san.
There's also one more signboard.
Here.
Miki-san, too?
Mine Nozomi Fanclub Management Office
Kōda Miki Fanclub Management Office
Yep.
Speaking of which,
you better hurry up.
She's at your home
paying respects to Pops.
You mean Miki-san?
Yeah.
Thanks!
Hello, Miki-san.
Nozomi-san…
I'm so glad you came.
Miki-san…
She wanted to come here
as soon as she was discharged.
Thank you.
Nozomi-san.
I'm so sorry.
I was so mean to you all the time.
It's all right.
You'd better get well.
You have to resume
your career as a singer.
Congratulations
on your solo concert.
How do you know about it?
Ah, Kuma-san.
It ain't a fanclub
for nothing, you know.
We have our sources.
I bet it was Sune-chan.
She's our informer, yeah.
Color me surprised.
Anyway, I don't think it was
a classified information.
Right, Pops?
Coming.
Thank you for coming.
– Good evening!
– Good evening.
Whoa, a gigantic cake!
Behave yourselves, kids.
We're guests.
Ah, it's so shiny.
What a beautiful plate!
It was very kind of Miki-san and your husband
to come and visit us the other day.
No, no, it was nothing, after all the problems
we had caused to poor Nozomi-san.
I'd like to express
my sincere apology.
Oh, there's no need at all.
After all, we're not free of blame, either.
May we ask for your forgiveness?
Naturally. Let's leave
things in the past.
Congrats.
Good to see you recovered.
Thank you, Fanni.
All right, everyone. Let's sit down.
Today is my 58th birthday.
We'll also celebrate Miki's recovery.
I sincerely thank all of you for coming.
Miki and Nozomi-san were born
on the same day in the same hospital.
This incident seems to have caused much trouble
and problems to both of our families.
But fortunately,
now we are all reunited
and I believe it is appropriate to consider
what happened as history of the past.
I would like us to get along with each other and
consider our family to have grown a little bigger.
I'm turning the lights off, Daddy.
Happy birthday to you!
Happy birthday, dear mister!
Happy birthday to you.
Happy birthday to you!
Happy birthday, dear mister!
Happy birthday to you.
One month later, Nozomi's solo concert
was performed in front of a huge crowd.
Thus, the phenomenal vocalist
Mine Nozomi
overcame the first big challenge
in the long career she's chosen for herself.
But naturally that was only the beginning.
Let's remember that just like for this girl,
in life there always are difficulties awaiting
and we shouldn't lose our courage to face them.
Just like, in fact,
Kōda Miki didn't lose hers.
Uta wa watashi no tomodachi dakara
Music is my friend
Kurushii toki mo watashi no mikata
When things get hard, it stays with me
Tatta hitori de sabishii keredo
Heard alone it's lonely, but
Kokoro no uta wo minna no uta ni
Heard together it resonates with everyone
Minna no uta ga bachi ippai ni
I hope the people downtown can hear it
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday
Itsuka hirogaru ashita wo shinjiyou
Let's believe in the tomorrow
that will spread someday