Masterpiece Romantic Theatre
kyou wa totemo ureshii kibun
Today I feel so happy
shiroi hato ga akai hana kureta
A white dove gave me a red flower
nandaka akogare no ano hito to
Somehow I have a feeling that
aesou na yokan ga suru wa
I will be able to meet that person again
RU · · · doushiyou aeru kashira
La la la, will we meet again?
RU · · · doushiyou hazukashii na
La la la, it's a bit embarrassing
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
France, about hundred years ago.
At that time, France waged a war
with the neighboring Kingdom of Prussia.
The French army was led
by Napoleon III.
It was a battle
that couldn't be lost.
Isabelle
Father · Léon
Mother · Marie
Bloody Bat
Sister · Geneviève
Piano Teacher · Jules
Army Captain · Victor
Young friend · Jean
Screenplay
Shudou Takeshi
Narrator
Inagaki Mihoko
Music
Isao Matsushita
Character Design
Fukuda Kiyomu
Kitajima Nobuyuki
Chief Director
Hayakawa Keiji
Director
Hakata Tan
- Episode 01 -
Age Fifteen:
The Day I Became a Lady
- Episode 01 -
Age Fifteen:
The Day I Became a Lady
If we lose today's battle, our enemies
will head straight for Paris.
Today's battle is not only
about the fate of France,
it is a battle that will determine
the fate of Emperor Napoleon III.
I expect all of you
to take this with the upmost severity.
I am counting on you,
gentlemen.
Yes, sir.
Andréa.
Be honest with me.
What are our chances of win?
I don't know. But what I know is
that losing is not an option.
Back in Paris, I have
my parents and two sisters.
I cannot put my family at risk.
Darling?
Settle down a bit.
Right.
You don't have
to worry about Isabelle.
She's already getting
dressed for the ball.
Even she will not remain
a tomboy forever.
Ms. Jeanne!
Ms. Jeanne?
Did you find Ms. Isabelle?
Yes, she's playing
at the fountain in the garden.
She doesn't think of us at all.
Make her stop whatever she's doing,
and let's prepare her for the ball.
I understand.
Today she is supposed to make her social
debut. What a troublesome little lady…
I don't wanna.
This thing is way too tight.
Ms. Isabelle has become
very beautiful.
Take a look in the mirror.
You're no longer that
mischievous little tomboy.
This is… me?
That's right.
You're an elegant lady now.
An elegant… lady.
An elegant lady!
Tell me, Jeanne, who is the
fairer maiden, me, or my sister?
Compared to Ms. Geneviève?
Oh, that look says it all.
Fine, fine.
My sister is in another
league, I get it.
What ever was I thinking?
No, that's not true at all.
Ms. Geneviève has her elegance.
However, you, Ms. Isabelle
have your young age.
It's a good weapon.
Is that so?
I could get used to such flattery.
It's not flattery.
Right, girls?
Yes, ma'am.
All right, let me
show myself to my sister.
I wonder what she'll say?
Oh, dear. She's still such a child.
Sister!
Sister, take a look!
Oh? Uh…
Look what I've done.
Isabelle.
When you wear a dress for a party, you need
to make more careful movements.
Here I am, finally trying
to show you something nice.
I'm such a klutz.
That is not true.
Isabelle, you're very beautiful.
Do you really think so?
Thank you, Sister.
By the way, Maestro, are you going
to the ball with us today?
Yes, I will play
the piano this evening.
I'm looking forward to it.
Isabelle, why don't you show your
wonderful dress to Mother and Father now?
I need to continue
with my piano lesson.
Mother and Father have been eagerly
waiting for you all this morning.
You're right.
I'm sorry I disturbed you.
Here we go.
Oops, that won't do.
I'm a proper lady now.
Excuse me.
That brings memories.
She makes me remember my own past.
The day I made my social debut.
Social debuts and balls?
France is now
in the middle of a war.
I don't understand
what the rich are thinking.
But…
But, Jules…
The feeling of love
remains constant.
Let's not go in
that direction, Geneviève.
I'm nothing but a poor piano teacher.
The worlds we live in
are too different.
Jules…
Besides, you have
an ideal fiancé, Victor.
That was my Father's decision.
You are the one I'm in love with.
Geneviève!
Some mountains
cannot be climbed.
I will not accept that.
A social debut.
She was about to meet
the high society for the first time.
Isabelle couldn't suppress her heart beat,
full of expectations and anxiety.
We will be there any moment.
There is no need
to feel stiff, Isabelle.
We're here.
This evening is your first step
into high society, Isabelle.
Thank you, Father.
Mother, I'm anxious.
My dear Isabelle.
I was just like you.
Where has your
usual bravery gone?
Right.
Please take my hand,
Ms. Geneviève.
Thank you, Gaston.
Let's go.
Ms. Geneviève…
Ms. Geneviève.
Léon and Marie Rostain
with their daughters!
This is the high society…
This is the high society, right?
From the moment of her
debut in the high society,
Isabelle's beauty
captured people's hearts.
You're so beautiful, Isabelle.
Mr. Victor!
You have grown into a fine lady.
Tell me, Isabelle,
would you say yes to a dance?
Or am I not worthy,
as your sister's fiancé?
No, of course not.
Father?
You can dance with him.
Here, Isabelle.
Oh… Yes.
Here.
That dance was
like a dream for Isabelle.
Isabelle was strangely attracted
to her sister Geneviève's fiancé, Victor.
Excuse me.
May I have a dance now?
You will be drafted soon as well.
I shall go back to my fiancée.
Victor!
Victor…
Isabelle, what's wrong?
Did you forget about me?
You bullied me all the time
when we were kids, remember?
We lived next to each other
in Versailles.
Jean!
It's you, Jean?
This is dangerous!
I'm going to fall!
Wait for me! Wait!
What a big catch!
It's so tiny.
Jean, I'll give you one!
Okay!
Catch!
Owie!
You're so weak.
Hey, Isabelle, will you be
my bride when we grow up?
Me, Jean's bride?
Fat chance.
No way…
Who would want to marry
a weakling like you?
What do you know?
Isabelle, you'll become my bride!
Get off your high horse.
Jean…
You're that crybaby?
That's right. Isabelle, do you remember
when I asked you to marry me?
I've completely forgotten.
Oh, what a pity.
Listen, Jean. Tonight, I've made
my debut into the high society.
I can't play kids games
with you anymore.
Won't you dance with me?
Not in a hundred years.
She hasn't changed at all.
Ha, that girl's pretty.
Oh, do you really think so?
Victor.
It's been two years since
your engagement to Geneviève.
Now that you are an army captain,
just like my son Andréa,
you've fully met the expectations
I've set for my daughter's husband.
Mr. Rostain. Even though the aristocratic
world is always dazzling,
France is now in war.
But it is evident
that we will win this war.
I am a soldier.
Andréa is fighting
on the battlefield as we speak.
I cannot selfishly seek happiness
in such a difficult time.
When this war is over,
I will marry Geneviève.
A marriage with Victor…
But Jules…
What about Jules?
Geneviève wanted to escape
from the brilliant ball.
Let us dance, Geneviève.
Oh?
Sure.
Victor could not imagine in his
worst nightmares that his fiancée Geneviève
could be in love
with another man.
Geneviève… You're so beautiful.
Jules… I'm so sorry.
I love you, Jules.
Just a little longer.
Hold out just a bit more.
If I was Victor's
partner in dance…
Captain Langlois.
I regretfully inform that you and your men
will be joining the Paris garrison.
Yes, General Gambetta.
Ladies and gentlemen,
crème de la crème of the French society.
I am General Gambetta
from the French Army.
We have fallen on hard times.
Our French Army suffered a crushing defeat
and surrendered in the Battle of Sedan.
Our Emperor Napoleon III was
taken prisoner by the Prussian army.
What?
I don't believe it.
How could this happen?
Silence, please.
The Prussian army has started
to advance towards Paris.
Paris is in crisis and needs immediate
mobilization of all available forces.
Andréa…
Andréa.
Andréa!
Ms. Rostain.
Please wake up. Wake up!
Andréa is not a man
who would sell himself cheaply.
I am sure he's alive.
He will come back home safely!
Captain, it's no use.
Leave me here and go ahead.
Don't be foolish.
Get up. Do you really want
to die in this place?
We're going back to Paris.
We're going to protect Paris!
Jules…
What will happen to us?
I wish I knew that myself.
But I feel like
something will change.
Jules… I am scared.
Geneviève.
Jules.
Don't let go of me.
Isabelle.
Sister…
You and Victor…
Isabelle.
I can not help it.
What I feel about
Jules is… It's just…
I don't want to hear any of this!
Poor Victor!
Isabelle…
Ms. Geneviève.
The carriage is ready.
You better go, Geneviève.
It is time to go, Geneviève.
The love towards Geneviève.
Tomorrow the Prussian army
may invade Paris.
Jules was left alone.
He just kept playing the piano.
After the French army,
commanded by Napoleon III,
lost to the Prussian army
in the Battle of Sedan,
the fate of Paris and its people
was about to greatly change.
To be continued
Next episode preview
Paris soon is going
to become a battlefield.
Our Rostain family is seeking
shelter in a villa in Versailles.
Versailles… The city with
the famous Palace of Versailles.
But I still don't know
the fate of my brother Andréa.
Also, what is going to happen
between my sister, Victor and Jules?
Finally, what about me?
Next time on "Isabelle of Paris":
"In a Valley Between Two Loves".
Please look forward to it.
anata no egao wa
totemo suteki
Your smile is so nice
soyokaze no you ni
atatakai ai ga aru
It displays so much love,
gentle like a breeze
RANRARA hazunda uta wa
ogawa wo koete
La la la, our song
reaches across the stream
hitori no yama ni
kodama suru
and echoes in the green mountains
hora omoikiri
kasekete yukou
Let's run with all our might
ano hito no iru
oka no ue made
to the top of the hill,
where our friend is