Masterpiece Romantic Theatre
kyou wa totemo ureshii kibun
Today I feel so happy
shiroi hato ga akai hana kureta
A white dove gave me a red flower
nandaka akogare no ano hito to
Somehow I have a feeling that
aesou na yokan ga suru wa
I will be able to meet that person again
RU · · · doushiyou aeru kashira
La la la, will we meet again?
RU · · · doushiyou hazukashii na
La la la, it's a bit embarrassing
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
There's English soil
on the other side, right?
Come on, Isabelle.
Let's look for a boat.
Right.
Carrying a letter from Geneviève,
Isabelle and Jean...
after overcoming
one danger after another,
had finally reached
the Dover Narrows.
Look, Jean!
It's a boat! And a house!
Yes!
Is anybody in there?
Is anybody in there? Hello…
Are you all right?
How is he?
Isabelle
Father · Léon
Mother · Marie
Count Red
Sister · Geneviève
Piano Teacher · Jules
Army Captain · Victor
Young friend · Jean
Screenplay
Shudou Takeshi
Narrator
Inagaki Mihoko
Music
Isao Matsushita
Character Design
Fukuda Kiyomu
Kitajima Nobuyuki
Chief Director
Hayakawa Keiji
Director
Hakata Tan
- Episode 08 -
Appearance of The Mysterious Bat Gang
Isabelle, now!
Go ahead of me!
All right.
Hurry up!
We're leaving, fast!
Jean, we're ready!
Good.
Isabelle, we've got to
detach the chain!
All right, I'll row!
You can do it, Jean.
Faster.
Do you think we can make it?
So far, everything's worked out.
It'll be fine. Don't worry, Isabelle.
Right.
Meanwhile, in Versailles…
Mr. Thiers, why
did you flee Paris?
After losing the capital, our troops have lost
their morale and are in disarray now.
I would appreciate it if you did not
blame me for your own failures.
It is you who did not manage
to gather the army you promised.
How do you intend
to take responsibility for this?
Further conversation is pointless. I don't
want to talk to a coward like you anymore.
Are you resigning?
I'm sorry to hear it.
General Gambetta…
Sir, what will happen
to France now without you?
Victor. There is no shame in executing orders
issued by an incompetent government.
Soldiers must obey
the orders they're given.
Even if the order is wrong, the military
must comply with it and fight.
In this war, thousands
of soldiers gave their lives.
Perhaps death on the battlefield
was their destiny.
But when you look
at each of them,
when you take their uniforms off,
you'll see a loving man in each.
Each of them had someone they loved:
parents, children, siblings, a woman.
Still, they left them
and went to fight.
The fate of their homeland
after their death
is the only small reward
they get for their efforts.
However, when their death
only serves the interests of Thiers.
I can't be called anything but
a traitor who has betrayed their trust.
My resignation
is the only right choice.
It is also compensation
for those who died.
How about you, Captain Langlois?
What will you do?
I am a soldier.
No matter what the order is,
the soldier must carry it out.
It is not my role to decide
whether the order is correct or not.
You yourself said so just now.
I understand.
That, too, is a way of life.
So this is where our paths part,
Captain Langlois.
Remember to always
value your life.
It's the only way I know to live.
That's who I am.
The next day, Victor
happened to see a wanted poster.
In it, there was Isabelle's face.
Hey, Jean, have you noticed
we're not moving at all?
There's nothing we can do about it.
There's no wind. Take a sit and rest.
Quit raving about it!
Sooner or later it'll blow and we'll sail.
Boy, you sure are reckless, Jean.
I need to deliver this letter
as soon as possible.
I was waiting for this.
For what?
To see your anger.
You're so beautiful when you're mad!
And this short cut?
It suits you perfectly!
I think I've fallen
for you all over again.
Real funny, Jean.
I've had enough.
You've got some nerve to joke around
under such circumstances.
This situation is the
perfect time to joke around.
You can't control the wheel of fortune,
only your attitude towards it.
You are so—
Oh! It's a ship!
– Look, a ship!
– I told you so! Ahoy!
It's a British flag! They must be coming home
from France. They can take us on board!
– Ahoy! We need help!
– We're here! – Help!
Hooray, they noticed us!
They did!
– We're saved!
– Thank goodness!
Something's wrong.
Isabelle, can you swim?
Can you?
Jump!
What on earth
is wrong with this ship?
Don't know but, something's
definitely wrong.
He got me good.
Take it.
Gotcha.
It's him again!
Are you kidding me!?
So much for the ship…
No, it's too early to give up.
You monster!
Catch me if you can!
We meet again,
Mr. Petty Officer.
Run, Isabelle! Run away!
Isabelle, behind you!
Climb that ladder!
Climb it!
Go up, quick!
What should I do?!
Oh, right!
Hang in there, Isabelle.
Almost there, Isabelle!
– Isabelle! I'm coming to you!
– Jean!
Isabelle, jump!
We did it!
Hooray!
Jean!
You were wonderful.
Hey, Isabelle.
Here, too.
No. One must suffice.
You're so greedy.
She likes me.
Soon gulls appeared in the sky,
a sign that they were approaching land.
The crew's eyes
laid on jagged cliffs.
Isabelle and Jean saw
the British soil for the first time.
Jean.
Hm? Ah!
How do I look?
So? How do I look?
Just perfect! You look good
in everything, Isabelle.
Thank you, Jean.
You've changed.
You really think so?
Yes, I guess I have, a little bit.
They say there's no progress
without change.
But I don't get you, Jean.
Why are you chasing after me so much?
I'm a terrible tomboy. Apart from
strength, I have no good points.
I've never had anyone but you.
I'd always been
weak, shy and timid.
You always had had to
save me from trouble.
You were my
only friend back then.
I knew that
I never wanted to lose you.
Fencing… Shooting…
Horse riding.
I learned it all because
I was interested in you.
That's… just who I am.
Isabelle, you'll be my bride!
Who'd want to marry
such a weakling?
I am not a weakling!
Learn to respect a lady!
But… you see, I…
I know already.
Just as I've adored you,
you've hated me
all this time.
It's not easy to change the feelings
we've had since childhood.
But I will make you
fall in love with me.
Some day. You will see.
Jean…
Because if I don't,
I'll be very, very sad.
Sniff… Just kidding, of course.
I know all too well
that tears don't work on you!
Jean, why do you always joke
and belittle yourself so much?
It's just that if I don't do that,
I think I'd die from embarrassment.
Sorry if I interrupt.
We will reach the Dover shore soon.
We have prepared a boat for you.
A boat?
You are illegal immigrants.
Illegal?
Yes. But if you steal this boat and disappear,
there's nothing we can do, is there?
Mister…
Thank you.
Thank you!
Sail safely!
Goodbye!
– Goodbye!
– Thank you!
So, young lady, you're about to
take your first step on the British soil.
Oh, my.
The night after Isabelle
and Jean landed in England,
they reached
their destination: London.
Let's look… SE9, SE10.
Are you sure of this address?
Yes, I am.
Domino Street, SE17.
Over there is 12, there 13…
Two lads. Two lads!
Look carefully.
One of them may be in disguise.
They both look like
plain boys to me.
– Watch their every move.
– Yes sir.
– We're here.
– Awesome. Let's knock.
Just a moment.
It'll take a second.
Oh, dear.
He took out a compact!
It's a girl!
Just like I suspected.
Very well. Shoot them.
Who's there?
I won't let you hurt her.
Gaston?
Look, it's our
would-be dead man.
Thanks for saving me the effort
of searching for you.
Let me deal with you before
I take care of the girl. Kill him!
Yes sir!
What a vigorous old man!
There is nowhere to run.
Panza! Welcome to London.
Who are you, you rubes?!
I am Count Red,
and this is my shadow army.
Count Red?
Panza. I suggest you
to retreat voluntarily.
Where are they?
Count Red?
What do you want?
It's the middle of the night!
Does someone by the name
of Martin Schmidt live here?
That's right.
Mom, where did you go?
Quiet! If you eat everything,
your butt is doomed!
We were sent by Jules from Paris.
Where can we find Mr. Schmidt?
Knowing him, he's
guzzling beer in a pub again.
In a pub?
His favorite is called "Max In".
Make sure to check there.
At that time, London was a refuge
for revolutionaries, thinkers,
and tramps looking for a way
to earn some extra money.
These people spent their free time
gathering and hanging out in pubs.
Max In was one of those pubs.
Isabelle felt a strange emotion
she had never experienced before,
as she stood shocked,
in this alien environment.
To be continued
Next episode preview
We arrived in the city of fog, London,
and we got to meet Mr. Schmidt.
Panza, however,
gives us no peace.
Then suddenly
Victor makes his appearance.
Next time on "Isabelle from Paris":
"Love Burning in The Night Fog".
Please look forward to it.
anata no egao wa
totemo suteki
Your smile is so nice
soyokaze no you ni
atatakai ai ga aru
It displays so much love,
gentle like a breeze
RANRARA hazunda uta wa
ogawa wo koete
La la la, our song
reaches across the stream
midori no yama ni
kodama suru
and echoes in the green mountains
hora omoikiri
kakete yukou
Let's run with all our might
ano hito no iru
oka no ue made
to the top of the hill,
where our friend is