Masterpiece Romantic Theatre
kyou wa totemo ureshii kibun
Today I feel so happy
shiroi hato ga akai hana kureta
A white dove gave me a red flower
nandaka akogare no ano hito to
Somehow I have a feeling that
aesou na yokan ga suru wa
I will be able to meet that person again
RU · · · doushiyou aeru kashira
La la la, will we meet again?
RU · · · doushiyou hazukashii na
La la la, it's a bit embarrassing
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
Down with Thiers!
Away with him!
Come out, you aristocratic dogs!
Defend Paris!
We don't need Thiers!
March 1871.
Seeing the uprising of the citizens of Paris,
ready to defend the capital by themselves,
Thiers felt threatened and
with the help of Prussia fled from Paris.
The government
evacuated to Versailles.
Paris is now in the hands of villains
who want to unlawfully appropriate it.
These enemies are
much worse than Prussia.
The citizens of Paris are crying.
I promise you that
I will take our capital back.
Gentlemen, I am asking you
for your support and trust.
"Villains"?
"Citizens of Paris are crying"?
What a load of rubbish!
Thiers is a Frenchman like us,
and he leads by the nose not just us,
but the entire world!
The uprising was the only way
to defend against the Prussian army!
He can't be thinking
he can get away with this propaganda.
We have to show to the world
how things really are.
I agree, but how?
Not only are we still under siege,
our troops are in Thiers' pocket!
What to do here?
I think I have an idea.
Geneviève!
Geneviève.
We will tell the truth
to my father, Léon Rostain.
That doesn't seem very sensible. I don't want
to drag your family into this mess.
My father is a rich landowner,
just like Thiers.
But unlike Thiers, he can
distinguish between good and evil.
Geneviève…
Don't let any of them
get to Versailles.
Understood?
Yes sir!
Isabelle
Father · Léon
Mother · Marie
Count Red
Sister · Geneviève
Piano Teacher · Jules
Army Captain · Victor
Young friend · Jean
Screenplay
Shudou Takeshi
Narrator
Inagaki Mihoko
Music
Isao Matsushita
Character Design
Fukuda Kiyomu
Kitajima Nobuyuki
Chief Director
Hayakawa Keiji
Director
Hakata Tan
- Episode 07 -
Now, The Birth of a Beautiful Swordslady
You imbecile!
Hand it over.
That's how you use it.
Now find the letter.
Who's there?
Gaston?
What happened, Gaston?
Please…
Please take it.
If it is true…
I don't want to believe it.
My lord, Mr. Thiers
came to see you.
What?
Mr. Thiers.
Let me hear a honest answer.
Does this letter express the truth?
Are you really a traitor who
sold the capital to the enemy?
What are you doing?!
Mr. Rostain.
If you want the Rostain family to live,
you will forget about this document.
I have but allies among the Versailles'
aristocrats and landowners.
I pity the fate of anyone
who attempts to change this.
Are you threatening me?
By no means. Our only goal is
to protect our properties in Paris.
I want to regain our wealth
from the thieves who took Paris.
What do you think, Mr. Rostain?
Maybe my way
of thinking is wrong?
By the way, I have
received an information
that the tentacles of the rebellion
have reached this mansion as well.
Gaston!
Get away from here. Fast!
It went as I thought.
There's no time.
Get out of here, Gaston!
Please take it.
This is a letter from Ms. Geneviève.
From my sister?
Quick!
Search the room.
What are you doing here?
We are looking for a little rat
that slipped out of the cage.
This is a lady's room.
Where are your manners?
Manners do not apply to us.
Do not ever talk back
to me again.
By the way, your brother Andréa
also tried to oppose us.
Andréa?!
Are you saying that…
Exactly.
Who knows?
You could be next.
We have an eye on you.
Understood?
– Let's go.
– Wait a second.
Are you trying to intimidate me?
Know that you will
never succeed!
Next time I will be
aiming at your face.
It is Thiers who betrayed Paris.
Other governments
have to learn of it.
We must gather people
who will be ready to defend Paris.
I want you to smuggle in the letter
I attached to my friends in London.
We would do it ourselves,
but we can't get out of Paris.
And Gaston unfortunately
attracts too much attention.
If it turns out
that our father won't help,
you remain
our only hope, Isabelle.
I can only count on you.
May God be with you.
London?
But what can I,
a stupid 15-year-old, do?
How am I supposed to get there?
London…
But…
They're watching me
all the time.
What should I do?
If only I was a boy…
If only I was a boy.
Manners do not apply to us.
Do not ever talk back to me again.
Who am I showing off to?
I'm hopeless.
The next day,
at the Palace of Versailles
a great ball was held
for the aristocracy and landowners.
Isabelle had a unique chance
to deceive Panza and get out of Versailles.
Are you feeling okay, Isabelle?
You never asked me to dance before.
Shh.
Jean, I have a request for you.
Be quiet and listen.
Isabelle revealed to Jean
the events that happened last night.
Sounds like fun.
You can count on me, Isabelle.
Damn it!
What happened?
They're gone! Find them!
Quick, Jean.
What are you doing?!
They're over there.
Damn squirts, almost
gave me a heart attack.
You're so handsome, Jean.
Isabelle, you are
so beautiful, too.
Oh, thank you for saying that.
Would you like
to dance with me?
I am Alain Belmont.
Your beauty captivated me as soon
as I saw you. Please, let's have a dance.
Something's not right here.
Why doesn't Isabelle want to dance?
Plus, she hides
her face all the time…
Oh, what a delicate hand.
Please, only one dance.
Excuse me.
Oh, my!
Yuck!
What a nasty girl!
Look for her, pronto!
Miss Isabelle!
Thank you, Jeanne.
I can go from here.
Why are you getting into
such a danger, Ms. Isabelle?
Don't even ask.
Just go back to Versailles.
Ms.… Ms. Isabelle…
Please, Jeanne.
Don't say a word to my parents.
Why is that?
To be honest, I'm not sure. Apparently,
I haven't grown out of adventuring yet.
Goodbye.
What did you say!?
You lost her?
It's just one girl! What kind of moron
you need to be to let her escape!?
I am so sorry, sir.
Fortunately, we know where
she's headed to, more or less.
London, huh?
Pursuing her in the British territory
will be very inconvenient.
Clearly I can't rely on you.
What do you mean by that, sir?
Karlov, you can come in now!
Find this girl.
I want her dead or alive.
What can such an oaf do?
I'm curious myself.
Why don't you try to find out?
With pleasure.
Get over here!
All right! My mistake!
Put me down.
Did you remember her face?
Go now.
What a monster!
Thank God he spared you.
Panza, just in case,
prepare an ambush in London.
However, I expect that by that time,
Karlov will have cleaned up this mess.
And so, throughout the country began
the checks to find the fugitive Isabelle.
Hey, you!
Where are you going?
What is it?
Why don't you answer me?
As soon as she speaks,
the guards will learn that she is a girl.
Isabelle did not know
how to get out of this situation.
What's up, man!
Jean!
You know, the guy
doesn't talk much.
He saw his folks getting torn apart
by a mortar right before him.
He hasn't said a word since then.
I understand. The poor man.
You know each other?
Yes. We are neighbors
and we're going to the market.
Can we pass?
Yes. You may go.
Thanks.
Jean, I don't remember
asking you to come with me.
You don't have to thank me.
I'm going where you are, for better or worse.
Enough with this
silliness already.
Don't pay attention to it.
Better take a look at this.
A pistol. A saber.
A grenade, even.
I'm not going to war, by the way.
You never know when they'll come in handy.
It's better to be prepared.
Night sky and shooting stars.
It's a bit romantic
how we sit here together.
Victor…
Who's there?!
Who… Who are you?
Don't come any closer!
Jean!
Wait!
One step further and I shoot.
There, Isabelle!
Upstairs!
Hop.
We got him.
We got him!
Oh… I'm sorry.
Let's go, Isabelle!
Water! We're
at the Dover Narrows.
On the other side,
there's English soil, right?
Yes. We are close.
What's this?
The frightful Karlov has survived.
Isabelle and Jean
didn't know that, however.
They were only thinking about how to get
to London, looking over the Dover Narrows.
To be continued
Next episode preview
We got on a small boat and
we're slowly approaching London.
Around us there's nothing
but endless water.
We thought we killed Karlov,
but this monster got us even here.
Can't he finally get a live?
Panza is already waiting
for us in London.
At the crucial moment, a group of characters
in black appears out of nowhere.
Next time on "Isabelle from Paris":
"Appearance of The Mysterious Bat Gang".
Please look forward to it.
anata no egao wa
totemo suteki
Your smile is so nice
soyokaze no you ni
atatakai ai ga aru
It displays so much love,
gentle like a breeze
RANRARA hazunda uta wa
ogawa wo koete
La la la, our song
reaches across the stream
midori no yama ni
kodama suru
and echoes in the green mountains
hora omoikiri
kakete yukou
Let's run with all our might
ano hito no iru
oka no ue made
to the top of the hill,
where our friend is