Masterpiece Romantic Theatre
kyou wa totemo ureshii kibun
Today I feel so happy
shiroi hato ga akai hana kureta
A white dove gave me a red flower
nandaka akogare no ano hito to
Somehow I have a feeling that
aesou na yokan ga suru wa
I will be able to meet that person again
RU · · · doushiyou aeru kashira
La la la, will we meet again?
RU · · · doushiyou hazukashii na
La la la, it's a bit embarrassing
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
Versailles.
We've finally reached Versailles!
Isabelle's group escaped in a balloon
from Paris which was still under siege.
After some adventures, they finally
arrived at their destination, Versailles.
Isabelle, look!
Your parents came to pick you up.
Mother! Father!
Isabelle!
– Isabelle!
– I'm coming!
Mother…
Isabelle.
Mother.
I'm so glad you're safe.
It's because I was with her.
Oh, it's you, Victor.
I am indebted for
taking care of our little Isabelle.
Yes, we wouldn't be alive
without Mr. Victor.
Right, Jean?
Huh? But I also… I also…
Never mind.
There is no talking to you.
Welcome to Versailles,
General Gambetta.
The hardest is yet to come.
We must gather as many people
as possible, and do it fast.
Then we need to go
and save the city of Paris.
Do you think that Paris
can hold out in the meantime?
The citizens of Paris are burning
with anger and want to protect it.
Your son is among them.
I fully trust Andréa.
Isabelle
Father · Léon
Mother · Marie
Count Red
Sister · Geneviève
Piano Teacher · Jules
Army Captain · Victor
Young friend · Jean
Screenplay
Shudou Takeshi
Narrator
Inagaki Mihoko
Music
Isao Matsushita
Character Design
Fukuda Kiyomu
Kitajima Nobuyuki
Chief Director
Hayakawa Keiji
Director
Hakata Tan
- Episode 06 -
News of Andréa's Death in Battle
Mr. Thiers, can you explain
what the government is thinking?
It's been already two months
since Prussia besieged our capital.
However, our soldiers
are sitting by doing nothing.
Soon we will run out of food supplies
and start dying from starvation.
And what is it that you would
like me to do, Captain Rostain?
Fight the Prussian army.
To cut a path that could bring food
to the plates of our people.
Next is a roasted duck?
I'm loving it.
Would you like
to join me, Captain?
Mr. Thiers!
You really have some nerve.
Excuse me.
On the streets outside,
an unpleasant winter wind was blowing.
Andréa could not hear this wind
over the groans of the Parisian people.
There, there.
We'll eat something soon.
To Isabelle, who now lived
in the gorgeous Versailles,
the suffering of the Parisian people
was something inconceivable.
Give our Paris back!
You sentenced us to death!
Yeah!
We're taking back our city!
Hurry up!
Quick! Bring water!
It's the army!
People of Paris!
Rebellion will be punished
with a death penalty.
Disperse immediately!
This is not a rebellion!
Geneviève?!
We wanted to protect our beloved Paris,
and went through many hardships!
But you people,
the army, the government,
not only do not protect anything,
you keep these piles of food!
And you don't share them with anyone!
What's the meaning of this?!
Down with the rebels!
Shoot. Shoot them!
That's an order!
That's right.
It is a valid order.
But can you really
expect them to comply,
to shoot their brothers and sisters who
likewise only want to defend their homes?
We're going back!
But… But, Captain!
Listen.
Our opponent is Prussia.
It is not our people!
Andréa…
Hyah!
If we let these savages keep running rampant,
Paris will burn down to the ground.
And so will our wealth.
The best way out of this predicament
is to hand over the capital to the Prussians.
Our condition will be
to leave our property intact.
But what are we going to do
with the Parisians, Mr. Thiers?
I have an idea.
Call the commander
of the garrison!
Yes sir.
Go inside.
Did you call for me, sir?
I will give you a chance to fight
the Prussian army, as you wished.
Very soon, you will lead
an attack on Champigny.
Yes sir.
It's finally happening.
Yes. It finally is.
I wish you good luck.
Thank you, sir.
Look at that stupid kid.
Panza!
Did you want anything, sir?
Deliver this to the Prussian army.
Time is of essence.
That letter contained
Andréa's plans.
Yes.
Thiers organized a trap
for his own soldiers.
The Paris Garrison
will be annihilated now.
What? Andréa's unit
went on a sortie?
Yes. Looks like Paris
finally goes on the offensive.
Victor, what are our chances?
It is hard to tell.
However, it is Andréa
we're talking about.
Exactly!
He will not be defeated.
Ah… I wish I was born a boy.
I'd help Andréa and
I'd torn our enemies to pieces!
Like this!
Do not get
carried away, Isabelle.
Yes, Father.
December 1870.
The French troops led by Andréa
set out for Champigny.
This sortie was set up to let
the rebels lose their energy to fight.
No one knew that
it was a miserable sacrifice.
We'll be arriving at Champigny soon.
Keep your heads on a swivel.
Yes sir!
Captain!
How did the scout go?
Well… I didn't see anybody!
What?
Not a single enemy soldier?
What does that mean?
Damn! They found us!
All forces, attack!
Andréa… Andréa!
Andréa!
Victor?
Why is he so late at night?
Whoa!
I am very sorry.
In the Battle of Champigny,
our French troops
were completely annihilated.
Andréa has lost his life
in a just cause.
No way… No way!
It's a joke, right? Right?
Somebody…
Somebody tell me
it's a bad joke!
Victor… Please,
tell me it's not true.
Andréa…
It can't be true!
Fire!
January 1871.
The Prussian army that had besieged Paris
finally launched an attack on it.
Somebody help us!
It's burning like hell…
That territory is unrelated
to our property.
How lovely to finally see
those ugly slums burn to ashes.
Now is the best time
to surrender to the Prussians.
We have to put out the fire!
Don't panic! Bring some water!
We can do it!
Hurry up!
Hurry!
Just a little more!
What are you doing? Hurry!
Isabelle.
Father?
Isabelle, listen to me.
I want to cry all the same.
However, the one who has it
the worst is your mother.
Geneviève had left our house.
And now Andréa
has passed away.
Isabelle, you are all
that's left for her.
Promise me that you will not
make your mother any sadder.
The three of us
must not be destroyed.
You are the only descendant
to the Rostain family now.
Isabelle.
No matter what you say
about Jean, he is a noble.
Hyah!
I'm touched.
It's the first time in my life
that you've called me.
What happened?
Isabelle?
Jean, when I was little,
I made a decision.
If I am ever going to marry anybody,
he must be stronger than me.
I hate crybabies such as yourself!
I'm not what I used to be.
Can you win with me?
Who knows? I might lose.
Looks like you've gotten
a bit stronger.
Isabelle, you're scaring me!
What happened?
Hop!
I lost.
Practice makes perfect.
Now you can see that
I'm different than I used to be.
Now, now. That's it for today.
I'm leaving.
Hop… Ahh!
Did I overdo it?
That's just so you, Jean.
Our homes and the city
burned down to the foundations.
Look at it another way,
Geneviève.
See? We're still alive!
This is our town,
for as long as we live.
Wise words, young lad.
We can always just rebuild it.
Right, everyone?
Yeah!
Big news, big news, big news!
Paris lost! Paris lost!
What?!
Paris officially lost.
We've surrendered!
That son of a gun, Thiers,
sold our city to the Prussians!
Paris surrendered.
It was Thiers' scheming,
to protect his estate.
When the Prussian troops
marched into the city, the citizens of Paris
made a silent protest
by shutting down the windows.
Did they really surrender?
I have a bad feeling about it.
Is this really Paris?
The capital of beauty and art?
Everything is shut.
They reject us.
Away with the Prussians!
Leave our city!
Leave it!
You insolent peasant!
Don't even think about it!
We are the proud Prussian soldiers.
We are not child murderers!
Paris has not yet surrendered.
Not yet surrendered?
What do you mean?
It seems that the surrender of Paris
was just your arbitrary decision.
As things stand, we cannot
station our army here.
I am a Paris representative!
I cannot trust a representative whose
opinions do not align with his people's.
I pray that your citizens
do not unleash their wrath.
I advise you to be careful
in future endeavors.
Well, then.
Citizens unleashing their wrath…
Away with Thiers!
Banish him!
Let's defend our city!
Yeah!
Our enemies leisurely walk
the streets of our city. I've had enough!
Damn right!
Thiers sold our city to the Prussians!
He's our enemy!
Damn right!
Away with Thiers!
We will defend
our city ourselves!
Yeah!
Let's protect it together!
Protect Paris!
Away with Thiers!
As if I let them
do as they please!
Sir, a big problem! The people
gathered in front of the building!
What? They must be forgetting
who they are. Make them disperse!
What's that?
We're going to escape.
Escape? Where to?
We will ask the Prussians
for asylum, you fool!
The Prussians?
We're going to ask our enemy for help?
Look at their numbers. Do you see
how many of them are down there?
They're scarier than the enemy.
Follow me.
We'll take the back door.
Okay.
March 1871.
Thiers, fearing the wrath of the Parisians,
sought help from the Prussian army
and fled away to Versailles.
Mark my words, you scoundrels!
I'll make you pay for this!
What? Thiers fled Paris?
So what is going on there now?
Only a handful of soldiers is still
trying to defend Paris and its people.
Unfortunately, none of them
are as good as Andréa.
How are Sister and Jules?
What is going to happen to Paris?
Jules…
Sister…
To be continued
Next episode preview
I received a secret letter
from my sister.
She has some friends in London
who can help us win Paris back,
and she asks me
to contact them.
What… What should I do?
London is so far away…
And I'm a girl.
I have to watch out for Thiers.
Next time on "Isabelle from Paris":
"The Birth of a Beautiful Swordslady".
Please look forward to it.
anata no egao wa
totemo suteki
Your smile is so nice
soyokaze no you ni
atatakai ai ga aru
It displays so much love,
gentle like a breeze
RANRARA hazunda uta wa
ogawa wo koete
La la la, our song
reaches across the stream
hitori no yama ni
kodama suru
and echoes in the green mountains
hora omoikiri
kasekete yukou
Let's run with all our might
ano hito no iru
oka no ue made
to the top of the hill,
where our friend is