Masterpiece Romantic Theatre
kyou wa totemo ureshii kibun
Today I feel so happy
shiroi hato ga akai hana kureta
A white dove gave me a red flower
nandaka akogare no ano hito to
Somehow I have a feeling that
aesou na yokan ga suru wa
I will be able to meet that person again
RU · · · doushiyou aeru kashira
La la la, will we meet again?
RU · · · doushiyou hazukashii na
La la la, it's a bit embarrassing
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
Prussian troops were
almost at the gates of Paris.
It was only a matter of time
until Paris was surrounded by the army.
The upper class and the landowners
were still evacuating to Versailles.
Among them was
the Rostain family.
Everything…
Everything is falling apart.
I won't see this room for a while.
Isabelle
Father · Léon
Mother · Marie
Count Red
Sister · Geneviève
Piano Teacher · Jules
Army Captain · Victor
Young friend · Jean
Screenplay
Shudou Takeshi
Narrator
Inagaki Mihoko
Music
Isao Matsushita
Character Design
Fukuda Kiyomu
Kitajima Nobuyuki
Chief Director
Hayakawa Keiji
Director
Hakata Tan
- Episode 04 -
The Road to Versailles
Jules.
No matter the result
of your duel with Victor,
I cannot approve of you
being my daughter's husband.
The Rostain family
is a family of a high social status.
You have left a stain
on our family's name.
But Mr. Jules risked his life
for my sister!
Silence, Isabelle.
This is adults talking.
But…
It's fine, Isabelle.
Father, I want to live
together with Jules.
I am ready for consequences.
– You stupid girl!
– Father.
You're terrible!
You're terrible, Father!
I see.
Geneviève.
I will no longer attempt to stop you.
From now on, you are
no longer a part of this family.
Do you understand?
Father.
Do not call me your father.
Marie. Don't be upset.
The Geneviève we knew is dead.
Our only children are now
Andréa and Isabelle.
Master, the preparations
for the departure are all done.
Very well.
All right. It is time, everyone.
Everyone go ahead of me.
Did I raise her wrong?
Geneviève.
You were such a kind child.
Master.
Everyone is waiting for you.
Gaston.
Yes, Master?
There is something
I would like to ask you.
I would like to release you
from serving our family as of today.
Yes, Master.
I can't say I didn't see it coming.
Take this with you.
What is inside?
I have one more favor to ask.
Please watch over Geneviève for me.
Very difficult times are coming.
Use this money to support her in need.
I know I am asking a lot.
Can you grant my wish
nonetheless?
Yes, Master.
I shall grant your wish.
Thank you.
To begin with, I was devoted
to Ms. Geneviève the most.
Andréa, I'm leaving
the rest to you.
Yes, Father.
Don't worry about anything.
Andréa…
I'll be fine.
I am not going to die.
Sister…
Isabelle.
All right, we're leaving.
Gaston.
Hyah!
Geneviève!
Mother!
Geneviève.
Sister…
Listen, Geneviève. This is the path
you've chosen for yourself.
Do not look away from it.
You can't take back
what you did.
Later this afternoon,
Jules and Geneviève
had a low-key wedding ceremony
at a small church in Paris.
In the name of the Lord Almighty,
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
Amen.
Jules, I won't take long.
Take care of my sister.
Andréa.
Brother.
You got what you wanted.
Cherish it.
Thank you, Brother.
Jules.
There's one thing
I fail to understand.
What do you mean?
I mean your lovely bride.
Even though she just lost it all:
the land, the money,
she looks so happy right now.
That's a good one.
Andréa!
Victor?
I've been looking
for you, Andréa.
I am sorry to disturb the harmony
of this occasion, but it is important.
The Prussian army
has started surrounding Paris.
What? So fast?
Damn it!
Victor, give me your horse.
Hm? What for?
My family is on their way
to Versailles right now.
They might come across
the enemy troops.
I understand.
I will go warn them.
No, it is too dangerous.
I will take care of my family by myself.
Give me your horse. Uh!
I'm sorry.
Victor!
You are beyond belief.
The Prussian army started
to encircle the city of Paris.
As the Rostain family
was heading to Versailles,
many of the Prussian troops were
already in the area, waiting for refugees.
However, the Rostains
did not know about it at all.
Hi! It's me, Jean,
with my daily marriage proposal.
Homesick already, Isabelle?
Geez, stop following me around.
The sight of your face
makes me nauseous.
Come on, before long,
you'll get used to it.
And once you do, it's in the bag.
I can already hear the church bells!
Tin-tan-din-dan!
My taste is not nearly bad enough
to get used to your face.
Oh, I wouldn't be so sure.
You see, from now on, I'll follow you
wherever you go, like a shadow.
Oh, is that right?
Like a shadow?
Shadows do not blabber as much
and do not keep sending unwanted flowers.
Oh, dear.
Another rejection today.
Today and tomorrow, too.
Oh, whatever. If I hold out long enough,
you'll grow to love me.
Are you stupid?
Yikes!
I can't believe him.
What was that?
What is going on?
Master, it seems we have entered
right into middle of a battle!
What shall we do?
Stay calm!
We will cross that bridge,
then we will go into the forest.
Yes, Master.
Hyah!
Mother!?
Father!
Mother!
We should be
at a safe distance here.
Where is Isabelle?
I can't see
her carriage anywhere!
What?!
Isabelle!
Victor! Jean!
Isabelle…
Isabelle, hang on to me.
Are you okay, Isabelle?
Yes.
Geez, Victor again?
Why is he always interfering?
Hey, buddy!
We must have a little chat!
On second thought,
we can do that later. Hyah!
Not good.
They blew up the bridge.
What about the rest
of the Rostains?
Well, they did cross the bridge.
I think they'll be fine.
They're probably
in Versailles by now.
Thank goodness.
What are we going to do?
The road to Versailles
is swarming with enemies.
Going back to Paris
seems to be our only option.
The way home
is full of enemies, too!
If we go on foot,
we'll get caught sooner or later.
It'll be fine, Jean.
Leave it to me.
– What was that?
– Not sure.
This way.
There's a guard.
There's a cart.
We'll snatch it.
Who are you?!
Isabelle!
Damn! Take this, you oaf!
Jean!
Damn! Don't think you can mock me
just because you're big!
Jean!
Now you've done it, kid.
You're so pathetic, Jean.
You can't do
anything without me.
I won't deny it.
Who are you!?
Hands up, right now!
Victor…
Jean, you take this.
All right, follow me.
Hurry up!
Hyah!
After them!
Don't let them escape!
Isabelle, can you drive?
I'll try.
Perfect.
You can't shoot
randomly like this.
Lean slightly forward.
Let your body absorb the recoil.
You don't need to aim at people.
Horses are enough.
Got it!
Mr. Victor,
your wound from the duel…
Now's not the time for that.
Shoot. Keep shooting!
You're pretty good.
Victor!
Stop right there!
It's our friends!
Fire!
The moment Isabelle had realized
they were safe, she fainted.
Isabelle.
You saved our skin.
Are you okay, Victor?
Yes. All thanks to little Isabelle.
Let's get her to a carriage
suitable for a lady like her.
Such a cute face.
You're still just a girl.
Ah, there he goes again.
Why does Victor
always look so cool?
Even though she was carried
by the person she longed for…
Isabelle remained unconscious.
To be continued
Next episode preview
General Gambetta heads to Versailles
in a hot-air balloon.
Thanks to my brother's position,
I get to fly with them.
Ah! Soon I'll be able
to meet Mother and Father.
Mr. Victor is flying with us, too!
And so is Jean.
The danger lurks everywhere.
I wonder if we can get
to Versailles safely?
Next time on "Isabelle from Paris":
"Escape in a Hot-air Balloon".
Please look forward to it.
anata no egao wa
totemo suteki
Your smile is so nice
soyokaze no you ni
atatakai ai ga aru
It displays so much love,
gentle like a breeze
RANRARA hazunda uta wa
ogawa wo koete
La la la, our song
reaches across the stream
hitori no yama ni
kodama suru
and echoes in the green mountains
hora omoikiri
kasekete yukou
Let's run with all our might
ano hito no iru
oka no ue made
to the top of the hill,
where our friend is