Masterpiece Romantic Theatre
kyou wa totemo ureshii kibun
Today I feel so happy
shiroi hato ga akai hana kureta
A white dove gave me a red flower
nandaka akogare no ano hito to
Somehow I have a feeling that
aesou na yokan ga suru wa
I will be able to meet that person again
RU · · · doushiyou aeru kashira
La la la, will we meet again?
RU · · · doushiyou hazukashii na
La la la, it's a bit embarrassing
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
The city of fog, London.
After overcoming numerous dangers,
Isabelle and Jean
finally arrived
at their destination.
Excuse me, do you know someone
named Martin Schmidt?
Is Mr. Martin Schmidt here?
Martin?
Can't say it rings a bell.
– What are you doing?
– "What are you doing?"
Ha. If you don't like the smoke of a cigar,
you'd better get out of here.
This is not the place for such munchkins,
all wet behind their ears.
What did you say?!
Oh, did I upset you?
If you're such a man, why don't you take your
pants off and show what you have under?
Right, guys?
Come on! Hurry up!
We're all waiting.
Give them a break.
One of you is Isabelle
and you have news from Paris, right?
Paris? What?
How do you know my name?
I've heard a bit about Jules from Paris.
I will introduce you to Martin Schmidt.
Isabelle
Father · Léon
Mother · Marie
Count Red
Sister · Geneviève
Piano Teacher · Jules
Army Captain · Victor
Young friend · Jean
Screenplay
Shudou Takeshi
Narrator
Inagaki Mihoko
Music
Isao Matsushita
Character Design
Fukuda Kiyomu
Kitajima Nobuyuki
Chief Director
Hayakawa Keiji
Director
Hakata Tan
- Episode 09 -
Love Burning in the Night Fog
Wake up, Martin.
What are you
screaming for, man?
Sir, I brought you a letter.
Please read it.
Let's meet tomorrow at the
British Museum library.
Okay.
You're uh… of Paris…
What's your name again?
Isabelle.
Ah, yes.
Here's to Isabelle from Paris.
A toast to Isabelle from Paris!
Cheers!
You got a problem, buddy?
It's that monster!
He chased us all the way here!
This is a place of rest.
Please, come over some other day.
You bastard!
Wait. If you want to make trouble,
take it outside.
Here, it's on the house. But after
you finish, I must ask you to leave.
Hey, buddy.
We're Englishmen, you know?
Our ancestors wreaked
havoc on the Seven Seas.
Believe me, you don't
want to mess with us.
I was asking you politely.
He's mocking us!
– Let's get him!
– Yeah!
If you chose not to
listen to reason, so be it.
The people who bring violence to our
beloved pub, we call them garbage.
And we deal with garbage
in a very simple manner.
All right, gentlemen,
back to drinking.
Don't sweat it.
These are just a few scratches.
To cheer you up,
everyone gets a free beer.
Incredible! I didn't know that
taverns had such contraptions!
You see, we British
love our machines.
A bit off topic, do you know
where to stay for the night?
No. We are in London for the first time
and we cannot tell left from right.
No problem. I will introduce you
to someone you can trust.
They have very good food there.
Especially roasted beef and puddings.
They melt in your mouth!
I just don't know if it will suit
your sophisticated French tastes.
Jean, that…
can't be him, right?
Run for it!
I see he doesn't know
when to let go.
No! Bullets don't work on him.
We have to run!
Impossible!
Hurry! We have to run!
Isabelle! We're running away!
I think we lost him.
Jean, I can't go on anymore.
I'm sick of all this running.
I want to go back to Versailles.
You think I don't?
I got tangled up in things I don't fully
understand and at times, I regret it.
Do you reckon we could just
straight up apologize and come back?
You know full well
it won't work, Isabelle.
We both got involved in it
on our own accord.
You are no longer Isabelle Rostain
or Isabelle from Versailles.
You are Isabelle from Paris.
Isabelle… from Paris?
Yes. Isabelle from Paris.
I am Isabelle from Paris.
As long as I liveth, i shalt protect
the freedom and people of Paris.
Long live Isabelle!
Isabelle is our savior!
Praise Isabelle from Paris!
So much fun!
Isabelle from Paris
and Jean from Paris.
Paris of Isabelle.
Paris of Jean.
Sounds like a title
of a novel, doesn't it?
Do you regret leaving?
The floor may be a bit hard here,
but we should catch some sleep.
Tomorrow we will go on
another great adventure.
Good night.
The situation is this.
Isabelle made contact
with the British revolutionaries.
Therefore, we must dispose not only of her,
but also everyone who talked to her!
Gather everyone
and don't spare anyone!
Panza!
I told you to leave the girl alone.
Who… Who's there?!
Close the door!
Don't let anyone leave.
Show yourself!
I don't hide from anyone.
I am over here.
Count Red?
How did you get here?
Why are you opposing us?
Count Red doesn't have to answer
the questions of cowards like you.
You deserve only to be wiped off
the face of the earth.
What is it?
What's that sound!?
In a moment or two, all that's left
from your boat will be a few splinters.
Damn, it's a bomb!
Withdraw! Withdraw!
It's a bomb!
Save yourselves!
Leave the boat!
Shoot! Shoot!
Kill him! Kill him!
Are you all right, Irma?
I'm fine.
You won't run away from me.
I don't want anyone's help.
I'll get rid of this rodent myself!
Don't put yourself
in danger, Irma.
Say your prayers.
Hey, boss!
They're our men.
Go without me!
I'm not important.
Save yourself!
You're the only one I don't want
to lose. Get outta here!
You're pretty good!
You too. You're doing
surprisingly well for a coward.
Watch your words, dog!
That would be it, you red clown.
The fire has spread.
The boat is about to explode!
What!?
Finally. How long
did I have to wait?
Until next time!
Next time, I will squeeze
the life out of you.
I look forward to it.
Wait a second.
I heard that voice somewhere.
Whose voice it is? Whose?
Indeed.
The Count Red's voice
sounded strangely familiar.
Panza, however, could not
remember at all who it belonged to.
Meanwhile Victor, worried
about the fate of our heroine,
learned from Thiers
Isabelle's whereabouts,
and was slowly
approaching London.
They want Isabelle dead or alive?
What could a fifteen-year-old
girl do to them?
Thiers has lost his mind.
God help you, Isabelle.
Don't look at it!
Seeing the portrait of Isabelle,
Victor got flooded with memories.
Isabelle's face reminded him
of her sister, Geneviève.
British Museum.
The largest museum in the world,
located at Russell Square in London.
From Ancient Egypt, through Greece,
Rome, India, to China and Japan.
The collections contain works of art, exhibits
from excavations, folk crafts and much more.
We're in for some nice views.
How can you be so calm in these
circumstances and think about the views?
Shh! Calm down, or else
you'll look suspicious.
That's their idea of a disguise?
In the end they're only kids.
After them.
The British Museum Library
can boast 8 million volumes.
The spectacular reading room can easily
accommodate over a hundred book lovers.
Interesting.
Sit down, please.
Pretend that you are reading a book.
I understand Jules' request.
This morning, 120 of our
politicians and military experts
set off for Paris
to help defend the city.
I don't know how many of them
will actually make it there.
This is all we could do.
Give this to Jules.
It contains the names
of everyone we sent.
Keep this list safe,
Isabelle. Now go.
Your actions will go down in history
as catalysts of wonderful changes.
I'm just helping my sister.
A man always acts
for his loved ones.
That's where it all starts.
Goodbye, Isabelle.
Thank you very much, sir.
The city that is protected
and ruled only by its citizens.
What a noble idea.
However, it is still too early.
I hope that the dream of the people of Paris
will be more than just an idealistic fantasy.
Isabelle!
Jean, he's got the letter!
What?!
Stop!
He'll escape us!
I was waiting for you, Isabelle.
It is time to die.
Look!
Isabelle, catch!
Thanks.
Not another step.
We can do it.
All right!
I admit that you
surprised me, brats.
I am afraid, however, that
your fencing show ends here.
All or nothing.
Boss! It's the London police!
The police is gonna come any second!
What? Damn it!
Everyone, retreat!
You're bloody lucky, you squirts.
Withdraw!
Ms. Isabelle,
I have your letter here.
Gaston!
I've arranged for us
a ship to France.
They'll be waiting on
the Waterloo Bridge at 7 o'clock.
The police will be here soon.
Follow me, please!
Okay.
Ah, it must be them!
That's our ship.
Oh, no! It's him again!
Will he ever learn to let go?
I'm so sick of him.
Time to end this,
once and for all.
Jean, don't be ridiculous.
Let's see who is stronger here.
Okay, Karlov! I'm yours!
Show me what you can do!
Jean!
Jean, are you all right?
Victor! It's Victor!
Where did he come from?
It's not funny anymore.
Isabelle, forget everything
that has happened so far.
I'll take care of Thiers.
You two just go back
to Versailles safely.
Victor, but I…
You came to London on a trip.
That is all. Understand?
No matter what happens
in Paris or the world,
I just want you to lead
a peaceful and happy life.
Victor…
Isabelle heard a declaration
of love in Victor's words.
"I finally caught his eye."
In Isabelle's heart,
Paris, Geneviève,
the dangerous trip
to London, everything…
became shrouded in a thick fog.
Isabelle was happy now.
To be continued
Next episode preview
When I returned to Versailles, it was
swirling with rumors of the Count Red.
Their masked leader
apparently has a red-haired lover.
And his identity…
you won't believe it.
Next time on "Isabelle from Paris":
"Love Blooming on The Battlefield".
Please look forward to it.
anata no egao wa
totemo suteki
Your smile is so nice
soyokaze no you ni
atatakai ai ga aru
It displays so much love,
gentle like a breeze
RANRARA hazunda uta wa
ogawa wo koete
La la la, our song
reaches across the stream
midori no yama ni
kodama suru
and echoes in the green mountains
hora omoikiri
kakete yukou
Let's run with all our might
ano hito no iru
oka no ue made
to the top of the hill,
where our friend is