Masterpiece Romantic Theatre
kyou wa totemo ureshii kibun
Today I feel so happy
shiroi hato ga akai hana kureta
A white dove gave me a red flower
nandaka akogare no ano hito to
Somehow I have a feeling that
aesou na yokan ga suru wa
I will be able to meet that person again
RU · · · doushiyou aeru kashira
La la la, will we meet again?
RU · · · doushiyou hazukashii na
La la la, it's a bit embarrassing
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
September 1870.
The city of Paris was finally besieged
by the Prussian troops.
Isabelle
Father · Léon
Mother · Marie
Count Red
Sister · Geneviève
Piano Teacher · Jules
Army Captain · Victor
Young friend · Jean
Screenplay
Shudou Takeshi
Narrator
Inagaki Mihoko
Music
Isao Matsushita
Character Design
Fukuda Kiyomu
Kitajima Nobuyuki
Chief Director
Hayakawa Keiji
Director
Hakata Tan
- Episode 05 -
Escape in a Hot-air Balloon
Mr. Thiers, are you telling us
to lose without fighting?
If Paris becomes a battlefield,
there will be fire everywhere.
Our mansions and properties
will go up in smoke.
We cannot let that happen.
The citizens of Paris are willing
to throw away everything and fight.
That is only because
they don't have anything to lose.
For us, it is unacceptable.
Paris is the pride of France.
Losing Paris means
losing the heart of France.
Can you even
call yourselves French?
We are French, indeed.
We just have assets that
we do not want to lose.
You are all so pathetic.
If we capitulate,
the citizens will not remain silent.
Well, this time, they'd better.
What?
They want to surrender Paris?
Are you kidding me? They expect us
to just hand it over to the Prussians?
No matter what Thiers says,
I won't give them anything!
We will fight!
That's right!
Paris is our city!
Yeah!
– We will fight for our city!
– Yeah!
Fight for Paris!
Yeah! Yeah!
Silence!
Silence.
We will arrest anyone
who defies the government.
Say what?!
I will not be pushed around
by spineless cowards. Screw you!
Hang in there!
What have you done?!
Don't move!
Stop.
I can't do nothing!
You're all under arrest.
Don't let them escape!
Damn!
Keep calm.
Now's our chance to escape.
Sister…
You look so overjoyed.
I am so happy to live here.
Hey, mister!
How about one?
Your playing
is as wonderful as always.
I'm so happy to be back in Paris.
You're so easygoing.
You should go to Versailles
as soon as possible
and reassure
Mother and Father.
But our enemies
are all around Paris.
Not even a mouse
could sneak in or out.
For the time being
going to Versailles is impossible.
Well, if you say so.
Something will change
at some point.
Rather than being
concerned about me,
shouldn't you worry
more about Jules?
About Jules?
We'll be fine.
Whoa, you've said it!
I'm so jealous.
Geneviève,
we're leaving this place.
Thiers started a witch hunt.
The police will be here
any moment.
Jules Francoeur?
I am arresting you on charges
of incitement to rebellion.
Do not resist us.
Drop your weapons.
Put your hands up
and open the way.
Gaston!
I will be always by your side.
Pick up the guns
and come with me.
Hurry up!
We're going upstairs!
Open up!
They're here!
Here they are!
Gaston, hurry!
They went outside!
Please watch your step.
Did you see them?
No! How about the other side?
Found them?
No!
Where did they go?
How's this side?
Nope.
It's over.
Sooner or later,
they will catch us.
I have an idea.
This is our only chance.
Here, this way.
It was an underground sewage system
that ran like a maze under the streets of Paris.
They went down there?
They're like a rats in a cage.
This way, please.
Found them!
They're here!
We found them!
Damn!
Geneviève…
Jules…
I… I murdered a man!
I killed him…
I killed a human being…
I… I murdered somebody.
I killed him with my own hands.
Take a hold of yourself,
Geneviève.
There will be time for that later.
Please follow me.
He's right, Sister.
Where are they? Where?!
They're around the corner!
Shoot them!
Stop shooting! It's us!
Wait, wait!
They're one of us.
Cease fire!
We risk friendly fire.
Do not shoot your guns in the tunnels!
We should be safe here
for some time.
We are close to Ms. Isabelle's
temporary residence.
Isabelle, this is where we part.
It is possible that we will
never see each other again.
No way.
I'm sure that some day…
It is actually for the best.
Both of us are chased
by the police.
It is better for you
not to get involved.
Do you understand? It's for your
and for the Rostain family's sake.
But how are you going
to live from now on?
Where will you go?
I will follow Jules
wherever he goes.
It is time to go,
before anyone notices us.
Farewell, Isabelle.
Stay safe.
Sister…
Ms. Isabelle, I will escort you.
I can go by myself.
Take care of my sister, Gaston.
Until next time.
The life of a fugitive.
Isabelle could only imagine
how painful it was going to be.
She also didn't know
if they'd ever reunite.
One day, we will meet again.
I'm sure of it, Sister.
I am going to repeat this.
Gentlemen.
Paris is the life of France!
We must avoid capitulation
at all costs.
Destroying the Prussian army,
all the while keeping our properties safe?
It sounds nice, but how exactly are you
going to achieve it, General Gambetta?
There is a way.
France still has enough strength
to beat the Prussians.
Let me go around the country
and assemble an army.
As a national hero, you would be able
to gather people and form an army, indeed.
But Paris is completely
surrounded by enemies.
How do you plan
to get out of the city?
Could you share that with us?
There is still a part of Paris
that is not guarded by the enemy.
What part? Where is it?
It is the sky.
The Parisian sky is still ours.
General Gambetta
asked for two hot-air balloons.
His idea was to use them
to sneak out of Paris.
We can reach Versailles
with these?
Amazing.
Think we'll be okay?
I hate high places…
Jean, you softy.
This is the opportunity
of a lifetime.
Mr. Victor and Andréa
personally asked General Gambetta
to take you to Versailles.
You can't back out now.
Well, if you are going,
I will, as well…
But still, it'll be so high…
Rest assured, Jean.
Victor is going with you.
That's right. With Mr. Victor,
we'll be safe no matter where we go.
Right, Mr. Victor?
Yes, somehow I always
end up saving everyone.
Geez, look at that buffoon.
Ah, General Gambetta
is about to give a speech.
People of Paris.
Our city is immortal.
There is no way
we'd hand it over to anyone.
I am going to gather soldiers
and I promise to you to come back.
Until then, I want you
to keep defending Paris.
I look forward to seeing
the bravery of the citizens of Paris.
Long live General Gambetta!
Paris will be safe
with us, Gambetta!
He sure is popular.
No worries. With him out of the picture,
the city will fall to our knees.
Let him do
as he pleases for now.
Jean, you will fly
the balloon over there.
Huh? Not the one with Isabelle?
I'm sorry.
We have to distribute the weight.
Is there no other way?
I really wanted to enjoy
an air trip with Isabelle.
Oh, that sure would be lovely.
Adieu and bye-bye.
Whatever, it doesn't matter.
I'm sorry, Jean.
In Versailles, we'll be neighbors anyway.
I'll be able to see her whenever I want.
All right, we're leaving.
Good luck, Andréa.
Thanks. You can count on me.
I'll defend this city like a lion.
Everything's ready.
Light the fire!
Amazing.
Ah… Lord, have mercy!
I told you!
I hate high places.
Let it be Versailles already!
Just let it be over!
Stay alert.
We're almost above the enemy.
This is it.
We're all going to die!
I don't want to die
by falling to death!
Argh, this is so annoying.
Hey! If you shoot us down, there's
no telling what I'll do! Stop shooting!
We're falling!
Victor, go and patch the hole.
– Yes sir.
– No, it's too dangerous.
Your weight will only
make the hole wider.
What should we do, then!?
I'll do it.
Isabelle?
No. It's too risky!
Crashing on the ground is even riskier.
Let me do it, please!
Very well.
Take them.
It's a needle and a thread.
May the Lord guide your hands.
The hole is too big.
I did it.
It's patched!
Good work, Isabelle.
Well done.
Women are good at sewing.
An ammunition depot?
Not anymore.
Jean is in danger!
Somebody save me!
Victor, do something!
Right away.
Descend us!
I'm slipping!
Jean, grab onto this!
You can do it, Jean!
Jean…
Thank goodness, you're alive.
As if I could die!
I'll stay alive until we get married.
Again with your delusions?
I shouldn't have worried about you.
Right, Mr. Victor?
I wouldn't be so sure.
I'd say you're quite a good match.
A good match?
No way.
Hmm?
Did I say something wrong?
Never mind. Never mind!
"Victor doesn't notice
my feelings at all."
Isabelle felt very sad
and unappreciated.
What's wrong, Isabelle?
Shut up. Why don't you just
jump from here and die?
Now, now. I'm not sure what you're arguing
about, but soon he won't have to.
We've arrived at Versailles.
And so, Isabelle and her friends who were
besieged in Paris by the Prussian troops,
made their great escape.
Bonjour, Versailles.
To be continued
Next episode preview
Life in Versailles is very quiet.
The food supply of the people
of Paris is about to run out.
Thiers is doing nothing about it.
The citizens finally give in to their anger.
My brother is finally
called to arms.
But that battle he goes to turns out
to be a trap laid by Thiers.
Next time on "Isabelle from Paris":
"News of Andréa's Death in Battle".
Please look forward to it.
anata no egao wa
totemo suteki
Your smile is so nice
soyokaze no you ni
atatakai ai ga aru
It displays so much love,
gentle like a breeze
RANRARA hazunda uta wa
ogawa wo koete
La la la, our song
reaches across the stream
midori no yama ni
kodama suru
and echoes in the green mountains
hora omoikiri
kakete yukou
Let's run with all our might
ano hito no iru
oka no ue made
to the top of the hill,
where our friend is