Masterpiece Romantic Theatre
kyou wa totemo ureshii kibun
Today I feel so happy
shiroi hato ga akai hana kureta
A white dove gave me a red flower
nandaka akogare no ano hito to
Somehow I have a feeling that
aesou na yokan ga suru wa
I will be able to meet that person again
RU · · · doushiyou aeru kashira
La la la, will we meet again?
RU · · · doushiyou hazukashii na
La la la, it's a bit embarrassing
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
September 2, 1870.
Prussian troops defeated
the French army in Sedan
and began to march
to the French capital, Paris.
The danger was imminent.
Do you expect us to die here?
We're going back to protect Paris.
We still have Paris!
We're here!
This is Paris.
Hey.
It's the lights of Paris.
We're finally here!
Who's there?!
This is Captain Andréa.
This man needs immediate medical help.
Yes sir!
Life's full of irony.
Just a moment
after we made it…
Andréa?
Is that you, Andréa?
Victor?
Victor!
Andréa!
Andréa.
I knew you'd be alive.
You're not a man that
would go down so easily.
I'm glad to see you here.
As long as I have Paris,
I will not die.
I won't give Paris to Prussia,
no matter what.
I came back
to defend our capital.
Let's defend it together.
This is our city.
The honor of France is at stake.
Let's do it together.
I'm in.
With the two of us.
Yeah.
Isabelle
Father · Léon
Mother · Marie
Count Red
Sister · Geneviève
Piano Teacher · Jules
Army Captain · Victor
Young friend · Jean
Screenplay
Shudou Takeshi
Narrator
Inagaki Mihoko
Music
Isao Matsushita
Character Design
Fukuda Kiyomu
Kitajima Nobuyuki
Chief Director
Hayakawa Keiji
Director
Hakata Tan
- Episode 02 -
In a Valley Between Two Loves
Soon, the city of Paris
was about to become a battlefield.
In fear of losing homes and properties
after being involved in battle,
the rich and powerful
started to seek shelter
and one after another
migrated to the city of Versailles.
Mommy,
where is everyone going?
The war is about to begin.
They're running away to Versailles.
Are we going to move, too?
I don't really want to.
Even if we escaped,
we don't have any villas to hide in.
There is no place for us
outside of Paris.
These people live in a world
that is entirely different from ours.
They don't care at all
what happens to this city.
That's right.
Only a limited number of people
had a place to escape from war.
The Rostain family
was among the lucky ones.
Quick, quick, quick!
No time for dilly-dallying.
The Prussian army
is just around the corner!
Remember,
only the nobles' belongings.
I don't like this.
What a drag!
I guess it's time to say goodbye
to this house for a while.
Hm?
Andréa… It's Andréa!
I'm sorry!
Outta my way!
What… What are you doing, young lady?
Stop right there!
Now is not the time for the lectures.
It's Andréa! It's Andréa!
Andréa!
Who do we have here?
Andréa… Andréa.
Ms. Isabelle…
You're just too much.
Hello, Jeanne. I'm back.
Young master!
What am I doing?
Young master is here.
Master! Milady! Mr. Andréa is back!
How have you been?
Stupid, stupid brother!
Do you have any idea
how worried I was?
Hey, hey, Isabelle.
What's with this messy reception?
Haven't you made your debut
in high society and become a lady?
That's right. I'm a lady now.
Isn't that right, Mr. Victor?
Yes. You made
an excellent lady that day.
It is a pity that we must part
just after our family has finally reunited.
Father, you'll be safe
as long as you stay in Versailles.
When we know
that our family is safe,
we'll feel much more confident
on the battlefield.
Right.
But don't do anything reckless.
I understand. We won't.
Our goal is not to die.
It is to protect Paris to the end.
Apropos, Victor. You will not be able
to see Geneviève for a while.
I was hoping you could
get married, even if just in writing.
Marriage? Now?
Yes, that's exactly what I mean.
Young people have a tendency
of making fools of themselves.
If you get married,
you will start to be cautious.
And caution in war
is at a premium.
Victor, now might be
actually the best time for that.
What will you do
if your betrothed has a little fun
on the side behind your back?
But I am going to fight
at the front line.
If something were
to happen to me…
Victor. I am a French man.
Do you think a French soldier's wife is afraid
that her husband will die protecting France?
I don't remember
raising my daughter in such a way.
Women do change their mind
about such things.
Isabelle felt uncomfortable.
Isabelle knew.
She knew that Geneviève had
another lover besides Victor… Jules.
Isabelle…
I can not help it.
Victor…
Poor Victor!
Why?
Why are you silent?
You're such a coward, sister.
Why don't you say anything?
Geneviève's mind was now full of thoughts
about her piano teacher, Jules.
You're the daughter
of a great landowner.
And I'm… a pianist who lives
in town on the first floor.
The worlds we live in
are too far apart.
I don't have what it takes
to make you happy.
You coward! I will…
I will follow you wherever you go.
There's nothing we can do!
Geneviève…
There's nothing we can do.
A wedding only in writing.
I understand.
I take your daughter as my wife.
You finally made up your mind.
Congratulations, Geneviève.
Very well.
Let us have a toast.
Geneviève.
I know I made you wait
a bit too long.
But please believe me, I have been
thinking only of you all this time.
Geneviève.
You will marry me.
Isabelle, who knew
about Geneviève's feelings,
only stood there
and watched this scene in silence.
The elite are all fleeing to their
nice safe properties in Versailles.
Must be nice,
having a place to escape to.
What about us?
Where are we going to escape to?
Escape?
You better be kidding.
I was born and raised in this town.
I am a proud Parisian.
I won't let anybody
have our city.
Damn right!
I'm not moving an inch from this city!
I'll say one thing. I won't stay idle
when the Prussian army comes.
Music to my ears. I'll fight
by your side when the time comes.
Good.
Hey, everybody!
We are Parisians!
Paris is our city!
Yeah!
Who is going to defend our city?
Who?
The army?
The politicians?
The aristocrats?
No. It'll be us!
It'll be us!
We'll protect our city
by ourselves!
Yeah!
We will be the ones
who protect Paris!
It'll be us!
We'll defend Paris!
We'll defend it!
Yeah!
We'll defend Paris!
– Defend Paris!
– Yeah!
Defend Paris!
We'll defend Paris!
Exciting times, huh?
Yes. These are the real feelings
of those truly living in Paris.
There is no love for Paris among the people
who leave it and flee to Versailles.
I heard that the Rostain family
is evacuating there as well.
Yes.
Must be nice, not having
to worry about anything.
Ordinary people have it
worse than ever these days.
I'm a bit jealous of you.
Cut it. Leave Geneviève out of it.
A relationship between us
is just not meant to be.
Thanks.
You had too much.
See?
Here comes the goddess savior
of the poor artist.
Jules…
Geneviève.
Take a look.
That little boat is home to a family
with God knows how many children.
Jules…
Marry Victor.
Huh?
Our relationship
is destined to fail, Geneviève.
Why? Because our positions
are too different?
The worlds we live in
are too far apart?
I don't care about any of that.
Jules, I care only about you—
I only want you to be happy.
Stop it! I'm so sick of others
making decisions for me.
I am a woman.
Do not decide for me
what my happiness is.
I decide my own happiness.
I want to live by your side.
I don't need anything else.
I'll throw everything else away.
Geneviève.
Geneviève…
I love you, Geneviève.
Tell me not to go.
Ms. Geneviève,
it is time to go.
Tomorrow I will go
and tell your parents.
Then, I'll be on my way.
Promise you'll be there.
I will.
Mr. Gaston,
what happened here…
I am Ms. Geneviève's
faithful servant.
Goodbye, Jules.
Jules… I love you.
Farewell, Geneviève.
"We'll never meet again".
Jules vowed inwardly,
looking at the departing carriage.
Forget her.
I have to forget her.
There are other things
that I must do.
That's right.
We have to defend Paris.
I'll defend it.
I'll defend Paris.
Defend Paris!
Defend Paris. Defend Paris!
It is very commendable that the citizens
of Paris are willing to take arms.
But I cannot say that
I am really happy about it.
What do you mean
by that, Mr. Thiers?
When the city of Paris becomes
a battlefield, there will be fire.
This means risk for
our homes and properties.
We must use whatever means
necessary to prevent this risk.
Our homes and properties?
Surely you don't mean that to protect these,
we should give up without a fight?
That is also a possibility, yes.
I can't believe it!
Paris is the pride of all of France!
Losing Paris is equivalent
to losing the heart of France.
I will never agree to that!
I can't believe this man.
What happened, Mr. General?
He's gone nuts.
The politicians want to protect their assets
and consider selling Paris to Prussia.
Victor?
Hm?
Geneviève!?
What are you doing here?
I would like to talk
to Victor alone.
I don't mind, but don't abuse
your privilege of being my sister too much.
What? You're not going
to Versailles? Geneviève…
I…
I'm leaving our home.
Wait.
What are you trying to say?
Forgive me.
Please forgive me.
But my heart is with Jules.
Who is it?
I am Victor Langlois
of the French Army.
Victor?
Jules Francoeur, right?
That's right.
I challenge you to a duel.
Marriage? With you?
Naturally, not right away.
Just an engagement, for now.
But, what do you think?
Are you serious?
I know we're
childhood friends and all,
but how can you ask me
for my hand so casually?
What? But this is
anything but casual.
I've asked you
countless times, remember?
Hey, when we grow up,
we'll marry each other, right?
Nope. I'm not marrying
anyone like you.
Hey, when are we
going to marry?
Listen, I hate
weaklings and crybabies.
Fine then!
What do you think
you're doing?!
Oww!
Isabelle, your wedding dress
looks so beautiful.
Of course it does.
But you'll be disappointed,
since I'll be wearing it for someone else.
No way… No way.
Do you remember that you
even agreed a few times?
I had to get rid of you somehow.
Jean, stop living in the past.
My answer is the same as before.
So you refuse?
I refuse.
Come on…
Don't be like that.
No means no!
– Come on…
– Knock it off.
I will withdraw for today.
We're going to live next
to each other in Versailles, anyway.
I'll be able to see you any time.
Versailles is a nice place.
Without you, that is.
Your words can't hurt me.
You silly girl.
Geneviève!
Where is Geneviève?
Do you need anything, Andréa?
Victor challenged
Jules to a duel.
Victor and Jules…
will duel each other?
It was something Isabelle
could hardly even imagine.
The adult world began to appear
in vivid colors around the 15-old Isabelle.
To be continued
Next episode preview
I'm overjoyed to see my brother
Andréa return home in safety.
But Victor and Jules…
are going to fight in a duel?
Victor is a soldier.
He's an expert shooter.
But Jules?
He's just a piano teacher.
What should I do?
In addition, there's also
the evacuation to Versailles.
Next time on "Isabelle from Paris":
"On The Day of The Duel, The One I Love…"
Please look forward to it.
anata no egao wa
totemo suteki
Your smile is so nice
soyokaze no you ni
atatakai ai ga aru
It displays so much love,
gentle like a breeze
RANRARA hazunda uta wa
ogawa wo koete
La la la, our song
reaches across the stream
hitori no yama ni
kodama suru
and echoes in the green mountains
hora omoikiri
kasekete yukou
Let's run with all our might
ano hito no iru
oka no ue made
to the top of the hill,
where our friend is