Masterpiece Romantic Theatre
kyou wa totemo ureshii kibun
Today I feel so happy
shiroi hato ga akai hana kureta
A white dove gave me a red flower
nandaka akogare no ano hito to
Somehow I have a feeling that
aesou na yokan ga suru wa
I will be able to meet that person again
RU · · · doushiyou aeru kashira
La la la, will we meet again?
RU · · · doushiyou hazukashii na
La la la, it's a bit embarrassing
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
May 1871.
At the time when Paris was
expecting an attack from Prussia,
Thiers was already putting in motion his plan
that used the French troops at Versailles.
The capital of France was
between a rock and a hard place.
The people of Paris
continued to call for battle,
encouraging each other to try to break
through the army besieging their city.
Their enthusiasm was slowly
rubbing off even on foreigners.
The troops of these Versailles
hypocrites are already close.
We must raise barricades.
Yeah.
Jules, I will help you, too.
No, you should sit and rest.
I'll be alright.
A little effort won't hurt me.
Geneviève, don't give me
more to worry about.
You know that you have
to take it easy now.
But…
Please, don't argue with me.
Maybe I can give you a hand?
Victor?
Victor!
Jules, let me help you.
I don't mean just you.
Exactly.
We will help you defend this city.
Andréa?
Yes. We're all back,
ready to defend our capital.
Isabelle!
Sister.
Ah, Isabelle!
How have you been?
I was about to ask you the same.
There is no time
to get emotional.
Our enemies will
be here any minute.
Citizens of Versailles.
We will soon launch an attack
on Paris and I am sure
that we'll be able to reclaim both the city
and our wealth from these scum.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this moment has come.
The moment when we will regain
everything that belongs to us!
Isabelle
Father · Léon
Mother · Marie
Count Red
Sister · Geneviève
Piano Teacher · Jules
Army Captain · Victor
Young friend · Jean
Screenplay
Shudou Takeshi
Narrator
Inagaki Mihoko
Music
Isao Matsushita
Character Design
Fukuda Kiyomu
Kitajima Nobuyuki
Chief Director
Hayakawa Keiji
Director
Hakata Tan
- Episode 12 -
Midday Dance Party
The Rostains' mansion in Paris was still
standing, as if nothing had happened.
It was the place where Isabelle was born
and raised without any worries.
I'm back.
I'm back here…
Something was definitely missing:
the laugh of her father Léon and mother Marie.
Isabelle?
Sister.
I remember our father sitting there
and listening to you playing the piano.
And there is Mom's chair.
After the fact,
I think they died because of me.
It's your fault.
You killed Marie.
You ruined the Rostain family.
Yes. We destroyed our family.
However, I do not intend
to regret anything.
You don't regret anything?
How can you be so strong?
It's all thanks to Jules.
It's thanks to my love for him.
He is currently building a new Paris.
One that the world has never seen.
I'm not that rich, naive
Geneviève anymore.
I am a Parisian now,
one of many.
We will create a city where
the poor will have something to say.
Stop. You're only
fooling yourself.
Yes. Perhaps you're right.
Isabelle,
I am carrying Jules' child.
What are you talking about?
The fruit of our love.
A new life.
Soon, this child will be walking
the streets of this city.
I hope it is so.
All the more reason for you to run!
All hell will break loose here.
I want to protect the city
that our children will live in.
Don't you get that you can die?
If you die… If you die, what
do you think happens to the child?
If that happens,
that's the God's will.
Our child will understand
this in Heaven.
Ah, is that so?
How about, like,
asking their opinion first?
What is it about this city
that you all want to die for it?!
Isabelle…
Why did you come back here?
Why?
Actually, that's a good question…
Why did I come back?
Certainly not because of you.
Isabelle…
I don't know what
the future holds.
But I want to believe
in Jules. I really do.
These points will be the most
effective positions for barricades.
But in order to win, we must accept
that we may have to abandon them.
There is always a chance that
the enemy will come from behind.
Sometimes you have to lose a battle
to win the war. That is all.
That's all nice, Victor, but you need soldiers
who can execute orders without complaints.
Unfortunately, we all know that our people
have never held weapons in their hands.
Well, since there's no other option,
we don't have much choice.
Exactly.
Okay, Andréa. You will take
command of the first barricade.
All right.
Jules, you over the second.
Blanchard,
you'll command the third.
With this map, we could suppress
the rebellion in a single day.
Well, well, what kind
of voyeur is this?
Damn…
I think that if we can hold these points,
we stand a good chance.
Hm?
Panza?!
What are you doing here?
Do you realize that this room
was originally occupied by Mr. Thiers?
There are many devices hidden here
that you have no idea about.
But who would've thought that
Count Red was Andréa all along.
You were supposed to die in the Battle
of Champigny. How did you survive?
Don't yammer so much. I'd like to
remind you that you're at our mercy.
At your mercy? Me?
Do you really see it this way?
Up against the wall.
Watch out!
It appears that
the tables have turned.
If you value this girl's life,
you'll bring me the map.
Bring me the map.
You scum.
I won't forgive you this, Panza!
Don't do that, my love.
Your life is priceless to me.
My love…
Andréa.
Irma!
All right, boys!
Tear them apart!
Irma! Why?
I wanted to.
I won't let anyone
get in your way.
I am truly happy that we met.
Irma… Irma!
This rat…
Die!
Irma!
Irma…
Andréa.
Victor, do you know… Do you know
what dirt and grass smell like?
Irma was a wonderful woman.
She taught me the smell
of dirt and grass.
Ladies and gentlemen, the time
to launch the attack is fast approaching.
We must eliminate the villains
who occupy our Paris.
They are devils
disguised as French.
Even in the skin of a woman or a child,
devil's nature remains the same.
We must erase Satan
from our world!
Kill everyone without exception!
Kill!
Think you're
aiming at the enemy.
If you don't shoot first,
they'll do it for you.
Then you will die.
Remember this
and do not hesitate.
You keep talking about this enemy,
but they're Frenchmen like us, aren't they?
That's right They're ordinary people who
didn't do anything to me. Why kill them?
Fire!
These people
wouldn't even kill a fly.
Good Lord.
What are our chances?
What matters is that
we cannot afford a failure.
A perfect city, ruled by its citizens.
This is the dream of many of us.
But what does it look like
in reality? Can we build this city?
Indeed, I want to defend Paris.
I want to stand up
for what I believe is right.
I know that many Parisians
share my feelings.
However, feelings alone
don't change anything!
The army that will come here
couldn't care less about feelings!
Sooner or later, the morale
of the people of Paris will break.
Exactly. None of us have
a clue about politics or war.
However imperfect it would be,
the idea of a city governed by the people,
for the people was born here.
We must show that it is doable.
I understand all this.
But how? How?
We can't do anything.
So you are leaving Paris?
No. If that was the case, I wouldn't
have come here all the way from London.
I will stay with the citizens
of this city to the very end.
Geneviève, do you really believe
that we can make a change?
Jules, where do
these doubts come from?
You don't believe in the voice of our people,
the voice that is crying as we speak?
We will defend our city!
If not us, then who? It's time to
take matters into your own hands!
This is it! Defend Paris!
Sounds good!
This is our city!
Defend Paris!
Praise Paris!
Just listen to this.
This is our voice. The voice of our hearts.
Our city is being built anew.
A new city, by the people,
for the people.
Yes. Their voice is
the voice of truth.
Remember that we must bring this
to an end also for the sake of our child.
Yes, of course, you are right.
Nonetheless…
Come on, stop worrying so much.
Tomorrow is Sunday.
How about we celebrate
the birth of our new city?
You are a Parisian.
You still like to have fun, right?
Geneviève…
Sunday, May 21, 1871.
It was a sunny day.
The citizens of Paris
have decided to celebrate.
Dance parties took place
on the streets around the entire city.
For the first time in a long time,
people relaxed a little
and they sang,
drank and danced.
Excuse me, gentlemen, would be one of you
willing to dance with my daughter?
Irma, today, we're celebrating.
Everyone is having fun.
Come, Andréa,
come dance with me.
You'll lighten up a bit.
No "but"s.
I can finally congratulate you.
Thank you.
I'm happy for you.
Can you still dance?
Yes, of course.
They look so enchanting.
As if they were made for each other.
Isabelle, let's go, too.
Come on, let's dance.
No.
What are you two sitting for
on such a beautiful day?
Jules! Let me dance with you.
I'm sorry, Jean.
I'm slowly getting used to the notion
that it'll always look like this.
My lady?
Really? With me?
That Sunday was the last one that
the citizens of Paris could blithely enjoy.
Everyone, take cover!
Andréa, follow me!
Victor…
Victor! Wait!
Isabelle!
Where are you going?!
Save yourselves!
The Versailles army has
finally launched the attack.
For the trained army of Versailles,
the citizens of Paris were not a challenge.
Everyone at once! Fire!
Okay! We're backing away!
Backing away? No way.
Excuse me?
This is our district.
We grew up here!
We're not going anywhere!
Fools! That wasn't the plan!
Retreat immediately!
If I have to die anyway, I'd rather do it here.
I want to go down near my house!
Exactly. This is our place.
We can't just give it up to them!
Long live Paris!
Long live our city!
Together—
We will defend our…
The citizens of Paris
didn't know when to withdraw.
Familiar side streets.
Cobblestone stairs.
The walls they doodled on
when they were young.
Finally, their own homes.
They just wanted to protect these.
One after another, they fell dead.
This is not a fight. It's a massacre.
A massacre of the Paris people.
I didn't know… I didn't know
that it was so important to you.
Victor!
Isabelle!
What are you doing here?!
Follow me!
We're getting out of here!
Victor…
Victor!
G… Geneviève?
Is that you, Geneviève?
Yes. It's me.
G… Geneviève…
I am here with you.
Victor…
Victor!
Isabelle!
Isabelle, we have to run!
Come on, now!
Victor…
Victor!
Let me go, Jean!
Victor…
Victor!
Victor!…
That evening in Paris,
a great fire broke out.
Flames escaping high into the sky crowned
the suffering of the city's inhabitants.
Victor!
To be continued
Next episode preview
One by one, the streets
of Paris caught on fire.
For the trained soldiers of Versailles,
the population of the city was no threat.
My siblings with Jules and Jean are doing
everything they can to defend our homes.
Finally, on May 28, the last gunfire
resounds and the battle is over.
Final episode of
"Isabelle from Paris":
"Departure For a New Life".
Please look forward to it.
anata no egao wa
totemo suteki
Your smile is so nice
soyokaze no you ni
atatakai ai ga aru
It displays so much love,
gentle like a breeze
RANRARA hazunda uta wa
ogawa wo koete
La la la, our song
reaches across the stream
hitori no yama ni
kodama suru
and echoes in the green mountains
hora omoikiri
kasekete yukou
Let's run with all our might
ano hito no iru
oka no ue made
to the top of the hill,
where our friend is