Masterpiece Romantic Theatre
kyou wa totemo ureshii kibun
Today I feel so happy
shiroi hato ga akai hana kureta
A white dove gave me a red flower
nandaka akogare no ano hito to
Somehow I have a feeling that
aesou na yokan ga suru wa
I will be able to meet that person again
RU · · · doushiyou aeru kashira
La la la, will we meet again?
RU · · · doushiyou hazukashii na
La la la, it's a bit embarrassing
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
Although it took them
a long time, Isabelle and Jean
succeeded in avoiding many dangers
and delivered the secret letter to London.
Despite having an arrest warrant
looming over them,
with Victor's help, they managed
to return to Versailles.
At that time in Versailles,
as if just waiting for them,
a rather peculiar event occurred.
What a beautiful ruby.
This is my first opportunity
to admire such a perfect gem.
Oh, please. Compared to your diamond,
it is but a worthless pebble.
What happened?
What happened?!
Why did the lights go out?
I do not like this.
Where's my necklace?
And the rings!
They're gone!
They disappeared.
Our jewelry is gone!
What to do?
Where has it gone?
Honey, my…
My necklace…
Get a grip, Bridget.
Don't panic over a handful of pearls.
A picture of a bat?
"To the people of Versailles,
setting the limits of human wealth.
You have our sincere gratitude for
your huge donation to our shadow army.
– Count Red".
Count Red?
Is that his doing?
Let's go.
Isabelle
Father · Léon
Mother · Marie
Count Red
Sister · Geneviève
Piano Teacher · Jules
Army Captain · Victor
Young friend · Jean
Screenplay
Shudou Takeshi
Narrator
Inagaki Mihoko
Music
Isao Matsushita
Character Design
Fukuda Kiyomu
Kitajima Nobuyuki
Chief Director
Hayakawa Keiji
Director
Hakata Tan
- Episode 10 -
Love Blooming on The Battlefield
Who the hell are they?
I don't think they're your
regular bandits looking for money.
It looked like a provocation
against our government.
A provocation?
In other words, this whole Count Red
is a supporter of the Paris occupiers?
In my opinion,
it is the only sensible option.
Panza, and what do you
think about it?
I agree with this gentleman.
In that case, they also obviously know
that we want to sign a secret agreement
with the Prussian army and that
we will try to sell Paris to them again.
This is a serious problem.
If Count Red steals the document
that Prussia is about to send to us
and make it public, we won't be
safe anywhere in France.
This document cannot see
the daylight, no matter what.
I am fully aware of this.
Panza, look out the window.
Count Red's minions!
Panza, don't!
But why, sir?
Now he will go to inform his leaders
about our agreement with Prussia.
You're so thick at times.
He's our pawn now!
Our pawn?
We'll smoke them out. The document
is just a bait that will let us find them.
You will receive
the real document, Panza.
We cannot afford another failure
like the one in London, you hear?
Yes sir! I swear on my life
that I will not let you down.
By the way, Mr. Thiers.
How did it happen that we let Isabelle return
to Versailles, as if nothing had happened?
It's Captain Langlois' wish.
Captain Langlois'?
He's popular with his subordinates
and easy to manipulate.
It's good to have some ace
up your sleeve.
We'll use him
until he's worn out.
Isabelle, what are you doing?
Do you have any idea how much your ridiculous
behavior hurt the Rostains' reputation?
Father, I went to London
not for our family, let alone for Paris.
I did it just to help my sister—
Silence, Isabelle!
I will not let you talk back to me.
Ah, it's you, Victor. Do you think
that I raised my children badly?
Why is it that my children don't care at all
about what is happening at home?
I do not know. I abandoned money
for a military career myself.
I'm not the one that can
answer your question.
Victor. The Rostains are a venerable family
that dates back three hundred years.
I could not bear the thought
that our lineage would be forgotten.
I just want to
protect our heritage.
Darling.
Both Isabelle and Geneviève are proud
women, perfectly worth our family's name.
Their actions are simply caused
by the times we live in.
The times we live in…
Mr. Victor.
A messenger from
Mr. Thiers came to see you.
What? From Thiers?
Captain Langlois, you are ordered
to appear at the palace immediately.
Count Red?
Yes. You are the only one
able to capture this criminal.
As far as I know, their group
is just a bunch of bandits.
Shouldn't the police handle this?
To involve the army…
Count Red is an enemy
of our country.
Are you going to argue
with my orders?
No, not at all.
Here is my order,
Captain Langlois.
Destroy the shadow army
led by Count Red.
Understood? I have already
made some preparations.
Victor against Count Red.
And so, these two men,
who saved Isabelle in London,
were put at the ends
of their swords.
Where have you been, Irma?
I know, I know, but…
I keep telling you
not to risk unnecessarily.
I want to be useful to you.
Besides, we're both in this together.
Together?
All these weapons and jewels are to be
used to defend Paris and its people.
That's why…
That's hardly a justification.
"You are a woman.
The role of a woman lies elsewhere."
I don't want to
listen to this rubbish.
Better tell me
what you think about this.
Soon Prussia will secretly send some
important document to Versailles.
What are you talking about?
Are you sure?
Neither Count Red
nor anyone from his shadow army
could even guess that it was
yet another of Thiers' traps.
What happened?
Please remain calm.
We are not interested in your life.
All we're asking you
is to hand over that parcel.
Bloody hell!
Count Red.
Resistance is futile.
Victor!
You fell into our ambush.
I do not like this method,
but that was the order I was given.
If you do not resist,
we will spare you life.
Did I say anything funny?!
Look what I got here!
Get down!
– Irma!
– Dear!
After them. After them!
Not good. Behind these trees
there's the Rostains' estate.
Be good and nobody will get hurt.
Believe it or not, but we don't like killing.
As I thought,
they took them hostage.
Who would've thought that of all places,
we're going to fight here. Life is so ironic.
Father. Mother.
Apparently,
their daughter is upstairs.
I'll go check it out.
Just don't hurt her, Irma.
That depends on
what she will do.
Stay calm.
Don't struggle and I won't
do anything to you.
Who are you?
One of the
Count Red's shadows.
It's… Is that you, Isabelle?!
Enough of this.
Words out of my mouth,
my friend.
Isabelle, cover yourself.
This fighting style…
You're good, Andréa.
That's impossible!
Count Red… You are…
How about you remove your mask?
Count Red, or rather… Andréa.
You saw through me, Victor.
I can't say I'm surprised.
Your fighting style gave you away.
I could never forget it.
I'm glad you're alive, Andréa.
Victor.
What… What just happened?
I'm sorry you had to worry
because of me, Isabelle.
Andréa… Andréa!
Isabelle!
Yes. Count Red was to die
in the Battle of Champigny.
It was Andréa whom Thiers was supposed to put
to death in a battle with no chance of winning.
After the Battle of
Champigny was over,
Andréa started wandering
aimlessly on the verge of death.
He was saved by a group
of Gypsies who were passing by.
Under the tender care of Irma,
one of the gypsy girls,
Andréa pulled through and
eventually jumped back on his feet.
Irma taught Andréa many things: sadness
and the hardships associated with poverty,
but also the simple joy of life
and how to appreciate each day.
It was a life that Andréa,
born to a wealthy family, never knew.
Andréa saw for the first time
what he really wanted to protect.
Spending day after day with each other,
Irma and Andréa got very close.
Dear…
Irma.
Good job, Irma!
The girl has a taste!
I can't sit here
doing nothing forever.
Somebody help me…
Andréa understood
what he should be fighting for.
All my brothers in arms
who survived the Battle of Champigny
pledged to take
revenge on Thiers.
By taking revenge on him, we will
save the oppressed citizens of Paris.
Over time, more and more
people joined us.
Soon we formed an army of shadows
and I became Count Red.
You do realize, however,
that you are breaking French law?
Laws made by villains from Versailles such as
Thiers don't amount to a spit in the river.
We respect the laws
of people who protect Paris.
What would you say, Victor,
if I suggested you to join us?
I am a soldier of the
Versailles government.
Whatever the government,
as a soldier, I must obey its orders.
You haven't changed at all.
What's happening?
What's going on there?
Trouble, boss! It's the army!
The French army surrounded
the mansion and they're shooting at us!
The French troops? But why?
Why are they attacking the Rostains' estate?
What's going on in Thiers' head?
Victor, now you can see
what a rat he is.
The Rostain family
gives shelter to Count Red.
This is treason.
Their property is hereby confiscated
by the government of Versailles!
Count Red. Inadvertently,
you have done us a huge favor.
Thanks to you,
the Rostains' assets will be ours.
Crumbling walls and pillars.
Isabelle, seeing the sudden collapse
of the Rostain family, forgot everything.
She just stood speechless and looked
at the hell raging around her.
To be continued
Next episode preview
Thiers' attack sweeps away
my family's mansion.
Mom loses her life
crushed by a chandelier.
Moments later, our father follows her.
Nothing makes any sense.
My brother, Victor and I barely escape.
Together with Jean, we decide to go to Paris.
Next time on "Isabelle of Paris":
"I Hate The War That Killed Mother".
Please look forward to it.
anata no egao wa
totemo suteki
Your smile is so nice
soyokaze no you ni
atatakai ai ga aru
It displays so much love,
gentle like a breeze
RANRARA hazunda uta wa
ogawa wo koete
La la la, our song
reaches across the stream
hitori no yama ni
kodama suru
and echoes in the green mountains
hora omoikiri
kasekete yukou
Let's run with all our might
ano hito no iru
oka no ue made
to the top of the hill,
where our friend is