Masterpiece Romantic Theatre
kyou wa totemo ureshii kibun
Today I feel so happy
shiroi hato ga akai hana kureta
A white dove gave me a red flower
nandaka akogare no ano hito to
Somehow I have a feeling that
aesou na yokan ga suru wa
I will be able to meet that person again
RU · · · doushiyou aeru kashira
La la la, will we meet again?
RU · · · doushiyou hazukashii na
La la la, it's a bit embarrassing
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
Fire!
The Rostain family
gives shelter to Count Red.
This is treason.
Their property is hereby confiscated
by the government of Versailles!
What's going on in Thiers' head?
Now you can see
what a rat he is.
Andréa…
Let's untie them and
get them out of here.
Andréa?
Andréa… You're alive?
You're alive, Andréa!
We'll talk about it later.
Mother!
Mom?!
Mother. Mother!
Mother…
I don't believe this.
I don't believe this!
Isabelle
Father · Léon
Mother · Marie
Count Red
Sister · Geneviève
Piano Teacher · Jules
Army Captain · Victor
Young friend · Jean
Screenplay
Shudou Takeshi
Narrator
Inagaki Mihoko
Music
Isao Matsushita
Character Design
Fukuda Kiyomu
Kitajima Nobuyuki
Chief Director
Hayakawa Keiji
Director
Hakata Tan
- Episode 11 -
I Hate The War That Killed Mother
Marie… please smile.
Why, Marie?
Why don't you smile at me?
Please, open your eyes, Marie.
Father…
This is your fault.
You killed Marie.
You ruined the Rostain family.
You killed Marie and
destroyed the Rostain family.
Get out.
Get out of my house.
Everyone out!
It is my house.
Get out of here!
Get out!
Get out.
This is my house. None of you
are welcome here. Out!
Father!
What are you doing?
We have to run!
Get out.
Get out of my house!
Don't come near me. Out!
Leave, now!
– Get out of here…
– Father.
Father?
Get out…
Mr. Andréa,
I can show you the way out.
What? Gaston?
There is a secret passage
that only I and my master knew.
Follow me, please.
Come on, Andréa.
Okay.
Everyone, follow me.
Yes sir.
Isabelle, you too.
Isabelle?!
No! I'm not going anywhere.
I will not leave my father alone.
I'm staying here.
Isabelle, come with us.
I'll decide what to do myself.
Andréa, if you want to defend Paris,
be my guest. But I'm staying here!
I will not leave Mom and Father.
Isabelle!
Go now! Get out of here!
Andréa, you go first.
I'll take care of her.
You're not coming
with us, Victor?
I'm sorry, Andréa, but as you know,
I serve the Versailles government.
Victor…
I still want to believe
in the French army.
I understand.
Talk some sense into Isabelle.
Everyone should
be dead by now.
Isabelle. Are you sure
that you want to stay here?
I don't know.
I don't know…
Why?
Why is this happening?
Victor, explain it to me.
What is this all about?
Hands up, traitor!
Shut up! Do you have any idea
who you're talking to?!
Captain Langlois.
Flames, raging like Léon's anger,
completely consumed the Rostains' estate.
The Rostain family fell.
My master…
My mistress!
A few days later,
at the cemetery in Versailles
a funeral was held
for Léon and Marie Rostain.
Since the Rostain family became
infamous as traitors to the nation,
not many people
came to the funeral.
Look, it's the daughter
of these subversives.
She's one cold piece of work.
She didn't even shed one tear.
What did you say?
Would you like to say it again?!
Ah, I just meant that
she's very strong, of course.
You dog!
Jean, leave him alone.
Please, don't make a scene.
The death of Marie and Léon,
and with it, the fall
of the Rostain family.
Isabelle still found it all
very hard to believe.
However, the cold rain
kept pouring endlessly
as if to remind Isabelle that
the recent events really took place.
Isabelle…
How was the Rostains' funeral?
It must have been
grandiose, no doubt.
What is it that you
want from me, sir?
This morning I received a secret letter
from Prussia. Here, read it.
This… This is…
Soon we will launch
an attack on Paris.
Within a short time we shall clean
this city of the villains who occupy it.
We will attack from this side,
and Prussia will strengthen us.
Because we will approach from the south,
they will be like rats in a trap.
You want to join the enemy and launch a
joint attack on the capital? Are you for real?!
That's right. The people who occupy Paris
raise their fists to their own government.
They pose a threat to every country,
not to mention Prussia.
As such, Prussia is more than
willing to cooperate.
Mr. Thiers, the people of Paris
are French, just like us!
You are wrong. The people
of Versailles are the real French.
Not these knaves.
Captain Langlois, you will
command the main attack.
You want to make me
kill Paris citizens?!
The goal is to win back
the capital and our properties.
Anyone who objects shall not be spared,
not even a woman or a child. Understood?
I have to refuse.
Excuse me?
I fight for France.
I won't put my hand to killing
French brothers and sisters!
Disobedience means betrayal.
I will not betray the people of France,
even if it means having to betray you.
So be it.
Panza!
Arrest Captain Langlois.
For treason, I sentence him
to death by firing squad.
Firing squad? For me?
Versailles doesn't need you
anymore, Captain Langlois.
Panza.
Mr. Thiers, as a soldier
of the French army,
I demand a legal trial
in front of the court martial.
Captain Langlois, our attack
on Paris will begin any minute.
I'm sorry, but we can't afford it.
In addition, I believe that
you might know a bit too much.
Thiers…
Scoundrels like you
are the real enemy of France.
I decide who is the enemy
of France and who is not.
Escort him out!
Yes sir.
Hands off!
I can go alone.
Isabelle?
Jean, I don't want to talk.
Oh, stop it. In such circumstances
it is best to talk as much as possible.
I want to see your smile.
If it makes you laugh,
I can even try to do a handstand.
Please, tell me.
What can I do for you?
Nothing.
So cold! Come on, there must be something.
Please tell me what it is. It can be anything.
Jean, leave me alone.
I am the daughter of a traitor.
My house and property were confiscated.
You deserve more than that.
You'd better stay away from me.
Come on, now.
Who I hang out with is my business.
Why are you so stubborn?
Please, leave me alone.
Fat chance.
What are you going to do now?
I'm going back to Paris.
To Paris?!
Isabelle from Paris goes to defend Paris.
I see that you regained your will to fight.
It's not quite like that.
I just can't stand it here
at Versailles any longer.
Our mansion in Paris
is the only place I have—
Miss!
Miss, terrible news!
Jeanne?
Mr. Victor has been
arrested for treason!
What?!
It's not all.
He's going to be shot tomorrow!
Shot?!
Why?
What will I do without Victor?
No… I don't want
to think about it.
What to do?
I'm sick of it all.
Miss Isabelle,
please remain calm.
Isabelle.
Isabelle, let's meet here
today at midnight.
Okay?
I'll give you a gift,
the best you ever had.
I probably won't be
coming back any time soon.
Marie… Françoise…
Brigitte… Sylvie…
Yvette… Joanne… Delphine…
Ha, I'm quite popular.
But I didn't get even one
from Isabelle.
Isabelle.
We should be living at Versailles now,
a life free of any worries.
What went wrong?
But know that no matter what happens,
or how bad it will be, I will never leave you.
Isabelle, I am going to save
the man you love.
For you, I can do anything.
Just wait.
I always keep my word.
Young master?
My master called for you.
Gotcha. I'll be right there.
Did you call me, Father?
Ah, Jean. Would you like
to eat with us?
Unfortunately, I'm leaving soon.
Oh? Ah yes, you are
probably going to a ball.
Uh… Yes, yes I am.
I understand. Good.
I'm just asking you not to hang out
with that Isabelle of the Rostains.
Do you understand?
Yes, Father.
It will be as you say.
Perfect. You can go now, Jean.
Yes, Father.
Adieu and goodbye.
Victor!
Move away from the window
as far as you can.
Jean? What are you doing here?
We'll talk later. When I count
to ten, I'll blow up the wall.
Ten. Nine. Eight. Seven. Six.
Five. Four. Three. Two. One!
Thank you, Jean.
I have prepared horses for us.
Follow me.
– There!
– They're running away!
They're escaping!
They're climbing the wall!
Three… Two… One!
After them!
Don't let them escape!
Hell, so much more to climb!
Jean, hurry up!
Don't let them escape!
Jean!
Damn! I will show you!
They'll escape us!
After them! Fast!
Yes sir!
Open the gate!
Almost there.
Jean! Did you do all this
all by yourself?
Yes. I can do quite a lot
if I only apply myself.
Thank you.
But why did you do that?
Isabelle needs you.
Isabelle?
You must take her to Paris.
But, Jean…
Honestly, now that I saved you, I wouldn't
mind if you disappeared somewhere.
But Isabelle…
She loves you.
Man, what a mess.
Jean, but you
surely know that…
Doesn't matter. For now, let's get
the hell out of here as far as possible.
Who would've thought that this kid
would beat us to it.
Nice one, kiddo.
All right.
We'd better hurry as well.
The time has come.
It is time to fight for Paris.
We will take our capital back!
Yes sir!
Isabelle.
Jean?
Here's the gift I promised.
Victor?!
Victor!
Isabelle, I'm going to Paris.
I finally understood
what I should really protect.
It is Paris.
It is the heart of France.
I'm going with you.
No. There will be
fighting everywhere.
It's too dangerous. I want you
to stay here and live happily.
No way. I will never
know happiness here.
Victor, please, take me with you.
I'm begging you, Victor.
Take me… Take me
with you to Paris.
Please.
All right.
Thank you.
Hop on.
Okay.
Please, take me too.
I don't have anywhere to go
without the Rostain family.
Jeanne?
You can come with me.
Jean, are you coming
with us, too?
I got used to the gunfire by now.
Versailles got too cramped
for me as well, Isabelle.
Let's go!
Direction – Paris!
Oh my.
"Let's go to Paris."
"Let's take our city back!"
Andréa, Irma, Gaston…
Isabelle, Victor, Jean…
Finally, maid Jeanne.
Over the clatter of horses' hooves, each of them
was thinking about what would await them.
However, Paris was completely
surrounded by Prussian army,
and in Versailles, French troops commanded
by Thiers were already preparing to attack.
The capital of France was stuck
between a rock and a hard place.
Kill. Kill them all!
Death to all who stand against us.
Paris is ours!
To be continued
Next episode preview
Sunday, May 21.
Paris is full of life, and the faces of people
are brightened by long-forgotten smiles.
Between one fight and another, the streets
of the city host lively dance parties.
Fireworks explode against
a clear blue sky.
For the first time in a long time,
the people of Paris enjoy alcohol.
However…
Next time on "Isabelle from Paris":
"Midday Dance Party".
Please look forward to it.
anata no egao wa
totemo suteki
Your smile is so nice
soyokaze no you ni
atatakai ai ga aru
It displays so much love,
gentle like a breeze
RANRARA hazunda uta wa
ogawa wo koete
La la la, our song
reaches across the stream
hitori no yama ni
kodama suru
and echoes in the green mountains
hora omoikiri
kasekete yukou
Let's run with all our might
ano hito no iru
oka no ue made
to the top of the hill,
where our friend is