Masterpiece Romantic Theatre
kyou wa totemo ureshii kibun
Today I feel so happy
shiroi hato ga akai hana kureta
A white dove gave me a red flower
nandaka akogare no ano hito to
Somehow I have a feeling that
aesou na yokan ga suru wa
I will be able to meet that person again
RU · · · doushiyou aeru kashira
La la la, will we meet again?
RU · · · doushiyou hazukashii na
La la la, it's a bit embarrassing
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
moshi sou nara totemo ureshii wa
I'd be so happy if it came true
aa kamisama hayaku oshiete
Oh, God, just let me know
Here is a poem written by Victor Hugo,
author of the excellent "Les Misérables".
On the barricade, amid cobblestones stained
with guilty blood and washed with pure blood,
a boy of twelve was captured
alongside the men.
"Who do we have here?"
"Are you one of those?"
The child proudly replied:
"We are.
We all are like brothers."
"That's good."
"We're going to shoot you."
The boy saw flashes of gunfire.
All his companions
fell against the wall.
He said to the officer:
"May I go take this watch
back to my mum at our house?"
"Ha, you want to escape?"
"I'm going to come back."
"Look at him, so afraid!"
"But I will really return!"
"Begone, rascal!"
The child left.
"He really thought we would believe him?
I can't believe how fast he was running."
But…
The laugh stopped.
Suddenly the pale child,
abruptly reappeared, proud like Viala,
came, leaned against
the wall and said:
"Here I am."
I don't know, child.
I don't know what is good or what is bad;
who is the hero and who is the villain
in the midst of this hurricane
that mixes everything up.
What urged you into this fight?
I don't understand it either,
but I know one thing.
Brave child.
It is this naivety that
makes you the most noble.
It is your pride.
Isabelle
Father · Léon
Mother · Marie
Count Red
Sister · Geneviève
Piano Teacher · Jules
Army Captain · Victor
Young friend · Jean
Screenplay
Shudou Takeshi
Narrator
Inagaki Mihoko
Music
Isao Matsushita
Character Design
Fukuda Kiyomu
Kitajima Nobuyuki
Chief Director
Hayakawa Keiji
Director
Hakata Tan
- Episode 13 -
Departure For a New Life
It is time to eliminate those
who occupy our Paris!
Make no exceptions!
Spare no women or children!
Kill.
Kill!
Kill them all!
Fire!
The Rostains' mansion in Paris had been
transformed into an improvised hospital.
Sister…
Victor is dead.
What!?
G… Geneviève.
Victor loved you
to the very end.
He lived for you.
And he died for you.
I see.
"I see"? That's all?
Victor is dead and
you don't even feel a thing?!
Isabelle. Did you ever think
what you're living for?
Everyone has a purpose in life.
Our father lived for our home.
Our mother lived for us, her children.
I live for Jules,
the love of my life.
For him, I can even die.
One day you will
understand how I feel.
Jules…
I want to live for him.
Not for Victor.
How can you say that? I feel
so sorry for him. You have no idea!
Forgive me, Victor.
Victor…
Jules Francoeur, right?
What a load of garbage. That is
the worst hooey I have read in my life.
We know very well that you are one
of the leaders of the Paris Commune.
If so, you will do whatever
you want with me, anyway.
I am ready for anything.
Who would have thought you could
find first-class wine in such a dump.
How about a drink,
Mr. Francoeur?
Who knows, maybe you
could get out of here alive.
It all depends on whether you tell us
where you have built the barricades.
Do you really not get it?
I live for Paris and I shall die for Paris.
Oh, is that right?
Shoot him!
Defend Paris!
Down with the Versailles' dogs!
The citizens of Paris fought
to the best of their ability.
Women and children
were picking up heavy rifles
trying to defend their homes.
But for the army of Versailles
that was used to fighting,
the people of Paris
posed no threat.
Once charming familiar
walkways ran red with blood.
Innocent citizens one
after another fell without life.
They've already taken
about half of the city.
Soon they'll be here as well.
I'll stay here, no matter what.
It's suicide. They don't take prisoners,
not even women or children.
They're like a bunch
of bloodthirsty murderers.
But so many people
can't move from here.
I can't just leave them.
I understand.
Heaven help you.
I can't die.
I carry Jules' child.
Be careful.
Sister…
Don't worry about me.
As I told you, I live and will live for Jules.
Go on, shoot me!
My voice is the voice
of all the people!
Defend Paris!
Long live the people of Paris!
Fire!
Geneviève…
What are you looking for? This is a hospital
and these people are wounded. Please leave.
Wounded or not,
they are enemy.
Our mission is
to eliminate our enemies.
Burn this place down.
Wait.
I cannot let you do that.
My lady!
Why?!
How could you… How could you
shoot the young lady?!
My lady, stay with us!
Get her out of here!
Gaston…
What about my child?
My lady, when
I carried you here…
I am so sorry, Gaston.
It's all right.
Thank you for everything
you did for me.
My lady…
My lady.
Soon this place will be
swarming with soldiers.
Jean, take Isabelle with you
and get away from here.
Okay, but where to?
Here.
Père Lachaise Cemetery.
Our people are still fighting there
and it should be relatively safe.
But that place has the most
Prussian troops.
Prussia, unlike Thiers, does not
murder women and children.
Isabelle, Jean.
At least the two of you should survive.
What about you?
I have one more thing to do.
I can't let this scum Thiers to continue
slaughtering us with impunity, even if I die.
Andréa, don't be reckless.
Isabelle.
Andréa?
Live on, Isabelle. Now go!
But…
Go!
Finally we can come
back here safely.
What do you say? Our troops have taken back
the city, our lands and our properties.
What city?
It's a pile of rubble.
Can we really say that
we've got something back?
Some losses are
unavoidable, of course.
What matters is that
Paris is ours again.
Who's there?!
Andréa?!
– What are you doing?!
– Time to meet your maker, Thiers!
Step aside!
It's not you I'm after!
Mr. Thiers, please let me go!
Come on! Step aside!
Shoot! Shoot him!
To hell with you, Thiers!
Irma.
Are you all right, Mr. Thiers?
Hm?
I'm fine.
Shame that it ended up this way.
No battle is without its losses.
I have an order for you. Make sure
this will never happen again.
Yes sir.
By the way, how are things?
Our army has already
taken over most of the city.
Only a handful of rebels remain
at the Père Lachaise Cemetery.
Perfect. Get rid of them all.
Do not spare women
and children. Understood?
Yes sir.
Let's go.
Killing women and children?
We have already practically won.
In all this battle one Frenchman
stood up against another.
What was this all about?
Everyone… Everyone is dead.
What for?
What were they actually trying to protect?
What did they devote their lives to?
I don't know.
I don't understand it myself.
However, I know that since that day
we saw each other at the ball
only half a year has elapsed, and as I live
for sixteen years, for these few months
I felt the most alive,
more than ever.
Over the past six months, more happened
than during my whole life.
You have to admit, however,
that it was quite crazy.
Crazy or not, we gave our best.
"We gave our best"?
You embarrass me, my dear.
Yes. This is probably what life is about. But
there is one difference between me and Jules.
I would never die
for Paris. No way.
I want to live. For myself…
And for you, Isabelle.
Jean…
You should live as well.
Let's screw this city and run wild
somewhere far away from this mess.
Yes. That's a good idea.
Doing your best, huh?
Such heavy stuff
gets me tired real quick.
Get down, Isabelle!
Jean?!
It's so warm…
Isabelle… I think I called it
when I talked about running wild.
No.
Stop kidding around, Jean.
You alone can't die.
It's not possible!
Why?
Everyone else died.
Why should I be an exception?
Because…
You were always with me.
You've always done
so much for me…
You've done so much for me…
Jean!
Hey, Isabelle, did you grow
to like me a little bit?
To like you? I love you, Jean.
You… You were always with me.
What a bad liar.
You don't have to do that.
Adieu.
Jean…
No. This is not possible.
Hey, Jean!
Jean… Jean!
Jean…
Jean!
Who…
Who was it?!
Which one of you
killed Jean, dogs?!
Who was it?!
Who, I'm asking?!
Who?!
Who's there?
A girl?
Even if she's a kid,
we have to shoot her.
No.
But, Captain…
The battle is over.
I'm sick of murdering.
Young lady.
Was that your boyfriend?
Who the hell are you?
I am the one who
commanded this battle.
– What are you doing?!
– Don't. All good.
Young lady.
Go and live wherever you like.
Wait.
Can i ask you your name?
No?
I see.
Oh, I'll tell you.
Isabelle. From Paris.
I am Isabelle from Paris.
I…
Live.
The end
Announcement
Good morning!
On the next episode, we start with
"Jeanie with the Light Brown Hair".
It's me, the titular Jeanie.
Nice to meet you!
North America, 1860.
Our series is a love story
set in the city of Agata, Virginia.
It all starts with the initials "LJ"
and a certain melody.
"Jeanie with the Light Brown Hair",
episode 1: "My first love". See you soon!
anata no egao wa
totemo suteki
Your smile is so nice
soyokaze no you ni
atatakai ai ga aru
It displays so much love,
gentle like a breeze
RANRARA hazunda uta wa
ogawa wo koete
La la la, our song
reaches across the stream
hitori no yama ni
kodama suru
and echoes in the green mountains
hora omoikiri
kasekete yukou
Let's run with all our might
ano hito no iru
oka no ue made
to the top of the hill,
where our friend is