Will you come to the
Christmas party this year?
I have been inviting you every year,
but you have never wanted to come.
You hate me, you hate parties, you hate
the month of December and you hate Christmas.
You hate too many things to count.
I'd like you to come
to the Christmas party.
I will try my upmost
to make this party fun.
To you, who doesn't like fun things.
A Christmas in January
It's the first snow, huh…
Snow is so beautiful.
Speaking of snow, don't you think
it resembles a woman in a way?
It seems so calm, then suddenly it can
become so violent that it gets out of hand.
You lose yourself in its sound and at some point
you become unable to move and become at its mercy.
It's painful…
Yes.
Fujioka-kun, I…
I'm in so much pain.
Yeah.
Heartbreaks are so painful.
Come on, cheer up.
I don't want to see you sink.
Usually you'd jump around
and say "wow, now we can ski".
This time I can't.
I really don't feel like I can
jump around today, Fujioka-kun.
I can see that.
You're right. Sorry.
You're so nice.
You always comfort me.
You're not interested in girls.
Why do I have to
like women so much?
Fujioka, I can always
tell you everything.
What a cute little girl.
I wonder if she
misunderstands this scene?
Let's smile a little.
Now she certainly misunderstands it.
Great.
Oh, Bouya-kun.
Let's go back to work.
Look, someone is coming.
So painful. So painful…
Snow is so beautiful.
It's pale like a woman.
It's a cold color.
I don't like it.
They fit you very well.
They go well with your clothes.
They may be a bit expensive,
but will last a long time.
Do you need another size?
I'm not convinced.
Are you sure?
Yes. I'm not convinced.
Take them off.
That pair over there might be better.
I'd like to try them on.
Sure, I'll bring your size.
But those red boots
looked so good on her…
These are also pretty.
They fit you very well.
These do not convince me either.
Look, the part here is pinching me.
It is?
Yes.
Ah, those pink boots over there!
Can I try them on?
– They look great—
– Take them off.
Huh?
Hey, I'd like to try these yellow boots.
Bring me my size.
Oh, and also these brown ones.
Oh, and these, too.
Poor Fujioka-kun.
Business is business.
Forget about those.
I'll try these.
What?
Damn, she's doing it on purpose.
Can you show me these?
Hey, show me these
in different color.
Oh, these look interesting.
Show me them, too.
Ah… I think I want to try
the previous pair again.
And those too!
She's tried so many.
She has to like at least one pair.
I'm not convinced.
I'm going.
Thank you, come again.
I heard pranks like that
are a new fad among schoolgirls.
That's why I hate children.
They bully people like that
without any sense of remorse.
They hurt adults like it's nothing.
Knowing no fear.
Having no responsibilities.
Carefree brats.
Hey.
Oh.
Can I keep these?
In the end, I liked these the most.
I've decided on these.
Can you bring my size?
Business is business.
Here it is.
Miss…
I'm very sorry, but we don't
have your size anymore.
We don't usually have
much of the small sizes.
You were a little bit too late.
Doesn't matter.
It's not like I wanted them,
no matter what.
Besides, this is not the only
shoe store in the area.
I almost feel sorry for her.
No, no. I can't forget
how she played me.
Stupid kid.
That was a little too cruel.
You think so, too?
I was referring to you, Junshou.
I know.
I feel sorry for her
for having left without a pair.
You're right.
In the end I felt the same way.
Maybe you saw your old self in her.
Perhaps that's why you got angry.
You were quite mischievous yourself
when you were little, Junshou.
Yeah.
I was an unruly, bad kid.
Sorry, sorry.
Don't get depressed.
I won't say it anymore.
Snow… I wonder if it piles up.
Bouya-kun, you said I'm not interested
in women, but that's not true.
What I want to say is…
We've been together since we were little
and I've never noticed anyone else.
But she doesn't seem to have noticed.
I wonder when
someone will move in.
As a matter of fact, Junshou, it seems
that there is someone living there already.
But there are no signs of anyone yet.
It's an empty house.
No.
Yesterday I saw that
the light was on.
It could be a thief.
Huh?
Dad, you're making me worry.
No, if something happens,
I'll call the police immediately.
Telephone number
is enough for me.
Which means you want me
to go take a look, right?
It's a nice house.
A pink roof and white walls.
Wow, it's not locked?
It's too nice.
Looks like the owner
was a wealthy one.
But there's no furniture.
I knew it. Not a soul.
Hm?
Who are you?
Huh?
Do you want something?
I-I'm from the temple next door.
Have you come to give me
an amulet or something?
N-No. We thought we saw someone,
and thought it might be a thief.
I moved in here three days ago.
I-I see. I apologize.
I've entered without permission.
How cold…
There's no stove.
Also, she looks like she's still a child.
Can this even be called moving in?
A shoe store clerk during the day, a thief
during the night. And maybe a homosexual?
Ah!
Y-You see, my work at the
shoe store is a part-time job.
There was no sign of anyone moving in
and we saw someone's presence here,
I thought it would be terrible
if there was fire.
Funny how you want to
explain everything at once.
I'm neither a thief nor a homosexual.
Do you want me to believe you?
What about you?
Are you really from this family?
You know, you may look nice when you smile,
but you're a pretty bad person, aren't you?
You actually did have those red boots
in my size, didn't you?
I apologize for that.
But you remember
what happened before, right?
Of course.
Yes, I've been pretty bad, too.
But you're no better.
If you were a good person,
you wouldn't have retaliated.
You wouldn't have done
something like that.
You're not nice at all,
and yet you pretend you are.
Go away and become
a better person.
Oh!
It's a pity there's nothing here
for you to steal, Mr. Thief.
What a nasty girl.
You're not nice at all.
I don't have to worry
about what that girl says to me.
I used to hear
that stuff a lot in the past.
Even Seiko told me
that I was a really mean boy.
I hate bullies like you, Junshou!
I hate you!
Those words hurt me,
but I can't tell Seiko how it felt.
Junshou, do you have a moment?
Our new neighbor who just moved in
has come to greet us.
She says you left
something yesterday.
I left something?
So the scarf wasn't yours.
If it's not yours, it must be his.
So that's how it was.
I'm sorry.
I'm leaving now.
Ah, you can stay a little longer.
I just came to make sure.
My father is preparing tea.
What's your name?
Tateno Mizuki.
And you're Fujioka Junshou, right?
You're going to become
a monk, aren't you?
No, this temple will go
to my little brother.
He's at the University
of Tokyo now, though.
Oh, it should be you.
It'd be perfect. The shape of your head is just right
and in a few years you'll make a great baldie.
You seem to have fun.
Here, have some tea.
Thanks.
It must be hard to live
alone in that house.
I heard your father was admitted to the hospital
due to an illness and you're all alone now.
She doesn't have a mother?
I like being alone, and I play outside
in the daytime anyway.
I was living in a college dorm until now,
but now I feel more free.
College?
But she doesn't look older
than a high school student.
I'm already in the fourth grade.
I'm graduating this spring anyway.
This fella here is still in college, too.
You're in third grade, right?
You're younger than me.
What a surprise.
Really?
You had to retake the year once,
so that makes you the same age.
She's pretty cute.
She's not cute at all.
She likes to do mischief,
but doesn't like when it's made to her.
That's pretty selfish.
She's selfish, but in a cute way.
She's just being rebellious
and that's it.
Doesn't she remind you
of someone?
Seiko.
Hm?
You're 24 years old
already, aren't you?
Why don't you get married?
I'm still 24 years old.
Why? Because there's
no one around.
What about you, Junshou?
Why don't you get a girlfriend?
Uh?
Why?
Do you like someone?
You'd make a good couple
with some cute girl.
See if you can find her soon.
I don't care if she's cute.
My aunt…
My aunt has found
someone recently.
She's done it
through matchmaking.
To tell you the truth,
I'm even more selfish.
I can't talk to you openly.
I don't want to take part
in matchmaking.
Junshou.
Junshou, I want you to stop me.
The truth is… that I don't really want
you to find any cute girls.
I love you.
I've loved you for a long time.
Engagement?! With Seiko-san?
About time, dude!
We're throwing
a party tomorrow. Come.
But man, I wondered
how long you'd stay like this.
Pretending the two of you
to be just friends.
Anyway, congratulations.
Now hurry up and
make plenty of kids.
T-Thank you…
Alright then, let's get back to work.
Give me a pair of red boots.
I know you have some.
The pair from the other day.
The one you told me
you had just sold.
It was size 22, right?
Please wait a minute.
What a direct girl.
Sorry for making you wait.
Here it is.
I've changed my mind.
I don't want them anymore.
Is it payback for my payback?
He's not following me.
I made him angry. I thought
he was going to follow me.
No one's ever followed me.
Everybody's been tired of me.
At some point it started to be like this.
"Will you come to the
Christmas party this year?"
You're the only person
who's ever loved me.
And you're a fool.
Cheers!
Congratulations!
When's the wedding?
After I graduate.
I still have one year to go.
Are you planning on making
Seiko-san wait for so long?
It's okay, I don't mind waiting.
I've been waiting a long time for him,
a year or two won't make a difference.
With all the snow outside,
it's pretty hot in here.
You got that right.
Now that I think about it,
my life's been a string of heartbreaks.
And now even you're
taken away from me.
Hey, your neighbor's house
is pretty nice, don't you think?
It looks like straight
from an illustration.
I wonder if she's there.
During the day, I'm playing outside.
I just come back at night.
I wonder if she has any friends?
Given the way she is,
I don't think she's seeing anyone.
I'm pretty sure that she's sitting all alone
in the dark in that cold, empty house.
She might be home.
Shall we invite her?
I guess she's not here, after all.
Good afternoon.
If you happen to have time,
would you like to come to my house?
We're having a party.
Why don't you come?
There are a lot of people
from around here.
If they knew such a cute girl lived nearby,
they'd definitely want to meet you.
Are you coming?
I'll get my coat.
Thank you.
How pretty!
To think you were so close
to someone so beautiful!
Are you really a college student?
I'm Hibino, the baker
from the Second Street.
I'm still single.
Pleased to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Here.
Alright, let's get this party started!
Cheers!
I'll sing a love song for you.
Do you want some juice?
No need for that.
She's awfully quiet today.
You know…
Hm?
I hate this kind of thing.
An engagement party?
You're too ridiculous.
What?
I'm going.
Will you walk me back?
No.
Is it payback for my payback
for your payback?
Stop saying garbage.
I invited you here because I thought
you'd feel lonely, being alone in that house.
If you didn't want to come,
you could've just said so.
I'm leaving.
Hold on.
Junshou, I'm going with her.
She's living next door.
She can go back by herself.
But…
I must look like a little kid
to you, right?
Especially when
I'm with more people.
No, you didn't like one to me at all.
You know, when the year begins,
I'll be moving in to the temple.
We've yet to marry, but we've decided
to live together before that.
We'll look for a flat
once he graduates.
This means we'll be
neighbors for a while.
Let's be friends, okay?
You can't get married.
You can't get married!
I won't let you!
I wonder if I did anything
to make her hold such a grudge?
It's me that she's holding
a grudge against.
Huh?
Never mind.
Look, it's already piled up so much.
And it's not even Christmas yet.
Let's spend Christmas Day
together this year.
Let's forget about our
bad-mannered neighbor.
Christmas…
That's wonderful.
Christmas this year will be
different from previous ones.
For the first time,
it'll be this wonderful.
What do you think?
I feel the same way.
I hate snow.
I hate when it's falling like this.
When it's like this…
Everything ends up
being totally white.
Everything seems to be going away.
How do you like these ornaments?
They look good.
I thought they were much bigger
when I was a kid.
But even though it's been more
than ten years, they're still fine.
They remind me of my mother.
I see.
They were there when she was alive.
Do you know what
that girl's doing now?
She must be doing something,
because we haven't seen her again.
Tomorrow is Christmas Day.
Maybe she'll be with her family.
Somehow it reminds me of her.
Looks like she's not here.
Not that I needed
to come to check on her.
Why?
Why did I get the impression
that she'd be inside, alone in the dark?
Careless as usual.
The Oak and the Pleasant Wind
Tateno Ken'ichi
Seiko!
W-What happened?
Seiko, could you prepare a futon?!
And call a doctor!
She almost got pneumonia.
It's no wonder.
It's winter and that house
doesn't even have a stove.
That's why…
That's why I can't say
I didn't see it coming.
I don't know what this girl's thinking.
Sleeping like that on a cold floor.
Junshou, come here for a minute.
They just called from the hospital.
From the hospital?
It seems her father has passed away.
He's dead?!
What do we do?
Should we wake her up?
No.
Let's tell her after
the fever goes down a little.
She's become completely alone.
It's amazing.
The fever went down
to 38°C overnight.
Where's my coat?
You shouldn't be up yet.
You should rest for a little longer.
I have to go see my father.
I have to see if it's his face, at least.
Huh?
I could hear you
from where you were talking.
I'm sorry.
Can you call a taxi for me?
Wait a minute.
Even if it's gone down a bit,
you're still running a fever of 38°C.
I hate being here.
Ah!
Okay, I'll call a cab.
But first, you have to eat something.
I'm not hungry.
It's disgusting.
I'm sorry. I made it.
I don't think it's bad, though.
Soups are my specialty.
But it is bad.
I hate porridge.
I especially hate plums.
If you don't want to eat hospital food,
at least put a stove in that house.
I hate stoves.
I hate warmth
and I hate Christmas.
Today is Christmas Day.
Even I have someone who loves me.
I'm going to live with that person.
He's been taking care
of me for many years.
He used to say I look very much
like his late daughter.
See? Even if I don't have my father,
I've got my next move figured out.
There's nothing to worry about.
So don't feel sorry for me.
I already knew.
I knew my father wouldn't live long.
That's why there's no stove
or furniture in that house.
Then what's that house for?
I don't know.
It was something
my father had built.
That's all.
I'll call a taxi myself.
"That's all"?
But…
Hey, tell me something.
How did you confess
your feelings to Seiko-san?
How did you say it?
How do you tell a woman
that you love her?
Tell me.
I just told her "I love you".
And what did she say?
What did Seiko-san say to you?
"I love you".
That's what she told you, isn't it?
How boring.
So simple.
Lovers' conversations are so stupid.
If you found someone
that you could love…
I'll never find someone to love.
Good bye.
Hold on. Do you want me
to go with you?
I'll be fine by myself.
I feel strange.
She's lost her father while we were decorating
the Christmas tree and eating a cake.
There's nothing we can do.
She has to feel lonely.
And she still has a fever.
Will she be all right?
You're right.
I love you.
Junshou.
Come with me for a bit.
In our temple?
Yes.
They just called us.
When they told me, I was surprised,
but it seems that I knew the father of that girl.
He was a writer
named Tateno Ken'ichi.
Tateno Ken'ichi?
The Oak and the Pleasant Wind
Tateno Ken'ichi
Oh, I think we have
one of his books, too.
He wrote nice stories
and I liked them a lot.
But rumor has it he was
a terrible alcoholic.
The light is on.
There are a lot of parked cars.
Must be the family.
Still.
In there, that girl…
She's probably sitting all alone.
Thank you for coming in this cold.
Excuse me, where's Mizuki-san?
She still has a fever.
She's taking a rest at our house.
Of course she has,
when she's so reckless.
That's your specialty,
the plum soup?
Good. I'll take it to Mizuki-san.
I'm sorry.
I have to help my father, so…
It's what she needs now.
Even if she complains,
make her eat it.
Fine, fine.
Seiko's late.
Maybe they're talking?
Seiko!
No way…
I won't let you!
It can't be!
Seiko!
Junshou!
Are you okay?
I suddenly saw fire
and I didn't know what to do.
What about her?
She's still inside.
The fire came from the kitchen.
I think she's there.
Junshou!
I…
Quick! Come here!
What are you doing!? Hurry!
But you're angry, aren't you?
You are, aren't you?
I'm not.
How could I be in this situation?
Don't worry and come here.
Come on, quick.
I…
She showed me her father's book,
then went crazy… Then the fire started.
Dad.
Dad…
Dad. Dad. Dad…
I was waiting for him, all alone.
I've been waiting for him
all this time, in this house.
This house.
All because of this house.
Dad!
The same thing happened
with you a long time ago.
You played with fire and
half of the temple went up in smoke.
At that time, you were crying
and calling for you mother, just like her.
I thought I'd burn all the letters.
The letters from my dad.
I've burned them all.
Come on in.
Are you going to do
something reckless again?
You must stay in bed.
I'm giving you that house.
What?
I don't need it anymore.
Go and live with Seiko-san
there one day.
You know, Christmas Day…
Christmas Day is my birthday.
Every year we were holding
a party with Mom,
and we were waiting
for Dad to come back.
Today… Today he ought
to come back, too.
Christmas Day is my birthday,
so it had to be today.
And yet, he…
He always came home in a bad mood
and tore the party apart.
My mom died without having fun
on Christmas Day even once.
That's why I hate Dad the most.
I hate December. I hate Christmas.
I hate my birthday!
If I didn't like anything
and never expected anything,
no one would betray me either.
But you were hoping your father
would come back, right?
You were waiting
for him in that house.
Because he had to build that house
all of the sudden. That old fool.
Long ago, I saw a house on a postcard
and said I'd like to live in it some day.
He remembered that.
I'll never grow up.
I'll always stay like this.
I've always felt like a little girl.
I can never mature.
But I'm a nasty child, not nice at all,
so no one will ever want me.
I used to be one bad kid, too.
I behaved badly, I wasn't honest,
I was always mischievous.
I was getting my parents
and friends in trouble all the time.
I'm adopted.
But, you know, even I wound up
being wanted by someone.
But I…
You hate me, don't you?!
I hate myself, too.
Deep down, I know that
I'm a selfish and cold person.
That's not true.
As a child, all I had heard was
my father's reprimands and yelling.
How can I speak gentle words?
Teach me.
What should I do?
How can I become a kind person?
How should I live my life now?
Tell me.
I'd like to stay that way.
After that, she got into the car with the man
who had adopted her and they drove off somewhere.
The year has started long ago.
You still haven't taken
the decorations off?
Where are you taking it?
Ah, someplace.
I hate Christmas.
I hate my birthday.
I hate December.
It's possible that I look
a little like that girl's father.
Merry… Christmas.
It was nothing special to me.
She wasn't in this house.
She wasn't in this dark room anymore.
Is she living with her relatives now?
Or maybe she's sitting alone somewhere?
I know.
I'm sure she's alone somewhere.
She's turned off the lights in her room,
and she's watching the snow
from a window somewhere.
Hey, Bouya.
Hm?
You said something the other day
when I looked at the snow.
About the snow being like a woman.
What?
Didn't you say anything like that?
It's possible.
I must've forgotten
if I said it only once.
By the way, Seiko-san
will be moving in soon, right?
Yes.
That girl showed up
and vanished like snow.
It's as if the bond we had developed
during that period was a gift from Santa Claus.
A Santa Claus who hates
Christmas, of course.