It's been stolen!
A picture more valuable than my life!
It's Saint Tail!
Detective Asuka!
Okay!
I'll definitely get some evidence
on you today, Saint Tail!
Ohh! Not the painting that I stole!
What's that?
Oops. Nothing.
Detective Asuka!
This picture...
It's the painting "Evening Primrose",
stolen from the city museum last week!
Ah. It's... oh no!
Detective!
This is also a missing painting,
stolen two months ago.
Well! What is this all about?!
Shall we hear your explanation?!
Chance!
Ouch!
Darn!
Good morning!
Good morning Meimi!
Good morning.
Hey! Have you heard?
She appeared again last night!
Yes, she did, she did!
This time it was a mansion in Ward 16.
Meimi, did you hear about it?
You're talking as if
a strange ghost appeared.
Are you talking about Saint Tail?
Her ponytail flutters in the wind
as she steals only from the bad.
Because of her classy figure
people call her Saint Tail.
But no one knows her true identity.
Her tactful capers
have never failed yet.
She's as lightfooted as the wind.
She's just wonderful!
And just what's so
wonderful about her?
Saint Tail or Sacred Tail,
whichever it is...
A thief is a thief!
How sickening, to call her "wonderful".
But I bet you'd like to meet her, too,
Asuka, Jr.!
No way! Saint Tail is a mature lady!
She wouldn't even look at you!
Isn't that right?
Shut up! A pest like her!
This is what she looks like!
What did you say?!
You know what kind
of person Saint Tail is?!
These are her crimes for
just the past month...
Seven jewel robberies and
two stolen paintings, ten thefts total.
My suspicion is that it's all
because of Saint Tail.
That's odd... I don't remember
taking any jewels...
What's that?
Anyhow, Detective Asuka keeps
slipping up again and again!
How can we believe
anything his son says?
Don't lump me in with my father!
I'll be the one who catches Saint Tail!
Saint Tail wouldn't be so cool
if somebody like you could catch her!
What was that?!
What about it?
Don't stop me Siera!
I'm not Seira!
Seira...
Miss Haneoka, Mr. Asuka!
The two of you just stay right there!
Yes...
Excuse me, do you have a moment?
Certainly.
Sister-in-training Seira.
Coldhearted Seira.
Coldhearted is much too cruel.
It is all the teachings of our Lord.
You passed a girl on your way in?
Her name is Saori.
She came to ask God for help.
Such a young girl?
Her grandfather is a jewelry appraiser.
One day, he was brought two sapphires.
One of them was the "Blue Meteorite",
a very unique and expensive gem.
As a precaution against theft
the owners had made a fake duplicate.
But the duplicate was so well made,
that the gems got mixed up.
They couldn't tell which
was the real "Blue Meteorite".
That's why the dealer, Umido,
asked her grandfather for the appraisal.
How does God
fit into a situation like that?!
That's not the problem.
Now the grandfather is asking for help.
What do you mean?
He was taken in by the gem's beauty.
He lied to Umido, telling him that
the fake gem was the real one.
Then he bought the other gem,
the real one, at a cheap price.
That's fraud. He's a thief.
Anyone can make a mistake.
But a good human being regrets what
he's done and tries to correct it.
And today, we're going to be
of assistance with that.
Assistance?
Thinking it was real, Umido sold the
fake "Blue Meteorite" to a rich woman.
So what are we going to do?
How do you think we should go
about making things right?
Well, I think switching the real gem
that Saori's grandfather has...
with the fake gem that was sold
should do the job.
Exactly.
The real gem?!
It's time for you to make
your appearance, Saint Tail!
I'm home!
Welcome home, Meimi.
Dinner will be soon.
How's that! It's my new magic trick!
Beautiful, isn't it?
Papa, you've got the hands of a wizard.
I love it! The next show will be a hit.
The two of you are making
a mess of the room again!
What's wrong with it? Meimi, you're
going to take after me, aren't you?
Who decided that? Meimi's going to take
after her mother, aren't you Meimi?
Ah... sure.
You've gotta be joking!
Your previous occupation was...
You're the one that took
one look at me and fell in love.
I'm getting out of here.
It's time to get to work.
I've got to help people in trouble.
Oh Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
May the blessings of God be with us.
This must be where
she keeps the safe.
That's strange... why is it open?
What?
It's been stolen!
The "Blue Meteorite"!
What happened?
It's a thief!
Better get out of here!
Kaido?
Did it go well?
Yes.
This is great.
We steal back the gems that we sell
and then resell them to another sucker.
There are no rules in making money.
That's terrible!
Absolutely unforgivable!
Meimi... you can't! It's dangerous.
And I don't have information on Kaido.
Don't worry, nothing's impossible
for St. Tail! I'll get through somehow!
First, let's check out
the houses of the wealthy.
Then overlap that with the locations
of unsolved crimes for the past month.
So her next victim is...
Right here!
Saint Tail!
I won't let you get away this time!
The alarm went off,
so we came over to check it out.
What's happened, Mr. Kaido?
Actually, a kid got himself caught
in our alarm system.
At this hour? Who's the little brat?
Hey! Let me go!
Son?!
Dad!
Detective Asuka's son, is it?
Well, how rude of me. Let him go!
Yes.
Hey, son, what are you doing here?
Saint Tail is coming here!
What?
In the past month, this is the only place
that hasn't been hit by a theft. So...
Leave this to the police!
You can't catch Saint Tail,
so I'm doing it for you!
I've got other things to do
than chase Saint Tail.
I'm very sorry for all the trouble.
I'd like to meet this Saint Tail, myself.
I hear she's a great thief.
It's Saint Tail!
What?!
It's showtime!
What happened to the lights?
They won't turn on!
Open the windows!
Yes, sir!
Saint Tail?
What the...?!
What's this?
I'll just exchange the fake
one for the real one.
May the blessings of God be with us.
So, that's what this was all about.
Asuka Jr. ...
What are you doing?
Well, how ingenious you are.
Stealing back the gems that you sell!
How dare you call me a thief!
What evidence do you have?
The evidence are these jewels,
Mr. Kaido!
These are all the jewels that
were stolen in the past month.
Saint Tail...
She always has a
valid reason for her capers.
Saint Tail is not a crook!
That man...
Mr. Kaido, the real crook is...
You!
You won't be rattling on for long!
Saint Tail, you're not
getting away either!
Now I've got you!
Darn it!
Oh, no!
Don't look at me!
Saint Tail, don't be a coward!
Come down here!
Wait! Challenge me!
At least send me a warning
the next time you plan to appear!
Don't forget to do that!
That was a bit fun.
Detective Asuka!
These are...
What is it?
Aren't these all the stolen jewels?
Saint Tail... She seems to be
about the same age as me.
I touched her.
Take care of your grandfather.
I present this award of appreciation
for the good deed you've performed.
Thank you.
And this one request, would you help us
in the arrest of Saint Tail?
This is an official
investigation badge.
Showing this will get
you in anywhere.
We definitely want to utilize your
expertise and knowledge...
in the Saint Tail case.
Of course, with the cooperation
of the police!
Yes, sir!
Today, Saori came to church
to express her thanks to God.
They returned the jewel to its owner.
I guess that's the end of the case.
Then I'll be going.
See you tomorrow!
Bye bye!
Oh, it's you.
I heard you got an award.
Yep! And next time,
I'm gonna get that Saint Tail.
Well, anyway...
hang in there!
Sure. Just watch me.