Asuka Jr.
Let's walk home together!
Sure!
We heard the news!
You've been asked by the Mayor...
to help arrest that
phantom thief, Saint Tail!
Is it true?
Yup, it sure is!
Wow! That's great!
They say you did great
on the last case!
How you protected the
jewels from Saint Tail!
It was all over the papers!
I read that article, too.
It said, "He protected the Blue
Meteorite from Saint Tail...
and helped in the arrest of Umido."
That's how it went?
Yup, that's how it went.
But you let Saint Tail get away,
didn't you?
That's why I've been
asked to catch her.
I'm the only one who's
seen her up close.
See! This is my official permit!
What is it?
It's the badge I gotfrom the Mayor.
All I have to do is show this
and I can get in to investigate.
Hey, that's really something.
Does your dad know?
He got himself all worked up over it.
He wants me to get the job done,
do or die.
Isn't that Saint Tail's first failure?
Failure?
And her nemesis is Asuka Jr.
I've got to hand it to you,
you're great!
It's true, it's true.
Ain't it fabulous?
Ah, it's nothing.
You've got it all wrong!
Huh?
I haven't failed!
Whose voice was that?
Beats me.
Oh, Meimi,
don't let it bother you!
I've never failed once!
I know, I know.
Why don't you drop by the
church for a while?
I haven't failed!
He's really asking for it!
As if a guy like that
could catch me!
My, you're fired up,
aren't you Meimi?
That's great!
Huh?
Your mission this time is...
This tiara.
It's called Electra.
Electra?
Named for the star
in the Subaru constellation.
Also known as "the missing one".
It was stolen from someone by Egami,
who lives on 7th avenue.
Let's return it to
its rightful owner.
Wait a minute!
What?
This wouldn't be a good time.
You heard, didn't you?
Asuka Jr. received a badge from the
Mayor, granting investigation power.
He's all wound up
and ready to leap into action.
Meimi, you're not afraid of
Asuka Jr., are you?
What?
If that's so, it can't be helped.
Let's forget about this caper.
Wait a minute!
You're kidding, aren't you?
Let's do it!
You just leave it to me!
I'm not afraid of a bumbling
detective like him at all!
I'm leaving!
Saint Tail... Isn't she wonderful?
She's exactly like me
when I was young.
Aww shoot...
That's strange.
What's the matter, Papa?
The balloons...
where have I put them?
Balloons?
The ones I use for my magic.
Aren't they supposed to
be in your trunk?
Yes, but they're not there!
Only the balloons have disappeared.
Papa, are you sure they're missing?
Remember what happened
the other day.
You put two socks on one foot and...
went around saying
"Where's my other sock?!"
Oh, don't bring that up.
Anyway, it's strange.
Hey! What's that?
Asuka! Up in the sky!
Huh?
What's that?
"I'll be picking up the Electra
tonight - Saint Tail."
It's a note from Saint Tail!
Hey, it's a challenge! What class!
You're kidding!
This is fantastic!
She's the phantom, alright!
She's got real guts!
I'll be ready for you, Saint Tail!
Meimi? Just what is this
all about exactly?
Hey have you heard? Saint Tail
sent Asuka Jr. a challenge!
Don't you think that's strange?
What is?
Why do you think she told Asuka Jr.?
It does seem too good to be true.
Doesn't it?
Maybe Saint Tail and Asuka Jr. are...
No doubt!
The two of them are in this together!
So...
Saint Tail has sent a challenge.
I won 't let anyone get
my tiara, Electra!
Sir, there is a rumor going around...
Yes, what is it?
What! Saint Tail and Asuka Jr.
are working together?!
Excuse me.
You're Mr. Egami, the tiara's owner,
aren't you?
And you are?
The Mayor asked me to assist in
the Saint Tail investigation.
My name is Asuka.
Oh, so you're Asuka Jr.
I've been waiting for you.
Excuse me.
I leave all security in your hands.
Yes, sir! I understand.
Please catch Saint Tail.
No matter what the rumors may say...
I trust you.
Rumors? What are you talking about?
You don't know?
There's great doubt
about you right now!
It's suspected that you
are Saint Tail's accomplice!
What did you say?
She sent you a note, didn't she?
Wait, please!
Of course.
I'm sure it's all just rumors.
For the sake of clearing your name,
please protect my Electra.
Of course!
Who'd want to work with
that girl, anyway?
Sir?
Everything is ready.
The tiara is in place.
Everything has gone well.
The fool trusted me completely.
I'd never be tricked
by a brat like that!
I'll set them both up and turn him in
to the police along with Saint Tail!
By the way, Mr. Egami,
where is Electra right now?
The truth is, hearing about the
challenge made me nervous.
I couldn't leave it in the mansion,
so I've hidden it in a safe place.
You're really a worrier, aren't you?
So, where did you hide it?
Over there!
At the top of that clock tower.
Why hide it in such a difficult place?!
Where exactly in the
clock tower is it?
On the face of the clock.
Behind the hour hand.
What!
On the face of the clock,
behind the hour hand?
That's a tough place to get it from.
Actually, I know for sure he's lying.
The tiara is really behind
the minute hand.
How did you get information like that?
Egami is trying to frame Asuka Jr.!
What? A trap!
There's a rumor that Asuka Jr.
is Saint Tail's accomplice.
Egami would never tell him the true
hiding place of the tiara, would he?
He lied so Asuka Jr. will be
arrested along with Saint Tail.
That's terrible.
It's all because of that note you sent
to challenge him, Meimi!
You think so?
I guess so... He's getting set up,
because of me!
If you steal the tiara from the minute
hand, Asuka Jr.'s name is cleared.
That's right.
My lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
May the blessing of God be with us.
But I'll tell you this...
I'm not doing this to help him!
Yes, yes.
Off you go.
Asuka Jr.!
Do you intend to sit there and
stake out the place all night?
Not all night.
Saint Tail will be coming at exactly 6:00.
How do you know that?
The only time Saint Tail can reach
the hour hand is 6:00.
To steal Electra at any other time...
is impossible!
I see.
I'm counting on you, Asuka Jr.
I'm waiting for you, Saint Tail!
What a fool! You don't know that
Electra is behind the minute hand!
At 6:00, everyone will see
that you and Saint Tail...
are both idiots!
Looks like there isn't any security.
I have to climb the clock tower.
That's...!
Almost 6:00. Time for Saint Tail
to make her appearance.
Sir! We've got trouble!
What's wrong?
Why are you so excited?
Sir! Someone is climbing the ladder
on the side of the clock tower!
What?
That ladder leads to the top stairs!
Oh, no!
Okay! Saint Tail, come on out!
Hi!
What?
What a beautiful moon.
I'm so happy you waited for me.
Saint Tail.
Why are you up there?
I know where it's really hidden.
Electra is behind the minute hand.
Behind the minute hand?
Well, that's it. I've got Electra.
My Electra is being stolen!
Wait! Saint Tail!
Darn!
What's going on?!
Mr. Egami, you said the Electra was
behind the hour hand!
Shut up!
Saint Tail, I won't let you get away!
You can't escape!
Don't move, Saint Tail!
It's showtime!
That's the balloon she used
to send me the challenge.
Bye, bye!
Darn it!
You won't get away!
Ouch!
This time,
I'll bust that big one!
Stop!
Shut up!!
This will get my Electra back!
Brat! How dare you!
Cut it out!! ...Stop!!
Stop... please...
I wasn't trying to protect you!
Don't misunderstand what I did!
Listen!
Keep sending me those challenges!
Give me a fair chance!
I'll get you sooner or later!
Are you listening?!
I don't know why,
but it's fun to have him around.
And I'll do anything
to keep on feeling this way.
Good Morning!
The real owner was very happy.
She says, "Thank you for
returning Electra".
Hang on a sec.
I'll catch up with you.
Sure.
That old man...
he even had me fooled!
Hey, great detective!
You're a hero in the papers, again.
You caught another crook, huh?
Yeah... but Saint Tail still got away.
Well, you can give us the details later.
Asuka Jr.!
What do you want?
Glad to hear your name's been cleared.
That's great!
Yeah. Thanks.
And you let Saint Tail get away again.
I hear you're on bad terms with her.
What do you mean, "again"!
Anyway, it's none of your business!
Ah, she's a hopeless case.
But that cut...! Could it be?
Well, hang in there till next time!
I know that Saint Tail is a girl
about the same age as me.
It couldn't be...
Nah, it can't be!
Saint Tail Mini-Theatre!
"The Great Hot Potato Chase!"
Autumn leaves.
It'll be fall in no time.
Meimi?
I'm at the best part of the story,
so don't talk to me right now!
Autumn, is a season for reading...
But how about reading something
other than comic books sometime?
Ah... "Autumn of Romance."
I'd like to be chased by...
a handsome, passionate lover,
like the girl in this comic!
But Meimi, you do have a passionate
person chasing after you, don't you?
Hot potatoes!
Meimi! How un-ladylike!
My, Seira.
Wasn't that your stomach just now?
That's right ladies! Come and get them!
They're hot and sweet!
Autumn's the season to
crave sweet potatoes!
Stone-baked sweet potatoes!
Hot!
Well then Meimi, please go ahead!
Hey, just a minute!
Why should I have to go buy it myself!
I'm a servant of God. Sister told me
it's forbidden for me to buy and eat.
Oh really? Then that means I don't
have to get one for you, right?
Buying is forbidden, but it's fine
to have a kind friend share a snack.
I always have to play these roles.
Someday, Seira's gonna get punished!
Natural and delicious!
Stone-baked hot potatoes!
Nobody's looking... here I go!
Sir!
Hey! Haneoka, is that you?
That voice!
Asuka Jr.!
What are you doing here?
Wha... what?
It's none of your business!
What about you!
What are you doing here?
What else?
I'm in the middle of an investigation
to catch Saint Tail's tail!
Don't even try.
Saint Tail isn't a slowpoke
that you'd be able to catch!
What did you say?!
The Mayor himself commissioned me!
So don't interfere!
Are you kidding?
This isn't a Samurai movie!
Who'd be impressed with
a thing like that?
-What did you say?!
-What of it?!
Stone-baked hot potatoes!
Piping hot sweet potatoes!
Wait! Mr. hot potato vendor!
What's with you?
Why are you acting so strange?
Did you want to buy a sweet potato?
That's right! Anything wrong with that?!
Go ahead and laugh!
How stupid.
That's nothing to be ashamed of.
I like them, too.
Sweet potatoes.
Get on!
Let's go!
We can still catch it!
All right!
There it is!
It's a patrol car!
What are we gonna do?
We can't stop!
What am I supposed to do!
You two on the bicycle up ahead!
Stop right now!
Oh, no!
It's my dad's patrol car!
Blah Blah Blah Blah...
I'm sorry Asuka Jr.
It's all because of me.
Don't worry.
I'm used to Dad chewing me out.
More importantly, I'm sorry we
didn't get to buy the sweet potato.
Oh yeah! I forgot all about it!
What do you mean you forgot?
Piping hot sweet potatoes!
Wait!
Sweet potato vendor!
Meimi sure is taking a long time!