By day she is a happy student
at St. Paulia School.
But at night, she becomes
the phantom thief Saint Tail...
to do good deeds for all who come
asking for help from Seira...
a nun in training.
Looking to capture the elusive Saint Tail
is an amateur detective...
and Meimi's classmate, Asuka Jr.
As for Meimi...
she may have more than a bit of
interest in such a determined boy.
Meimi's lover is a hedgehog?!
That mom of mine!
It's Sunday, and she has to make me
go do the grocery shopping.
Hey, hold it there!
What is it?! What's so funny?!
You're a really rude creature!
Humph!
I'm leaving!
Hey, wait!
If it's the cat, it went that way.
Thanks!
Oh, please watch the shop
for a moment!
What? Hang on a second!
Stop!
Good grief!
What could this be?
Y... You!
You're the rude one
I met the other day.
Humph!
I see.
You're all alone, aren't you?
Cheer up, cute little hedgehog.
You're the only person that this
hedgehog has warmed up to.
Really.
My name is Meimi Haneoka.
I'll come to see you ever day from
now on! So let's be friends.
So cute!
Oh, no! I'll be late for school!
Oh, no! Not again!
Hey, hold it!
Come back!
Don't run away!
Meimi, want to stop for
ice cream on the way home?
There's a new shop that just opened
beside the park on 2nd Avenue.
Sorry, I've got something to do today.
Something to do?
A date.
What?!
Yup! See you!
A date?!
Good afternoon.
Have you had a nice day?
Hi! Back again?
You're fond of her, aren't you?
She's so cute!
Why don't you ask your mother and
father if you can buy her as a pet?
I promise I won't sell her to anyone
else until you get their permission.
Really?
You won't sell her
to anyone else until then?
Sure. I promise.
Great!
Wait for me, my little hedgehog.
Mister, I'll be back!
All right, see you!
Hey!
Yes?
This hedgehog, sell him to me.
But it's already...
Look, I said I want this hedgehog!
Please Dad, can I?
Can I have the hedgehog?
Did you say hedgehog?
That's right.
I even have a name for her.
I'll call her Ruby.
Ruby?
The ring that dad bought you
is a ruby, right?
Yes, my engagement ring.
That's why I named her that.
Hmm... a ruby...
It does bring back memories
of the old days, doesn't it, dear?
It sure does.
Eimi, you haven't changed
a bit since then.
Why, dear, you haven't either.
Eimi...
Genichiro...
Hello, you two?
Oh, gee, Meimi, were you there?
Of course, where else would I be?
Then it's all right for me to have
a hedgehog named Ruby?
Sure.
Phew...
It helps, having easy-going parents.
Good afternoon!
What?!
I'm really sorry...
You promised you wouldn't sell her!
He insisted on buying it.
He wouldn't take no for an answer.
I'm really sorry.
Moping will get me nowhere.
I'm sure Ruby is having
a nice life, too.
Right! I'm sure of it!
"Polar Tear?"
Yes, it's a beautiful diamond.
Legend says it's a teardrop
of the North Star.
I shared the diamond with Hayase,
an old friend from my school days.
We took turns, keeping the gem
for two months at a time.
That was our agreement.
I never expected he would betray me.
He betrayed you?
Yes.
Yesterday was the day I was to receive
the diamond for the next two months.
Hayase, what are you saying?
You haven't given the diamond to me!
That's ridiculous, Kamimura.
Of course I gave you the diamond.
If you doubt me, search the house!
Kamimura... maybe...
You're not trying to keep the
diamond all to yourself, right?
What?
That's what you're trying to do!
Cut it out.
Do you have any proof that
I didn't give you the diamond?
That's the story I heard today.
They finally called the police
and searched the house, but...
They couldn't find the diamond.
And according to the contract,
if the Polar Tear is lost...
the one that loses the gem
has to pay for it.
Then...
On top of stealing the diamond...
Hayase is holding him
liable for the cost.
I'm really angry! Phantom Saint Tail
shall retrieve that diamond!
Is something wrong?
You're not usually this touchy.
Seira!
What happened?
I went to the pet shop.
The pet shop?
Someone bought my hedgehog!
She's gone!
I'd even thought up some hedgehog
magic to use on the next caper!
What's that supposed to be?
Well then, let us continue
from line 20.
Mr. Asuka! Read!
Yes.
Let's see.
"Tonight, I'll be at the Hayase
mansion to get the Polar Tear"
"Signed, Saint Tail."
What is this?!
That's my line!
Idiot.
My Lord, forgive me, for I use
no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
May the blessings of God be with us!
Meimi, do your best!
I will.
To help me forget
my little hedgehog...
I'm gonna nail this guy!
I don't need your security!
The police checked it out, but
the Polar Tear is not in this mansion.
Whatever Saint Tail
is supposed to be...
how can she steal something
that isn't here?
But Saint Tail sent me a warning
that she'll show up here.
That's...
The Mayor's special
badge of investigation.
I'm staking out
your home, Mr. Hayase.
The question is where's the diamond?
That must be Hayase.
That's...
But why is my
hedgehog Ruby here?
I must say, this is ingenious.
No one would ever think that the
Polar Tear is inside your stomach!
What a terrible thing to do!
Absolutely unforgivable!
Come in.
Oh, it's you.
It's rude of me,
but are you really sure...
the Polar Tear is
not in the mansion?
Persistent, aren't you?
I told you, I handed the diamond
over to Kamimura.
Wow!
A hedgehog?
What an unusual pet.
Don't touch it!
I'm sorry.
Stop!
It's Saint Tail!
Darn, you're not getting away!
My Polar Tear!
Hang on tight!
Hold it!
They sure are persistent!
Look out!
Ouch!
What the... why are you on my head?
Don't move!
Wait!
What are you chasing me for?!
Shut up! Stop running away!
Asuka Jr.! I'm over here!
I won't let you get away!
You brat!
Why are you running away!
I'm not running away,
I'm chasing Saint Tail!
Where are you? Saint Tail!
Asuka Jr.!
Hand over that hedgehog!
You just wait right there!
I'll get you for sure!
Hold it!
How hopeless can he be?
There she is!
It's showtime!
You little pest! Hand it over!
Hold that elevator!
Shoot!
It's no use trying
to escape like that!
I'll catch up to you
in the other elevator!
Wait!
What?!
What are you planning to do to her?!
Shut up! The hedgehog is all...
Look this way, Saint Tail.
Maybe I can see her face.
I just want to get
a look at her face.
Show your face!
How...
is...
this?!
I'll be getting off here. Bye bye!
Hey! Stop! Stop!
Do something, you brat!
Shut up! Stop being a pain!
Too bad that elevator doesn't stop
until it gets to the top!
Wait right there!
I'll get you for sure!
I know I should probably
just escape now.
Right?
It really bugs me.
Why can't I just let that guy be?
Wait, it's coming up?
What a stupid phantom,
she's going to follow us up here!
Here it comes!
Saint Tail, we've got you!
Hand over my hedgehog!
What?!
I didn't think I'd get a chance
to use my hedgehog magic so soon!
Saint Tail?
One! Two!
Three!
Oh, you were able to cough it up!
I'm so glad!
That's what you get for being bad
and hoarding the gem all to yourself!
Ouch!
Wait!
Goodbye!
Take care of the rest for me!
A star?
Oh, it's the Polar Tear.
Hey!
Why did she give this to me?
Hey, son!
Dad!
Hayase is out cold down there.
But I'm arresting him
on charges offraud.
And this is Mr. Kamimura,
the owner of the diamond.
I'm so glad...
the Polar Tear is safe,
thank you so much!
Ah... don't mention it.
Saint Tail, she...
Well now, Hayase has been caught.
Wanna come live at my house?
Okay! One, two, three!
This is to celebrate our friendship!
Let's be good friends!