Meimi Haneoka is 14 years old.
By day, she is a happy student of
St. Paulia School.
But at night, she becomes the thief,
St. Tail, to do good deeds...
for all who ask for help from Seira,
a nun in training.
Looking to capture the elusive St. Tail
is an amateur detective...
and Meimi's classmate, Asuka Jr.
And Meimi? She may have more than a bit
of interest in such a determined boy...
I Hate Wedding Veils
So what are you going to do?
Are you going home?
Well, I guess I'll go with you.
Thank you!
Now that it's decided, let's hurry!
Oh! It's already full!
It sure is popular.
Shall we come another day?
No way!
I didn't get any last time and today,
I wanna eat some chocolate chip!
You're acting very immature.
Yeah, just like a child!
Your obsession with ice cream
proves your lack of maturity.
Keep your opinion to yourself!
It's popular with
college girls, too, you know!
Those college girls
are just as immature as you.
Just who are "you" calling immature?
Look who's talking!
You're barely out of diapers!
Should we teach him
how to have fun?
Um... I... Goodbye!
I'm sorry.
Heaven's punishment.
But still...
Here.
It's nothing.
But...
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
It's all right.
Meimi...
What is it?
See ya!
Oh, welcome home!
I'm back.
What's the matter Meimi?
You don't look very happy.
The happiness of a family
comes from healthy greetings.
Let's try again!
Welcome home!
I'm back!!
My new trick...
Meimi!
Looks like she's in a bad mood.
Maybe she did badly on a test?
What's that jerk's problem?
Oh, Ruby, I'm sorry!
I didn't mean to snap at you.
Why am I so irritated?
He's not supposed to
mean anything to me and still...
I don't get it.
I don't even know why I feel this way.
How annoying!
God, please grant my wish.
Thank you.
I'm so glad...
Yeah.
Oh, there you are.
Oh, how beautiful!
It's a wedding veil, right?
It's really pretty.
Papa, why is it here?
Who is it for?
Does it make you happy, Sayaka?
The wedding veil is for you.
For me?
It's a gift from your fiance.
Isn't it wonderful, Sayaka?
Yes, isn't it?
Meimi, Seira, good morning!
Good morning!
Good morning.
What's the matter Meimi?
You don't look too happy.
Maybe she's found
that special someone!
Who is it? Who is it?
Today is an important day...
but you haven't prepared
for it at all, am I wrong?
That's right...
Oh no! I haven't prepared either!
I'm sure you're well prepared,
aren't you, Seira?
Tell me, tell me!
Studying is something
one must do on their own.
That's harsh.
That's just how she is.
You've got ten minutes
until class starts.
Excuse us...
Seniors...
They're the badminton club freshmen.
Aren't they cute?
Oh... that girl is...
That's Sayaka Shinomiya.
She's cute and really popular.
I hear she lives in an
old mansion at the edge of town.
Hey, I wonder what
she's staring at so intensely.
You're right.
She's staring pretty hard.
So the wedding veil is a
token of your engagement?
Yes, but...
I've never even met him.
My parents arranged
the engagement themselves.
You poor thing.
On top of that I...
There's someone else I'm in love with!
Oh, I see.
I don't want to be engaged
to a stranger!
If only that veil would disappear!
Please!
Please give me the strength
to dissolve this engagement.
May the blessings of God be with you.
And there's nothing
Sayaka can do about it?
It seems that way.
All right! St. Tail shall steal
that wedding veil!
Even if the person Sayaka
is in love with is Asuka Jr.?
Gross! What terrible taste!
What are you going to do Meimi?
Why are you asking
me something like that?
Then you don't mind?
Of course not!
St. Tail never has second thoughts!
I'll steal that wedding veil,
no matter what!
Just as I thought.
So you see, they completely
disregarded a young girl's feelings.
It's unforgivable.
Isn't that right, Ruby?
"Tonight, I'm going to steal a
wedding veil from...
the Shinomiya residence."
What?!
What's all that noise
this early in the morning?
It's a vocal warm up!
Forget it.
Music doesn't run in our family.
Is that right?
I know I told her to
keep me informed, but...
I guess I won't wash my face.
Hey, what are you doing?
Hurry up and eat.
Look, I made a really good
sunny-side-up egg today.
I don't want any.
What's with you?
When you make them, you grumble
if anything is left on the plate.
I don't want to eat!
A growing boy like you?
If I eat, the note might dissapear.
I've just got some stuff going on!
What, you found yourself a girlfriend?
Don 't be stupid!
Why do you keep your back turned?
When you talk to somebody, face them!
I've got stuff going on so... see you!
Is that really St. Tail's note?
That's amazing!
Sure is.
But you're a real idiot, having slept
through her writing it on your face.
Shut up!
Let me touch it real quick!
Stupid! Don't touch it!
Your hands are dirty!
How silly...
Hey, come on.
Cut it out, you idiot! Knock it off!
She's mine! I'm gonna get her!
What was that?
But why?
Even if the person Sayaka
is in love with is Asuka Jr.?
Coming!
Asuka...
Hi.
...therefore I'd appreciate
you letting me stake the place out.
Uhm...
Are you sure about this?
There's no doubt about it!
St. Tail has never gone back
on a warning or failed in a caper.
If you take her lightly,
you'll be in a terrible situation.
Let's go over the
plan for this evening.
On top of getting the veil stolen,
I can win over Asuka Jr., too.
If this is the case, I wish
Miss Thief could come every night.
Well, time to work.
Gotta help those in trouble.
What's the matter?
I thought I heard
something in the yard.
I think someone's out there.
In situations like this
it's usually a cat.
Meow.
You're right. Just a cat.
She's my daughter, all right.
Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
May the blessings of God be with us.
Well, then...
Are you really going Meimi?
I'm going!
If I were Sayaka, I wouldn't want
an engagement like that, either!
If the veil is returned, I'm sure
the engagement will be called off.
Can you do it, St. Tail?
Without a doubt, if it's God's will!
This "Tail" thief is probably thinking
of entering through the attic.
So I'm going to stand watch in the room
directly below the attic, for an ambush.
But, what if she enters
from a different place?
If I say she's coming through here,
that's how it will be.
I've met up with her many times
and I know what to expect.
Are you absolutely sure it's okay?
Papa, don't be rude to Asuka Jr.!
Papa, Mama, will you wait outside?
Asuka and I will keep watch here.
I'm sorry.
Well, it's true.
I'm sure you'll be able to catch her!
What's all this?
Okay, just watch!
There's something odd...
St. Tail never steals without a reason.
Why would she want
to steal a wedding veil?
Well that's...
Mr. Asuka!
The inner courtyard...!
Hurry and do something!
Even if she uses a decoy
or some sort of camouflage...
there's nothing to worry about!
I'm not such a dimwit that I'd
be caught with the same trick twice.
He's not falling for my tricks.
How boring.
Well, if he's looking for a challenge,
I'll give him one!
The security is pretty bad.
No guards or anything so far.
The wedding veil and
Asuka Jr. are waiting just for me!
One small setback.
But, with the veil right in front of me,
I can't back down now!
St. Tail! You've taken the bait!
Applause!
Applause, my foot!
That's no fair! You idiot!
Let me go! She's going to get away!
But I'm scared!
Let go!
Miss Thief, take it away!
Let me go!
She's gonna escape!
I don 't care!
Stealing this veil means Sayaka's
engagement will be called off.
It's the right thing to do, but...
She's mine!
I'm gonna catch her!
Darn it!
Wait! Answer me one question!
Why are you stealing that?!
Are you just a thief, after all?!
Haven 't you always stolen
to help those in trouble?!
How about you?!
How about you? Why don't you
ever understand how a girl feels?!
If you want to know who
the troubled one is, ask Sayaka!
You super-dingbat!
Ding... bat?
She got away again.
I won't give up!
I'll never give in to you!
Darn it!
So, St. Tail dissolved
the engagement?
She returned the wedding veil
to the sender's house.
Then, he got angry
and called off the engagement.
Thank you very much, Asuka Jr.
Hey, it's not right to thank me.
But I'm so happy!
Stop it.
C'mon... cut it out!
Excuse me.
What is it?
Haneoka, what are you doing?
Hey! Hold it!
Darn it, why am I always
chasing after...
What is it? What's so funny?
What have you written?
It's best you don't know.
"I hate you!"
Hey, Haneoka!