Meimi Haneoka is 14 years old.
By day she is a happy student
at St. Paulia School.
But at night, she becomes
the thief St. Tail...
to do good deeds for all who
come asking the help of Seira...
a nun in training.
Looking to capture the elusive
St. Tail is an amateur detective...
and Meimi's classmate, Asuka Jr.
As for Meimi...
she may have more than a bit of
interest in such a determined boy.
Legend of Happiness?
The Clock Tower Commotion
Did you see the ad
for the Wonder Garden?
It just opened this month.
Oh, I love amusement parks!
Actually, I've already been there.
Who with?!
If you must know...
Look, it's Tominaga from class C!
Since when?
It's a wonderful place.
The flowers are really lovely.
But the main attraction is... this!
The mechanical clock
of Wonder Castle!
The dolls move and it's so beautiful.
It was built by a famous
foreign doll-maker.
Every one of his creations
costs a huge amount of money.
Also, it's said that if...
you watch this clock with the one
you love, it'll bring happiness.
And you watched it together!
Yeah.
How wonderful!
I'm jealous, I've never
even been on a date.
Who do you want to date, Meimi?
Don't tell me
you want to date Asuka Jr.
Don't be silly!
Who'd want to date
a dinky detective like him?!
Just who do you think
you're calling "dinky"?!
If that bugs you,
why don't you go ahead...
and catch St. Tail,
you bungling detective!
Even if I do capture her,
I'm not letting you see her!
Who cares, she's not like
some beetle on display, is she?!
Shut up!
Same to you!
Hey, Asuka!
Yeah, I'm coming.
Seira...
What is it?
Meimi, there's only one reason
why I would ask you to come here.
I have a favor to ask of St. Tail.
Something that only she can do.
The doll at the amusement park?
Yes, and it's located
in a very high place.
You mean that amusement park?
Yes, Wonder Garden
Amusement Park.
Then, by a high place,
you must mean...
The mechanical clock
of Wonder Castle.
This girl tied a precious doll
that she had brought with her...
to the strings of her balloons.
This is the doll you
want me to get?
Yes, she borrowed the doll
from a friend...
and must return it
the next time they meet.
However...
The doll!
They contacted the
amusement park...
but were told to forget
about the doll.
All I have to do is
get the doll back.
That's easy.
Only, you have to get
it back by Sunday.
Sunday... that's tomorrow.
The doll's owner is coming to the
girl's house tomorrow to play.
She needs it by then.
Which means I have
to do it tonight.
And the doll emerges from
the clock on the hour.
So you have to get the doll
before the balloon carries it away.
Okay, leave it to me.
I'm home!
Welcome back, Meimi.
What's up?
This...
You haven't gone
there yet, have you?
Huh...? No.
We were just about to go.
Do you want to come, too?
It'll complicate things
if I go with them...
You want to go, don't you?
Yes.
Good.
Besides, you might find
some ideas for new magic tricks.
Jeez, they always use
me as an excuse.
You want to come?
But I've got work to do...
Ready yet?
Almost.
I want you to stay home
and watch the house.
It's been a long time since I've
been to an amusement park.
It's time for the doll to come out.
Hey, hey... what's the rush?
I have something I want to see!
There.
It's almost time.
Asuka Jr.!
Haneoka!
What brings you here?
To have fun... what else?
Yeah, that makes sense.
So that's the clock tower
the girls were fussing over?
When you watch it with
the one you love...
it brings happiness.
Why don't they come out?
Hey there, what's going on?
Is something wrong?
It's just some malfunction.
There's a temp repairman here,
if I remember correctly.
Yes, I'll get him!
They say it's just
some malfunction.
See you.
Ah! ...My balloon!
That's right.
At least I can check
if the balloons are still there.
Too bad, Meimi.
I'm going to go get some ice cream.
"Employees Only"
Oh, it's a costume.
Good, it's still there.
Good work.
All I did was remove a gear.
Piece of cake.
The big job's coming up.
Identical dolls.
Why bother with all this stuff?
Why not just go ahead and steal it?
The police are on guard.
Sometimes it's better
to use your brain.
Well, faking a malfunction...
and switching the dolls
during the repair...
I guess that's using your brain.
Which means those are all fakes!
Who's there?!
Cool it! It's nothing!
Okay, let's get to work.
They won't
get away with this!
Bye.
Please come by.
It's an ad for Wonder Garden.
"I'm going to Wonder Garden
tonight to get the doll... St. Tail."
How dare she!
She was in that
rabbit costume!
I'll return this later.
Haneoka!
What?!
That amusement park...
That clock at Wonder Castle
with the dolls that's said to...
You mean...
bring happiness to couples when
they view it together.
Yeah.
Is he trying to ask
me to go with him?
About how much is it worth?
Excuse me?
Is it true that it's very expensive?
It's supposed to be.
Why would she do
something so villainous?!
I got it, never mind.
See you.
What's with him, anyway!
I hate him!
He's so insensitive.
Oh, look who's grouchy.
I'll take you the next time I go.
I've got to get to work.
Meimi.
Meimi?
Are you there?
Oh, no!
What's wrong?
She's not answering.
What are you doing over there?
I was thinking of going to
get some juice or something.
From the window?
I thought I'd try something new.
I'll be off, then.
Going in and out
of the window at night.
She's my girl, all right.
Please forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
May the blessings
of God be with us.
That doll was specially made.
It's invaluable...
There's only one of its
kind in the world.
If it were ever stolen...
Please be rest assured...
St. Tail always has some
reason for stealing.
I'm sure it's the same this time.
You can't be too sure.
Dad!
If the latest artwork thefts
are the work of St. Tail...
then everything falls into place.
No, it can't be.
You're still green, son.
She may be called "Saint", but
she's no more than a thief.
I'm done with the repairs for now.
All right, thanks.
Don't mention it.
What an idiot.
If St. Tail is going to appear...
it'll be when the dolls come out.
What the...?!
"These dolls are fake!
St. Tail"
St. Tail!
When did she...?!
Don't tell me she
switched them with fakes!
St. Tail! Where is she?!
Stay calm, don't leave your posts!
They still don't get it?
Talk about dense.
I won't let you get away!
She's trying to confuse us
with bits of paper!
I can see right through you.
Light her face up! Her face!
I can see right through you, too!
If you want to light up something...
leave it to St. Tail!
It's Show Time!
The lights are moving by themselves!
What's going on?
We don't light up at night.
Now for the real show.
Hold it! St. Tail!
I can't see!
Identical dolls.
These!
These are the real ones!
And there's the statue
that was stolen last week.
Dad!
You're under arrest!
Ouch, you're squashing me, too!
St. Tail!
The rest of you, go after St. Tail!
Here goes.
One...
Two...
Three!
Asuka Jr!
Which one should we arrest?!
Yikes!
What the...?!
Do you have a St. Tail parade
or something at this amusement park?!
Of course not!
I lost her.
Fantastic, isn't it?
St. Tail's illusion parade!
There's no way to
find me in all this.
No way!
Don't underestimate me.
No matter where you go...
I'll find you!
How?
You're not getting away!
Asuka Jr.! That's dangerous!
Fool!
I won't...
miss this chance!
Like I said... I'm taking
the doll with me!
The doll...
That's the doll
you wanted?
If you had asked me out,
it would've made me happy.
But...
it turned out to be
like a date, anyway!
I really enjoyed myself!
Date...?
Cut the jokes!
I'm serious, you know!
I'm serious... darn.
Thank you, Asuka Jr.
All of the dolls have been recovered,
thanks to you.
Those two turned out to be the ones
responsible for the art thefts.
I thought it was strange
for her to do such a thing.
What?
No, it's nothing.
Don't ever tie it to
a balloon again.
It brings happiness if you watch it
together with the one you love.
Well, who cares...
My nights are always filled
with the prospect of happiness.