"Cherry blossom"?
We learned it in
English class, Meimi.
It's the English
words for "Sakura".
Oh, is it?
There's a painting
called "Cherry Blossom"...
at the Central Museum.
Oh, I know about that painting.
Isn't that the masterpiece
so admired...
for it's life-like
withering petals?
I'd like to see it once myself.
You're going to steal the painting.
Rather, I'd like you to get it back.
Get it back?
An old man came to me
for help yesterday.
He says that the owner
of the museum deceived him.
Meaning?
The old man thought
he signed a contract...
to loan "Cherry Blossom"
to the museum.
Later he found out they had
switched the contract to one...
that transferred ownership
of the painting.
What is that?! How mean!
The modern art exhibition
has just opened.
So during the...
I get the idea, Seira.
Just leave the rest to St. Tail!
New Student Rina.
A Formidable Enemy
Darn!
I still can't beat this game!
Me neither.
And I've used up
this month's allowance.
Hey, where's Asuka?
Over there.
He's been like that the whole time.
Take that!
Hey, I think you
should retreat a bit.
Huh?
That's from you butting in!
No, dodge those!
And those, too!
Too slow!
Now, punch!
No, dodge again!
What are you doing?!
Kick! Kick!
Jump! Jump!
Go now! Do it! Do...!
Shut up!!
Quit your yakking!
You're so frustrating.
Here, let me!
What do you think you're doing?!
You...
Bad form.
Whose fault is that, huh?!!
Just who the heck are you anyway?!
Butting into other people's business!
Your interference ruined my game!
Hey, are you listening?!
Hold on, what's that?
Huh?
"I'm going to the Central Museum
tomorrow night...
to get Cherry Blossom".
This is...?
It's a warning from St. Tail!
St. Tail?
Who's that?
Ah?
You're living in this town
and you don't know St. Tail?
What's wrong with you?
How rude! I just moved here!
Hey, she's...
taller than me...
and I don't have time.
-I have to think up a strategy!
-Hey, wait...!
Wait up!
St. Tail, I'll get you
for sure this time!
Hey, hold on!
Huh?
Sheesh, I 'm busy!
-I said hold on!
-You 're annoying me!
Darn it!
You 're not very fit, are you?
Shut up.
Hey, tell me about St. Tail.
No way.
Hey, what are you doing?!
Cut it out!
So, you gonna tell me now?!
Forget it.
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Okay, I'll tell you!
Let go of me!
Ooh, that hurt.
I thought I was gonna die.
I'm sorry, did that really hurt?
Of course!
And...
St. Tail is a girl thief.
Oh, a thief.
That means she's a bad guy.
What else?
Her true identity is unknown. But she's
so sly, that the police can't catch her.
The police can't catch her?!
I've made up my mind.
Where's the Central Museum?
At Third Ave and Bay Street, but...
OK, thanks.
Sorry if I was
a bit rough on you.
I'm Rina Takamiya.
I'm 14 years old.
See you!
What's with her?
Time to eat, Meimi!
Alright!
Wow, it looks delicious.
Don't!
Really!
Now call Papa.
Okay.
You scared me!
I'm sorry.
What am I gonna do with you?
What are you doing, Papa?
Hmm? This.
Those are Tarot cards, aren't they?
Yeah.
I'm wondering if I can use tarot card
fortune-telling to do some new magic.
That sounds like fun!
Will you try it on me?
Sure.
What's wrong, Papa?
Is anything wrong with that card?
Mama, don't scare us like that!
Really, Meimi!
You should keep your mind
on the task at hand.
It's time for dinner, both of you.
Alright.
What's so funny, dear?
Nothing.
It's just that you and Meimi
do the things the same way.
What?
I'm a little worried
about Meimi, though.
What's the matter?
According to the cards,
she's in for a bit of an ordeal.
Oh?
She'll be all right, because like me,
her best feature is her cheerfulness.
That's true.
And besides, my bad fortune-telling
is probably wrong.
Well, well, what's
for dinner tonight?
Today it's your favorite, beef stew.
That sounds great!
Papa, Mama, I'm gonna start eating!
Hey!
Oh, I'm full.
Come on, Ruby.
I can't today, I've got work to do.
I'm sorry.
OK!
Oh, I forgot to ask Papa
about the tarot cards.
Oh well.
I'll just give it
my all today!
Forgive me, for I use
no gimmick or trick.
One...
Two...
Three!
May the blessings
of God be with us.
It's gonna be great today!
Meimi, be careful tonight.
Why?
I feel strangely uneasy.
You mean Asuka Jr.?
He's nothing to worry about.
Not Asuka Jr., something else.
Something else is going to happen.
Don't worry!
So long as the blessings of God
are with us...
there's nothing
St. Tail can't do!
Well, I better go.
Asuka Jr.
Everyone is in position.
All right, good work.
If you see someone suspicious,
don't let him get away, understand?
We found this one loitering.
Whaa?!
Come along!
All right, I'm coming,
you don't have to pull me like that.
Now what?
Hey, it's you!
It's you...
What are you doing here?
You're in charge of security?
Wow, you're only in grade school.
I'm in Junior High and
I'm the same age as you!
Oh, really?
She insists that she's
authorized personnel...
and refuses to move
from the entrance.
Asuka Jr., this one is a girl.
Maybe she's St. Tail?
Take your filthy hands off me!
I'm going to stand
guard over here, too.
Hold on!
I was appointed by the Mayor
to investigate St. Tail!
You can't go around doing whatever
you want without my permission!
The Mayor?
Yes!
The Mayor happens to be my Uncle.
Which makes you the Mayor's niece?
Yes! Besides, we've got a lot
of our paintings here, too!
We can't have a thief breaking in!
But... but...
Well, you go ahead and
do what you have to do.
Darn it.
Asuka Jr.
Get off me!
"Cherry Blossom"
It's splendid, just as they say.
Hey, cut it out!
That's so annoying!
You know, it's all because of you!
What's up?
It's St. Tail.
Don't move!
Asuka Jr.!
Don't panic! Switch on
the emergency lights!
All right! Everyone, check
up on your assigned posts!
What's wrong?
Cherry Blossom is gone!
It can't be!
Darn it!
This is a cherry blossom petal.
There are more
trailing off that way!
If we follow the trail,
we' ll run into the thief!
Hold it!
Don't go acting on your own!
Why don't you stay here, then?
I have confidence in my legs and my
strength, so I'll go nab the thief!
Hey!
Oh shoot! That's her way of
throwing us into confusion.
Hey, maybe that girl has
already caught St. Tail.
Could be. That would really
make us look like fools.
All right! We'll follow the
cherry blossom petals! Follow me!
Yes, sir!
Darn it, I'm the one who's
going to capture St. Tail!
Hmm... pretty good...
but not clever enough.
I wonder who that girl is?
Here I have with me a piece of cloth.
Nothing up my sleeve.
The masterpiece, Cherry Blossom,
that disappeared...
Appear!
Ta-da!
As a matter of fact,
I didn 't steal it, yet!
I'm not letting you
get away, St. Tail!
So, that's the room!
Hold it! Hold it! Hold it! Hold it!
I'm the one who's capturing St. Tail!
"Please keep the supply closet clean."
Hey, what are you doing?
And just why are you here?
I couldn't help it.
The petals led me here!
This is St. Tail's usual
way of confusing people!
Which means you fell for
the same trick every time?
There are more petals.
Let's go!
Wait for me!
Hey! Isn't this her usual trick?
Shut up!
You are just worried about
your paintings, aren't you?
That's all you're worried about!
What? You actually
believed me?
What?
What I told you were, obviously,
all lies.
What?!
They say that lying makes a thief!
Even a thief possesses an ounce of logic!
This is absurd!
Don 't you forget it!
In other words, you're pretty bad
at avoiding and dodging things.
What's this?
We're outside.
There's something strange going on.
Although it's not the right season,
the cherry blossom is in full bloom.
What's going on?
Asuka Jr.!
Up there, on top of that thing!
St. Tail!
St. Tail? That's her?
Good work. I'm taking
Cherry Blossom with me.
Just a minute!
Hey, hold it!
When I grow up, I'll become a police
officer. And I'll arrest St. Tail!
No way! If anyone arrests St. Tail,
it'll be me!
It really doesn't matter
who arrests her, does it!?
Be quiet!
Nyaaah!
I know it's not the right season,
but I'll give you two a free show...
of falling cherry blossom petals!
It's Show Time!
Thank you.
Hold it!
Ouch...
Hey! Let go of me!
What? Oh, sorry.
She's outwitted me again.
Humph! She may be a thief,
but she's just a girl!
If only you didn't get in my way,
I would have captured her!
You really are so...!
Thank you!
Good morning, Meimi.
You're going to be late.
Oh, good morning, Kyoko.
Seira... nothing happened yesterday.
Miss Haneoka!
Oh, good morning, Sister.
Good morning, Miss Haneoka.
I'd like you to do me a favor.
This is a new student who will be in
your class. Please take her with you.
Sure, I'd be glad to.
Miss Takamiya!
"ST. TAIL EXPOSES MUSEUM SWINDLE
Owner Arrested"
What!?
This is Rina Takamiya, a new
student who has just arrived today.
Nice to meet you.
She's... yesterday's...
Just a minute!
I'll become a police officer...!
Please take care of her,
Miss Haneoka.
Uh... yes!
You keep staring at me.
Is there something on my face?
No. I'm Meimi Haneoka,
glad to meet you.
If you ever need anything,
just ask me.
-Okay. I do have one question.
Huh?
There's this boy I'd like
to meet, named Asuka Jr..
Is he at this school?