There's this boy I'd like to meet,
named Asuka Jr.
Is he in this school?
A First Rendezvous of Tears?!
I've finally found you!
Asuka Jr.!
All right!
H... hey, what are you doing here?!
I looked all over town for you!
But what are you doing here?!
It took so long to find you!
I guess I couldn't find you,
since you're so small.
Answer my question,
before this turns into a fight!
Meimi, who is she?
She's a new student!
I'll tell you about her later!
I guess she doesn't need me
to take care of her!
Some nerve!
Humph!
Cute... cute...
Knock it off!
Relax. It's nothing.
What is with her?
"Rina Takamiya"
I'm Rina Takamiya,
a new student.
Nice to meet you.
Asuka, why don't you show me around?
Why me?
Why not?! You should be
nice to new students.
She's cool, I like tall girls.
She doesn't look 14.
She's got a nice figure.
Maybe she's a model, right?
Stop! You over there!
Don't go making assumptions!
She heard us.
When I grow up, I'm going to
become a police officer!
A police officer?
That's right.
I'm going to catch bad guys.
Especially that sneaky thief,
St. Tail.
I'm going to arrest her with
my bare hands.
Wait a minute!
I'm the one who's going
to arrest her!
Well, Ms. Takamiya, Asuka Jr. was
appointed by the mayor...
to investigate St. Tail.
Well, the Mayor happens
to be my Uncle.
The Mayor's Niece.
That's right?
Is... that... right?
Then I'll go right over and ask
my Uncle for permission!
There's nothing to worry about.
St. Tail won't be captured
that easily.
Meimi?
Poor thing, you're trembling.
What's with her,
sticking so close to him!
Humph! Suit yourselves!
What?
Ancient Hidden Treasures Exhibition?
Yes, it's being held now
at the Central Hall.
The problem is...
The "Dagger of Yatto"
that's on display...
is not what it seems to be.
It's not a hidden treasure!
What?
What do you mean?
The dagger is a copy
that I made.
It's a replica!
Replica... you mean it's a fake?
I usually work as a sculptor...
But one day, I was asked by the man
in charge of Central Hall, Mr. Mizutani...
to make a replica of the
Dagger of Yatto.
I made it because he promised me that
he was only going to use it as...
a decoration in his house,
just to enjoy.
I never thought he would exhibit it
as the real Dagger of Yatto!
If I report it to the police,
I'll probably be arrested, too!
I can't sleep at night because I think
about everybody I'm deceiving.
What should I do?
The Lord will surely forgive you.
After all, you've confessed
and repented.
Sister...
Don't worry. I'm sure the Lord
will guide you.
So that's the story, Meimi.
Leave it to me!
I don't know much about
ancient relics...
whether it's Jomon period earthenware,
a burial mound figure, or a clay doll...
you can count on
St. Tail to recover it!
Meimi...
it's a dagger.
I've got an idea of how things are
between you and Ms. Takamiya...
but try to stay calm.
I'll show her!
I'm home!
Welcome back.
Meimi, I'm quite sure my magic
trick will work this time.
Want to see it?
Not right now. But, could I
borrow one of your magic tricks?
One of my magic tricks?
I'm going to send him a warning
that will blow his mind.
Asuka!
Can I eat lunch with you?
No way!
Girls always want to trade snacks.
I'm not interested in doing that.
What's this...
"I'm going to Central Hall tonight
to get the Dagger of Yatto..."
"St. Tail"
For a thief, she sure does send
lovely warnings.
Doesn't she Asuka?
Idiot!
What was that noise?
What's up?
It's a warning from St. Tail!
What?!
Let me taste some, too.
Hey don't eat it!
It's my lunch!
What are you talking about?
Don't hog it all.
-Hey don't eat my hand!
-Let go!!
What is with them?
Your chopsticks broke.
Yes, it seems so.
I've been waiting for you, Asuka Jr.
My name is Mizutani and I'm the
one in charge of this exhibition.
Nice to meet you.
The pleasure is mine, Asuka Jr.
Let's get down to business.
May I see the Dagger of Yatto?
Please follow me.
It's almost like a movie set.
All this justfor the exhibition?
Yes, I even have a special exhibition
room just for the Dagger of Yatto.
This way please.
It's inside this pyramid set.
We've set up a room in here.
If the dagger is stolen and
there's an investigation...
The cameras are on 24 hours a day.
Asuka Jr. ...
Are there any particular orders
you have for the guards on duty?
Shall we guard it
from inside the room?
No... just guard the entrance
of the exhibition hall.
But...
I'll hide inside that Sarcophagus,
if it's ok with you?
Huh? Oh, yes.
St. Tail usually appears from above.
So this should give me a good view.
We'll make her think this place
is not heavily guarded.
When she comes in here...
I'll catch her in the act and
arrest her!
This set is perfect.
The place is narrow, so I'll get
her for sure this time!
Not clever enough, Asuka Jr.
Takamiya?!
You've got to trap her
more aggressively.
It's none of your business!
You're bothering me,
so go on home!
Hmm... You really mean that?
Wh... what?!!
"To Askua Jr. ..."
"Please look after my niece, Rina.
I'm sure she'll be able to help you."
"Please let her assist you."
Mayor Hideo Morinaka"
I'll be in the surveillance room,
watching for your strategy to fail.
Darn...!
But with my strategy, tonight will be
the last night for St. Tail.
Who said that you could...
Read... Read...
Forgive me, for I use
no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Be careful...
Especially for Ms. Takamiya.
May the blessings of God be with us.
I won't lose tonight's fight.
They will see my victory.
They're only guarding the entrance.
That's pretty lenient, considering
they're up against St. Tail.
There.
So that's the Dagger of Yatto.
It's...
Show Time!
Rina, the security camera!!
What did you say!!
How could this happen at
such a critical moment?!
Please Stand By.
She's here...
St. Tail.
That's right, as soon as you touch
that case, you're finished!
Wait a moment, Rina!
She's got to be kidding,
not taking us seriously!
I can't count on Asuka's strategy!
Set target: Inside the pyramid!
Now!
That's as far as you go, St. Tail!
Asuka, it'll all be over in a minute!
Let me see your face!
What?!
What is this?!
Damn...
There, now the gas will
fill the room.
You can't escape now, St. Tail!
Try not to... breathe in...
as much as you can.
He'll see my face...!
I've got to get out of here!
Take it easy Meimi.
But... I can 't move!
Aren't you going to flee, St. Tail?
Maybe I'll get to see your face.
It's no use... I can't run away.
St. Tail!
Oh no!
My eyes are so teary,
I can't see!
Tear gas?
It should have worked by now.
What the hell is he doing with her?!!
St. Tail!
Where is St. Tail!
There couldn't have been a better
opportunity to catch her!
What were you doing?!!
Idiot! "What were you doing!"
is something I should be asking you!!
I thought I was gonna die!
Killed you, my foot!
You two were hugging each other!
Rina! The Dagger of Yatto
has been stolen!
St. Tail!
Damn!
I'm sorry, but I'm taking
the dagger with me!
One!
Two!
Three!
What?!
Goodbye Mr. Detective.
It's been fun, thank you!
She did it again, St. Tail!
Damn it! Show me you face!
St. Tail!!
Hey you, what do you think
you're looking at?!
Thanks to you, I can't see a thing!
Stupid! Stupid! Super Stupid!!
Who are you calling stupid?!
We could've caught her,
if you held onto her tighter!
I don't want to have to use
tear gas to catch her.
What did you say?
I'll say this one last time!
I'm the one who will capture
St. Tail!
Suit yourself! Humph!!
Hey, wait!
Ouch!
I left security for this place
up to him because he's your son!
I trusted him, but...
Are you listening to me?!!!
Do you know how valuable the
Dagger of Yatto is...
both as an archeological
and artistic treasure?!
It's so valuable, that no monetary
value could be placed on it!
How are the police going to take
responsibility for this?
Ah... it's a nice painting.
Don't tell me this is an imitation, too?
What?!
I've already investigated.
I hear that your Dagger of Yatto
is a genuine replica.
Getting the police involved
in your conspiracy...
that's taking it a bit too far!
"IT WAS A FAKE!"
What a stupid thief,
stealing a replica.
She ends up stealing for nothing.
That's not the point.
Huh?
She knew...
She probably was helping
somebody out again.
Are you stupid?!
And just how would you know!
I know...
because I've been chasing
her all this time.
Oh, is that so?!
St. Tail, I'll reveal your
true identity!
You were crying last night,
weren't you?
How did you know?!
'Cause your eyes are red.
Why did you cry?
Shut up!
Hey, tell me why.
It's none of your business!
Men have a lot things to
attend to.
I know, it's because you're always
dedicated to the job you 're doing.
It's because you're kind.