Someone help me!
It's St. Tail!
She's heading for the
exit on the first floor!
Just as I suspected.
I know she'll come out this way!
Here she comes!
I've got you now, St. Tail!
Darn it!
Asuka!
Takamiya!
Better luck next time!
Be seeing you!
She's getting away again! Darn it!
Dolphins Vs. Eagles
St. Tail dropped these?
Pinch!
Beware of Lost Objects
My form's not all that bad.
Sorry.
I shouldn't have
done that in the chapel.
It's all right.
Excuse me.
Oh! Are you Oikawa, the pitcher
for the Southern Rainbow Dolphins?
You know me?
Of course, you're a celebrity!
I was until last month.
I'm on a losing streak now.
Don't give up.
My prayers are with you.
Thanks.
And what brings you here today?
Oh, nothing.
I may not be of much help...
you can share your troubles with me.
The truth is I lost my lucky glove.
What?!
Strike three! You're out!
The daughter of our owner's
friend wanted my autograph.
May I have your autograph?
Sure thing.
I asked her to hold the glove
while I signed her board.
But then, both she and
my glove disappeared.
This was the glove I had used
when I pitched a no-hitter.
It brought me luck, and
I'd been using it ever since.
I see.
Our next game is for the championship.
I came here to pray for her to return it.
When is the game?
This Sunday, against the Eagles.
Have faith, the Lord
is looking out for you.
...and that's why I want you
to get his glove back.
OK, Seira.
The truth is...
...ta-da!
I've got tickets to Sunday's game!
What? Oh no!
What's wrong?
I lost the tickets to
the Dolphins game!
I didn't know you
were a baseball fan.
No, it's not for me.
Remember math class the other day?
Your score is terrible!
If you score below 30 again...
I'll revoke your recess and
you'll have to go to study hall.
What?
Tough luck!
Mister Asuka!
Yes, ma'am.
I want you to tutor Miss Haneoka.
What?!
Having an honor student
tutor her should help.
-Oh, no! Not him!
-Oh, no! Not her!
Enough of that! This is not
a request, it's an order!
I don't quite remember the incident,
but how lucky for you.
That's not luck! Do you know
what he did after class?
You know, I'd really like to see the
next Dolphins game at the Big Dome.
Let's make a deal, Miss Haneoka.
Are you telling me to treat you?
Or you can stay in
study hall during recess.
See you.
No, no! It'll be my
pleasure to treat you!
The creep had me cornered!
So you have a date with him.
You must be looking
forward to Sunday.
Don't be ridiculous!
It was blackmail.
I had to beg Papa for the tickets!
And after all that, I've lost them.
What should I do, Seira?!
Well, anyway, let's go
look for them tomorrow.
Tickets to the Dolphins game?
I must have dropped them.
Have you seen them around?
No.
Neither have I.
Too bad.
The Dolphins are so popular.
I doubt you'll get more tickets.
Shh! Don't talk so loud.
He might hear you!
Hey, Haneoka!
Don't forget about Sunday and
I promise you'll score 100 on the test.
She promised to take
Asuka to that game.
What?!
You're going with him?
You two are always fighting!
What gives?
It's not like that!
I can explain!
Oh?
Um, anyway, I lost the tickets!
The tickets St. Tail dropped,
and the tickets Haneoka lost...
are for the same Dolphins
game. Could she be...
Now I remember! I had them
with me on that last caper!
That's it, I must have lost them
while I was escaping.
Good show, Meimi!
That was a 10!
No, I just got lucky, that's all.
I think I overdid it.
Such technique...
Quite extraordinary. It must be her.
There it goes!
Get it, Asuka!
Who picked him to be goal keeper?
Asuka, are you alive?
Hey, what's this?
"Tonight, I will enter
the Uehara residence...
for pitcher Oikawa's glove.
Signed, St. Tail."
Hey, Asuka, it's a
challenge from St. Tail.
Do you hear me?
Snap out of it, Asuka!
I just don't get it,
both St. Tail and Takamiya!
Why are they always after this guy?
Pay attention, will you?
Meimi Haneoka...
you're mighty suspicious.
Now, to go look for those tickets...
Where do you think you're going?
I... I have to go somewhere.
No way!
The test is tomorrow!
Solving trigonometry problems
is like a criminal investigation.
You find each and every clue,
fit them into place, until...
Bam! See, you've
solved the problem.
Is detective work all
you ever think about?
Mathematics is one of the
foundations of detective work!
Is arresting St. Tail
that important to you?
Well, is it?
None of your business.
What's that mean?!
It's between St. Tail and me!
Why can't you tell me?
Sorry.
Now, the next problem...
The angle of a figure on a flat plane...
all the points at a given distance...
Hey! Hey!
Miss Haneoka!
I'd like to speak to you.
What is it, Miss Takamiya?
Here.
Aren't these yours?
Actually I found these the other night.
Do you want to know
where I found them?
Um, thanks, but these aren't mine.
Oh, really?
Well then, I guess I'll
keep them for myself.
Asuka is a big Dolphins fan, right?
I'm sure he'll be happy to go,
if I ask him. Bye!
Rats!
What'll I do?
The game's this Sunday
and I don't have the tickets!
And of all people,
why'd Rina have to find them?
I've got to get those tickets back.
But I could get caught. Still...
Still...
Don't forget!
He was so excited about going.
I can't just tell him it's off.
I said no! This is mine and
I'm not letting anyone take it!
But you have to put
the glove on that table.
No!
What's so important about this table?
Don't!
What is this stuff?
A special fluorescent paint.
I'm using it to expose St. Tail.
Why are you so obsessed
with St. Tail, anyway?
I told you, I'm going to
become a detective...
and I'm not letting that ridiculous
petty thief get the best of me!
A ridiculous petty thief, eh?
Give it to me!
No!
I've got a great idea.
This time, we do a double-cross!
Oh, Lord, forgive me, for
I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
May the blessings of God be with us.
Be careful, remember
your last caper.
I will.
We've got you!
The real glove is at the Big Dome!
Grab her!
Did we get her?
Sure did!
Turn on the lights!
What?!?
It's a dummy!
Damn! She got past us again!
So, it was a trap.
Oikawa's glove, huh?
Boy, you're lucky that I'm a big fan.
Too bad, you can't have it!
Asuka...
I have tickets to the Dolphins game.
Takamiya!
Will... will you go with me?
Sorry, but I'm already
going with Haneoka.
Oh, really? I just hope she
remembers her promise.
What?
I know who St. Tail is.
Shall I tell you?
Oh no!
No!
Don't you want to know?
I just want to capture her.
I don't care who she is. I just
want to capture her on my own!
A breeze?
The dome roof is...!
St. Tail!
Good evening!
How'd you know we were here?
Never mind that, quickly, arrest her!
And here's the first pitch!
It's Show Time!
Help!
And we're already in the 7th inning.
Asuka, do something!
It's out of my hands.
I'm sorry!
Oh, be quiet! Stop your bawling.
All right, let's end
the game, shall we?
One!
Two!
Three!
I'm giving this back
to pitcher Oikawa.
You may be his fan,
but taking his glove was wrong!
What?
She stole the glove?
I'll never do it again.
And I'll take these back, too!
Darn.
St. Tail! Wait!
Goodbye!
Thank you, my love.
Man! How many times
do I have to tell you?
Listen, meet me at gate #2!
You listen! I don't know
where gate #2 is!
I told you, it's the
entrance on the North end!
And which side is North?!
Meimi Haneoka,
I'll get you next time.
And the championship game between
the Dolphins and the Eagles...
is about to start!
On the mound is Oikawa, who hasn't
been doing too well the past few games.
Let's see what he has
in store for us today.
Steerike!
Strike! You're out!
What a fastball!
Three strikes! Looks like
Oikawa is out of his slump.
All right!
Oikawa has struck out
three batters in this inning.
He's really looking good!
Sure is.
No! I just want to
capture her on my own!
I guess we have to thank St. Tail.
Why are you blushing? Weirdo.
You wouldn't understand.
It's very hot.
I love you!