Well?
Hi!
What are you doing, Haneoka?
There's going to be a contest.
A contest?
You know Miki from our class?
Yeah...
She's entering the Junior Design Contest
that the city's putting on.
And I'm going to
model the wedding dress!
Model? You?
She said I'm perfect for it.
I've already gone for the fitting.
I'm just waiting to see
the finished product.
And who's going to be the groom?
The Frog Prince?
Frog's Bride
How rude!
Asuka Jr., you're always
making fun of me!
It's nothing, I'm just being honest.
Why you!
Miss Takamiya...
Contest in Chaos
Is there something you want from me,
Miss Takamiya?
Oh, nothing.
I just happen to be going this way, too!
Don't mind me.
I see.
Darn. She got away.
Hush, Meimi.
You must be quiet in the chapel.
I finally got away from Takamiya.
She's been following me all over
the for place the past few days.
Really?
She's very persistent, isn't she?
By the way,
have you seen Miki?
My wedding dress
is supposed to be ready today!
She... came to see me about that,
just a little while ago.
She did?
Yes. The truth is...
What did you want
to talk to me about?
Someone stole the
drawing for my design.
Who'd do such a thing?
I think I know.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
I have such long legs.
Miss Suzushiro...
It's Suzushiro from Group E.
We're competing in the same contest.
Mami Suzushiro?
Yes.
I'm sure that's when it was stolen.
She's always thought
of me as a rival.
If she uses my design in the contest,
it'll put me in a difficult position...
because her presentation
comes before mine.
I don't know what to do.
Miki, don't lose faith.
The right will always be rewarded.
And that's what happened.
I see... and I was
looking forward to the contest.
Meimi, please get
her design back for her.
Alright! Leave it to me.
At least, I wish I could.
It's Miss Takamiya.
With her following me around,
I can't turn into St. Tail.
Don't give up hope.
You'll think of something, Meimi.
I'm trying!
I want to wear that wedding dress
and model in the contest too! But...
I understand.
I'll help you this time.
You will?
I'll fix you an alibi.
In the meantime,
you become St. Tail and get the design.
Hold on.
What do you mean by alibi?
First, you specify the contest's date
on the challenge to Asuka Jr.
Okay.
And then...
"...at the Conversational
English Seminar..."
Hey, Asuka, are you listening?
Be quiet, will you?
I asked you if you wanted to know
St. Tail's identity!
Are you still harping on that?
What a pest.
I told you what I think.
I don't care who she is!
I just want to arrest her!
All right then, I won't tell you.
Fine, I don't care.
Junior Design Contest.
So this is what Haneoka's
been worked up about.
What's so great about it, anyway?
"Tomorrow,
at the Junior Design Contest...
I will steal Mami Suzushiro's wedding
dress design drawing. -St. Tail"
Of all the nerve!
I've been waiting for this.
I knew she'd make a move.
That St. Tail...
she's after a wedding dress this time!
I'm going to follow
my own lead this time.
Good luck!
Huh, what?!
We'll soon learn
St. Tail's true identity.
Suit yourself!
You were so cute back then, Mama.
And you were a bit slimmer, Papa.
No magic will bring
back the old you, huh?
Of all the...
Change back,
change back, change back...
or something like that... wow!
Oh, it's you, Meimi.
Shame on you.
You're a professional magician.
That shouldn't catch you off guard.
Well, I... what's up, Meimi?
There's a wedding
dress contest tomorrow.
I'm one of the models.
She's going to get married
one of these days, isn't she?
It's too early
to start getting lonely, Papa.
Tomorrow, I have to
be St. Tail and a bride.
I've got to work hard at both!
What's wrong?
You want to go with me?
I'm sorry, Ruby, you have to stay home.
Hey you,
you better do a good job protecting me.
Sure, of course,
to some degree.
What do you mean,
'to some degree'?!
I mean, St. Tail is sure to appear
after the contest begins. That's why...
You're positive?
Yes, that's why you
can relax until then.
So, I'll see you later.
I think they can protect themselves.
Green Room 1
What are you doing here,
Miss Takamiya?
Nothing.
I was looking for a phone.
I have to call Asuka.
You there.
Me?
You're not wearing an ID tag.
Only models and contestants are
allowed in here. Please leave.
She's sticking to you like glue.
She's not moving from that spot,
not for anything.
Seira, are you sure it's all right
for me to participate?
You have nothing to worry about, Miki.
Right, hang in there.
Get out of the way!
You're in my way!
Is that Mami Suzushiro?
Yes.
That dress!
It's definitely the one I designed.
I won't let them get away with this.
Let's put on a good show,
shall we, Kono?
Yes. Of course.
See you later, then.
The city's Junior Design Contest
will soon begin.
Final preparations are being made.
All contestants,
please assemble on the stage.
I have to go.
I'll be there as soon as I change.
Don't worry, I'll help her change.
Thank you. I'll leave it to you.
Takamiya, you're welcome to watch.
Oh, gee, thanks.
Seira, let's get going.
Okay.
She's changing.
We've got to be quiet.
Oh Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!!
Oh, dear!
Transforming into
St. Tail quietly is so hard!
Meimi.
Oh Seira, you're beautiful!
Once I put on the wig and veil,
everyone will think it's you.
Oh dear, and I'm supposed to be a nun.
I'm counting on you to put on
a good act and keep Takamiya here.
I will, be careful too.
May the blessings of God be with us.
What are those two doing in there?
Miss...
Judging by your looks
you must be one of the models.
The contest is starting.
You'd better change.
But, I'm...!
Is this your dressing room?
No.
Then it's this way.
W... Wait a minute!
You're making a mistake!
Meimi, now's your chance.
Okay.
I thought I saw a black shadow there.
It must have been your imagination.
Oh boy.
Show's starting.
I'm so nervous.
Me, too.
Everything is going good so far.
Now for the hard part.
We will begin the judging at this time.
Entry #1.
Hey!
No!
My design!
Look! What's that?
When is she going to
turn into St. Tail, I wonder?
Hurry up, Meimi.
Haneoka, don't you have to go?
Yes, but my number is last.
Hmmm.
Oh, Meimi, please hurry!
Whoah!
Good evening!
Please, God!
We are experiencing a power failure.
For your safety, please remain seated.
St. Tail is here in the hall!
What are you doing?!
That's impossible!
Haneoka's still here.
Meimi.
The entire hall is in an uproar,
but stand by, okay?
Okay.
Takamiya?
Phew. They're gone.
Now, I've got to get this ready.
Everyone, quiet, please.
What's going on there?!
That's the dress.
It's Show Time!
Hey! Wait! What is this?!
Sorry, you have to wear that instead.
I'm taking the design.
I'm giving this back
to the real designer.
What?!
Don't just stand there, get her!
Just hold it! What does she mean,
'real designer'?!
Um...!
And this is in apology
for causing such a commotion here.
Wow!
Bouquets?!
For the future brides.
Hold it!
Bouquets from St. Tail!
I want one too!
Ooh, they're beautiful!
Outta my way!
Let me through!
She got away.
And what are you doing?!
None of your business!
Junior Designer Contest
There, it's finished.
Fly up high.
Asuka!
She's heading for the exit!
She got away again.
Where's Meimi?
Takamiya!
Now where's she going?
Green Room 1
Impossible.
What'd you come back here for?
Well, Asuka Jr., isn't she beautiful?
For goodness sake, say something.
Miki, that's enough.
Yeah, really beautiful.
Really very beautiful...
Your design that is.
Oh my, thank you.
But that's not what I meant!
So... So that's what St. Tail was after!
He's trying to change the subject.
How typical of a man.
Asuka, let's go.
O... Okay.
Entry #30, you're up next.
Report to the stage immediately.
Meimi, let's go.
Yes.
Hey, Takamiya,
you can go without me.
Asuka, where are you going?
It's none of your business!
Bye!
And the winning entry in
the Junior Designers Contest is...
#30, Miki Kono's design!
Miki, you did it!
Congratulations!
Meimi!
It's not fair!
A wedding dress sure is mysterious.
It even makes Meimi seem different.
And what if she's St. Tail?
What?
I'm asking you how you'd feel
if she was St. Tail?
What are you talking about?
That's a really bad joke.
It's no joke.
I'll even make a bet on it.
Stop it! Is that why
you've been following her around?
She's one of your classmates.
All right, how about this then?
If Meimi isn't St. Tail,
then I'll stop following her.
You promise?
But if I'm right, you'll have to date me.
What?
Well?
You promise you'll stop following her?
All right.
There's no way...
that Meimi is St. Tail.