Good morning!
Good morning, Meimi.
That was some design contest.
You took first place!
It was a good design.
I know that!
It was such a gorgeous dress,
I wish I could wear it!
I'm sure Miki will let
you if you ask her.
You think so?
Then I'll go ask. Bye!
I told you!
I told you I haven't heard anything!
Asuka, wait.
We have a bet, remember?
A bet?
Your part: when you get a challenge
from St. Tail, let me know right away.
Don't try to cheat me!
I'm not going to cheat!
Geez!
What's going on?
Hello.
"You Confessed?!"
Good morning.
Good morning. You're looking well.
Um, I'm sorry, I
couldn't help overhearing.
Do you and Junior have a bet going on?
Is it for ice cream?
Or maybe a hamburger?
You really want to know?
At the contest the other day...
If Meimi isn't St. Tail,
then I'll stop following her.
You promise?
But if I'm right, you have to date me.
What?
Well?
What's that supposed to mean?
Which means, if I prove you
are St. Tail, then I win the bet.
I don't give up easily.
In y=-2x+4 reversed,
y equals one hour.
Furthermore, in 2x+y=4, x equals...
Why?
Why'd you make such a bet?
Miss Haneoka? Miss Haneoka!
Miss Haneoka!
Were you paying attention?!
Come here and solve this problem!
Yes.
That's because
you're always daydreaming.
Stupid!
What's with her?
I see.
And I thought we did such a good job of
fooling Miss Takamiya at the contest.
I just don't understand.
Why'd he make the bet?
I...
I certainly don't
want to be caught now!
You mean you wanted to at one time?
Of course not!
Okay.
Recently, a man came
to me seeking help.
I didn't know if I should tell you.
His name is Mr. Kanamori.
His grandfather had
recently passed away...
leaving him a jewel in his will.
And then?
Then some relatives rewrote the will
and took the jewel from him.
How cruel.
They have lied to him,
saying they will put it in safekeeping.
But in actuality,
they have put it up for sale.
Mr. Kanamori went to see those relatives
to get his jewel back.
Uncle, Aunty! I'm begging you!
Please, give it back! Please!
He desperately wants to get
the jewel before it is sold.
I wish I could help,
but Miss Takamiya is...
The way things are going,
she and Asuka will never settle the bet.
Because St. Tail won't be caught easily.
But then Miss Takamiya
will keep following me.
What should I do?!
Don't worry.
Leave it to me.
I have an excellent idea.
I'm home!
I'm home.
Ruby.
Are you all right?
Hey, Meimi!
Yes?!
What is it, Papa?
You said you like my hands because they
look like a magician's hands, didn't you?
Yes.
Then... take my hand.
Like this?
Yes. And then...
I know!
You want me to close my eyes,
you've thought up a new trick!
I'll count to three,
then you can open your eyes.
Okay.
You ready?
One!
Two!
Three!
Mama! How'd you do that?
This is great!
Isn't it? I'm sure this trick will be a hit.
This sort of trick
has been done before.
But never while holding hands.
This is great!
Absolutely fantastic!
Show me how to do it!
No.
Why not?
Because it is the fruit of our labor.
You could say it is a symbol of our love.
Hey, Dad!
Wake up!
I thought you were leaving early!
You're gonna be late!
Jeez. And he just has
to have ham and eggs on Wednesdays.
I will visit Kanamori's house tonight
to steal the jewel.
Why's the note burnt?
Cuz it was in my breakfast.
Oh, never mind.
I have a great idea.
We lure St. Tail into our trap by
playing on her weakness.
You'll help, won't you?
I don't know what your plan is.
But I want no part of it if it's sneaky!
Oh, all right.
If you won't help, I'll do it myself.
But...
You do want to settle our bet, don't you?
Then don't interfere.
Give me your word.
This will just be between
St. Tail and me.
Have it your way!
Lord forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!!
Meimi, take this.
What?
Did you concoct another of
your strange colognes?
It will come in handy tonight.
May the blessings of God be with us!
No! Never! Absolutely no way!
Why do I have to go outside?!
You promised, remember?
You said you wouldn't interfere.
You're not going back
on your word, are you?
Now Asuka, you wait
outside the room. Hurry up!
Is everything under control?
Yes, sir.
Shouldn't we guard the inside, too?
No, just the outside.
Those are Miss Takamiya's orders.
Darn that Takamiya!
She got her nerve, ordering me around!
Okay, he's here alone. He's my target.
Hello.
Sorry, but I need your cooperation.
It's so dark.
That must be the heirloom!
Strange. Asuka Jr. isn't here.
Asuka Jr.!
What happened?!
Who did this to you?!
Fooled you, didn't I?
Saint Tail.
Takamiya!
Now, let's see your face!
Asuka! I know you're here!
We're finally going to see her face!
The switch... is over there!
Hurry, turn on the lights!
St. Tail is...
One!
Two!
Oh no!
You're not getting away!
Three!!
Asuka, hurry, turn on the lights!
I'm arresting her!
Don't interfere!
Take a look...
this is St. Tail!
What went wrong?
I was right, wasn't I?
A moustache?
A man!
St. Tail's... a man?
It wasn't Meimi. It's a man.
One...
two...
three.
I wonder if I overdid it.
Sorry, I'm taking this jewel.
I thought I heard St. Tail's voice.
Nah, probably just my imagination.
The cat-burglar... I've been
after all this time... is a man.
And a transvestite at that.
It can 't be true.
"I must speak to you, but you
must promise not to come close to me.
Please come to D Park.
-St. Tail."
Me?
I really don't want to see that man.
But I guess I'll go see what he has to say.
Good evening!
I'll bet you had quite a shock.
You guys were trying to trap me.
That's why you were punished.
Take that!
A girl!
If you've had enough, don't try to
discover my identity any further.
Just forget all about it.
I know it seemed like
I was in cahoots with Takamiya...
but there was nothing I could do.
We had a bet.
A bet?
Takamiya made this bet.
If I won...
she promised to stop
following Haneoka around.
Haneoka's one of my classmates.
Sure, she's kind of noisy...
but I don't think following her
around all the time is right.
That's fine.
That's not why I'm angry.
I'm gonna arrest her!
That's not...
Oh, did you want to be caught?
what I meant...
I didn't want to be caught by her!
If... If I...
If I'm going to be caught by anyone,
I want to be caught by you!
That's all.
Goodbye!
What did she mean by that?
Anyway...
What a relief! St. Tail's a girl!
I'm not telling Takamiya about this.
St. Tail was a man!
Which means I win the bet, Takamiya!
Yes. You're right.
You'd better keep your word.
I will.
See you later.
Oops!
What kind of bet?
If I'm going to be caught by anyone,
I want to be caught by you!
What's gotten into me?
She's nowhere near here.
None of your business!
You're always so rude!