A little to the right. Lower...
Saint Paulia School Festival
St. Paulia Academy's festival
is almost here.
Our school has a little ritual
that has become a tradition.
Tada! Feast your eyes.
This is Mikami's locker key.
Really? The real thing?
I'm gonna hang it up on the roof.
Meimi, what's this about a lock?
It's a charm.
Honestly Seira, you're so dense
when it comes to things like this.
Okay? If there's a boy you like,
you get hold of his lock...
then attach it to the fence
on the east side of the roof...
then, at the festival's finale,
that boy will ask you to dance.
So that's why that fence
is covered with locks.
That's right. It proves that you have
his feelings locked to yours.
The big problem is how to get
the lock there in the first place.
Ryoko, please, please
ask Yamamoto for me.
What? No way!
Hey, I've got the curtain!
I wonder if he's
already given his lock to someone.
Asuka, put your leg in here.
What for? Like this?
Heave!
Hey! Hey! What are you guys doing?!
Junior in a bag, ready to go!
Do you think doing this kind
of thing to someone is funny?!
I guess I have
nothing to worry about.
The Scoop Picture Causes
Trouble at the School Fair
Is anything troubling you?
You can tell me if you like.
Miss Mimori... I mean, sister,
have you heard?
About how to get a partner
for the festival's dance party?
Oh that, yes.
Lucky, I just heard about it.
A friend of mine asked me
to get this boy's lock for her today.
But when I went to talk to him, Sawatari
from the school paper took our picture.
Sawatari!
Yeah, that shot was okay.
Sawatari, wait!
What are you going
to do with that picture?
Put it in the school paper, of course.
I'll call it 'The Trading of Love Tokens'.
How's that?
You can't do that.
I was only doing a favor for a friend.
That won't show on the picture,
so it's not my problem.
You can't...
The problem is,
I already have a boyfriend.
If that picture is published,
it'll cause a huge misunderstanding.
That's terrible.
Sawatari is that guy who will
do anything for a story, isn't he?
He's also quite popular
with the girls in the school...
Yes, I know. I hope there's some way
we can get that film from him.
Alright, I'm all fired up!
St. Tail will teach that enemy
of girls a lesson!
The big problem is,
we don't have much time.
Can you send your challenge out
before he develops the pictures?
I understand.
But when will be a
good time to do the job?
Let's see.
The Festival is the day after tomorrow.
All the students will be staying late.
Everyone's free to wear
a costume during the festival.
That should be the perfect day.
Huh?
It wouldn't look suspicious to see
one or two people dressed as St. Tail.
That's right!
What?!
A St. Tail costume?!
That's right! See!
We made it for you because, being so
athletic, you're perfect for the part!
Now wait a minute.
Let's rehearse for tomorrow.
You're right. Let's dress her!
And your hair has
got to be in a ponytail!
Hey! Hold it!
Relax, just relax.
This is just plain silly.
Don't fidget.
You girls! You have got to be joking.
You're ruining the image of St. Tail!
What did you say?!
What exactly did you mean by that?
Exactly what it sounded like.
How rude!
And I thought I'd
get a cute shot of you.
But I think that big piece of junk
got in the picture, too.
Don't refer to me as a piece of junk!
It's Sawatari, now is my chance!
Oh well.
Here, a present for you anyhow.
This is...!
"I will come to the
school festival to take Sawatari's film."
It's a challenge from St. Tail.
Really? You're kidding.
A big piece of junk in the way, eh?
Journalism Club
You're a real pest, aren't you.
St. Tail says she's
coming for your film...
I can protect my own stuff.
You think I'd trust the guy
who keeps letting St. Tail get away?
I'm not giving up!
You're always trying to be
the center of attention.
You're beneath my concern, Asuka.
For the time being,
I've got to hide the film someplace.
I guess the locker
should be okay for now.
Sawatari!
Hey, what are you all doing?
We'd like to have your lock.
Gee, sorry, but I only have one.
That's okay! We bought you some!
What?!
There!
Put these on his locker.
Just a moment, and...
your new locks!
Sawatari
What is this...?!
And don't you dare take them off!
I don't think I have a choice.
We'll come take them off later.
They shouldn't make
so many of these things!
Darn! This is stupid! Where am
I gonna hide this film?!
Asuka
Boy, Asuka sure is careless.
Wait a minute.
Maybe I'll stash the film in here.
I doubt any of the
girls would want his lock.
It's probably safer in here.
What are you doing there?!
Isn't that Asuka's locker?
I... well... it's not...
Why did you do that?!
Now it's locked!
Now I can't get Junior's lock!
What?
Darn. And I wanted
to dance with Asuka.
You've got to be kidding.
What did you put in there?
Oh, just something
I didn't want to get stolen.
What on earth are you talking about?
Wow. I let a girl catch me off guard.
I'm sure he was after
another of his silly stories.
Aha. So the film's...
in my locker.
What are you going to do
with the lock, anyway?
Oh, nothing in particular.
So, will you let me remove your lock?
What? Yeah, sure.
Oh, no!
You're going to give it to her!
On second thought, you can't.
Hey, why not?
Could it be?
I kinda forgot the combination.
Huh? Where'd they go?
Saint Paulia School Festival
The preparations took forever,
but once it got started...
time passed so quickly.
It sure did. It's almost getting dark.
Where's Meimi?
Now that you mention it, where is she?
She's goofing off somewhere.
Lord forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
May the blessings of God be with us!
It's getting dark. Isn't it almost time?
They said it's the real St. Tail.
You're kidding!
Eek! It's St. Tail!
Over there?
Sorry.
I'm not letting you get away today!
So, there you are, St. Tail!
What?!
We're the St. Tail trio!
St. Tail's in the 2-A classroom!
What was that?
She had a lot of nerve,
appearing in MY class.
Eek! St. Tail's
in the audiovisual room!
What?!
Darn!
St. Tail's in the connecting walkway!
What?!
Oops!
Darn you, St. Tail!
Is this where you are, Saint Tail?!
Hurry up and Join!
One Million Saint Tails Planned.
Yes it is!
Give me a break!
Stop dressing everyone
up like St. Tail!
Spoilsport.
Every girl in school!
Hey, isn't that St. Tail?
Where?
Where's St. Tail?!
Our decoy operation was a success.
Everyone's gone.
The film's mine now.
The festival's finale will soon begin.
All those interested in
participating please change...
and assemble on the school grounds.
I want this lock.
Sure, it's just a silly superstition,
but what if it does come true?
Hold it right there!
St. Tail!
You thought everyone was out
on the grounds, didn't you?
But you couldn't fool me!
Asuka Jr.!
Don't move!
And don't forget me,
hand over the film, you little thief!
One, two, three!
What's this?!
Geez! Asuka, what's going on here?!
You're playing dirty, St. Tail!
Would you mind... if I took this lock?
What the heck are you talking about?
Take it for all I care, just
come out and fight fair and square!
Thanks.
Let's see, the east side is...
Perfect!
St. Tail!
Now you'll get yours!
It's St. Tail!
Where?
Over there!
It's the real thing!
You're kidding, really?
I'm trapped!
There's nowhere to go!
Give me back my film!
Ladies and gentlemen!
Please forgive this commotion!
What is that?
A balloon?
Someone's floating up there.
And in a bag, no less.
It's Junior-in-a-bag. And...
Sawatari-in-a-bag!
You idiots!
Don't just stand there like dummies!
St. Tail, put us down!
One, two, three!
St. Tail disappeared!
Junior and Sawatari have also...
disappeared.
I return this to you.
Oh, the film!
Thank you very much.
We did it.
Wow!
Asuka!
How'd you do that?
Uh, she did it again.
Miss Haneoka.
Are you alone?
Yes...
Will you dance with me?
It's no fun dancing by yourself.
I... um... no, thank you.
But why not? Come on, let's go.
But, I...
What'll I do?
I was going to ask Asuka Jr.
Hold it!
I said hold it!
Ouch!
Hey! What's going on here?
I... but... it hurts,
you don't have to pull so hard!
You'd better explain that!
You're always whacking
me with a broom...
so why couldn't you tell
him to back off there?
If you didn't want to go,
you should have made it clear!
I know.
Oh, you don't hate me, do you?
The charm...
it actually worked!
Rats! Darn that St. Tail!
I'll make you pay for this!
Ouch!