Good morning!
Good morning, Meimi.
Good morning.
Good morning. It's getting
so cold these days.
Of course it is.
Christmas is almost here.
Christmas. Wouldn't it be nice
if it snowed?
It certainly would.
Has anybody noticed how quiet
the class has gotten lately?
And the reason is
right over there.
Asuka Jr.?
He hasn't received any notes
from St. Tail lately.
And that's why
he's been down in the dumps.
I understand how he feels.
He misses the chase.
Is that why he's so gloomy? How silly.
Cheer up, Asuka Jr.!
Oh. It's only you, Haneoka.
How rude.
So what if St. Tail doesn't appear?
It only proves
the world is at peace.
Shut up.
How can you jabber so much
first thing in the morning?
That's why I can't stand
the girls in this class.
What do you mean by that?
You're all nosy, loud-mouthed
and unfeminine on top of that!
Okay, then tell me
what's your ideal girl like, huh?!
Come on, tell me!
It's not you, that's for sure!
There's no such thing
as the perfect girl.
Yes, there is!
Take St. Tail, for example.
What's wrong with you?
It's always St. Tail, St. Tail.
Idiot!
Meimi?
You moron!
I hate you!
I'm St. Tail.
And if I'm her, then why...
Surprise!
The Large Lizard Santa Claus?!
Mayu, isn't it?
There's no one here but me.
You can tell me
your problem now.
Sister, Goh stole Tama from me.
Goh?
He's in my class
and he's so mean.
I'm not even bothering him...
but he kicks my blocks
and hits me with the ball.
And he's the one
who stole your pet, Tama?
Uh huh.
Did you tell your mother?
But Mama hates animals.
She said he should keep Tama.
I see.
I really love Tama.
I understand. Don't cry.
I'm sure God will help you.
Really?
And that's the story.
Goh is really Gohta Ogasawara.
He's five years old.
And he lives on the hill
on the outskirts of town.
And what does Tama look like?
She's black in color and
has a ribbon around her neck.
I think she'll be easy to spot.
Alright. I guess I'll go now.
Wait, what about a
note to Asuka Jr.?
Forget it.
Who cares about that promise?
That means
you'll be breaking the promise.
I don't care!
Meimi...
He only thinks of St. Tail!
I'm not sending another
note to that guy. Not ever!
The bully's room
should be underneath me.
Pardon me.
So you're the little meany.
You'd better start
thinking about how girls feel.
Or you'll end up like
a certain blockhead I know.
Phew. Gee, I almost forgot.
Now, where's that Tama?
Here Tama... Oh, Tama...
Black in color,
with a ribbon. It can't be, can it?
TAMA
Are you Tama? I thought you'd
be a cute little black cat.
What'll I do?
I'm too scared to touch it.
Which means I can't steal it.
This is ridiculous.
My reputation is at stake.
Tama, what's the matter?
Huh?
I'll call it quits for tonight.
I've got to get away.
Detective Asuka, over there.
After her.
It's St. Tail! After her!
Oh no!
We've got her cornered now!
Look out!
I warned you.
Oh, damn!
Detective Asuka!
Don't hang on to me!
I can't help it.
Let go of me!
-Don't do that, sir!
-Help, I'm sinking!
St. Tail appears!
But what is her target?
The mystery thickens!
Detective Asuka
misses the arrest by an inch!
It's been pretty long
since St. Tail's last caper.
I heard your Dad came close
to capturing her this time.
Isn't that right, Asuka?
Shut up!
She never sent me a note!
That's not my fault.
Who does she think
she's dealing with, anyway?!
Calm down, Asuka!
I was waiting for a note!
Why'd she do it
without letting me know?!
What'll I do?
It's all my fault.
Cheer up. I'm sure she just
forgot her promise to you.
She's not like that!
She'd never break her promise.
Then I'm sure she has
a very good reason.
Just mind your own business!
I don't want to hear your ideas
about St. Tail's motives!
What?! You'll never capture St. Tail,
not in a million years!
Oh, be quiet!
You don't know anything!
Oh, yes I do!
Liar!
Yes, I do!
Because I'm St. Tail!
Meimi!
Huh?
What was that about St. Tail?
Oh no...
Oh, brother,
I can't believe I said that.
Ruby, do you think
Asuka caught what I said?
SEIKA NEWS STATION
Good evening.
This is the Seika News Station.
Our first story this evening features
the city's Christmas Eve festivities...
Hey, you!
How'd you get in here!
You shouldn't be here!
Mama, come look at this.
What is it, Papa?
Isn't that Meimi's classmate on TV?
Where?
Give me a break!
I'll make it quick!
See? It's that smart kid.
The mayor's pride.
That's not possible right now!
You're right.
I wonder what he's doing.
Meimi!
Grump!
Ow! Get him!
Hey! Hey! That's my mic!
What is it, Mama?
St. Tail!
I have a message for St. Tail!
Meet me tonight at Park A!
Look, isn't that boy in your class?
I have a message for St. Tail!
Meet me tonight at Park A!
I'll be waiting alone!
I'm doomed.
If you don't come,
I'll reveal your identity...
...to the entire city!
There's no escaping those eyes.
Quick! Cut the cameras! Cut!
You hear me?!
I'll repeat it once more!
Please Stand By
SEIKA TV
St. Tail, eh?
I'll bet she's a beauty.
Just like when you were younger.
Hey, I'm still beautiful!
Meimi, what do you think?
Meimi? Huh?
You mustn't go. It's a bluff.
It might be one
of Asuka Jr's. tricks.
You're right.
Do you think I'm crazy?
If I'm going to be caught,
I have this funny feeling...
it'd be better if Asuka
was the one to catch me.
Meimi...
Do you think
I shouldn't go, Seira?
It wouldn't do any good
to stop you, would it?
But listen, Meimi.
You must never reveal your
identity to him on your own.
You must take him by surprise
as you've always done.
But...
We don't know how much
he really knows, do we?
Besides, you have
a job to do tonight.
I do?
Yes, for Mayu.
Oh, that's right.
I haven't gotten Tama back yet.
Poor Mayu. She's been waiting
anxiously for Tama.
You're right. But why
does it have to be tonight?
The truth is,
Mayu and her family are moving...
to another city far from here
tomorrow, Christmas Day.
She's moving away?
Mayu, just forget about it.
That's why tonight
is the last chance you have.
Alright, Seira.
Let's give her an
unforgettable Christmas.
Yes.
Meimi, when the time comes that
you're captured, we'll go together.
Lord, forgive me
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
May the blessings
of God be with us!
Maybe she wasn't watching TV.
Snow... It's going to be a white
Christmas. Brr... it's freezing.
Well, I guess
she's not going to show.
What's that?
St. Tail!
You must take him by surprise,
as you've always done.
I don't know what good it'll do but...
It's Show Time!
What is this?
Will you stop?
I've had enough of this!
Why do you think
I left that cell phone over there?!
Listen! I'm not leaving here,
so you can just relax!
Did you hear me?
Yes! But you said
you'd reveal my identity...
It was a bluff!
Oh, brother.
He doesn't know.
Never mind that.
Why didn't you send me a note?
How do I explain?
Is that why you called me here?
This is very important,
so listen!
You know what it means...
if you don't let me know
where you're going to strike.
It means I won't be there!
And that means... um... er...
let's put it this way...
What'll happen if
somebody else captures you?
I mean...
Oh... what I'm saying!
I...
I'm coming over.
What?
Forgive me, Seira.
You must never reveal
your identity to him on your own.
But... I...
Darn, the glass is
so fogged up, I can't see.
St. Tail.
Hello.
Uh, hello.
My promise...
I'm sorry I broke my promise.
I'll never do it again.
Yeah. Okay.
That's why...
What is it?
I don't want you to
give up on me.
I have to go.
St. Tail! Don't get caught
until I catch up with you!
Alright!
It's a promise!
Don't you forget!
Right.
"I am going to
the Ogasawara residence..."
"this evening to take
their pet, Tama - St. Tail."
Tonight?!
I don't have much time left!
Darn her!
I'm sorry,
but tonight's the only night.
Hey! Tama's not here!
"Don't be mean to little girls!"
Oh, shoot!
What's that?!
St. Tail has shown up!
Daddy, Mommy, wake up -
you gotta see this!
Santa is flying in the sky.
Santa is flying in the sky?
You must be dreaming.
What is that?
Santa Claus?
It's Santa!
Wow! Presents from Santa!
Police vehicle coming through!
Clear the street!
I repeat, clear the street!
Darn... she got away.
Mayu, forget about Tama and go to bed.
It's Tama! Tama's come home!
Tama, oh Tama!
I guess we have no choice but
to take Tama with us, right, Mayu?
Hurray!
St. Tail...
I'll get you
for sure next time!
Merry Christmas!