Ah... I wish there was a
great scoop somewhere...
Hazama Residence
Come on, hurry up!
I am!
Looks like we did it.
Yeah. The old lady didn't want anyone
to know about this mirror...
and once we put it up in
Thursday's auction, we'll be rich!
I hope we get a good price.
We will.
What's this...?
You got the appraisal?
Right here.
Hurry up and drive.
Okay.
Thieves...?!
This is my scoop!!
Mystical Princess Rosa's Mirror
My, it's such a finely crafted mirror!
It was made in the 17th century
for Princess Rosa of Reyche.
No wonder...
it's such a magnificent mirror.
The truth is, last night...
the mirror was stolen
along with its appraisal form.
There is a lovely legend regarding
the princess who owned this mirror.
Antique collectors around the
world are anxious to possess it.
If the word of its theft gets out...
I fear the collectors will do
anything to get their hands on it.
I merely want to live out my
life in peace with my mirror.
Then we can't notify
the police either, can we...
No, all I can do is pray that it's
returned to me without a scratch.
I understand.
Let us pray. I'm sure our
prayers will be answered.
And does she have any suspects?
Yes, the mirror could have only been
stolen by people in Mrs. Hazama's home.
She knows those two wanted it
and has no doubt they stole it.
She says they visited her the
other evening and after they left...
she noticed the mirror was gone.
It was there when they arrived.
You'll need to find out where they've
hidden it before you can get it back.
I know what I have to do Seira.
Leave it to St. Tail.
It's done!
It's all done!!
Good Morning Miss Haneoka!
Beautiful morning, isn't it?!
Oh, good morning Sawatari.
Oh, it's the latest school newspaper.
Look, the feature story is my scoop!
Mirror stolen from estate...
St. Tail is the thief?!
What's the matter, Haneoka?
Great, isn't it?
That's how I'll
strike a blow against St. Tail!
I've got more secret
information on this case, too!
Hey, what's going on?!
What are you doing! Let me go!
Hey, monkey boy!
Who are you calling a monkey?!
St. Tail would never do
anything like this and you know it!
You don't have any proof,
so don't print lies!
At any rate,
you'd better rewrite your story.
Th... they're right!
You wrote it without any proof...
so you're the one who's going to
look real bad in the end you know!
Why is she so upset?
Let me tell you something...
we reporters stake
our lives on our stories.
The universe could explode,
but we'd never rewrite our story!
He's hopeless.
I guess I have no other choice...
What the...?
"My target is Princess Rosa's mirror...?"
A... a scoop!
Hey, give it back!
No way!
A note from St. Tail is a great scoop!
I've got to go rewrite my story!
Excuse me ladies! Adieu! Adios!
What was all that
about never rewriting a story?
But it worked out well.
Now he won't write about
the mirror belonging to Mrs. Hazama.
I think he knows more about the mirror.
I've got to find out.
Journalism Club
Where'd Sawatari go off to anyway?
He's not here or in the classroom...
I've always been interested in journalism,
even when I was younger.
Really? You too, Miss Haneoka?
That's right!
Sawatari and Haneoka...?
I didn't know you were
interested in making the school paper.
Your constant enthusiasm
must have rubbed off on me.
Look around for as long as you like.
Girls are always welcome here.
Thank you.
Hey! Why am I hiding for?
Wow, is this your camera?
Did you take this photo
with this camera?
This is great!
There's a lot more! Want to see?
Yes! Wow!
You've even taken pictures of stars?
They're beautiful.
I feel like I'd be
intruding if I go in now.
But what I'm doing is eavesdropping...
I've put on a good act
pretending to be interested.
Now all I have to
do is get the information.
By the way, about that mirror...
Haneoka!
What's with him?
I'm so happy!
Wait...
Every girl who's come to me was
only interested in my good looks.
You're the first one who
showed an interest in my work!
You don't understand...
What am I gonna do?
Haneoka, if it's alright, would you...
Asuka Jr.! Why is he here?
Monkey boy, I want to talk to you.
That's not my name!
Besides, I have nothing to say to you!
He couldn't be jealous?
Sawatari, you know a lot more
about that mirror, don't you?
No, I guess not...
Reporters never reveal their sources.
The world could end,
but we'd never talk.
I'd like to hear more about it, too.
It must be a beautiful mirror.
It sure is!
There's a story about a
princess in the mirror's history.
And it sure is interesting.
I thought you said you'd never talk,
not even if the world came to an end.
Alright already.
You want to hear it too, don't you?
Party pooper.
The legend behind this mirror...
is a love story about
Princess Rosa of Reyche.
A love story?
I did some research and
learned that a long time ago...
Princess Rosa fell in love with a
young mirror maker from her village.
She was sad because
she knew their love could never be.
Then one day...
she asked him to make a mirror
that would reflect her true self.
Not the figure in royal robes.
And when the mirror was
finished and brought to the castle...
The woman reflected on
it was not Princess Rosa...
but a simple young maiden named Rosa,
her face filled with love.
The princess forsook her title...
and took only the mirror with her.
She left the castle
to marry the mirror maker.
And they lived happily ever after.
It has been said that any
woman possessing that mirror...
will live in happiness.
The real me...
A mirror that will reflect
the me that isn't St. Tail...
I guess that's why antique
collectors around the world...
especially women,
all want that mirror.
They can't even estimate
how much it will sell for.
And why would
St. Tail want that mirror?
As I suspected.
It's always about St. Tail.
That I don't know.
And this is top secret...
the mirror is being put
on the block at the city's auction.
What did you say?!
Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
I'm leaving now Ruby.
Seira, I want to ask you something.
Can you put a
stolen item up for auction?
Usually, no.
But the thieves also
took the appraisal slip with them.
So it's possible...
Take care of Ruby please.
I will.
May God bless and protect us.
This magnificent Evans violin...
has been sold for
20 million dollars to this gentleman.
Hey you, don't get in the way.
Tonight's the
night I capture St. Tail.
I gave you important information.
The least you can do is
let me photograph the auction.
The next item...
is something we collectors have
been searching for for a long time.
And now we have it!
The famous Princess Rosa's Mirror!
Amazing!
So that's the famous
Princess Rosa's mirror!
It's fabulous!
What's happening?
What happened to the lights?
What's going on here?
Wha...? A flower?
This flower is called...
The Princess Rosa!
It's Reyche's national flower!
They're lovely...
Oh, I get it!
It's part of the presentation!
This is great.
The ceiling!
Wait! That mirror was stolen!
Who said that?
It couldn't be the Princess' ghost...
Please, everyone,
please remain calm.
Good evening.
Please forgive my intrusion.
Where?
Where's that voice coming from?
If I'd been on the stage...
she'd have been in my
blind spot and gotten away.
I was right about staying right here.
Those two men stole that mirror.
Stolen property... so you didn't...
Now!
I think we're in trouble!
Now that you've been discovered,
why don't you be good and return it?
Damn you!
We worked hard to get it!
Alright, here's my chance!
I'm going to beat that St. Tail!
Damn!
It's Show Time!
It's too bright!
For you!
Brother!
One!
Two!
Three!
St. Tail, where are you?
A reflection of one's true image...
The lights are back to normal!
Darn! The mirror's gone!
Hey, look on the stage!
What?
The thieves?!
"I have taken
Princess Rosa's mirror, St. Tail. "
Darn.
It was so bright,
I couldn't take any pictures.
What's gonna happen to my scoop?
It was never meant to
be printed in the first place.
What?
What was that back there I saw?
Lord, thank you for
returning my mirror.
"St. Tail returns priceless mirror.
Mirror taken from auction block. "
What do you think?!
My scoop made the front page again.
He never gives up...
Good morning!
Good morning, Meimi.
Your hair looks nice today.
Really?
Maybe it does...
Were you at the auction last night?
I... um...
Did he catch on?
What do you mean?
It's me! I'm St. Tail...
Why?
Why are you asking me that?
As if I'd answer...
Oh, never mind.
Besides, it's unscientific to see
someone else's reflection in a mirror.
The lights blinded me for awhile...
maybe something happened to my eyes.
I must have been seeing things.
But if I was hallucinating, then why?
Why was it that I saw...
Haneoka?