All I can say is
what we have is true love.
Oh, Joseph.
Are you forsaking our love?!
I'll never forget you, Joseph!
Joseph!
It was an old movie, but I know why
Meimi's parents recommended it.
Yes, it was great!
Gee, how I hope I find
a love like that one day.
He kinda looked like Asuka.
Meimi, are you listening?
Huh? Oh, sorry.
Let's go out and find us
some fantastic boyfriends!
Yeah, let's go!
The Platform of Love and Tears
And how was the movie?
It was the best!
It was so touching.
It was a true love story.
They fall in love
despite their differences.
But in the end, they part.
Joseph!
The actor who played
Joseph was so handsome.
How sickening.
What's all this mush about?
How dare you eavesdrop on us!
Humph.
Why do girls always get so excited
when they talk about love and stuff?
You wouldn't understand
about true love!
And I don't care.
Of course you don't.
All you ever think
about is St. Tail.
What's that?!
Well, it's the truth!
Listen, I'm...!
Yeah, what?
Never mind.
Asuka Jr. ...
You've traveled all of
Japan on a bicycle?
Yes.
And I met Minako here in this city
on the last leg of my trip.
How romantic.
But then his bicycle...
Wow, that's so cool!
Not really, if you
have the determination...
you could do it as well, Minako.
Really?
Since you live in Japan,
you can try it anytime you like.
Then maybe I'll give it try.
Still, I'm really glad I got to
meet someone nice like you, Minako.
I've met a lot of people along
the way but none so nice as...
Hey, wait!
Wait!
Give me back my bike!
Who are you?!
Please open this gate!
Shut up!
John!
What is all the commotion?
Madame, these people
are demanding to be let in.
A boy took John's bike
and went into the gate.
That's why we...
Are you accusing
my son Tatsuo?!
That's right.
You must be joking.
Tatsuo has a first class American
bicycle, ordered especially for him.
My name is on that bicycle.
Please go check!
Enough!
I don't want to hear any more of
your ridiculous accusations!
Please leave!
I see.
We went back several times,
but no one would listen to us.
And since it concerns a child, John
doesn't want the police involved.
That bike was my best friend.
We'd been through good times
and bad times on our travels.
All we can do is wait for the boy to
return the bicycle on his own.
I understand.
Let us pray.
I'm sure our prayers
will be answered.
John and Minako.
They're in love, aren't they?
Yes, you may be right.
Such a dramatic meeting.
And their love will burn furiously,
only to end in a sad parting of ways.
Ah, Meimi...
Alright.
I'll take care of it!
Only we don't have much time.
John is returning to America
on the last flight this evening.
We have to get it back by then.
Very well!
I'll do everything I can
in honor of their love!
Meimi...
Dad is a pain.
He insists on eating Oden tonight.
Ah, this is my favorite...
I'll put a lot in.
"I will be at the Ninomiya residence
tonight to retrieve a bicycle."
"St. Tail."
How'd she know
this was my favorite?
Very good!
Ruby, that's fantastic!
Meimi, it's time for dinner!
Okay!
Yum. We're having Oden tonight.
Ruby!
There, Ruby's aerial
merry-go-round.
Wonderful!
Yes, you can use it
in your next magic show.
Would you like
to be part of my show?
Wow, look at all this stuff!
Take whatever you want.
And where's the bicycle?
Over there.
I don't care if that
bike gets stolen.
Do whatever you want.
But isn't it
supposed to be special?
Not really.
If that's how you feel...
we should have given it
to that bothersome American.
What? Yeah that's right.
Please take care of the situation.
Tatsuo Ninomiya
Now, why would St. Tail
want to steal this?
Lord forgive me, for I use
no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!!
In order for John
to make his flight tonight...
he must take the train by 9 pm.
9 pm at the station.
Okay.
May God's blessings be with us.
Alright, I want this room and
the house closely guarded.
Yes, sir!
It's?
It's Show Time!
What is this?!
This is...
Hi!
St. Tail!
What?
Taking what is not
yours is very bad!
I don't know what
you're talking about!
Oh, really?
Now do you remember?
I'm sorry!
It was so cool,
I couldn't help myself!
So you stole it!
Alright, you're forgiven.
St. Tail! Come on out!
Now for the real Show Time!
What happened?!
Stay calm!
Somebody go check the fuse box!
Hurry!
One!
Two!
This is the second floor!
Three!
Impossible.
A bicycle that flies...
Or something like that.
Now, I'll let the wind carry me
right to the station.
What?! You're not going to?!
Bring the patrol car around!
Oh yeah! I have an extra
balloon here somewhere.
You're not getting away
this time, St. Tail!
Here goes!
I did it! I got you!
Asuka Jr., look out!
Alright.
Oh dear, I've got to
put Asuka Jr. down somewhere.
Get down.
No way!
I need to borrow your bike!
Yes, sir.
Excuse me, what time is it?
Let's see... it's 8:50.
Thank you.
Hey... what was that?!
Darn!
Hold it!
Hold it! Hold it! Hold it!
Tatsuo Ninomiya
It's that kid's!
Hey, who's John?!
Hey! You idiot!
Phew. That was close.
St. Tail!
I'm not letting you get away!
I don't know why,
but I'm so happy.
Oh no... I've got to hurry!
That's... the train station.
Huh?
I want you to come to the airport.
I can't, John. It will
just make things harder.
John... so that means
it was his bicycle.
I didn't get my bike back,
but I'm glad I got to meet you.
I feel the same.
I think...
It's yours John!
But who brought it here?
Our prayers were answered.
John, we'll meet again, won't we?
We will.
I thought I'd never see
my bike again, but I did.
So I know you
and I will meet again.
John!
That's nice.
St. Tail.
Good morning!
Haneoka...
What's the matter?
You look so depressed.
It's none of your business!
What's with you?!
It wouldn't hurt you
to talk about it!
Humph. It's only love.
Oh, so Asuka Jr. is
in love with somebody.
Listen, you...!
We're gonna be late!
Oh, no!