You can't beat a hot bun
in winter, can you?
Mmm. It's the best!
Oh, my. Meimi, that big mouth.
It's really un-ladylike!
Well then, I'll just have another.
What?!
It's gone!
Those are my buns!
Give them back to me!
Meimi, wait a minute!
Hold it!
Look out!
Meimi, pull yourself together!
I'm so glad you're okay.
What's with that dog?!
Run After a Jewel Thief!
Little, The Naughty Dog
Little?
He's quite popular
at that park.
They say he goes off
with whatever he pleases.
With a name like "Little"
and a big body like that...
what a strange thing to call him.
But I feel sorry for Little.
Sorry?
Little's original owner was
transferred to work abroad...
because of his job.
Little was left with a friend...
but the friend's wife
didn't like him.
He doesn't get
any attention at all.
I see.
He's trying to get attention
by taking people's things.
This bun is really delicious.
Wasn't that good?
Here...
Go get it!
Little! Here we go again!
Fetch!
Are you alright?
Haneoka, what do you
think you're doing?!
Have you got some kind of
grudge against me?!
What?!
It's your fault for reading
the paper while walking!
I read the paper to gather
information on St. Tail.
Not very much help, is it?
She just keeps slipping
past you every time.
What's that?!
What about it?!
The Jewel Thief Appears!
Hey, you! Wait!
Hey, I said hold it!
Darn dog running
into a place like this.
I see.
He hides the things
he steals in that hole.
Little!
You shouldn't do
things like this!
Right?
You two...
There it is!
Hey, brother, that's it!
The raccoon stuffed-animal.
I'll go get it back.
What are you doing?!
Get to work!
Ouch! What are you doing, brother?!
Hey, Mister!
I'd like this stuffed animal.
Yes, welcome!
"Stuffed Toy Shop CHILD"
Here you are.
Thanks for waiting.
Little is an innocent, good dog.
Not the best looking, but...
Is it possible you're
jealous of Little and me?
Don't be stupid.
I like you best of all.
Akira, everything will be fine.
Your prayers will surely
reach God.
That boy, Akira, took the
stuffed animal raccoon from Yoko.
He likes her so much...
he probably did it
to get her attention.
Akira, regretting what
he had done...
tried to return the
stuffed-animal right away.
But someone stole the
stuffed animal from him.
Who would do such
a terrible thing?
Well, the culprit is a dog.
A dog?
Do you mean, Little?
We know that the stuffed animal
is somewhere in that park but...
Hold it!
I'll get that stuffed animal.
Meimi!
Little!
Maybe he's not here today?
That's strange.
He's not over here, either.
What?
The stuffed animal is gone.
Little!
Hey! Be quiet!
You idiot!
Why did you bring the dog along?!
What could I do?!
He wouldn't let go
of the stuffed animal!
Let's just get out of here!
Little!
Shut up! I just got
the baby to sleep!
Oh, it's alright.
I'm very sorry.
Little!
Little, where are you?!
Hey, be quiet!
You caused a lot of trouble.
He's the one that
made the mistake...
and put the toy out for sale!
Hey brother, let's stop doing
this stuffed-animal business.
We're supposed to be jewel thieves.
You idiot!
The stuffed animal-toy shop is
to camouflage the jewel thefts!
How dumb can you be?
Never mind!
What counts is that
the jewel is back.
We hide the stolen jewels
in the stuffed animals.
When things cool down...
we can take them to another
city and pawn 'em off.
It's a great racket.
The only thing left
is to get rid of the dog.
You're gonna kill him?!
That's outrageous!
Even if he's a dog...
we can't let anybody
who knows about us get away.
Little!
Where has he gone?
Hold him still!
Brother, I don't like
this sort of thing!
You imbecile!
Sorry.
After him!
Little...
Little!
You're alright, aren't you?!
Hey, that tickles!
Hey! Hold it!
Where have you been all this time?
Little!
Yipes! Get out of sight!
What's the matter?!
What? Is there something wrong here?
Okay, okay!
That's Yoko's raccoon!
Hey! What are you doing?!
Little, stop it!
Ah, may I take a look around
in this warehouse?
This place is off-limits.
Jerk.
What's that?!
Oh, nothing.
Thank you very much.
Can we just let
them go like that?
We've got no choice.
We'll have to change plans.
Mr. Asuka Jr.
St. Tail!
"I'll be picking up a
stuffed-toy raccoon..."
"from the number one warehouse.
- St. Tail."
A stuffed-toy raccoon?
What's she gonna do
with a thing like that?
Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Looks like it's necessary for St. Tail
to make an appearance after all.
But I wonder what the raccoon
is doing in a place like that?
That storage area is rumored
to be connected with criminal activity.
Be very careful.
Sure.
I'll be fine.
I'm only going there
to get that stuffed animal.
May the blessings of
God be with us!
Not even St. Tail would be able
to get past this security.
Well, there's no way into the
warehouse other than this door.
Don't underestimate St. Tail!
Stay on guard.
Yes sir!
Asuka Jr! What's that?!
What?!
St. Tail!
Everyone! Stay at your posts!
Yes, sir!
I've got you now, St. Tail!
A rubber doll?
Oh, no!
Asuka Jr!
One!
Two!
Three!
Darn it!
St. Tail has gotten
into the warehouse!
St. Tail, today I'll get
you for sure.
It's...
Show...
Time!
What's going on?!
Why?
Yoko's raccoon isn't here!
Darn it!
Oh, no!
Hold it! St. Tail!
Where could Yoko's
raccoon have gone?
Little?!
Why are you here?
Wait, Little!
Could the raccoon be here?
Someone's here!
Little!
This is bad! Hide over there!
You!
Where are you?! St. Tail!
You won't get away!
Thank you, Little.
Darn it!
What are you doing?!
You're jewel thieves, aren't you?
So what if we are?
Okay...
hand that thing over.
Hurry up and hand it over!
What! That mutt!
A diamond!
You...
Akira returned the
raccoon to Yoko.
They've really become close.
The jewel thieves
have been arrested.
So I guess we can consider
this case closed, right?
We owe it all to Little, don't we?
That's right.
Little deserves the credit.
That dog, why was he
at the warehouse?
Little...
I'll race you to that tree!
Ready!
Go!