We haven't dined out for a while.
Let's make the best of it
by eating something great.
But there's a long line everywhere.
Leave it to me! I know a place.
Well, here we are.
Tsujimoto Mansion? It looks pricey.
-Don't worry. Father's paying.
-What?
Are you sure it's okay?
I came here a few years ago.
Their rice gruel is delicious!
Reasonable prices, nice owner.
But something's strange.
Did they redecorate?
I'm sorry, but we don't take
customers without reservations.
I don't remember needing one.
Isn't the chef Mr. Tsujimoto?
That is correct,
but the owner has changed.
I'm Ohkura, the owner. Is there
something I can do for you?
Is it true you need
a reservation to eat here?
We only prepare meals for
three groups of customers per day.
So we refuse those
with no reservations.
That's why there's no line.
If you want to eat here, please make
a reservation and come again.
And when would that be?
Probably about three years.
-Three years?
-We look forward to your visit.
That owner has such a rude attitude!
Some cuisine critic must have praised
them and it's gone to their heads!
Well, well....
Let's get ahold of our feelings.
STEAL THE CHINESE IRON CHEF
Good morning!
That place has the greatest sauce!
-It's delicious!
-What's this?
A new octopus fritter shop
near the train station.
We're discussing whether that one
or the one near the park is better.
-What do you think?
-Maybe the one near the park.
See, I told you! That's a taste
that's hard to come by.
Since we've all agreed...
...let's stop by there after
school for a small snack.
How can you talk about that
so early in the morning?
-Something's wrong with your stomachs.
-What did you say?
Aren't I right? You're all going
to end up with faces like this:
How rude! And you're taking
forever to catch St. Tail!
Now you've said it!
You don't know if
they're friends or not.
Wasn't that Miss Sato?
Yes. She came to ask us
for help with her grandmother.
Her grandmother has been in the
hospital for a very long time.
Lately she's lost her appetite
and can't get out of bed.
Feeling sorry for her, Miss Sato
asked what she wanted to eat.
There was something she wanted
to eat again while she was alive.
-What could it be?
-Rice gruel.
-Rice gruel?
-Yes.
It's an unforgettable dish
an old boyfriend made.
The story goes back to when
the grandmother was young.
She fell in love with a young chef.
But they were destined
to be torn apart.
Goodbye. My parents have decided
on a fiance I am to wed.
Chiyo!
Ajinosuke!
That was the last time she saw him.
Recently she found out that
he became a famous chef...
...and opened a restaurant here.
But the grandmother is in no
condition to leave the hospital.
For her sake...
...Miss Sato kept going
to the restaurant.
But she hasn 't been able to meet him.
That's just terrible.
No, the one who 's terrible
is the restaurant owner.
Business has been bad
since the new owner took it over.
He's gone against every
wish the chef has.
He's even made sure that this story
hasn't reached the chef's ears.
Do you mean Tsujimoto Mansion?
That's right. The chef is Ajinosuke
Tsujimoto, the Chinese lron Chef.
But how do you know
of the restaurant?
Just a tiny incident.
The grandmother's wish is
to eat his cooking, but....
She really wants to see him.
Leave it to me!
St. Tail will make it happen.
Those girls only think about eating.
They have no sex appeal. What?
-Asuka, let's stop here before we go!
-Hey, guys.
-Look! It's a message from St. Tail!
-What?
"Tonight I will be stealing
the Chinese Iron Chef. -St. Tail"
Didn't think St. Tail was
a gourmet fan, did you, Asuka?
Sorry, guys. See you tomorrow!
You're saying that St. Tail's
going to steal the chef?
Well, that is a great honor.
Don't joke. You will cooperate
with us in her arrest, right?
Yes, most certainly.
Let me introduce you. Tsujimoto.
This is the Chinese Iron Chef
himself, Ajinosuke Tsujimoto.
This is Asuka Jr.
A pleasure. I am guarding you
from St. Tail today.
St. Tail?
Yes. Tonight, please do as I ask.
A master chef.
You little idiot.
Here.
Thank you very much!
-Delicious!
-Your name is Asuka, right?
-Yes.
-Is St. Tail really going to--?
Yes, but there's nothing to worry
about. I'm going to get her for sure.
I'm sorry.
Dad! What are you doing!
That's my line!
I came after St. Tail.
-St. Tail is coming here?
-Yeah.
-That's not good.
-What's wrong?
-You know of the Washington Treaty?
-Washington Treaty?
Oh, it's to protect animals
like koalas and pandas...
...from bad hunters, isn't it?
It forbids buying and selling
protected animals...
...and punishes poachers.
Right. And the owner of this
restaurant is breaking the treaty.
They're running a black market
of protected animals.
-A black market?
-Be quiet!
Did you get the evidence?
Can't you tell by looking
at this outfit? Kids!
Why'd I have to meet you?
If you've got a problem,
tell it to St. Tail!
Is something the matter?
Oh, it's nothing.
Ouch!
Dad, I'll remember this!
It's nothing.
Meimi isn't coming down?
She's got a ton of homework.
I was going to teach Meimi
some card tricks.
No, you don't. You're trying to get
Meimi to take after you again!
What's wrong with that?
She has talented hands, like me.
What? She got her talent from me.
As usual, they're getting along fine.
Ruby, be a good girl now.
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Be careful. There are many other
bad rumors about Tsujimoto Mansion.
Don't worry, I know!
May the blessings of God be with us.
-What's with all the police?
-St. Tail is supposed to come.
St. Tail? Then today's deal is--?
Don't worry.
Her target is the chef.
And don't you think a racket
like that is to our advantage?
Hurry and sit.
-Who are they?
-Today's customers.
-Are there others?
-This is all.
Then please close the shutters
until the meal ends.
I thought so. Just chickens.
Please enjoy this evening's feast.
What's this? A blackout?
-Turn the lights on!
-I can't! They won't go on!
The dinner will be put off
for another day!
Where are you, St. Tail?
Chef, don't let go of my hand!
That's the chef.
It's showtime!
What are these things?!
Chef! Take refuge in
the storage room! This way!
You won't escape.
Oh, no!
That's far enough, St. Tail!
You thought you cornered me,
but now I've got you!
Imagine catching St. Tail in
a place like this! What luck!
One! Two! Three!
Are the animals all right?
The animals--
I mean, is the chef all right?
The chef is fine as of now.
"I'll be taking the Iron Chef.
-St. Tail"
Darn!
This is a baby bald eagle
illegally imported into Japan!
This is....
A lesser panda!
That was wise of you to camouflage
these protected animals.
What are you talking about?
Cut the act.
You're under arrest, Ohkura.
What will you do with me?
-It's not me who wants to see you.
-Then who?
Your girlfriend from 50 years ago.
This is....
Here you are.
It's the same taste as
50 years ago, Ajinosuke.
Chiyo.
It's as if it were only yesterday.
The first time I met you, that is.
Excuse me.
Will you dance with me?
Yes.
Did you see today's paper? The animals
were returned to their homeland.
And Ohkura and the others
were arrested. Case closed!
I wonder what happened to the chef.
Tsujimoto Mansion was closed.
-Are you interested?
-Of course!
Chinese Food: Shanghai Tei
Seira, I'm really not
in the mood for noodles.
Isn't it Meimi and Seira?
-Asuka Jr.!
-I was thinking of having a meal.
I know the owner here.
Are you two going in?
I'll be passing this one up.
See you later!
-Seira....
-How about you?
Welcome! Oh, it's you.
-What does that mean?
-Is this a date with your girlfriend?
No, it's nothing like that!
It's empty as usual. At this rate,
you'll close down in no time.
Maybe I'll advertise around
town for you. The owner is--
-Don't do anything of the sort!
-Yes. I'm sorry.
That's....
-Here you go.
-Eat! The rice gruel here is the best!
-Delicious!
-Didn't I tell you? Let's eat!
Hot!