How about going to buy chocolate
after school today?
It's almost Valentine's Day.
I'll have to give some
obligation chocolates this year.
-Meimi, you're going too, right?
-Valentine's. What shall I do?
Aren't you giving
Asuka Jr. chocolate?
What? You're kidding!
What's that?
Is that how you really feel?
Someone's giving me chocolate?
"True love" chocolate?
You've got it wrong!
It's obligation chocolate!
I don't care which it is...
...but a better gift would be
a meat bun or octopus fritters.
What a kid! Valentine chocolates
aren't a 3:00 snack!
You won't get any
"true love" chocolates!
-Be quiet!
-What do you mean, be quiet?
-What's it to you?
-What do you mean?
Jeez!
Asuka, what are you doing?
That's no way to treat a lady.
You've got to be gentle.
It's Tohru Ijuin!
Hey, who's Tohru Ijuin
supposed to be?
You don't know?
Right now, Tohru Ijuin is...
...an ultra-popular guy
among the freshmen.
Sure! He models, always
in the latest magazines.
Then how could such a guy
know Asuka Jr.?
Who knows?
Oh, good morning!
I'm a freshmen in class A.
Tohru Ijuin.
THE HEART THIEF ON
ST. VALENTINE'S DAY??
Just know that I'm not friends with
this guy. We live near each other--
That's mean!
We played a lot together as children.
Be quiet, don't follow me!
In the first place, you're younger!
So why are you bigger than me?
Asuka, you're at it again?
He's always like this.
He absolutely despises my good looks.
-Pardon me! You're Tohru Ijuin, right?
-Yes, I am.
-Isn't she from another school?
-I think so.
-Please enjoy these cookies I made.
-Thanks.
And will you let me take your picture?
-Sure.
-Thank you!
Wait a minute! I look best diagonally
from the right, at a 30-degree angle.
Okay! I understand.
This is stupid.
Let's go and leave this guy.
Hey, wait for me, Asuka!
Asuka! Please wait for me!
Yeah, just like that!
"There is nothing stronger
than a mother's love.
I am prepared for anything.
The mountain that you see
over there is Mt. Asahi."
Well, we shall stop here.
We will have a test next week
on today's lesson. Review it well.
-What?
-You're joking!
Can you lend me your English notebook?
I didn't take any notes.
Well...
Hey, Tohru! Hurry up
or I'll leave without you!
Yeah. Give me a minute!
Is it no?
It's okay.
Here, this is it.
Thank you!
I'll return it tomorrow!
This is the English notebook.
Wait! That's the wrong one!
Oh, no, what am I going to do?
-What? You're gonna buy that much?
-But they're all obligations.
And who's the true love?
That's a secret!
And, Meimi, what about you?
What? Me?
-Who'd give him anything?
-Meimi, how about you?
That's my secret too!
Unfair, you've all got secrets!
-So, Ryoko, yours is...?
-Me?
You keep asking about us,
but what about you?
Isn't it obvious? It's...
Yes?
A secret.
So you lent him the wrong notebook?
Yes, exactly.
That notebook is the one
I use as a diary...
...to write my daily thoughts in.
In that notebook,
I've written many poems...
...thinking about Tohru.
If Tohru should see any of that...
...I'd be so embarrassed
I wouldn't be able to live!
Don't worry.
I'm sure God will lend you a hand.
Get a notebook back from Tohru Ijuin?
Right. And it has to be today.
Before he gets a chance
to look at that notebook.
Oh, I see.
Kanako Shimamura is in love with him.
But she's afraid
to have him find out.
This would be the chance to tell him.
And it's almost Valentine's Day.
You may be right, but...
A boy as popular as Tohru would
never even give me a second thought.
And I'm happy just to
be able to look at him.
There are many girls who are unable
to honestly display their feelings.
Meimi, you're probably...
Right?
I understand. Right!
St. Tail is a supporter of girls.
I will get that notebook
back for Kanako.
ART ROOM
-Let's clean up quickly and go home!
-Yeah.
Jeez, what a filthy classroom.
What's this?
"NOTE" GETS CHANGED
TO "HEART"
Ouch.
It's a...
Tonight I will be stealing
Tohru Ijuin's heart away.
St. Tail!
His heart?
What about his heart?
-What are you doing here?
-Let's go home together, Asuka.
Never mind that. Look.
"Tonight I will be stealing
Tohru Ijuin's heart away. -St. Tail"
-What's this about?
-That's my question!
What does it mean?
If it says "heart"...
You're kidding! My heart?
This heart? She's gonna perform
open-heart surgery on me?
Of course not, you idiot!
Think seriously.
For example, maybe you have
a pet cat or dog named Heart.
-No, only a turtle named Samantha.
-I see.
Then what could it mean?
What could St. Tail
want to steal from you?
Well...
Heart, heart, heart...
That's it!
I know what it is, Asuka!
What is it? What's she gonna steal?
To put it simply...
...St. Tail has fallen in love
with me, and tonight she's coming...
...to flirt with me
and steal my heart away.
-Think seriously!
-I'm serious!
Besides, what else could
"steal my heart away" mean?
Stupid. That's just stupid!
Asuka, what are you so upset about?
Asuka! Could you be jealous
of how I attract all the girls?
Be quiet!
That St. Tail, with a guy like this.
I, Tohru Ijuin...
...shall allow my heart to be stolen!
-What's wrong?
-Don't talk to me!
Hey, wait a minute.
Where are you taking me?
Where else? To buy a present.
We're going to buy a present
to give St. Tail.
A present? Look here!
What are you thinking?
St. Tail is coming to steal
my heart away, you know.
Wouldn't it be rude
not to be prepared for it?
Imbecile! She's a thief!
Never mind. Just tell me
what gift would make her happy.
How should I know?
Okay, I can't be
dragging my feet here.
That wonderful chocolate smell!
-Don't look yet.
-Why? What's wrong with it? Delicious!
I said no. I haven't put
the finishing touch on it yet.
The finishing touch?
A special flower.
With lots of love! Sprinkle!
I see.
You're right. This is delicious!
-Isn't it?
-I wonder why.
Listening to them is embarrassing.
Isn't that so, Ruby?
Aren't I right? Valentine's Day.
Ruby, do you have someone
to give chocolates to?
I've been waiting for you.
Well? Don't I look great?
Hey, what are you up to, anyway?
What are you talking about?
This is the proper etiquette
for receiving a lady.
Kanako, it's dinnertime!
Come down here!
Yes! I'll be right there!
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Please be careful, Meimi.
Yes, I know!
May the blessings of God be with us.
You can stay,
but please don't get in the way.
I know.
St. Tail, come if you dare.
I'll get you for sure.
Who would give St. Tail
to a creep like him?
My style!
She's here!
Wait, Tohru!
Welcome!
What's the matter, Tohru?
It's a present, Asuka!
Wait a minute, idiot!
Don't bring that in here!
But why--?
What did I tell you?! Idiot!
It's about time.
Quick! Open the window!
Is that you, St. Tail?
-This must be it.
-St. Tail!
Please steal my heart!
-Why are you running away?
-What's going on here?
Where are you?
Where did you go, St. Tail?
Please steal my heart!
What? Steal his heart?
St. Tail!
Stop it! I'm not St. Tail!
What?
Hold it, St. Tail!
St. Tail!
Do you love Tohru that much?
What's he mixed-up about?
I'm taking the notebook,
just as I told you!
Notebook?
Oh, it's not "heart."
It's "notebook."
-See you around!
-I won't let you get away!
Asuka!
St. Tail!
Steal my heart!
-You're in the way!
-No, you're in the way!
I'm gonna catch St. Tail!
Asuka, up ahead!
My heart, please steal it!
I'm pretty sure that
Kanako's house is in this area.
St. Tail!
Please wait! My heart!
Something's going on outside.
-St. Tail!
-I'll go look.
Please wait!
I give you my heart.
Tohru.
You're cute.
I've made up my mind!
Okay!
Hold it, St. Tail!
What's happening?
Now you're caught!
Darn it!
I'll remember this, St. Tail!
You won't get away from me next time!
What happened to you yesterday?
You said you'd buy chocolate with us.
Oh, sorry about that!
Something urgent came up.
Good morning, Asuka Jr.!
St. Tail got away again?
Be quiet! I almost had her!
If only that ship hadn't passed!
Next time, I'll get her for sure!
Asuka! Asuka, good morning!
Good morning!
-Kanako?
-Yes?
-Where are your glasses?
-I changed to contact lenses.
She's much cuter this way, isn't she?
Hey, what's going on?
My heart was stolen,
just like the notice said.
By St. Tail?
Of course not! By Kanako!
Is that so?
You better hurry too,
or you'll be late for school.
-But...
-Really.
What a guy!
We're the happiest people alive!