Meimi! Seira!
The Tomb Stones are playing
at the Portside Concert Hall!
-Really?
-Tickets go on sale today!
-What's that?
-You've never heard...
...of the Tomb Stones? They're hot!
Well, I...
You're so dense about these things.
Come with us!
SOLD OUT
ALL TICKETS
I see. Thank you, anyway.
Too late!
They sold out before noon.
We didn't have a chance.
Oh, rats.
Hey, you girls!
Did you come to buy tickets too?
You guys too?
Too bad. They're sold out.
What?!
She's right!
We should have waited
in line last night!
It's a school day!
-It's only one day!
-What a bunch of kids.
Rats! That's not fair!
They're making such a fuss.
DANGER, DO NOT TOUCH!
SUPER ELECTRIC TRAP
I'm home!
Hi, Meimi.
Hi, dear. Would you
like some Russian tea?
No, maybe later.
What's wrong? Why the long face?
Don't worry. I'm fine.
You sure? All right.
I'll show you a great trick.
It'll put a smile on any sad face.
That'd be terrific.
You are now feeling happier.
That's right.
So happy you want to sing.
Now you feel like laughing.
You're so happy, you want to burst.
You want to hug your dad
for making you so happy.
I think it's working.
Now for the final touch.
-What?
-Here!
Tickets to the Tomb Stones concert!
How did you get these?
A client gave them to me, but I'm
just not into loud music like that.
I love you, Dad!
-They're not good seats, though.
-That doesn't matter! Thanks, Dad!
She changes so quickly.
Two tickets. Who should I ask?
Seira's not interested
in this sort of thing.
Kyoko and Ryoko would be thrilled,
but they're bound to fight about it.
Sure, he would be happy to go...
...but wouldn't it be
sort of like a date?
-Catch you later.
-Right.
Good morning!
-Good morning.
-Too bad about yesterday.
I was so upset, I couldn't sleep!
You liar, we're late because
you overslept today.
I'm missing my chance.
-Hey, Emi! Let me see your homework!
-Me too!
Oh, Meimi, it's you.
-What is it?
-Well....
If you have something to say, say it.
-I have these tickets--
-Asuka!
You're a Tomb Stones fan, right?
Why do you wanna know?
-Tickets to the concert!
-And front row seats too!
-How did you get these?
-From my uncle!
-No way!
-Hey, let's go together.
-How about it?
-Well...
-Well?
-Yeah.
What's with her?
What's with him?
Meimi!
-What did you want?
-Nothing.
Nothing?
-You started to say something.
-Forget it.
Why the attitude?
Rina will get mad if
she catches you talking to me.
She's got nothing to do with this!
Well, neither do l!
What's with her?
What's with him?
May I help you?
Forgive me for entering unannounced.
That's quite all right.
Do you have a problem?
So you're a sculptor.
Yes, but I only make metal monuments.
Aren't you Daisuke Noguchi?
You were given many awards
at one time.
Yes, I had it good.
But I've been in a slump
for some time now.
I was recognized as a real sculptor...
...only after I made
the Steel Weathercock.
Until then, I borrowed a space
in a workshop and did odd jobs.
All I wanted was
to create a masterpiece.
But as soon as I unveiled
the weathercock...
...my life changed.
All my past hardships like a dream.
The Steel Weathercock
was my lucky charm.
That's why I wouldn't sell it,
no matter how much anyone offered.
But it was stolen a year ago.
And I haven't been able
to finish a piece since then.
These past six months
have been particularly bad.
Then recently I learned
that my sculpture...
...is being displayed atop
the Misato building.
You must contact the building's owner.
Of course I did that! But...
Please give it back!
The weathercock is mine!
I believe you are mistaken.
I purchased that piece
from a legitimate art dealer.
-That's not possible!
-Hey.
That is the contract.
Well? Now do you understand?
No, these documents aren't real!
If you have complaints,
go to the police.
But I warn you, I do have
the documents to prove...
...I bought the sculpture,
so there's nothing you can do.
Unless, of course,
you offer to buy it back.
However, I have promised to sell it to
a businessman in Hong Kong next week.
So decide quickly.
I beg you!
I'm lost without my sculpture!
I must ask you to leave.
It's frustrating since
I can't do anything.
When will he sell it
to that businessman in Hong Kong?
It will be removed three days
from now. I don't know what to do.
And if he gets the sculpture back...
...I'm sure he will be able
to create more pieces.
But there's not much time left.
-Meimi? Meimi!
-Oh, sorry!
Are you okay? Since there's
no time, maybe we should reconsider--
No! If we forsake a person in trouble,
we'll damage St. Tail's reputation.
I'll get it back for him at any cost!
The day after tomorrow.
The same night as the concert.
Oh, well.
It won't be fun going alone anyway.
I wonder what he'll do.
Will he go to the concert or--?
I can't pull a job
without giving him a warning.
Good morning!
Asuka!
What time should we meet today?
-What are you talking about?
-The concert!
Can't you go by yourself?
I want you to come with me,
or give me back your ticket!
Hey! Give it back!
I will steal the Steel Weathercock
today from the Misato building.
St. Tail.
No, no, no! The concert's today!
Forget about St. Tail!
We're going to the concert!
St. Tail, huh?
What a bothersome situation.
You must do your utmost
to capture her at once.
I'm completing the sale
tomorrow afternoon.
How did you come
to own that sculpture?
I bought it, of course.
From an art dealer.
St. Tail never steals anything
from its rightful owner.
She's just a petty thief,
with no reason for stealing.
Or are you taking her side
on this issue?
Listen, the mayor and I
are close friends.
I can easily have you fired.
By the way, do you mind
letting me see that sculpture?
By all means. I'll go with you.
This isn't good. If St. Tail is
arrested, they'll know we stole it.
Not if she can't talk
when she's captured.
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
May the blessings of God be with us.
What?
For security, a high voltage current
runs through the sculpture.
One touch and you're dead.
Even St. Tail can't beat that.
You're insane! She'll be--
All it means is a foolish
thief was electrocuted.
That's murder!
No matter. After all,
she is just a thief.
-I won't allow that!
-It's time for you to leave.
What are you doing? Let me go!
Hey, did you hear me?
You won't get away with this!
What's wrong, Asuka Jr.?
They said they don't
need our protection.
But I'm not giving up that easy!
Funny, no one's around. Maybe
he went to the concert after all.
-Don't do anything, you got that?
-Yes, sir.
Don't touch it!
It's wired with electricity!
That fool! Get them!
So that's it! But for now....
Get her!
It's...
...showtime!
Stop! You won't get away, St. Tail!
-Don't let her escape! After her!
-Yes, sir!
Hold it!
Over there!
She went into quadrant 24C.
Shut her in!
-Who's there?
-Oh, excuse me.
There was no one downstairs,
so I just came on up.
You won't get away!
Oh, no! I'll be locked in!
Look out!
Now!
I made it.
Oh, no, I'm trapped!
Where is St. Tail?
I'm sorry, but she escaped.
I believe my son came here.
Yes, earlier, but he gave up and left.
-Mr. President--!
-It's okay. He's about to leave.
I'll see you later.
Sorry to have bothered you.
We've trapped St. Tail.
Turn the cooler on.
Make sure it's on full power.
-But Asuka Jr.'s in there too.
-So what?
It's freezing!
I'm freezing.
Put this on.
This is for helping me back there.
You helped me first, but...
Thank you.
-You've got a lot of guts.
-So do you.
There's this really headstrong girl
in my class too.
I don't know why,
but we always end up fighting.
I don't mean to, it just happens.
We had a fight today too.
-I don't know why, but she was mad.
-You're so dense!
But I could have been
to blame too. Probably.
We've got to do something
or we'll freeze!
-Hey, son, you in there?
-Dad?
If I can break through that...
-Dad!
-I knew you were up to something.
So where's St. Tail?
Rats.
Stop! Come back here, St. Tail!
I'm taking the sculpture! Give
my best to your headstrong friend.
Come back here, you!
Things look bad.
Now that Asuka Jr.'s out...
If his father investigates,
we're in trouble.
It seems the rumors were true.
Your hobby is
collecting stolen artwork.
That's absurd!
You're not being cooperative.
My God, look at all this!
These are all listed as stolen.
You have quite a collection.
More than rumored!
Mr. President.
-Hey, why are you two blushing?
-What do you mean?
Never mind that! Where were you
yesterday? I waited all night.
Yesterday, St. Tail...
Were you two together last night?
Don't be ridiculous!
I wouldn't be caught dead--
Hey, that hurts, Meimi!