I heard that Graham's comet
will soon be visible!
What's that?
I know Halley's comet,
but not this one.
It's the comet that passes
close to Earth every 50 years.
Wow.
I'm sure it's this Thursday
when it'll pass by Earth again.
How wonderful!
This Thursday, you say?
How romantic!
But you can't see it with the naked
eye. You have to go to an observatory.
What would happen
if a comet crashed into Earth?
I guess we'd all be blown to bits.
-Then what will you do, Ryoko?
-Get my important things and run!
-To where?
-Your important things?
-Let me think...
-Important things, she says.
-My parents, for sure!
-Mine's my favorite fishing pole.
My pillow! I can't sleep without it!
-You guys are a lost cause.
-What about you, Sawatari?
Let's run to the end of the world!
No way.
A COMET APPROACHES!
THE EARTH'S FINAL NIGHT??
You're all idiots!
A comet never leaves its orbit,
so it'll never crash into Earth.
I said "suppose"!
Don't call me an idiot, you idiot!
You want a fight?
So that's it! You don't have anything
important to take, so you're mad.
What? You're wrong!
I do too have something precious!
-Then tell us!
-You really want to know?
Are you two friends or enemies?
Make up your mind!
-Who wants to be friends with him?
-Same here!
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
He didn't have time to tell me
what his important thing was.
Make up my mind.
I'm not in love with her or anything.
I just don't know.
I'm home!
We must let the American people
know to prevent a tragedy!
But that will only cause a panic.
-You're saying to keep quiet?
-We only have a few minutes.
I'm home.
Oh, welcome home.
It's too late!
It's too soon to give up.
-Mom, where's my snack?
-There should be something.
Nope!
Gosh! What are they watching anyway,
all cuddled up during the day?
COMET COLLIDES!
THE LAST NIGHT ON EARTH: 1953 USA
It brings back memories.
It sure did. This was the movie
we saw on our first date.
Genichiro.
Eimi.
I guess I'll go change.
This is so embarrassing.
Sorry I'm late!
What is it this time?
Well, it's an incident that
occurred about an hour ago.
I'm first!
Ouch! You mustn't run around here.
I'm sorry, Sister.
You're in the choir, aren't you?
What's the big hurry?
Truth is...
Graham's comet?
That's right, Sister.
We have to see that comet!
Akio's going to move away soon.
That's why we all decided
to go see the comet.
-You can't see it with your naked eye.
-I know.
So I went to the observatory and asked
if we could use the telescope.
At first they agreed, but then...
No one's told me anything about that.
But I talked to
the director last week!
Last week? That director was
transferred to another observatory.
What?
Then let us talk to the new director!
He's a busy man.
You're disrupting our work. Go home!
-Oh, my.
-It's not fair.
We were looking forward to it.
So we came to pray for God's help.
So we can get to see the comet!
Isn't there some other way, Seira?
You can only see it with an
observatory's astronomical telescope.
Of course.
Okay! Let St. Tail handle this.
It looks like that Sawatari's
really serious about Meimi.
I wonder what got into him. He was
never interested in girls before.
-What do you think, Asuka?
-How would I know?
What a grouch!
-Who cares?
-Hey! The enemy is approaching!
Prepare to fire!
What--?
What is this?!
Rotten kids! How dare you
attack an innocent passerby?
Adults are all liars!
Hey, Asuka, looking good.
You can't hit me!
Great strategy!
"Dear Mr. Detective:
I will steal Graham's comet
this coming Thursday. -St. Tail"
-It's a challenge!
-A challenge?
Wow! Let me see!
How's she gonna steal a comet?
There's no way...
So that's it!
She's gonna steal
the observatory's telescope!
That's the only way to see
the comet around here!
My theory's definitely right.
Never mind.
You're dripping all over the place.
-But stealing it won't be easy.
-I also agree.
Did you hear that?
She'll think of a way!
I'll be ready for you, St. Tail!
How can he be so sure
based on no facts?
I don't know.
It must be love, love.
It's a perfect night to present
the comet to the children.
Ruby, take care of things here.
No, Ruby! I have work to do!
Oh, all right. Will you help me?
Okay. But just this one time.
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Meimi, hurry! Everyone will be
here soon for choir practice.
I know. You and Ruby take care
of the other things.
The children will be happy for sure!
You can count on me!
May the blessings of God be with us.
Wow. This certainly is
a magnificent telescope.
Asuka Jr.!
But why does she want a telescope?
-It will go smoothly tonight.
-Especially without those pesky kids!
We can't let those kids ruin
such a great astronomical event.
-How's it going?
-Everything's going smoothly, sir.
Is that so?
Asuka Jr., is St. Tail really
coming to steal this telescope?
I'm certain of it.
You've got the right idea
except for the last detail.
We'll leave you
to take care of St. Tail.
We don't want our research
hampered by a thief.
Of all the nerve!
The comet passes once every 50 years.
It's just as important to children.
They want to keep it for themselves.
God will never forgive this!
One!
Two!
Three!
-Where did they come from?
-Who did this?
Stop this!
-No, stop!
-I was wrong!
I know it's you, St. Tail!
How's she gonna steal
this huge thing anyway?
Well, that's all for today.
And now, I have some sad news
for all of you today.
Today is Akio's last practice...
...since he will be leaving soon.
-Take care.
-Thanks.
Too bad we couldn't see the comet.
-It can't be helped.
-See you!
Akio, I hope you never lose
your bright outlook on life.
-I won't! Goodbye, Mother Superior!
-Goodbye!
-Mother Superior, where is Seira?
-She's not out here.
Oh, but I am outside.
Though this is a little embarrassing.
Hello, children! These balloons
are for you from the snowman!
-This is a reward for being so good.
-Gee, thanks, Mr. Snowman!
There's one for everyone.
Here you go.
Wow! A snowman!
Here you go!
Thank you!
Hey, Akio. There's something
on your balloon.
Come to the observatory.
I'll give you Graham's comet.
-Let's go!
-Where are you kids going?
We'll be right back, Mommy!
-What's this?
-Get down here, St. Tail!
If you don't, I'm going up there!
I'll get you for sure today
and unmask you!
It's...
...show...
...time!
Sir! This is terrible!
-Look at the monitor!
-What is it?
A part of the comet has broken off...
...and is falling towards us
at great speed!
That's ridiculous! Let me see!
-Why didn't you see this before?
-I don't know.
A part of the comet. That's
something like a meteor, isn't it?
No, very far from it!
It could make a huge hole!
We may not be safe here!
-Let's get away!
-Wait for me! Come back here!
Everyone's gone finally!
Now's my chance!
Hey, you! Don't you move from there!
Why aren't you running away?
A part of the comet is heading here!
So what?
So what? What could you
be thinking about?
I'm gonna arrest you!
My legs, I can't move them.
Is there another reason?
Like what if you died, what's
the most important thing you'd take?
Something important?
-Yes. Do you have something?
-No!
I can't think of anything
until I arrest you!
Meimi, no! Get ahold of yourself!
I'm sorry. It was an act.
Nothing's falling to Earth.
I rigged the whole thing.
You what?
One! Two! Three!
COMET COLLIDES! THE LAST NIGHT
ON EARTH; THE END
What?
Hey! Why did you do this?
Don't worry. I've recorded
the correct data too.
And could you let in
the children waiting outside?
Outside?
Rats!
Come back here!
Boy, that was close!
But he wouldn't have said it
like that...
...if he knew I was Meimi.
I'm sure of it.
The children waiting outside?
What's going on?
Wow, there it is! I see it!
-The comet!
-It really has a tail!
Yeah, this is great!
-I wonder when we'll see it again?
-In 50 years.
Then let's all come here
again to look at it!
Yeah!
I just don't get it.
Why did St. Tail--?
Hey, what's this all about?
Thank you, sir.
We all prayed to God.
We asked Him to let us see the comet.
Thank you, God!
God.
Look, falling stars!
Did you ask God for something?
-No.
-Why not?
Because my wish...
...is for God.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org