-Good morning, Meimi.
-Good morning, Seira.
-Another lovely day, isn't it?
-It sure is.
Seira, what's going on there?
Maybe Asuka Jr.'s solved a case
and they want his autograph.
That's ridiculous!
Yutaka, please!
Get your father to sign this.
But my father's not even an actor.
What's going on here?
Didn't you know?
Yutaka's father wrote a bestseller.
Oh, really? Seira, did you know?
I bought one. It's titled
Expedition Journal of Jurassic Island.
His father discovered an egg
of the legendary bird.
A legendary bird?
GET BACK THE PHANTOM BIRD EGG!
-Seira, have you read it?
-Yes, would you like to read it?
It looks so hard.
Maybe I'll just go get his autograph.
Professor Mochizuki, Yutaka's father,
is a well-known explorer.
He was investigating
the existence of the bird...
...in a jungle
in the southern hemisphere.
And he discovered the egg?
Yes. A fiery red Apua bird said
to have lived on the island ages ago.
Then he compiled his report
into a book.
Exploring a jungle,
a fiery red bird. How romantic!
A lizard!
You'll never go exploring the jungle
if this little thing scares you.
Mr. Asuka, pets are not allowed
in the school.
As punishment, you will clean
the birdcage after school!
Yes, ma'am.
Your father's precious egg?
Yes, a Professor Hyuga from
the Scientific Research lnstitute...
...came by, claiming
to be my father's friend.
I'd appreciate you letting me
borrow your father's egg.
My father's not in tonight.
Can you wait until tomorrow?
I have his permission.
I'd like to study the egg...
...as part of my research
of the Apua bird.
Why, I promise to return it
in two or three days.
He said he'd return it and I let him
take it without thinking it through.
What? Hyuga took the egg last night?
Oh, God, I'm finished.
Dad, what do you mean?
Yutaka, I made the egg. It's a fake.
I painted an ostrich egg.
Then you lied
about discovering the egg?
You wrote that book
based on pure fiction?
No, I'm certain
I really did find the egg.
Animals are very delicate creatures.
Being tossed around on
a long ocean voyage to Japan...
...would kill any animal.
That egg is priceless,
so I didn't bring it back.
-I wanted the bird to be raised there.
-I see.
But I had to let the world
know of my discovery.
I needed proof
to convince my colleagues.
So you made the fake to use as proof.
But I never imagined my book
would cause such a sensation.
A man in my position should never have
used a fake to prove his discovery.
Then why don't you explain it
to everyone now?
You're right.
But of all the bad luck...
...it will be Hyuga
who breaks the news.
I see.
Professor Hyuga has always
criticized my father's research.
If he analyzes the egg,
he's sure to realize it's a fake.
I need the egg back before that.
And where is the egg now?
Hyuga's Scientific Research lnstitute.
A fake egg, huh?
Using a fake to prove one's theory
is certainly unforgivable.
But Professor Mochizuki
deeply regrets it now.
And it's too bad Professor Hyuga
will reveal the truth.
I did some checking and learned
that Professor Hyuga...
...is scheduled to go on TV
tomorrow to discuss the egg.
I understand.
You want me to get the egg
before he analyzes it.
Brilliant deduction.
I knew I could count on you.
Why did she have to stick me
with this dirty job?
I need to clean this place up.
What's this?
What? "Tonight at 8:00, I am going
to Professor Hyuga's lab...
...to steal the legendary egg.
-St. Tail." St. Tail's note!
-I'm home!
-Welcome home, Meimi.
What's with Dad?
Hi, Dad!
Oh, Meimi, welcome home.
What's the matter? You promised
to show me your trick when I got back.
I'm sorry. I got so involved
with the program.
What program?
UNCOVER PARANORMAL PHENOMENA
WlTH DR. HYUGA
-You know him?
-Yeah, in a way.
You were saying there is nothing
that is scientifically unexplainable.
That's right.
Supernatural phenomena and legendary
creatures do not exist in our society.
For example, mirages
and a dead person's spirit...
...which so many romanticize about,
have been scientifically explained.
This is a mirage, right?
Isn't it incredible? Even a machine
is capable of creating one.
And now, to continue...
A dead person's spirit!
Lately, I've been hearing of fools
causing a sensation by ranting...
...of miracles and legends,
but I will expose them all!
This journal is a bestseller, right?
Yes. In my professional opinion,
the legendary Apua bird...
...does not exist anywhere.
This book is a fake.
And tomorrow on this program,
we will reveal the infamous egg!
The egg Professor Mochizuki found
cannot be real!
And I will expose--
Mom!
Why'd you turn it off?
It was interesting.
Because I don't like that man!
The other day at a magic show,
that awful man...
...revealed the secrets
in front of the magician!
Then he's one of Dad's enemies.
That's right. Without the world's
mysteries and magic...
...there'd be no dreams or hope!
You're right. Eimi, I appreciate
you always thinking of me.
Oh, dear, I...
Oh, brother, here we go again!
Hi, Ruby!
I've got work to do. I'll play
with you in just a little while.
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Meimi, you have to be
extra careful this time.
Don't worry!
I've heard Professor Hyuga has
a state-of-the-art security system...
...wired in his laboratory.
It just makes the job
more challenging for me!
May the blessings of God be with us.
HYUGA SCIENTIFIC
RESEARCH INSTITUTE
I appreciate you reporters
coming out here.
Professor Hyuga, there are reports
St. Tail has announced--
I don't know about any St. Tail...
...but my computers will capture
any brash, petty thief!
Well, just wait and see!
You seem to be
my personal bodyguards...
...but I told you,
I don't need your protection.
You're not taking St. Tail
very seriously!
If she says she's coming, she will!
Detective, I appreciate your concern,
but I want you to leave.
I have enough help here.
We can't do that.
Since she has made her announcement,
it is our duty to arrest her.
This laboratory has been equipped with
the latest computers I've invented.
When it comes to police intuition
or experience...
...I just don't believe in that.
That is your prerogative, but
our job is to stand guard right here.
Have it your way then.
That door is unlocked, isn't it?
St. Tail can easily enter from here.
As part of my plan, I'm letting
St. Tail get in easily!
I will capture her alive and then
my secret weapon will go into action!
Secret weapon?
And this is it!
I AM A GENIUS!
Perfect.
What is that?
These will not kill or hurt anything.
It's like a tranquilizer gun
for live capture.
That's quite impressive.
And what is this?
Oh, that.
That's the character analyzer.
It looks like it'll fry someone.
Shall I demonstrate it?
You just stand there quietly.
Daisuke Asuka. Born August 22.
Horoscope: Leo. Blood type: AB.
Fantastic! It analyzes one's personal
data just by shining a light.
Does that mean
if the light hits St. Tail...
...we'll learn her true identity?
That's right. Today's the day
we learn her true identity.
Aren't you happy?
Just in case, I'm going
to tape St. Tail's capture...
...and have it shown on national TV.
What a showoff!
If I am unable to capture her...
...I will shave my head completely!
It's almost time.
What's that? It's St. Tail!
We've got you, St. Tail!
Assistants A, B, fire!
Here I am! Here!
Drat! Give it to me!
-She'll never be able to get close!
-Not here, at any rate!
You idiot! What are you shooting at?
You call this gun safe?
It's...
...show...
...time!
What are these things? Stop!
Here goes!
Now's my chance!
You're not getting away!
Damn! I'll reveal her identity!
Look out!
I won't let you get away!
Take that!
Here!
Stop, St. Tail!
I'll let you go today...
...only because I don't want
to capture you with machinery!
Thank you.
-Professor! Professor!
-The egg, the egg.
Professor, snap out of it!
What was I doing? That's right!
I'm sure my computer grasped
St. Tail's true identity!
Are you sure?
St. Tail's identity.
Everything's in order!
What happened?
It's all white.
Hey, what's the meaning of this?
This is one of those pebbles
St. Tail threw.
-What is it, Dad?
-Impossible!
Hey! Dad, isn't this a magnet?
I get it. These machines
don't take to magnets.
That's ridiculous!
But the video should show her face.
My machines of the latest technology
were thwarted by mere magnets. Damn!
What's that?
What's this?
Dad, it's the egg! The egg's back!
What did you say?
This.
Yutaka, I'm going to make
a public apology.
About the egg being a fake?
Yes, and I'll ask everyone to help
preserve the island's natural state.
Dad.
I'm so glad.
-Good morning!
Professor Mochizuki was so very happy.
-Good morning, Meimi, Seira.
-We'd better hurry!
-Please let us through!
-Again?
Congratulations! I saw the paper.
The Apua bird's egg on
Jurassic lsland hatched, didn't it?
It's so neat! Please get me
your father's autograph.
Well, I...
DR. HYUGA WENT BALD!
Good morning, Asuka Jr.
Did you see this?
Look at that bald fool!
A bet's a bet. And he bet he could
reveal St. Tail's true identity.
I guess that means capturing St. Tail
should be left to you, Asuka Jr.
That's right, because I'm the best.
I know everything about St. Tail!
Though she's always getting away?
What did you say? I had a good reason
for letting her go this time!
I know.
You said, "I don't want
to capture you with machinery!"
And you work so hard at it!