Hold it, St. Tail!
St. Tail! I won't let you get away!
What's going on?
-You two go after that one!
-Yes, sir!
Darn! Wait!
You thought I'd get tricked
with your magic?
Today I'll get you for sure!
Darn it!
The next time, I'll have
complete data on you...
...and you won't get away!
STEAL THE MEMORABLE HARMONICA!
Miyuki, please cheer up.
I'm sure God is with you.
Yes, thank you very much.
Music competition?
Yes. They're holding the Seika City
Youth Music Competition tonight...
...at the new hall that opened
on Bayside Street.
And Miyuki is one
of the contestants, right?
But a problem has come up.
What do you mean by a "problem"?
Miyuki was supposed to play
a harmonica at the contest.
But a certain person has tricked her
and taken her harmonica.
Tricked her and taken it?
Yes.
FUKUYAMA MUSIC INSTRUMENTS
To have the harmonica tuned...
...Miyuki took it
to a music store on First Avenue.
A music store on First Avenue
means it's the shop owned...
...by Mr. Fukuyama,
one of the city's wealthy citizens.
But Miyuki's harmonica was switched...
...with a fake one by that Fukuyama.
She isn't the only one he's deceived.
He's tricked others, taken
their instruments and sold them.
What an unforgivable thing to do!
Miyuki's harmonica is
a rare foreign-made one...
...given to her by her late father.
She's used it
since she was little, so--
She won't perform as well
on another harmonica.
Right. You have to get her harmonica
back by the time the contest begins.
We have to help Miyuki give a
successful performance, no matter what!
I'm starved.
Let's grab a few hamburgers.
-I'll pass on it today.
-Then how about a game?
No, I've got some things to do.
Sorry, but I'm heading home. See you.
St. Tail? This way!
Rats! She's teasing me!
NICE JOB - ST. TAIL
Ouch!
"Tonight I'm taking a harmonica
in the First Avenue music store."
What? St. Tail, you--!
-Dad!
-Son, sorry, but your dinner's pizza.
No time for dinner!
Tonight, St. Tail's gonna--
Calling me in for backup when
I'm off duty. What a rotten deal.
The First Avenue music store,
St. Tail's--
Okay, okay.
Oh, I almost forgot something.
A photo of the man we're guarding.
The chairman of the panel of judges
for the music competition.
Mr. Wilson, famous composer
and competitor in music contests.
Now I've got to involve myself
in international affairs.
I better not forget
to get his signature.
Wait, Dad! Darn it!
Please forgive me
for not being finished.
My, that's a cute doll!
Hello.
-This is Daddy.
-That's right!
I'm going to be putting on a magic
show at the hall on Bayside Street.
The hall on Bayside Street?
Yeah, it's a magic show
at such a grand hall...
...that I've got to put together
quite a gimmick.
So I'm using miniatures
to plan out the whole setup.
-What magic will you be doing?
-A great escape act.
A great escape act? Wonderful!
There's a little escape route
under the stage of that hall.
I'm planning to use it.
And it's called "Escape From Flames."
-An escape from water may be better.
-You have a point.
With Mom's ideas
and Dad's magic put together...
...it'll probably be a wonderful show!
-Ruby expects it to be fabulous too.
-Thank you, Ruby.
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Miyuki is scheduled
to perform at 8:00.
8:00. I've got to hurry
or I won't make it!
Good luck, Meimi.
May the blessings of God be with us.
What? The schedule has changed?
That's a problem. What's going on?
Mr. Fukuyama, I simply will not
be able to meet you at your shop.
Actually, my next performance
was suddenly moved up...
...and I must leave Japan immediately
after tonight's competition.
I understand.
Then I will take the instrument
down to the hall.
Oh, that would be excellent.
Well, then, Mr. Fukuyama.
Mr. Wilson, we will be arriving
at the hall soon.
-Mr. Fukuyama, isn't it?
-What do you want, kid?
I'm Asuka Jr. and I was commissioned
to help catch St. Tail.
I received a notice
that St. Tail will come...
...to steal a harmonica in this shop.
St. Tail or Hail or whatever, I don't
know about it! Go home, I'm busy!
That won't do.
You will cooperate
in staking this place out.
That's an official investigation
from the mayor! Do as you please.
Okay, now...
That St. Tail.
So that's what she's after.
St. Tail.
She can have any harmonica
in the shop she wants.
The stolen instruments are
all stored right here!
7:00. Okay, come from wherever
you want, St. Tail!
St. Tail!
You won't get the harmonica!
What? Hey, the harmonica is
over here, you know!
It's that magic again. According
to my analysis, the real one is here!
That's strange. The storage
room door was left open.
You're kidding. According to Seira,
the harmonica should be here!
Hold it, St. Tail!
Oh, no!
You won't escape today!
Where can Miyuki's harmonica be?
Fukuyama!
That wooden box! Miyuki's harmonica
is probably in there.
Where the heck is he going?
Rats! I won't let her get away!
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you for attending...
...the Seika City Youth Music
Competitions this evening.
Tonight's purpose is
to create artists of the future.
We offer an opportunity to study
abroad to one outstanding performer!
Well, then, let me introduce to you
our panel of judges!
That's the Bayside Street Hall.
What? He can't be going in there!
Now I'm pleased to introduce the
world-renowned composer, Mr. Wilson!
Mr. Wilson is chairman of the panel
of judges for this competition!
It is time to begin our competition.
Entry number one!
A junior at Seika High School...
...Megumi Hirose will be displaying
her talents on the piano!
Darn! Where's that St. Tail gone?
What? That's the--!
The first half is now complete.
We will take a 10-minute intermission.
Excuse me, Mr. Wilson.
May I have a word with you?
-And you are?
-Fukuyama. I called you earlier.
Oh, I appreciate you coming here!
Well, I don't know if you will
find anything you like...
...but I think it will be
worth your while.
I look forward to it.
I already prepared the instruments
below the stage of this hall.
Oh, thank you!
He's planning to sell
Miyuki's harmonica to Wilson here.
That won't happen!
-Dad!
-Son! What are you doing here?
It looks like St. Tail's
sneaked into this hall!
St. Tail, you said?
Yeah. She said she'd take a harmonica
from the music store...
...but I don't know what's going on.
A harmonica.
Ladies and gentlemen, the second half
of the competition will begin soon.
Please return to your seats.
Son, we'll talk later.
St. Tail is definitely planning
to start something here.
Where in this hall could St. Tail
try to pull something off?
Under the stage!
It's no good. I can't perform
properly on this harmonica.
Miss Miyuki Morishita, you're to
appear soon. Please get ready.
Yes.
I found it!
Asuka Jr.!
My data is correct.
St. Tail will show up if I wait here.
Next we have Miyuki Morishita...
...a student at St. Paulia School,
performing on her harmonica.
What a fix. What should I do?
That's--
That's it! The escape route
Dad was talking about.
Here we go!
Where did this flower come from?
Now's my chance!
St. Tail!
Hold it, St. Tail! Darn it!
-What's the matter? Are you all right?
-It's no good.
I can't perform unless
I use my father's harmonica.
Cheer up, Miyuki!
St. Tail!
-St. Tail?
-Wow! Really?
Miyuki, your precious harmonica
is here in the hall!
She's over there!
It's...
...show...
...time!
-What's this?
-What's going on?
Son!
Yeah!
What are these instruments?
-Don't touch them! Stop it!
-Mr. Fukuyama?
Don't touch any of my instruments!
Ouch! Your instruments?
This is the violin that
I asked Mr. Fukuyama to repair.
And that's my flute!
Stop it! These are my instruments!
So that's it! Fukuyama stole these!
-Son, what's this all about?
-He's the one!
They were probably stolen by Fukuyama!
What?
Darn it!
Hold it!
Hey, are these instruments
that you've stolen?
Well, how about it?
Ouch! Yes, that right!
Darn it! St. Tail got away!
Mr. Fukuyama, were you planning
to sell me instruments like that?
Were you attempting to deceive me?
You better think of how those
whose instruments were stolen feel.
Mr. Wilson, I will take
the responsibility of returning...
...these instruments to their owners.
Miyuki, now you'll be able
to play your best on the harmonica.
St. Tail, thank you!
Miss Miyuki, please perform your best.
The audience is eager
to hear you play your harmonica.
Yes, sir, I'll do my best!
Darn it! She's escaped again!