-See you later!
-Bye!
Hey, Shota!
-Are you looking for UFOs again?
-You don't give up.
That's my business!
We're in the fifth grade now.
It's time you gave it up.
-Why? UFOs really exist.
-How can you believe that?
-Sure they do!
-They don't!
-Do!
-Don't!
-lf I say they do, they do!
-Show me some proof!
Right, proof. The proof!
Proof, proof, proof, proof!
-I'll show you.
-You're sure?
I'll show you for sure! For sure.
THE UFO APPEARS!?
A TOWN IN PANIC!
Good morning!
-Good morning, Kyoko, Ryoko!
-You saw the UFO last night?
The one in the morning paper?
Meimi, don't you read the papers?
Here.
A UFO? "Several eyewitnesses
in Seika City."
It says people saw a shiny object
flying in the sky.
-That's definitely a UFO!
-But why the city of Seika?
What else?
It's because St. Tail is here!
St. Tail is probably
a messenger from outer space!
Yeah, a thief who roams
the universe, right?
How stupid! Who says
she's a messenger from outer space?
-What a terrible way to put it.
-There's no such thing as aliens.
-Then what's this article about?
-An optical illusion!
It says many people saw it.
Can you still call it an illusion?
An airplane, a shooting star...
Anyway, something else!
UFOs aren't scientific!
Science has yet to prove many things!
-Miss Haneoka, Mr. Asuka.
-Be quiet!
The two of you, use that energy
and go do your science homework.
Yes, Sister.
Meimi! Have you heard about this?
What is it?
"From the space shuttle to UFOs.
Cosmo World.
Popular event producer Yuji Kuroda
turns the Big Dome into outer space."
The UFO in the papers,
a guy took a photo of it.
Wow! Unbelievable!
And that photo will be exhibited
at this event.
You're saying you wanna
go and see it, right?
Of course not!
If I see it, I'll know if it's real
or not. And tomorrow's Sunday...
Good idea.
Let's go and check it out.
-Well, now, is this a date?
-Of course not!
Okay, we're ready. Go get Dad.
Sure!
-Dad, dinner's ready!
-Okay!
Is he outside?
That's strange. No one's here.
Ruby!
Isn't this great?
Wow! It's a new magic trick, right?
This is much thinner than the piano
cord I used. Can't see it, can you?
Ruby, don't struggle.
Don't struggle so much.
Is she all right? Ruby!
Looks like the reeling mechanism
needs more work.
Sorry, sorry!
I said that to Seira,
but this is exciting!
Meimi!
Yes!
It's us!
What's with the sour face?
Sorry we're not Asuka Jr.
Ryoko, what are you talking about?
-We heard about it, how it's a date.
-Of course not!
-Can we come along?
-Well, sure, why not?
What's up?
You guys came along too.
-This has to be enjoyed together.
-Right, right!
I guess you're right.
Not very many people are in here.
This model is also cheaply made.
There's no detail whatsoever.
Where's Asuka Jr.?
-Now that you mention it...
-Maybe he's stuck to something?
Wow!
Hey, Asuka! Let's take a look
at the UFO photos.
-What's this?
-"The photos are being enlarged.
They will be shown on the last day
at the UFO summoning event."
There, you see? It's a fake
so they're delaying it.
No, they're probably having
an expert examine the photos.
I'll go ask someone!
Mr. Kuroda, what's going on?
You're not drawing a crowd.
At this rate, we'll be in the red.
Don't worry, a turnout will come on
the last day. No one will miss this.
You mean that UFO photo?
Yes, it's fabulous. It's the hottest
conversation piece in this town.
But shouldn't an expert examine it
before you show it to the public?
By the time we do that, the event
will be over. It'll be fine.
But you--
My job is to gather people.
I've planned, along with the photo,
an event to summon a real UFO.
It'll be a smash hit, that's for sure.
-Anyway, we're counting on you.
-Just watch.
It's the man in the picture.
But, sir, if we enlarge the photo,
everyone will know that it's a fake!
Stupid fool! You're talking too loud!
Hey, Meimi.
Why are you hanging around here?
Hurry up so we can see the UFO--
-What's wrong?
-You're the one who stepped on--
The UFO model's that way.
Let's go!
Kids nowadays are too mature.
Yikes!
You're talking about the UFO
in the papers?
Yeah. I want to see a UFO so badly,
I always carry a camera.
But because of that,
my friends make fun of me, so I...
All right!
-Wow!
-That's neat!
Is this some sort of hoax?
It's real.
It was even in this morning's paper!
-It's probably the same UFO.
-Shota, you've done it!
Sure did.
Then it was just
a remote control airplane?
Yeah. I didn't expect it
to become such a big sensation.
And then my friends took the photo
to Cosmo World without me knowing!
Oh, my.
And it's going to be
exhibited at that event.
-Have you asked for the photo back?
-Yes, I did! But...
My friends brought it in without
my permission, that UFO photo.
Oh, that one.
It's just the thing for this event,
so we're putting it on exhibition.
I'm sorry. It's a fake.
So please return it to me.
Too late now. We already advertised
that it'll be on exhibition.
But...
You better not tell anyone
it's a fake. They'll never know.
That's unfair. Please return it.
I'll return it to you
when the event is over.
If only I hadn't taken that photo.
I understand. Let's pray.
I'm sure God is with you.
I see. So that's the story
behind it all.
Shota regrets what he has done
and promises not to do it again.
Okay! The thief St. Tail shall get
that photo back for him.
This is...
"Tonight I'll be stealing
that UFO photo at the Big Dome.
-St. Tail"
St. Tail is after that photo.
Yes, so we'll be taking care
of the security for the photograph.
I can use him.
I thought that if we could get a photo
to reveal St. Tail's identity...
What would you do with it?
An event, of course. With that photo,
crowds will swarm to such an event.
Absolutely not! To make
St. Tail into such a spectacle!
Well, I'll leave the security to you.
The photograph is set
in that slide projector over there.
Weren't you having it enlarged?
There are limits to enlarging a photo.
We're going to project it
on a slide, like, bang!
Well, I've got things to prepare
so I'll be on my way.
Who's gonna let a guy like that
reveal St. Tail's identity?
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
May the blessings of God be with us.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to Cosmo World!
All of you here tonight will
witness a historical event!
The boy who took the photo we'll
be showing had these words to say:
"The UFO will definitely return
to retrieve this photo!"
There's more!
We've been informed that St. Tail
might appear to steal this photo!
Ladies and gentlemen,
have you brought your cameras?
What scum, saying a thing like that!
For those who photograph a UFO
or St. Tail's true identity...
...we have big rewards prepared!
Now, let us begin!
Mr. Kuroda, there aren't
any rewards prepared.
It'll be hard for anyone to photograph
St. Tail's true identity.
But what if someone
does photograph her?
I'll buy it in cash.
If we have that, I'll surely be able
to fill the Big Dome unlike before.
-But what about the UFO?
-Don't get your hopes up on that one.
Didn't you say that a UFO
will come to retrieve the photo?
Just an act to arouse the audience.
And that photo, it looks like a fake.
That's a problem!
Let's cancel the event right now!
Hey, calm down.
The only one who will be criticized
is the boy who took the photo.
We're only victims of a trick.
And luck is on our side if
a crowd gathers, am I not right?
How could you--?
-Mommy, when is the UFO coming?
-I'm not sure.
-It won't come, will it?
-What's going on?
-Hurry up and summon the UFO!
-Yeah!
This is where we end this.
It looks like our UFO has decided
to make a sidetrack somewhere.
While we're waiting for its arrival,
we'll present the UFO photo--
It's the UFO!
The UFO appeared!
A picture, a picture!
We can get the reward!
What's this?
Could it be a real UFO?
It's St. Tail! After her!
Everyone! St. Tail has appeared!
-What?
-St. Tail?
Where, where?
Hurry up and turn on the lights!
-No good! The switch won't connect!
-Darn it!
There she is!
She's over there!
Don't let her escape!
-Are you all right, Asuka Jr.?
-Never mind me, get her!
Hold it!
There she is! Over there!
Oh, no!
St. Tail!
St. Tail! This is
where the chase ends!
-What's going on here?
-I can't see a thing!
The flash won't reach
from this far away!
This is just fabulous!
Mr. Kuroda! This is big trouble!
A UFO has really appeared!
What are you gonna do?
You know there aren't any rewards!
-What's that?
-Now!
It's...
...showtime!
What's this?
Well, Asuka Jr., I'll be
leaving with the photograph.
Darn! Don't think
I'll let you get away!
-Stop it! Let go of me!
-I won't let go!
I can't stand this, you pervert!
-I'm not a--
-Never mind! Just let go of me!
Ouch.
Not again!
That hurts. I shouldn't use
experimental devices.
Hold it! Just as I thought!
Hold it!
-Open this door! I've taken a picture!
-Give me my reward!
-What is your plan now, Kuroda?
-Sir?
It's over.
Hope you get a picture
of a real UFO next time.
Hey, you!
How did you get that photograph?
-It fell from the sky.
-From the sky?
It's a fake.
I was in trouble because...
...they forced me to have it
revealed at the event.
I see.
So that's why. St. Tail.
Good morning, Asuka Jr. There was
another UFO appearance, wasn't there?
That was just one of St. Tail's
tricks. UFOs don't exist.
You still don't believe?
You're stubborn.
In the first place,
anti-scientific things--
-What is it? What's the matter?
-That.
-Was that a--?
-UFO?
-Wasn't it?
-Guess so.
Wait!