UNFORGIVABLE!
THE BAD GUYS DESTROY A HOUSE
-Good morning!
-Good morning, Meimi!
Hey, Meimi, look at this!
This brings back memories.
Isn't this a Miho-chan doll?
I had one like this.
I found it cleaning my room. It brought
back memories so I brought it with me.
I wonder if I still have mine.
I'll try looking for it.
We girls have a lot of memories
in these dolls, don't we?
You girls are lucky to have
that much time on your hands.
I don't even have time
to make memories.
I'm so busy trying
to catch St. Tail that...
Right. With all those memories of
St. Tail escaping, you're frustrated.
What's that?
If you don't like it,
try catching her quickly.
It'll be your most precious memory.
Though it's probably impossible.
Now you've said it! I'm not after
St. Tail for a reason like that!
Precious memories, what nonsense!
Is that so? Are you saying there are
no memories between you and St. Tail?
Why are you so upset?
-How should I know?
-My doll...
It disgusts me to know
what a dingbat that guy is!
Oh, my. We should be
the ones appreciating him.
Why is that?
He's never done anything to save--
That's not true, is it?
When you're angry, Meimi,
it's usually about Asuka Jr.
Seira, you're mean!
Anyway, today there was another
lost sheep that wandered by here.
A while ago, Michiru came by
to ask for help.
She used to live happily
in a mansion with her parents.
But one year ago, Michiru's father
co-signed a loan for a friend...
...and because of that,
they lost their mansion.
That friend he co-signed for...
...took the loan money
and disappeared.
Not only did the loan company
take control of the mansion...
...but everything inside
of it as well.
Michiru's jewelry box
was a precious thing...
...filled with all kinds of memories.
Michiru hid the box in the house.
Right after that, they were forced
to vacate the property.
Then that jewelry box is
still hidden in the house.
She was planning to get it back later.
But Negoro, who owns
the loan company...
It's you again. You'll get nowhere,
no matter how many times you come.
Just for a little while.
I want to see the inside
of the house one more time.
This house doesn't belong to you
anymore, young lady. It's mine.
Also, this land is being sold...
...so we're gonna have
to tear down the house.
What will happen to her memories?
The jewelry box of memories?!
There's nothing that can be done
about Michiru's house being torn down.
Then at least the jewelry box
should be returned to Michiru.
If it isn't, it'll be too sad.
Ever since the house was taken,
Michiru's mother has become ill.
They're breaking down
the house tomorrow.
We only have tonight
to carry this out.
Let's get those memories back!
What's this?
Is this a--?
"Tonight, I'll be entering
the Misaki mansion...
...to pick up a jewelry box.
-St. Tail"
It's a notice from St. Tail!
-A notice from St. Tail?
-Where is it?
Don't push. I can't see it!
So that's the Misaki mansion.
What's happening?
-I'll leave tomorrow up to you.
-I understand.
This is really troublesome, isn't it?
Tearing down a mansion like this.
Making this an open lot is the terms
the buyer made. What can I say?
It'll all be done by tomorrow.
We're finally getting to the cash.
Didn't think that it'd go this smooth.
Like a bubble on a wet hand.
Nobody would suspect that
you borrowed the money and I lent it.
Not realizing a thing...
...your co-signer Misaki is
either a real nice guy or an idiot.
-Oh, how my heart aches.
-That guy picked a bad friend.
-Speak for yourself.
-Excuse me.
Who are you?
Mr. Negoro? I'm Asuka Jr. I'm assisting
in the St. Tail investigations.
St. Tail?
Actually, we just received
a notice from her.
She's going to appear here tonight
to steal a jewelry box.
A jewelry box? Impossible!
How could there be such a thing
in this unoccupied mansion?
By the way, what's that for?
Tomorrow we're clearing this lot.
You're going to tear it down.
If St. Tail is coming, there will
be a horde of cops here too!
I know.
Anyway, you'd better disappear.
But is there really
a jewelry box in there?
I got everything in there out.
There shouldn't be anything left.
Something's fishy.
St. Tail wouldn't come to steal
something that's not there.
Could she have uncovered our scheme?
And the proof is hidden in this
mansion? And she's coming to steal it.
St. Tail has caused many criminals
to be arrested.
Maybe we should clear
the lot off tonight.
Whatever St. Tail is up to,
if there's no place here...
...there's nothing to worry about.
If the mansion isn't here,
there's nothing that can be done.
Since it's been decided,
let's tear it down right away!
Here it is!
It's a woman!
Hey, look at this!
What's all the panic about?
Look! Doesn't this
bring back memories?
It's the Miho-chan doll
that you bought for me.
I remember!
I bought it for your fifth birthday.
You've had it all these years.
This doll was so very precious
to you, Meimi.
You didn't want any doll
other than this Miho-chan.
Papa, can you make this doll
new again with your magic?
Well, let's see. I wonder if I can.
But your precious memories
may disappear too, Meimi.
Well, I'll keep it the way it is.
Here.
I'm sorry, I've got to go to work.
So please entertain our guest.
You're joking!
I can't let you do that!
Why? We've got to complete
the clearing of the lot by tonight.
Get out of the way.
You said it'd be done tomorrow,
didn't you?
The plans have changed.
St. Tail's coming!
There's no time for that!
She can take anything she wants.
What could be
in an empty house anyway?
A jewelry box. I understand.
Then please let us check if there
is really a jewelry box in there.
There isn't one.
Well, if it's not there,
I'm clearing the place.
But should we find one,
you'll have to leave things to us.
If stolen things are in there...
...we have an obligation
to protect them from St. Tail!
You won't find one.
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
St. Tail, hurry.
I don't know why, but they're
planning to clear the lot tonight.
You're kidding! But why?
I've checked up a bit
on that loan company...
...and it seems to be a little shady.
Meimi, be very careful.
Don't worry. I'll be back
with Michiru's box of memories.
May the blessings of God be with us.
Please let me get there in time!
Well? There's nothing here, is there?
Now, are you satisfied?
St. Tail has probably made a mistake.
I'll be keeping you to your promise
and start clearing the lot.
I haven't said it's not here yet!
A promise is a promise.
I won't stand for this any longer.
The work is going to be started.
Even if I stay?
You should be careful
of the chandelier.
It'll probably come falling
with the tremor.
What a stubborn idiot!
Stop it! Stop it right now!
What a pesky brat!
What do you think you're doing?
It's St. Tail!
Everyone! Get to your positions!
That's St. Tail!
Knock her down with the bulldozer!
Never mind! I'll do it myself!
How terrible can he get?
Stop it!
Darn! Quit scampering around!
After her!
St. Tail has entered the mansion!
Darn it!
Hold it!
It can't be.
I'm sure it was this room.
St. Tail, you're in full view.
Give yourself up, St. Tail!
It's unforgivable
to take someone's memories!
I've got you cornered, St. Tail!
You! Come here!
Wait a minute!
What are you guys doing?
With all this weight,
the chandelier is gonna fall!
There!
That's where it was?
St. Tail, I'll have you
show me your identity!
That idiot! At a time like this!
Unforgivable!
If I get rid of this mansion,
there's nothing St. Tail can do!
What?
I won't let you destroy any more!
It's...
...Show...
...Time!
You pesky worm!
Exactly what I was worried about.
He's getting licked! Darn!
Goodbye. And I've got
the jewelry box of memories.
Memories?
What do you mean, memories, St. Tail?
Hey, what are you doing here?
Hold it right there!
-And where are you going?
-Well...
-Hey, son!
-Dad? Why are you here?
I had business with these two.
Negoro and Momochi.
-You're under arrest for fraud.
-Fraud?
These two are convicted criminals.
We already know
that you two teamed up...
...to swindle this mansion
from Mr. Misaki. Give up!
Darn it!
-Mother, here, some water.
-Thank you.
I'm home!
Father, my treasure box has come back!
My precious memories are back!
I'm glad! Then Michiru's able
to return to that house.
Yes. It's only natural because
those two have been caught.
But the house has
been damaged so much.
Don't worry.
The memories haven't been damaged!
What is it?
I've heard that you've made
a few more memories.
Memories! Quit bugging me about them!
You act just like someone I know.
Someone you know?
Well, who was it?
Oh, forget it!
It's none of your concern!