I've caught you, St. Tail!
You won't get away this time!
Meimi!
Asuka Jr.
So you were the thief, St. Tail.
You had me fooled all this time.
No, no. I wasn't fooling you!
All this time I just couldn't
get myself to tell you the truth!
A dream?
Ruby, I just can't get myself
to tell him...
...that I'm St. Tail.
I definitely can't tell him. And I
definitely can't let him catch me.
A FAKE CALLING CARD!?
THE SECRET OF THE PERFUME TRAP!
I'm leaving!
Addressed to me?
Good morning!
Is it my imagination? Aren't the girls
putting extra effort into their hair?
Yep. And here's why!
A cosmetic company is looking for
a girl to introduce their new shampoo.
Sawatari says that he's taking
a photo to compete in the event.
I see.
Well, just sit and watch.
These hands will be sending
a supermodel into the world.
Meimi, look this way!
Nothing different.
Just doing his same old stunts.
It's Meimi, after all.
How can you fight it?
She's got beautiful hair.
St. Tail's hair is
a hundred times prettier.
You don't change either, do you?
What's that?
Speak of the devil!
It's a notice from St. Tail!
What will it be this time?
-Let me have a look!
-What are you doing?
"Tomorrow night I will be stealing
the Parfum Takarada Special. -St. Tail"
-She's going after some perfume?
-So that's the next caper.
What's this supposed to mean? I didn 't
send this notice. Who could it be?
Why are you in such deep prayer?
You look very depressed.
I have just lost my father
in an accident.
I'm very sorry to hear that.
My father was a perfumer.
He developed fragrances
for perfumes, didn't he?
Yes. Before his death, he mentioned
a new perfume that was completed.
And he was very happy about it.
A perfume? Could it be--?
But just before it was to be completed,
he got into a car accident.
When Father died, he had
a notebook clenched in his hand.
The notebook contained the formula
for his new perfume.
Your father passionately loved
his work until the very last moment.
Yes, but the final ingredient
wasn't written in the notes.
Now that he's gone,
we don't have any idea what it was.
Oh, my. You don't have a single clue?
The last entry in the notebook
was "Earring of Snow."
But it was written like a secret code.
It's probably a flower
that blossoms in the winter.
Were you in deep prayer trying
to find out what it is?
Oh, no! I will definitely complete
Father's perfume on my own.
That's not what is troubling me.
I ask for God's help,
for the sake of my brother.
Your brother?
After Father's death, my brother
has become a different person.
He doesn't care about the perfume,
only about how much he can sell it for.
He is planning an outrageous scheme!
This is the greenhouse.
This is where we raise flowers and
concoct ingredients for the perfume.
And this is the Parfum
Takarada Special, Asuka Jr.
We haven't mass-produced it yet,
so this is the only bottle.
For St. Tail to crave this,
she must see its true value.
Please leave the security to us.
Let's make the security a big thing,
as extravagant as possible.
As extravagant as possible?
I'm selling this to a major
manufacturer in three days.
It would be a disaster
if it gets stolen before that.
Yes.
In any case, it's a product
that's sure to be a big hit.
I see.
It'll be a smash hit with the help
of our little St. Tail.
A St. Tail brand perfume?
That fake notice was probably sent by
Miss Takarada's brother to Asuka Jr.
What's that?
He is trying to sell an incomplete
perfume formula for a high price...
...by advertising it as "a perfume
worth being stolen by St. Tail."
What a dirty trick.
His sister, Yuriko,
says that she's against...
...sending the incomplete formula
out on the market...
...and deceiving people
with false advertisement.
I'd really like to help her.
Meimi, you'll do it, won't you?
OK. Let's make the best
of that fake calling card!
Well, now, let's begin
our long homeroom.
Oh, the petals are falling!
-What's wrong?
-The cherry blossoms in the yard.
Will the flowers hold
until school is out?
Sister!
Oh, my goodness. Well, all right.
We'll have you go out to play in
the yard for this hour of the class.
Just for this hour now!
Really, they're supposed
to be junior high students.
Is it the season
or do they just want to play?
Sawatari, how could you bring
your camera at a time like this?
You amateur, it's in
beautiful scenery like this...
...when true beauty
can be photographed.
Hey, Meimi!
The same routine.
Where's the difference?
Meimi looks the same to me.
-Meimi, come, come!
-What is it?
What's wrong with me?
That's totally impossible!
Asuka Jr.
What is it?
There's something I want
to ask you, all right?
Do you know what the secret code
"Earring of Snow" means?
What's that?
Asuka Jr. knows a lot of things.
He just might know.
So winter flowers,
what kind are there?
I don't know anything about flowers.
There's just one I've heard of.
When I was 5 years old, my mother...
Tell me!
I think it's a story that
goes back to the Creation.
The Creation?
Well, a story that
goes way back in time.
Everything in nature
has a color, right?
Just as the sky is blue
and the clouds are gray.
Well, the snow went to see God...
...and told him, "It's unfair
that I have no color."
God told the snow, "Ask a flower
to give you its color."
But there wasn't a single flower that
would give the cold snow its color.
How pitiful.
But, just as the snow was
about to give up...
...a flower came forth and said,
"You can have my white color."
Then what?
Since then, it's said that...
...the snow protects that small flower
during the winter.
That's got to be it!
What's the name of that flower?
I forgot.
I know it was
a delicious-sounding name but...
Oh, boy! You're hopeless
at the crucial moment!
Careful!
What are you all worked up over?
It's just a story.
I want to know about the flower
that is able to survive near snow!
I can't tell him I'm St. Tail.
I definitely can't let him catch me!
Thank you. Forget about it!
What was that all about?
I'm home.
Welcome home.
Meimi, come over here a bit.
What is it?
-Mother. Mother.
-What?
Here, Mother.
Strange. It's not my birthday or our
wedding anniversary, but a present?
Never mind, just open it.
What's this? You two are terrible!
It's my new magic trick.
Oh, you! Just look at this mess!
What? Snow? Snow!
Isn't it great?
Father, it's a great idea...
...but isn't it
a bit off-season for snow?
Maybe you're right.
Oh! What am I going to do?
The dinner has...
I'm sorry, Eimi.
Meimi seemed depressed.
I was trying to cheer her up.
I know. She was moaning
in her sleep last night too.
I wonder if something
happened at school.
Don't worry.
She's our daughter after all.
She'll get herself back on her feet.
I hope you're right.
Ruby, well, it's time to work.
I won't, I won't...
I can't let him catch me!
Don't worry!
I'm just fine. I'll be back.
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Meimi, the flower that
Asuka Jr. was talking about...
...it's probably called the snow drop.
How did you find out?
It's the only winter flower
that has a delicious-sounding name.
I see! Thanks, Seira!
May the blessings of God be with us.
The perfume in Mr. Takarada's hand
is St. Tail's target.
-Let's keep the security tight.
-Yes, Asuka Jr.!
With this security alone, St. Tail
will be associated with this perfume...
...even if the notice is fake
and St. Tail doesn't show up.
-Asuka Jr., this woman.
-Who are you?
Yuriko! I told you to get out!
Brother, please stop all this!
St. Tail!
Good evening!
Thank you for the invitation.
-Invitation?
-This can't be! The notice is a--
-Something wrong with the notice?
-Oh, nothing.
Why is the real St. Tail here?
I'm the one that sent
the fake calling card out.
- Darn it!
-Brother, wait!
You won't get away!
God sees through everything!
One! Two! Three!
Hold it! That's--
-I'm leaving with the perfume!
-Hold it, St. Tail!
Who will let you get away with it?
Wait! Give that back!
There you go!
Asuka Jr., the perfume!
Get that perfume back for me!
Mr. Takarada, it's time
for you to wake up!
What's going on here, St. Tail?
It's...
...Show...
...Time!
Asuka Jr., this is...
What's happening?
The temperature is-- It's snowing!
Is it her famous illusion trick?
Stop! Father's flowers will die! Stop!
If the flowers die, we won't be able
to make the perfume! Please stop!
Brother, it's your fault. If Father's
flowers die, it's all your fault!
Yuriko, I understand.
Yuriko.
You two will be able
to make a wonderful perfume...
...even without the use of my name.
What are you blabbering about?
Let's forget about it, Asuka Jr.
But the perfume...
That calling card, I was the one
who sent it to you.
Instead of completing the perfume,
all I thought of was how to sell it.
If St. Tail was after it, it would
become famous. That's why I...
What's that?
Asuka Jr., I should have gone
and told you of it sooner.
Snow?
No, they're white flowers!
The fragrance of this flower,
could it be...?
The final ingredient in the notebook,
"Earring of Snow," is this!
We can make it! Father's perfume!
Yuriko, let's try
to complete it together!
Brother!
St. Tail, come down here
and challenge me!
You had me fooled all along,
didn't you?
I didn't mean to fool you.
I can't say it with words.
I can't tell you.
Asuka Jr., I'm sorry
to have troubled you.
I'm glad it was stolen.
St. Tail has helped me to wake up.
Is that so?
This puts me on the spot.
All because of St. Tail.
No, not yet.
I can't afford to get caught yet.
I can't get caught.