St. Tail, that's as far as you go.
You've done it, Inspector Kitamura!
-Thank you for your trouble.
-Yes.
That was just perfect!
It's no good.
The real St. Tail is much faster.
No matter how many simulations
we do, it's no good.
I'd like the chance to meet the real
St. Tail as soon as possible.
I'll get her for sure.
St. Tail, prepare yourself.
A STRONG FOE!
CONFRONTING AN ELITE DETECTIVE
Doesn't Asuka Jr. seem a bit down?
Maybe his idol gave him
the cold shoulder.
Are you serious?
Lately, St. Tail hasn't been
showing herself, right?
So that's it.
Still, he's really down, isn't he?
Looks like it.
I heard about it, Asuka Jr.!
The police department has put together
a team to arrest St. Tail.
Heard that your father's lending
a hand in it too.
Don't bother me.
It isn't a big thing. Just routine.
Sawatari, what's the news?
Let me in on it!
According to Takamiya...
...looks like the police have finally
put together a team to catch St. Tail.
And they're bringing in
a secret weapon!
What's that supposed to be?
It's a super detective, the first ever
for the police department.
Well, just hold on to your horses
for the rest.
I'll be back with more fantastic news.
Meimi.
-Asuka Jr.!
-What is it?
Don't let it bother you.
No matter what kind of
super detective they bring in...
...he'd never be a match for you.
Obviously!
Asuka Jr.!
May I help you?
I'm surprised. Such a cute Sister.
Is there something I can do for you?
So you were in the art business.
Yes, my wife and I travel worldwide...
...collecting all sorts of artwork.
-I'm sure you make a wonderful couple.
-But my wife has fallen ill.
Angel's Smile?
To pay for my wife's medical expenses,
I had to sell our works of art.
But only that statue of the angel...
...I had no intention of letting go
of Angel's Smile.
But the owner of the Parkside Museum
tricked me.
Oh, my.
He was to borrow it
only for the exhibition.
But before I knew it, he said
that I had sold it to him.
Can't something be done?
Nothing. Without me knowing, he made
documents saying I had sold it to him.
That's horrible!
Just one more time...
...I want to display the Angel's Smile
beside my wife's pillow.
I'm sure God will grant you
your wish. I'm sure.
Mr. Asakura's wife is
in quite bad health.
So there isn't much time left.
I'm a bit worried.
According to my information,
the police's secret weapon...
...is really something.
What's so super about this detective?
I don't know all the details...
...but this brilliant detective
has solved many tough cases.
I see. But I'm gonna show that lady
the Angel's Smile one more time!
No matter the opponent,
I can't run without a fight!
That would tarnish St. Tail's name!
You're being a pest.
Oh, come on, just one. Pose!
Leave me alone!
"I'll be at the Parkside Museum tonight
to pick up Angel's Smile. -St. Tail"
-It's a note from St. Tail!
-Is it for real?
-So you're Asuka Jr.
-And just who are you?
Metropolitan Police, special
investigations, Inspector Kitamura.
I'm in charge of
the St. Tail investigations.
-You're the--
-Wow!
-You're joking. She's a detective?
-That's neat.
Wow, the Metropolitan Police has
a woman as its secret weapon.
Kaede Kitamura, 26 years old.
After graduating top of her class,
she entered the police department.
A normal person would have stayed
on that path to success.
She's gone out of her way
to take part in this St. Tail arrest.
Five feet, six inches tall
and approximately 105 pounds.
-What are her measurements?
-I'd say it's about 34, 23, 34.
How disgusting can guys be?
St. Tail may be sailing
into rough waters with this one.
That's for sure!
I won't lose to her!
My Lord, please protect me.
Ruby, pray for me too, okay?
Worried, aren't you? Thanks.
But today's not a good day,
since it'll probably be tough.
St. Tail isn't stupid enough
to get caught with this!
We'll have to see about that.
Son, are you all right?
Darn it!
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Seira, here I go!
That woman detective, I heard
she's going to use a special weapon.
Please be careful.
Don't worry, I know.
I won't be reckless.
May the blessings of God be with us.
If St. Tail is gonna show up,
it'll be from the ceiling.
She'll slip through their fingers,
so I'll get a head start.
With this, we can identify the
movements of everyone in the museum.
Right. It uses an ultraviolet ray.
No matter her disguise,
she can't hide her body temperature.
I see. And that's this red dot?
There's an invader
above the exhibition room!
Welcome, St. Tail.
That was close!
But St. Tail isn't so dumb as
to get caught with this.
Bye-bye.
This seems too easy. Is there really
a secret weapon, I wonder?
It's St. Tail!
It's...
...Show...
...Time!
Just as I thought!
After making such a grand statement,
what's this all about?
Everything is going as planned.
St. Tail is headed southwest
on First Avenue.
What a cute little thing.
She doesn't even know it's bugged.
If we follow this light,
we'll find out where her hideout is.
Tonight is St. Tail's last caper.
Let's see... Where's the hospital
that she's supposed to be in?
Hold it, St. Tail!
Hold it right there!
Asuka Jr.?
I was waiting for you!
I'll be the one to arrest you!
What a guy!
Darn!
I'm definitely gonna be
the one to arrest St. Tail!
Inspector Kitamura,
St. Tail is about to land.
She's going to
the Seika City Community Hospital.
Why a hospital?
The answer is simple. Catch St. Tail
and we'll know everything.
Head her off!
After she steals, regardless
of how good she is...
...she'll let down her guard.
Come on over, St. Tail.
She's here!
St. Tail, this is as far as you go!
You sure blundered this one.
If you didn't get in the way,
we would have had St. Tail!
Be quiet! St. Tail's mine!
Darn! Let me go!
Inspector Kitamura.
Don't worry, I'll find her no matter
where she escapes to with this.
That woman detective,
how did she know my destination?
That's it, run. The tougher
the opponent, the better the game.
- Darn it!
-Just keep cool.
Now she's a rat in a sack.
How does she know where I'm going?
It's a tracking device!
Ruby!
Ruby, where did you come from?
It's no good. I'm...
It's too small.
What shall I do?
No doubt about it. She's in there.
-Let's go in.
-Wait a minute!
It's moving. The inner courtyard!
No, she's headed out of the hospital!
This time, for sure.
It's stopped.
That mansion.
Uncle, grant me my one and only wish.
Leave the St. Tail investigation
in Asuka Jr.'s hands. Oh, please!
I'm sorry to say this...
...but by now that woman detective
has probably caught her.
What do you want here?
Now I've got you cornered!
You're St. Tail, aren't you?
St. Tail, you're under arrest!
This is a bad joke!
It's no use trying to escape!
Dear.
It's definitely an angel
who brought it to us.
Hey, Asuka Jr.!
Heard that you're back in charge
of the St. Tail investigations.
Yep. The mayor came
personally to ask me.
How disappointing. That woman
detective, she had some real pizzazz.
Looks like I'm the only one
who can catch St. Tail after all.
Asuka Jr., good morning!
Why the sudden attack?
You're getting so big-headed
early in the morning.
Darn it! You're a real pest!
Hold it!
Catch me if you can!