-Bye!
-No breakfast?
No, thanks! I'm late!
That hurts!
Watch where you're driving!
-I'm sorry.
-Oh, really! Be careful!
Are you all right?
Are you hurt?
No.
Please accept our deepest apologies.
I'll be late for school!
Master Ryutaro, she forgot it.
I'm almost positive
it's a St. Paulia School hat.
I've found her.
MEIMI IS ENGAGED
TO A MULTI-MILLIONAIRE'S SON!?
-Don't be depressed about being tardy.
-Sister's lecture is starting.
Good, if that's all it is.
It might be the Board Chairman
who will give you a lecture.
You're kidding!
I was only late for school!
Meimi! Please come
to the Chairman's office.
Yes.
Don't you think something's strange?
-Oh, it's you, Saruwatari.
-The name's Sawatari!
What's so strange?
Do you think you'd be called to
the Chairman's office for being tardy?
-Who knows?
-I think this is gonna be a scoop!
-Meimi, come here.
-Yes!
I'm very sorry!
I was tardy because a car--
She's the one! No mistake!
She's the one I've been looking for!
You're--
I'm very sorry about this morning.
My name is Ryutaro Tomikoji.
This morning you dropped your hat.
This gentleman came to return it.
Thank you very much.
And also it's very sudden...
...but Mr. Tomikoji requests that
he be given the chance to date you.
Date? With me?
This meeting is a God-given destiny.
Love at first sight is
what you'd call it.
It's all so sudden and...
Meimi, if you accept, we shall
forget the tardy incident.
Well, he's a most courteous young man.
To go out of his way for permission
to date one of our students.
You're correct.
Everyone tells me so.
I understand.
Are you sure?
I was sure you'd give that reply.
Well, it's time we leave for our date.
Please take good care
of our Meimi. And now...
Regarding the contribution, I will
have a company employee prepare it.
Thank you very much.
Contribution? I've been sold.
-Then we'll be back.
- Have a nice time.
Scoop!
It's a scoop.
A simple park like this
can be quite refreshing.
I couldn't think of anywhere
for a date.
I think your pureness is so cute.
That's it!
I should ask him for the impossible.
Then he'd be convinced
to forget this date.
-I've thought of something!
-Wherever you wish.
I'd like to eat at Tetsujin-tei
and go to a musical at Bayside Hall.
-Let's not forget Wonderland Garden.
-OK. Let's get going.
What a long line!
Meimi, what's the matter?
The entrance is over here.
But we've got to stand in line.
We came in without standing in line.
Are you sure it's OK?
Mother is sponsor of this restaurant
so we can come in anytime.
I see. Ryutaro, your mother
is quite a woman.
Yes. After Father's death, she's been
running the company by herself.
But she does too much
when it comes to me.
Like deciding my fiancee.
I'd like to decide on my own fiancee.
-You're right.
-Well, the musical is next, isn't it?
Yes. Could you possibly be sponsors
of the Bayside Hall as well?
You're kidding.
But Mother has special reserved seats
so there's no need to worry.
This guy has no idea
what standing in line is.
-Shall we go?
-Wait.
My parents will be worried
if I'm late.
You're right.
Next time, we'll get permission
from your parents and enjoy our date.
I'll take you home.
Don't worry. I can get home
by myself. Goodbye.
Meimi! You're shy, aren't you?
This is the fourth day. No matter
what Sister says, I'm exhausted.
Meimi, don't be such a spoilsport!
She's right. You get to go
to all the popular places.
It's God's teachings. That's what you
get for accepting a date so easily.
Oh, Seira. I'm leaving from
the back gate so he won't catch me.
I'm leaving the rest to you.
Young lady, we've been waiting
for you. Shall we go?
Yes.
Is something troubling you?
If you're OK with it,
I'd be glad to listen.
Someone switched the heirloom necklace
my mother left me with a fake one.
-This is it.
-What? This shop?
Mother is the sponsor
of this boutique.
Is that so?
-I'd like to select something for you.
-You don't have to buy me clothes.
You're meeting my mother,
so please be conscious of your dress.
Meet your mother?
Yes. Tomorrow evening,
Mother's having a party.
I want to introduce you
as my fiancee there.
Fiancee? You can't do that!
I have no intentions to--
I'm still a junior high student!
You didn't hear the Chairman? I'm
dating you with intentions to marry.
I've heard nothing of the sort!
It's a scoop!
Good morning.
-The news is all over the class!
-Is it true he proposed?
He's the son of the owner
of the Tomikoji Group!
How do all of you know?
Looks like the source of the news
is from over there.
Asuka Jr., have you seen it?
It's my greatest scoop! Hey, Asuka Jr.!
Be quiet!
Are you a show business reporter?
Don't get so upset.
-I said, be quiet, Saruwatari!
-It's Sawatari!
If you don't like Saruwatari,
how about Sawagani?
That's jealousy.
Hey, Meimi, Miss Popular?
Meimi, I'm sorry to disturb you
when you're so busy.
Oh, Seira, you too! Don't be mean.
It's work, isn't it?
The job is for Miss Yumi Imamura.
She was a secretary for that
woman entrepreneur, Madam Ranko.
But Madam Ranko has switched...
...her mother's heirloom necklace
with a fake one.
What's that?
President, this isn't the necklace
that I left with you the other day.
What in the world
are you talking about?
Are you saying
I replaced it with a fake?
I know the real one.
Please give it back to me!
Stop this right now!
If you don't trust me,
then you don't have to work here.
Leave here at once!
Yumi, who complained to Madam Ranko,
lost her job as secretary.
What a terrible woman!
I understand.
Just leave things to St. Tail!
This is the fake necklace.
It seems that Madam Ranko always
has the real one on her.
And your only chance is the party
that's being held tomorrow night.
Wait, tomorrow's party?
Is it...?
Right. Madam Ranko's real name
is Ranko Tomikoji...
...Ryutaro's mother.
The party tomorrow will include
foreign diplomats and other VIPs...
...so the security will be
quite tight.
What are you saying?
I think the best way to get in is
to go to that party with Ryutaro.
Seira! Do you know what
going to that party means?
I won't! I'll get in there
on my very own!
Meimi.
Hey, Asuka Jr.! Kick the ball!
Sure. Just wait.
Tonight at the party hall, I'll be
picking up Madam Ranko 's necklace.
A notice from St. Tail!
Hey, Asuka Jr.
What are you going
to do about this ball?
-I'm home!
-Welcome home, Papa.
Welcome home. I'll get tea for you.
Thanks, but, Mama...
It's beautiful!
I've always wanted one like this!
OK, you're getting sleepy.
One, two, three!
Wow! Papa, is this hypnotism?
But it's still in the research stage.
All right, when I count to three,
you'll become a cat.
One, two, three!
I'd say it's quite good.
When I count to three, you'll
return to normal. Three, two, one.
What? I...?
Mother, you were a cat a minute ago.
You used me as a guinea pig,
didn't you?
-I'm sorry. Here's the pendant.
-You won't get away with that!
-Forgive me!
-No, I won't!
Shall we go? We're in the way.
Good evening.
I knew you'd come to the party
without telling your parents.
Ryutaro!
Shall we go?
But that dress just won't do.
-Old man, bring it to me.
-Yes, sir.
What do you mean by "it"?
He'll bring the dress I selected
for you, so please change.
Young lady.
Isn't it beautiful?
Got no choice.
I'll have to do as Seira said.
Plus, that's a nice dress.
I don't need the security. As you
ca n see, I have the necklace on.
But St. Tail is able
to steal from anywhere!
As I've said, that is why
we've hired our own security guards.
Also, to have you roam around
dressed like that is a nuisance.
I don't mind if you do your security
but do it outside.
Please wait! I'm not finished.
Darn it.
Asuka Jr.
-Meimi.
-Yes.
Meimi.
Meimi. He really proposed to her.
That woman over there is my mother.
That's the necklace.
- Meimi.
-Yes?
Let's have one dance
before I introduce you.
- No, thanks. I can't dance.
-I'll teach you.
-Meimi, you're quite good.
-Thank you.
Where's Madam Ranko?
There!
Ryutaro, I feel a bit ill.
Would you like a drink?
No, don't worry. I'll be fine
with a bit of fresh air.
Wonder if she's OK.
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
May the blessings of God be with us.
-What's this?
-Where's the lights?
What's going on?
My necklace is gone!
It's St. Tail!
She's appeared! Let's go!
-It's St. Tail!
-Hurry! Hurry! Get it back!
Out of the way!
I'll be leaving with the necklace.
It's...
...Show...
...Time!
Oh, no!
Darn it! I won't let you escape!
Hold it!
Wait! St. Tail!
I'm the one
who's gonna catch St. Tail!
Wait!
Oh, boy. Why is Ryutaro here?
That's it. It'd be just right!
Miss St. Tail,
I'd like to talk to you.
One, two, three!
Take this fake back to your mother.
St. Tail, you won't escape this time!
Asuka Jr., please take care of him!
What a dirty trick!
Three, two, one!
Rats! What a coward!
Take good care of this memory
of your mother.
Thank you, God.
Mother.
Ryutaro! You got it back
for me, didn't you?
She doesn't know it's fake!
As a reward, I'll do
anything you want me to!
Really? Then I don't want to marry
the person you decided on.
You're not introducing me
to your mother now!
I want to marry St. Tail!
Her long, graceful movements.
Beautiful hair. Her long, slim legs.
Meeting her is a God-given destiny.
Young lady, I'm very sorry.
Looks like Master Ryutaro's got
that illness again.
So, what's everybody
gonna say about me?
Yumi was very happy that
the necklace was returned to her.
Hey! Too bad about
Mr. Prince Charming, Meimi.
Oh, cut it out! Love at first sight
is a big pain in the butt.
Sorry, sorry.
Well, I'm going on ahead.
Asuka Jr. seems to be in a good mood.
Sure does.
It's nice to see him smiling again.