Who's there?
No, you mustn't be holding that jewel!
Evil spirits are in it! The moon's
evil spirits are locked in that jewel!
The moon's evil spirits?
You've got to come up with
a better story than that.
It's true! If you hold it up
to the full moon...
...the evil spirits will
be resurrected.
Stop your babbling!
This moon's jewel belongs to me now.
STEAL THE JEWEL OF THE MOON!
-Meimi!
-Oh, Sawatari.
Hi. Talk about great timing.
I'm on my way to cover a story.
Do you want to come with me?
Why should I go with you, when I'm
not even on the news-writing staff?
Because you understand
my intellectual reporting.
-I wouldn't say that, exactly.
-Anyway, we're wasting time!
Hey, wait a minute.
Sawatari, let go of me!
That Sawatari! Where does he think
he's taking Meimi to?
May I help you?
I came because I wanted to pray,
but I don't know how to start.
My name's Mochida.
This is rather embarrassing.
I used to be a burglar.
I just got out of prison.
A burglar?
Please don't get me wrong.
I'm trying to go straight now.
Only thing is, I have a problem.
Perhaps it would help
if you talked about it.
All the things
I stole were returned...
...to their rightful owners
by the police while I was in prison.
All except one. A jewel which
contains the moon's evil spirits.
The moon's evil spirits?
Right after I stole the jewel,
its owner died.
He had no family,
and the jewel was forgotten about.
After that, it slipped past the police
and was sold several times.
I finally located the present owner
and asked him to return the jewel.
What did you intend to do with
the jewel when you got it back?
I want to return it
to its rightful owner.
I mean, I want to leave it
at his gravesite.
That's very honorable.
That's the only thing
I can do in atonement.
But the present owner turned me down.
I thought about stealing
the jewel back, but...
No, you mustn't steal, not after
you worked so hard to reform.
You're right.
Stealing it just wouldn't be right.
Why don't you pray again and this
time put your entire heart in it?
Yes, I'll do that.
Thank you for listening.
By the way, where is that jewel now?
It's called the Jewel of the Moon
and is on display at the Space Museum.
Oh, yes, I've heard it's supposed
to glow like the moon.
So this is the Jewel of the Moon.
It's beautiful!
There's a rumor that the evil spirits
of the moon are trapped in it.
That's just hearsay.
I wonder. Still, it is exciting
to think about it.
That's the space stage...
...made to simulate
the weightlessness in outer space.
That planet looks like the real thing!
That's a holograph,
a 3-D picture of the real thing.
Rats, I forgot to take pictures!
Meimi, get closer to
the Jewel of the Moon. Hurry!
Yes, two beautiful objects.
This will make a nice shot.
Wait a minute, don't bother me.
I'm busy!
Like I said-- Asuka Jr.!
Didn't you see that?
Never mind that. Why are you here?
Well, I...
I'll bet you followed us here because
you got jealous seeing us together.
Why would I be jealous
about a girl like her?
Well, excuse me!
All right then, why are you here?
I came here to see how
their security system is set up.
The security system?
Please, Mr. Urano!
Please, Mr. Urano. Give the Jewel
of the Moon back to me, please!
You must be out of your mind.
I'd be a fool to give it
to a former thief like you.
Why can't you understand?
-Enough of this! Throw him out.
-Yes, sir.
Let me go!
Mr. Urano, listen to me!
I went through the black market and
paid a lot of money to get that jewel.
I'm not letting that thief
get his hands on it.
I'm going to get rich
putting it on display.
The trouble with you is...
Are you all right, sir?
Thank you. I'm fine.
I see. So that's what his motive was.
The way things are, Mr. Mochida
will resort to stealing again.
Let's get that jewel back for him.
Yes, Seira, let's do it.
Boy, that Sawatari sure
has a big mouth.
What's this?
"I'm going to
the Space Museum tonight...
...to steal the Jewel of the Moon.
-St. Tail"
What's going on? Rats!
I wish she'd give me
notice ahead of time.
Stupid Asuka Jr.
He's always interfering.
Hey, Asuka Jr., what's the big rush?
Get out of my way!
I can't be wasting time with you!
It's from St. Tail!
This is the break I've been
waiting for! Asuka Jr., wait!
Sorry, Ruby. I have a job to do.
I'll see you later.
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Still, it does bother me to think
there's evil in that jewel.
Oh, Seira, that's nothing but hearsay.
Yes, but you mustn't let your guard
down. Be careful, Meimi.
Don't worry. I'll handle it!
May the blessings of God be with us.
I don't need your services.
Please wait.
Even if you don't hire me, the mayor
has ordered me to arrest St. Tail.
Follow me.
Wow, look at all the equipment!
With equipment like this, St. Tail is
no more than a mouse, don't you agree?
Mr. Urano, this equipment is
no match for St. Tail.
Well, if you're going to insist,
do as you wish.
Just don't interfere with our work.
-Yes, I understand.
-Boy, what a grouch!
It's been forced open, but by whom?
Boy, I'm getting old.
I'm already out of breath.
-What's wrong?
-I thought I saw a shadow on monitor A.
-You what?
-Is she here?
Why, that's Mr. Mochida!
I can't let him commit a crime.
I've got to do something!
-It must have been my imagination.
-Don't fall apart on me.
It's St. Tail.
Hey, wait up!
Even the infamous St. Tail couldn't
steal the jewel from this museum.
Hey, wait up!
What is this?
Crap!
Rats! You're not
getting away, St. Tail!
Do it.
It's a high electrical current!
Oh, no!
Here goes.
Come back here, St. Tail!
Snap out of it, Mr. Mochida.
Mr. Urano, using high voltage
is very dangerous!
I will use every means available
to protect my priceless display.
You didn't tell us you hid the jewel
and were displaying a holograph!
That's dirty!
I'm not so stupid that I'd let
someone steal my jewel so easily.
It sent St. Tail--
I mean, Holy Tail...
...scampering away with her tail
between her legs. How fitting.
Damn that Urano.
He hid the Jewel of the Moon.
Mr. Mochida, I promise I'll get
the Jewel of the Moon back for you.
I can't do my job unless
you tell me where the real jewel is!
Your services are not needed. We can
take care of St. Tail ourselves.
Let's go. St. Tail took quite a blow.
I don't think she'll be back tonight.
No, I'm sure she'll return.
It's in her nature.
That's strange.
Monitor F has stopped.
What's going on?
The hologram system's being activated.
All the monitors are showing
the hologram system.
What's going on?
No!
I've got it.
I know where the jewel's hidden!
What'd you say?
Mr. Urano,
that moon is the jewel, isn't it?
Oh, I get it. He hid it
inside the holograph image!
Good evening!
St. Tail, I'll get you
for sure tonight!
It's Show Time!
I'm inviting you three
to the space station!
-Rats!
-This is some scoop!
If I turn the power off,
the anti-gravity field will disappear!
St. Tail, you'll be thrown
to the floor!
Why doesn't she fall?
The jewel is mine.
I'm not giving it back!
What's happening?
What's this?
This couldn't be...
It's the evil from the moon!
No! The jewel is acting as a lens.
The moonlight hit it and it's
giving off that blinding glow!
There.
I'm taking the Jewel of the Moon
back with me.
St. Tail, stop!
Rats! She got away again.
Don't get depressed. I have a picture
of her right here in my camera!
I am returning your jewel.
May you rest in peace.
St. Tail, with your help,
I managed to stay clean. Thank you.
We're finally going
to uncover St. Tail's identity!
-What's this?
-I don't remember taking this!
You lousy reporter, all that talk
about unveiling St. Tail's identity!
Shut up, you miserable detective!
-Why, you!
-The same to you!
If you're so hot,
why don't you arrest St. Tail?
Why, you!