Excuse me, aren't you Emi Honma,
the teenage idol?
Yes. Have we met somewhere?
-I see your picture in the magazines.
-I'm flattered.
What brings you here today?
You don't have to say if it puts
someone in a difficult situation.
No, I want to tell you.
The truth is, I have a problem.
I've been dating someone, but no one,
not even my management agency, knows.
I put a picture
taken of us together...
...in my locket
and always kept it near me.
Once, when I left it in
my dressing room for a moment...
...Mr. Iwasaki from a rival
production came and stole it.
Oh, dear.
And then Mr. Iwasaki came
to me and said:
Let me see, what should I do
about this, this picture?
The press would go crazy
if I sold it to them.
But that would mean
the end of your career.
-Please, give it back to me!
-OK, I'll give it back to you.
In exchange, your part
as Yoko in that new movie...
...you could turn down the part
and give it to one of my girls.
You could pretend to be sick
or something.
If you don't do it, I won't be
responsible for this picture.
How terrible!
I don't want to cause trouble
for my agency.
I came here because
I don't know what to do.
Please cheer up.
I'm sure God will help you.
SAVE THE PRETTY IDOL GIRL!
Meimi!
Big news, big news!
Sawatari.
The shampoo company's
image girl contest!
Look, you passed
the preliminaries! See?
Wow! That's great!
Yep, you're one step closer
to becoming a big star.
-This is great!
-You'll go to the contest, won't you?
Just hold on there!
And when you become a big star,
don't forget about us!
Listen...
No way! She'll be so busy, she won't
even be able to come to school!
-Oh, wow!
-Sawatari!
If you think becoming a big star
is that easy, you're crazy!
-What's with him? Spoilsport.
-Really.
I wonder, was it something we said?
I don't think so, no.
Oh, I almost forgot.
Rina also passed. See?
No!
I'm pretty sure she entered herself.
She has a lot
of confidence in herself.
I'm not going to participate
in the contest! No way!
Now, Meimi, listen. That girl Emi
who came here yesterday for help...
The one who wants her locket?
I'll do it!
You don't understand. Emi is one
of the judges for that contest.
She was one of the past winners.
And that Mr. Iwasaki is
also one of the judges.
Unless Emi announces she is turning
down the role by that day...
...he says he'll publicize the picture
after the contest.
I think our best bet would be
to get the locket...
...during the contest
and return it to Emi.
But why do I have to enter a contest?
I understand.
I would never have guessed that
you were so afraid of contests.
-Just hold on there!
-Forget it. Just forget it.
Who says I'm afraid? All right then,
I'll show you. I'll enter that contest!
Forgive me, Meimi.
I didn't mean to say what I did.
A note!
"On the day of the beauty contest,
I'll take a locket...
...from Mr. Iwasaki of the Rainbow
Production Company. -St. Tail"
Hey, come back here!
Rina. Give it to me.
Did you hear?
I'm entering that contest too.
I want to test my capabilities.
The one Sawatari was talking about,
you're in it too?
Will you come and watch me?
Why do I have to go?
Girls are a pain.
Oh, all right. Now give it back!
That's all you think about, St. Tail!
It was a man dressed like a girl!
There's a future star
standing right in front of you!
Give it back!
Asuka Jr., have you, you know,
gotten taller?
I'd better make my move. Soon the
other girls will start noticing him.
I'd better stake my claim on him.
I'm home!
- Hi there!
- Hi, Meimi.
-Emi Honma's being interviewed on TV.
-Really?
Emi, congratulations
on getting the role of Yoko.
Thank you.
I owe everything to all my fans.
And does that include your boyfriend?
My boyfriend is all of my fans.
Poor Emi, it must be hard for her.
She's right. She's too young
to have a boyfriend.
I wouldn't be so sure.
Even junior high kids have
significant others these days.
Meimi, you don't have a boyfriend,
do you? You're much too young.
I never imagined!
My Meimi's got a boyfriend!
I what?
Oh, dear, my idyllic life
is coming to an end.
Calm down, dear. Meimi hasn't said
anything about liking a certain boy!
What? You don't like boys?
Does that mean you prefer girls?
That is a problem.
Let's have a heart-to-heart talk.
I'm going to my room.
-Enough of this nonsense!
-But, Eimi...
I'm home, Ruby. Did you miss me?
You're my best friend, aren't you?
Sorry. I had something on my mind.
If I become a star,
I wonder if he'll look at me.
We've been waiting for you.
My name is Yamashiro.
I'm in charge of this contest.
This is Mr. Iwasaki
from Rainbow Productions.
Hello.
You'd better arrest that burglar.
She's such a nuisance!
I'm doing my best!
Your father may be a detective,
but how will you arrest her?
Judging from this building's floor
plan and her mode of operation...
...there's a high possibility
she'll appear directly on-stage.
And so I thought we could rig
the stage curtain...
...to fall on her like a casting net,
thus trapping her.
I understand. You have my permission.
I will capture her.
I won't fail this time.
And now the contest begins.
First is a question-and-answer
segment, then a camera test.
Entry 1, please come forward!
Entry 1, Manami Yoshizawa.
I'm 16 years old.
What are you currently most devoted to?
To my music and dancing.
I am also serious about putting
every effort into this audition.
Thank you.
-What are your dreams for the future?
-To become an actress.
-Please turn to the right.
-Of course.
All right. Now turn around and smile.
Make a complete turn.
That's fine, thank you.
-This isn't easy, is it?
-Next contestant, entry 2.
My name is Mutsumi Hijiri.
My name is Yoko Hizawa.
My name is Yuki Uchida.
Seira, where's Rina and Meimi?
-I'm sure they'll be out soon.
-I guess.
My name is Rina Takamiya.
I'm 14 years old.
I'm pleased to meet you all.
15, is there someone special
in your life now?
Yes, there is.
All right, smile.
Now turn to the right.
Darn that St. Tail. Why does she
want the locket Mr. Iwasaki has?
I don't understand.
Never mind. I've got to concentrate
on capturing her, that's all.
All right, come on, St. Tail.
Look, it's Meimi!
Number 18.
My name is Meimi Haneoka.
How old are you?
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm 14.
What is your idea of the perfect man?
This I've got to hear!
Someone like my father!
Rats.
Oops, I think I goofed.
And that concludes
our program for today.
The results of today's judging
of these 50 contestants...
...will be sent out within 3 days.
There's still one left, 51!
What's going on?
This part of the show?
What's going on here?
-Is there someone left?
-No, I'm sure there were only 50 girls.
Turn on the lights!
Where are the lights?
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
On the screen...
St. Tail?
One!
Two!
Three!
It's St. Tail!
Hi!
What is this smoke?
Is it St. Tail?
Meimi, I pray God is with you.
Now, drop the curtain!
Seira!
We'd better not move around now.
Besides, you seem pretty slow.
Sorry.
Don't worry, you'll be safe with me.
What's so funny?
I haven't told any jokes.
Drop the curtain! Hurry!
What's the holdup?
Sorry, Asuka Jr.! We can't move!
Number 51, St. Tail!
I am a thief! How's that?
Damn! You're not getting the locket!
I see you, Mr. Iwasaki!
You won't get away!
It's...
...Show...
...Time!
Beauty contests are fun
but how's this shampoo?
Now, watch closely.
One!
Two!
Three!
St. Tail, that's not fair!
My locket.
I have the locket!
Thank you.
Damn this smoke!
I'm definitely going
to get that St. Tail!
You should be ashamed.
As the mayor's niece, I'm embarrassed.
We're sorry!
Rats. You're not
getting away with this.
I don't care who does it,
just pull the rope!
Rope?
-Asuka Jr.!
-Meimi!
Oh, no!
It's so heavy.
Hurry. I've got to get out of here.
This isn't exactly going as I planned.
- This can't be happening!
-I've got you at last!
He'll hate me!
Let me see your face!
Please don't hate me.
No!
Asuka Jr.! Sorry! Are you all right?
Don't arrest her!
She got my locket back for me!
Asuka Jr.?
It's a sure bet that I didn't pass.
You can never tell! Sometimes
they go for things like that.
-Seira.
-Yes?
I can't wait for the results!
Don't worry about it.
You had the best response!
I goofed up.
Give it up, trying to be a star.
What?
Your father wouldn't approve.
If I were your father, I wouldn't.
Yes, you're right.
What a disappointment!
Both Meimi and Rina didn't pass.
We thought they'd be able to
introduce us to some handsome actors!
Listen here...
I'm positive
he had her trapped back then.
But he let her go.
I'm positive of that!
I've got a great idea.
I'll keep St. Tail away from him.
That way, he's sure to notice me!