Too bad about that contest,
huh, Meimi?
Yeah, and Rina too, but I heard
you did pretty good. Right, Asuka Jr.?
They both didn't make it.
That means they weren't good enough.
You're right, it was stupid...
...of you to let St. Tail get away
when you had her trapped.
Why, you! Back then--
-Back then what?
-Back then--
I just remembered. I have things
to do. I'll see you later!
Me too!
Back then, I...
Meimi, don't rub it in.
He's really hurt.
I don't know what got
into me that night.
Asuka Jr., I swear
I'll get you to notice me.
THE MAYOR'S AMBITION!
STEALING A SWAN (PART 1)
Excuse me, Mayor Morinaka.
The sculpture from Sakuraoka
has arrived.
Thank you.
Have them bring it up here.
What sculpture, Uncle?
Rina, you've heard of Ichiro Kanoh,
haven't you?
Yes, the renowned sculptor?
Thank you.
Is this one of his sculptures?
This is The Swan,
one of his first pieces.
Wow, it's beautiful.
It's crystal, isn't it?
It belongs to the city of Sakuraoka...
...but the mayor's lent it
to us for a month.
I want our citizens to see this,
so I'm displaying it at the museum.
It looks expensive.
By the way, Rina, what did you
want to see me about?
What's wrong?
It's about Asuka Jr.!
Asuka Jr. You've been fond of him
from the time you moved to this city.
-What about him?
-Asuka Jr. ...
He has no intention
of arresting St. Tail!
What do you mean by that?
I saw him. He had her trapped
the other night...
...but he let go of her hand!
He let her go!
You're sure about that?
Letting him remain on the case
is a waste of time.
You must take him off
all of St. Tail's investigations.
I understand. Let me think about it.
Yes, Uncle. You know what's best.
Has The Swan reached Seika City?
Yes, we just confirmed it
with Mayor Morinaka.
Good work.
I guess you could say
the stage is set.
Yabe, when did you get here?
Mr. Okajima, you are truly
a corrupt mayor.
You lend the crystal to Seika, then
have it stolen and fill your pocket.
Just call me smart.
That's why I hired an experienced
thief like you to help me.
I'm aware of that.
If it's stolen from Seika...
...the responsibility's not yours,
and you get the crystal.
On top of that, Seika has to pay you
a lot in compensation, don't they?
Never mind. How are
your preparations going?
Don't worry.
Everything's taken care of.
Do a good job getting it.
I'm counting on you.
Good morning, Meimi!
Ryoko, Kyoko, good morning!
Did you read the newspaper?
I was absolutely shocked!
"Tomorrow evening, I'll go to the art
museum to steal The Swan. -St. Tail"
-She's being very bold this time.
-She sure is.
What's going on?
I didn't make this announcement.
What are you gonna do?
She's making a big deal.
-It's obvious--
-Obvious she'll get away with it?
Shut up! I'm not letting her
get away purposely!
Sorry.
If you keep letting her get away,
the mayor will lose patience.
I know! This time for sure--
This time she's not getting away!
We hope.
You guys aren't human!
I'm gonna kill you!
Oh, save us!
Chase her to your heart's content
for the time being, Asuka Jr.
Because very soon now
you'll never be able to.
My, so you came here
all the way from Sakuraoka?
Yes, because I heard The Swan
was here in Seika.
-So you came here to see it?
- No, I...
Is something the matter?
I know the truth!
St. Tail's announcement in today's
paper is a fake! It's a lie.
Calm down. Who are you, anyway?
I'm a maid. I work for
Mr. Okajima, Sakuraoka's mayor.
I heard the mayor
and another man plotting something.
After I steal it, you'd better sell it
overseas before they trace it to us.
I'll do that.
You'll help me, won't you?
You can count on it.
I thought of going
right to the police...
...but I'm a live-in maid.
If I were to lose my job,
I'd have nowhere to go.
And so you came here.
Forgive me.
I just had to talk to someone!
It's all right.
Don't worry.
I'm sure the Lord will guide you.
What did that article
in this morning's paper mean?
Seira says she didn't know about it,
and I didn't do it. Could it be a fake?
Dad!
Can I come in?
What were you doing? Is this
another experiment in suspension?
The last one was a failure.
But now this time, watch.
-See?
-Wow!
-How did you do that?
-I'm glad you asked.
When you push
the switch on my wrist...
...the motor on my hip extends
and retracts the wire.
Wow, it's fantastic!
And it can even do this.
Instant transit.
Look how fast I go!
That's great.
And you can do something like--
Meimi, dinner's ready.
Why, Dad, I thought you were outside.
He came in through the window.
What were you thinking,
sneaking into her room?
You see, I...
Did you say dinner? Let's eat.
How childish!
Then that announcement...
Yes. I'm sure Mayor Okajima told
that Mr. Yabe to have it printed.
They want St. Tail to get blamed.
What terrible people!
They won't get away with this!
Is there some way we can get The Swan
before that Yabe steals it?
Of course there is! I'm going
to the museum tomorrow night too!
Have you finished
setting up the display?
-Mr. Mayor.
-Yes, we're almost finished.
Because it's a crystal swan,
we put it in the setting of a lake.
Asuka Jr. suggested we put a lake
around it so no one can get too close.
Naturally, security will
be very tight.
I intend to spend the night in
the space between the case and lake.
You personally?
Can't we use a security camera?
Well, machinery can be reprogrammed.
She's not getting away this time.
I intend to capture her myself!
He has no intention
of arresting St. Tail!
Is there something wrong?
Since I already announced yesterday
about the exhibit, I can't cancel it.
I'm counting on you.
Don't let me down!
I won't!
Asuka Jr., I believe in you.
Asuka Jr., it's your own fault,
not mine.
All right, men, it's almost time,
so please take your positions.
Yes, sir!
I'm ready for you, St. Tail.
Tonight's the night.
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Ruby, you rascal, you followed me.
Tonight is important.
My reputation is at stake.
Meimi, I'll take care of Ruby.
Come on, Ruby.
Thank you, Seira.
I'll keep The Swan until Yabe is
arrested, then return it to the museum.
Be careful.
May the blessings of God be with us.
St. Tail, I'm ready for you.
Just touch this case and I'll nab you.
That's right. I'll have no problem
if I catch you in the act.
I need you to take a little nap.
So that's it.
Good, Yabe's not here yet.
-She's here!
-Where?
Wait, take it easy.
You've got to catch her in the act!
It's St. Tail!
It's...
...Show...
...Time!
They're all asleep.
I've got to hurry.
What a fitting display.
She's here! It's St. Tail!
I got her!
You're not taking that, St. Tail!
So this is where he was!
Don't fight it! Give up!
You're not getting away, St. Tail.
Oh, no!
Rats! She's a decoy!
Asuka Jr.!
Ow, my leg.
Oh, no!
What happened? Oh, my God!
-The sculpture's been stolen!
-What'd you say?
Where's Asuka Jr.?
Asuka Jr.
Aw, shoot! Where'd he go?
Hold it! Rats!
That's a straight road! Yes!
I'm not letting her
get away this time!
You're not getting away!
What was that?
That's funny.
I didn't think St. Tail used cars.
Thank you, St. Tail! Who'd have
thought it'd go so smoothly?
That fake ad in the paper
did the trick!
What'd he say?
I finally made it up here.
Asuka Jr., I never thought
it'd turn out this way.
Asuka Jr., be careful.
Come back safely.
Asuka Jr., come back safely!