A fake warning letter?
What's going on?
Wasn't it St. Tail
who stole the swan?!
That means the one
I caught was the real St. Tail?
Great! My hands
are getting numb...!
SAKURAOKA
THE MAYOR'S AMBITION!
STEALING A SWAN (PART 2)
Asuka Jr.! You're safe!
I'm sorry. I not only
let St. Tail get away...
...but the swan was stolen, too...
I heard all of
the security guards...
...were given knockout drops.
I'm sorry.
Asuka.
I'm wondering...
...if you are really serious
about catching St. Tail.
Someone
mentioned that to me.
No way! I'm...!
Either way, if the swan
doesn't come back...
...I have no choice
but to resign as mayor.
Naturally, your assignment...
...to catch St. Tail
will be terminated, too.
No way...!
Let's go back.
Then who is
going to catch her?
Someone else...
Someone else and not me...?!
I couldn't stand that!
PIease wait, Mr. Mayor!
"Tomorrow night...
...I'm going
to the Okajima residence...
...the mayor of Sakuraoka...
...in order to pick
up the "Swan."
-St. Tail"
This is...!
SAKURAOKA
If Okajima's license plate...
...and that car's license
plate are the same...
...this is a real warning note.
What should I do?
Should I leave it to the police?
What on earth is St. Tail
going to do with the swan?
What should I do...?!
That's all right, Meimi.
If the swan is returned...
...Asuka Jr. won't
be fired, will he?
I... I don't care about him!
I'm thinking about the people
who came for help...!
Why did you go to the trouble
of giving him a warning note?
Because I promised it,
and he was depressed...!
It seems to me
you are Iooking forward...
...to seeing him as St. Tail.
Am I wrong?
Anyway, the important thing now
is to get the swan back!
She isn't wrong...
I wanted to see...
...the eyes which
stare only at me...
I wanted to see him...
That's why I sent him
the warning notes.
I'll definitely get
the swan back. Defiinitely!
Man! This wall is awfully high!
That's why
the rich people are...!
Who's there?!
Have I been spotted?!
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
May the blessings
of God be with us.
And with Asuka Jr., too.
Seira...
Thank you...
It went better than I thought.
Mr. Okajima.
Don't relax until we take
the swan outside tonight.
You're right.
They must be
Okajima and Yabe...
I wonder where the swan is...
Sir!
Who's this?
This guy was trying
to sneak in here.
Oh, he really did it...!
What should we do with him?
Call the police?
The police aren't a good idea.
I have something to do now.
Until I can give
you instructions...
...lock him up somewhere.
What...?
I understand.
Come on!
What are you doing?!
Let me go!
Asuka Jr. ...
How do you do?
Are you,
by any chance, St. Tail?
If you are, that boy
is your friend, isn't he?
Oh, shoot!
I was careless...
...because I was
distracted by Asuka Jr. ...
It's no use...
There's no way out of here.
Why on earth did I come here?
I'm pitiful!
I'm the one
who will catch St. Tail!
No matter what,
I have to get the swan back!
This way!
As you can see,
your friend is safe, Ms. St. Tail.
We've been hospitable,
haven't we?
Keep quiet for a while.
It can't be true!
In this darkness...
...I'm sure
he can't see my face...
Good evening!
Hey...!
What shall I do?
- Excuse me!
- Yes!
Is it true that
the warning message...
...in the newspaper was fake?
Did that man do it?
Please tell me
what's going on with this case.
Otherwise...
...I can't catch you...!
I see.
So they're taking it
out of the country tonight...
Why are you...
...going to such lengths
to get the swan back?
Why are you?
Oh, shoot!
If the case wasn't like this...
...I could have arrested you.
Why don't we
cooperate with each other...
...just this once
until we get the swan back?
All right!
Now that we've decided,
just step back.
I'll be a decoy,
and you can find the swan.
One!
Two!
Three!
Watch out!
We're on the second floor!
He fell...!
I heard something.
What's that?!
Chase her! Don't let her go!
If she could escape
from the room so easily...
...why didn't she tell me...?
We'll be late
for the boat's departure.
Don't worry
about the intruders, Yabe!
Bring it quickly!
Is that the swan?
Hurry up!
The back door isn't shut.
What? That's strange...
Asuka Jr. got in the car...?
That means the swan is...?!
I have to chase them!
Here it is! The swan!
But I can't jump out with this.
Why are you here?!
Don't give me any trouble.
Hand it over.
No! I won't give it to you
even if you have to kill me!
God knows all your evil actions!
Return the swan!
Hey! Don't you care
about what happens to him?
It's...
...Show...
...Time!
My eyes...!
Grab hold of me!
I won't let go of you!
You...!
I didn't feel a thing...!
Let us down!
Hey! Return the swan!
Swans fly away in the spring.
You promised me
you wouldn't arrest me.
But only this once!
The next time we meet,
I definitely will...!
You're right.
I'll see you again...
Thank you, Asuka,
for getting the swan back.
I can't express
my gratitude with words.
My pleasure.
But St. Tail is...
I now believe
you are still passionate...
...about catching her.
I would appreciate it
if you would continue to be...
...in charge of arresting St. Tail.
Really?!
I'll do my best!
What were you scheming?
What are you talking about?
Rina. Nothing works
on him right now.
I know that!
I know...
Because I Iove him!
It's all right, it's all right...
I heard that Mayor Okajima
and Yabe were arrested.
What happened to that maid?
Mayor Morinaka found
a new job for her.
Really? I'm glad to hear that.
Look, Asuka!
The mayor is praising you
in the newspaper.
That's great!
Are you going
to chase St. Tail again?
Of course!
I will definitely catch her!
I won't allow
anyone else to do it!
Hold on!
Come and catch me!