Wait a minute!
Hey, Ruby! Wait!
Listen...!
Meimi! Look this way!
Hello!
HER TRUE CHARACTER REVEALED!
MEIMI'S CRITICAL MOMENT
Sawatari. What are you doing?
Sorry about the last contest.
I want to start taking
photos now for the next contest.
You're beautiful
in your school uniform...
...but you're also beautiful
when you're playing at home.
You're so bad!
Senorita!
I'm leaving now.
See you tomorrow!
May I have a second of your time?
Neverland Toy Shop?
Oh, it's the big toy store
that just opened...
...on Second Avenue.
Did you know
that there used to be...
...a small toy store there, Sister?
Now I remember...
...there was a very big tree there...
Yes...
Until a year ago
that was my father's store.
But it was taken over.
We had to let the store go.
And you came here for help...?
No, I'm all right with the store now.
But I need your help with the tree...
...in front of our old store.
The tree is still there
as the new store's display.
Recently I remembered...
...that I left my music box in the tree.
I thought that I had lost it.
Why did you leave it
in such a high place?
When I was a child,
I often climbed the tree.
Recently I was going through...
...my grandfather's belongings.
Then I suddenly...
...remembered my music box.
It must be in the hole in the tree.
It's very important to you, isn't it?
Yes. My grandfather gave it to me.
It's a souvenir...
...from my grandfather's
trip to Switzerland...
...when he was young.
Since that time, he was
interested in music boxes...
Immediately after coming back...
...he opened his toy store.
At the time...
... I didn't know the story
behind the music box.
But that was my favorite
thing when I was child.
I always had it with me,
even when playing or sleeping...
But I misplaced it
without even realizing it.
So she wants to get it back, right?
She says it's a beautiful music box...
...which plays the hymn,
"Ye Fair Green Hills of Galilee."
Naomi has asked
the owner many times...
...to return her music box...
No, no.
We just opened the store.
We can't take on extra stuff.
To others,
it may just be a music box.
But to me,
it's something very important.
All right!
This is a job
for the Mysterious Thief St. Tail!
Hey, Asuka!
Hey!
How's it going?
- Hey, good morning!
- Huh?
You have something in your hood.
This method is...?!
"Tomorrow night...
...I'm going to Neverland
to retrieve a music box...
...which plays 'Ye Fair
Green Hills of Galilee.'"
St. Tail?!
A note of warning!
As usual, you're caught off guard.
Saruwatari...
Are you challenging me
this early in the morning?
Oh, no!
Don't touch that!
It's a special photo of Haneoka!
What?!
Oh, it's just a regular...
Hey, Asuka Jr.!
Don't touch it with your dirty hand!
What's this thing with Meimi?
I don't know.
Unfortunately...
...I only have eyes
for the beautiful Haneoka.
Are you even listening to me?! Hey!
I've seen this before!
If I remember correctly,
at that time...
...it was with St. Tail.
Meimi!
What...?!
What is it?!
Ruby...!
This is...
Give it back, Asuka!
I took that picture!
Meimi! What is that next to you?
What should I do?!
That's a...
That's a stuffed animal.
Seira...
What do you want to do...
...with the stuffed
porcupine, Asuka Jr.?
It's a stuffed animal?
Yeah, that's right!
I know I have to grow...
...out of collecting
stuffed animals but...
You're in trouble, Meimi.
Let's go.
Wait! Meimi!
Stop it!
If you're too pushy, she'll hate you.
How can you say that...?
Thank you, Seira.
You saved me in there.
Anyway, now is
the time to be careful.
In school, let's maintain...
...that Ruby is a stuffed animal.
Yeah.
And Asuka Jr. is still
having doubts about you.
Don't let him provoke you.
I know that!
Mice is the plural form of mouse.
Now I'll read...
...from Aesop's Fables...
..."The Town Mouse
and the Country Mouse."
- PIease listen to me carefully.
- Meimi, I have a favor to ask!
I'm going to buy
concert tickets this afternoon.
Can you come with me?
Meimi.
Could you be...?
I don't know why
this bothers you so much...
...but do you want me to find out...
...if this is a real stuffed animal?
Sawatari, you...
...are nicer than I thought.
Of course! We're classmates!
Haneoka!
For that reason...
...please go out on a date with me!
Wait a minute!
For what reason?!
I want to take
another picture of you...
...with the stuffed animal.
May I?!
Uh, I'm sorry, but...
Well, how about
after school tomorrow? All right?
Asuka!
Which would you like,
rice balls or sandwiches?
In the middle of this mess,
you're talking about food?
What's the matter?
Of course I'm talking...
...about the snack
for tomorrow night.
You'll get hungry...
...during tomorrow
night's surveillance.
Which one would you like?!
Neither! Give me some space!
- Sawatari!
- Yes!
I'll go on the date after school!
Me-Meimi...
What?! It's my lucky day!
What?!
Oh, Lord...
That's why I'm asking
for forgiveness! Seira!
What are you going to do?
Your date and warning note
are on the same day.
It will work out somehow...
We were able to manage Ruby...
...without too much trouble...
But I was careless, too.
There are stuffed porcupines...
Yeah, I have seen one
at a toy store before.
It was a stuffed animal...
...with a music box,
and it looks exactly like Ruby.
We can buy it and fool Sawatari.
That's not all!
The music that plays is also...
"Ye Fair Green Hills of Galilee."
All right!
Then I'm going to get
the stuffed animal...
...that looks like Ruby!
Actually...
I checked earlier...
...and it's out of stock now.
Out of stock?
What should I do, Seira?!
There's no other way now...
Ruby, could you do me a favor?
Can you pretend to be...
...a stuffed animal
for the rest of the day?
- Eimi!
- What?
It's another peaceful day.
Yes, it is!
Oh...?
TROUBLE
Are you going to take
Ruby to school, Meimi?
What? Ruby?
Well, Ruby seems
to have caught a cold.
So I'm thinking of
dropping her off at the vet.
That's all! I'm going!
I managed to fool Dad and Mom...
The harder part
is coming up, Ruby.
Let's hang in there all day today!
One hour later.
Three hours later.
After school!
Haneoka!
Where should we go?!
Is it going to be okay...?
Well, in our store,
a music box with the hymn...
..."Ye Fair Green Hills of Galilee"...
...is only sold with this item.
That's all?
Yes. They're out of stock now...
...and we have only
this one for display.
I see. So this is the one...
...that St. Tail is targeting.
Whew! It's a big toy store!
That must be the tree
where the music box is...
Anything wrong?
Oh, no.
Right now, we're having
a grand opening sale.
So we can't close the store,
no matter what.
Well, I would like
to borrow something.
EMPLOYEE LOCKER ROOM
Shoot! Why do I have to do...
...this?!
Asuka Jr. ...!
This time your strategy...
...is to disguise yourself
and then catch her, isn't it?!
Aha! Great idea!
Yeah, right...!
Cute!
Sawatari! Hey!
I don't know any fox.
It's me! Me!
What are you doing
in that costume?
I... I am doing this...
in order to catch St. Tail...
It doesn't really matter.
But you do look good
in that costume!
Shut up!
Enough about me!
What can you report?
It's a stuffed animal. Probably!
Really, you can't see past...
...Meimi, can you?!
I'll look into it myself.
What's the matter, Haneoka?
As you can see, it's a fox.
Come on! Let's go!
I just want to know...
...if that's really a stuffed animal.
That's all!
Oops. Sorry!
Great!
A smiling fox is
falling down the stairs!
Ohhhh, ouch...
I knew the way
that fox fell was familiar.
It's like I thought...
This isn't good!
Oh, no! I've caught a cold!
What should I do, Seira?!
Here she comes! St. Tail!
I won't let you escape today!
Where?!
Disappeared?
Where is she?!
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
She just appeared
on top of the tree!
For me, it was pretty good.
May the blessings
of God be with us.
Good evening, everyone!
I'm sorry for disturbing you.
Don't move, St. Tail!
It's...
...Show...
...Time!
My store...!
Oh, shoot!
There it is!
I'm taking the music
box with the hymn...
..."Ye Fair Green Hills of Galilee!"
What? I thought there
was only one music box...
Oh, she's gone...!
You couldn't catch her once again!
Shut up!
Where did you get
the one on your back?!
Oh, this?
I bought it before
the store was out of stock.
I see. It's a stuffed animal...
Of course it is!
What's the matter?
Of course it is...
Rather than thinking too much...
...I should just catch her!
When I catch her...
...everything will become clear.
Ruby, I love you!