The stolen sword was...
...Kikuchiyo, which is as valuable
as the national treasure.
The thief hasn't gone too far yet.
Turn on the lights!
Right there!
That's...!
That's the mysterious
thief, Mouse Kid!
Don't let him escape!
He's disappeared!
Another famous
sword was stolen!
This is the sixth sword this month!
He's good... He's very good!
Now is not the time to admire him!
Find Mouse Kid and do it now!
Yes, sir!
A SWORDSWOMAN'S WISH!
TO STEAL THE EXCELLENT SWORD
...according to these calculations...
...x=2y.
I would like someone
to solve this problem.
Noriko, please solve it.
Noriko!
Yes!
Well...
It's not like you...
...to daydream during class.
I'm sorry.
Noriko wasn't her usual self,
and she was absent-minded today.
It was strange...
I guess she couldn't think
of anything but today's match.
She said she wanted
to win no matter what.
What do you mean?
Ten!
One!
Two!
Three!
Four!
Five!
Six!
- Seven!
- Noriko is considered...
- Eight!
-...a talented martial artist...
- Nine!
-...from St. Paulia's School.
- Ten!
- Her family has had a Dojo...
- One! Two!
-...for a long time.
- Three!
- If I remember correctly...
- Four!
-...her grandfather, Saburota...
-Five!
-...is the owner of a Dojo.
- Six!
- He's considered...
- Seven!
-...the best in town.
- Eight!
- A man named...
- Nine! Ten!
-... Kumayama challenged him.
Ten more!
If I win, I'll take
the famous sword, Munemasa.
The famous sword
Munemasa...
...is an heirloom
in Noriko's family...
...which has been passed on
from generation to generation.
Grandpa!
A promise is a promise.
I'll take Munemasa.
Since then her grandfather
hasn't been well...
...and keeps saying
that he is sorry to his ancestors.
Today, Noriko is going to compete
against Mr. Kumayama.
That means she is looking
to avenge her grandfather.
Kumayama... Kumayama...
Oh, that must be it!
KUMAYAMA DOJO
If I win, you promise that you'll
return the Munemasa to me, right?
I consider myself an honorable
martial artist. I don't lie.
AIthough I don't think
I'll lose to little girl like you.
No time limit.
One shot decides.
Bow to each other!
Begin!
Kote (hand)!
Men (head)!
Hang in there, Noriko!
Do (Chest)!
Count "Do!"
Great! Mr. Kumayama!
Wait a minute!
Noriko won the match!
Who are you?
I saw you cheat!
What did you say?!
What?!
Stop it, Meimi!
But...!
Thank you very much.
Noriko!
Aren't you frustrated, Noriko?!
No matter how you lose
the match, a loss is a loss.
No way...!
My grandfather always says so.
But if that's true...!
Thank you, Meimi.
Noriko...
See you, then.
She is, indeed,
Saburota's granddaughter...
I almost lost.
Before she
challenges me again...
... I'll have to hide
the Munemasa somewhere...
That's my chair, Mouse Kid.
It's a good sword.
We can sell it at a high price.
Don't say something so stupid.
I earned this sword
after I fought with Saburota.
I will never sell it.
I know that!
Because of this sword,
I'm rising in rank...
...and the number
of my students has increased.
You're an important
customer to me.
I won't steal the sword from you.
And what do you have today?
This.
That's one of the best swords,
Kikuchiyo, isn't it?
Do you like it?
Another fantastic sword
is added to my collection.
All of it is due to me.
I know that.
This is what I promised you.
Please examine it.
That Kumayama is really unfair!
"I couldn't get Munemasa back.
Grandfather, I'm sorry."
What?
Noriko came by to say
that prayer a little while ago.
It's time for St. Tail, isn't it?
Let's get the fabulous
Munemasa sword back ourselves.
You're right!
St. Tail will teach that fake
marital artist a harsh lesson!
"Tonight I'm taking
the fabulous Munemasa sword...
...from the Kumayama Dojo.
-St. Tail"
What?!
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Be careful, Meimi.
It Iooks like...
... Kumayama has some sort
of connection to the Mouse Kid.
The Mouse Kid?!
Isn't he the one...
...who's stolen many swords
from different places?
After hearing about
St. Tail's warning note...
...he may set something up.
Don't worry!
Sacred tail doesn't
lose to a mouse thief!
I'm going to teach him
a lesson using Kumayama!
I'm counting on you!
May the blessings
of God be with us.
Please calm down,
Mr. Kumayama.
How can I calm down?!
The Munemasa
has been targeted!
Don't worry.
Our security is perfect.
We'll protect your Munemasa.
I'm counting on you, Asuka Jr.
I can't show weakness
in front of my students.
Being a top martial artist
puts a lot of pressure on you.
It's almost time.
I'm going to check
on our security guards.
Everything is going
according to my plan.
Bring it on, St. Tail!
Is there anything unusual?
Not so far!
Huh? That's a...?
Oh, it's just a balloon.
Wait! It may be
a trap set by St. Tail!
Hey!
Like I said, it's just a balloon.
What's this?!
Asuka Jr.!
Asuka Jr.! Please help us!
We're stuck in this stuff.
What are you guys doing?!
I can't get up!
It's super glue!
Let's help Asuka Jr.!
St. Tail!
Hey, wait a minute!
Good evening!
Everyone! Attack!
It's...
...Show...
...Time!
What are you guys doing?!
We can't control our movements.
It's St. Tail's line dance!
It's a little disappointing
because we have all men.
You...!
I TOOK THE FAMOUS SWORD
MUNEMASA INDEED. -ST. TAIL
Oh, no! It's too late!
Shoot!
I'm going to catch her!
It's my decoy.
I'm aware of your plan.
You're the mysterious thief
Mouse Kid, aren't you?!
I will take the famous
Munemasa sword!
That's Mouse Kid!
Wait a minute!
I get it. The one that
flew away was a decoy...
Oh, boy...
Who would have imagined
that two thieves were after it...?
- Let's go after them!
- Yes, sir!
Listen! Mouse Kid
has the Munemasa!
Let's spread out
and search for it!
Yes, sir!
But where did St. Tail go?
Hey! Did you find him?
No...
Where did he go?
- Let's search over there, too.
- Yeah.
Mr. Kumayama...?
Why?
Good job.
Mouse Kid.
It went well, didn't it?
You had me
steal the Munemasa...
...to keep it from...
...Saburota
and his granddaughter.
And because you dealt
with both St. Tail and Mouse Kid...
...your reputation will increase.
Good plan...
I couldn't have done it
without you.
So give me back the Munemasa.
Where's the money
you promised me?
All right.
I look forward
to working together again.
Same here.
Mouse Kid! Hey!
I'll take the Munemasa!
I'll make a lot of money
selling this sword!
You betrayed me! You!
Both of you!
Don't move!
Make sure you catch him!
Wait! Mouse Kid!
He's persistent!
Look out!
How about that?
It's a simple trick using an illusion.
St. Tail...!
I'll take the fabulous
Munemasa sword!
St. Tail!
Hey, you! Give up!
Get off of me!
No way!
Captain. At Kumayama's Dojo...
...we found the fabulous
Kikuchiyo sword...
...which was stolen the other day.
All right.
Come, Mouse Kid.
Kumayama, you, too.
You caught two
bad guys by yourself.
Like father, like son!
Oh, well...
I was just chasing St. Tail.
Grandpa! The Munemasa...!
The Munemasa is back!