She's an angel! It's like
an angel is riding a horse!
I've never seen
such a beautiful lady!
I wish I were that horse!
I'll be the horse's rear legs!
Angel?! If she had wings...
...she wouldn't have
to ride on the horse!
They're so stupid!
Rear legs? Is he talking about
a two-man horse in a play?!
What about a two-man
horse in a play?
It's stupid boy-talk.
They're talking about
the princess of their dreams.
On their way to school
there's a mansion.
In the large yard, a lady
who gracefully rides a horse...
...is the Madonna
that the boys are admiring.
They sneak by to watch her
every day on their way home.
How perverted!
Oh, is that so?
I wonder if Asuka Jr.
goes there, too...
Is she that pretty?
What?! You haven't seen her?!
- No.
- Well, then...
I can take you there today!
No, thank you.
I'm not that interested.
Man! Asuka's head is...
...filled only with
thoughts of St. Tail.
RETURN THE THOROUGHBRED!
You are...?
What?! She was cheated
and lost the horse...
...that the boys
were talking about?
Yes. The horse's name is Billy.
Both Billy's father and mother
were very famous racehorses.
He's a top-notch Thoroughbred.
But that Madonna, rather,
Ms. Maki Nishina was against...
...turning him into a racehorse.
So he became a riding horse.
That's a very extravagant
thing to do, isn't it?
If he's so famous,
he's worth quite a bit.
Like they say, she must be
an extremely rich princess!
Yes. And according
to some people...
...she's wasting a fortune.
A man named Soma
kept visiting Maki's house...
...asking her to sell Billy to him.
But Maki flatly refused his offer.
But Soma wouldn't
give up, and one day...
Well, hello, Lady Maki.
I won't sell Billy.
No matter how many
times you come here...
...the answer remains the same.
Now, hold on.
I've got a wonderful idea
that may appeal to you.
First, please look at this horse.
He's Wild Bunch.
He's from a very
famous bloodline.
He is as good as your Billy.
This horse isn't
a bad trade for Billy.
Don't you get it?
I love Billy!
I'll never give him
to someone like you!
Billy!
What's happened?!
It's broken!
What are you going to do?
His leg is broken!
The medical report
Soma brought definitely stated...
...that the leg
was broken, Maki said.
I've heard that a broken leg is...
...the same as
a death sentence for a horse.
Yes. That's why Soma
demanded Billy in exchange...
...as if he had
the right to take Billy.
She said her father
couldn't refuse.
But something is strange.
Things were
too convenient for Soma.
Only Soma is winning here.
You mean...!
Yes. Maki is thinking that, too.
She thinks they were
set up from the beginning.
Soma wanted Billy very badly.
And the horse's
broken leg was supported...
...only by the medical report.
He tricked them
in order to get Billy.
He had no intention
of giving up his horse, either.
Maki thinks so, too.
She thinks they
somehow surprised Billy...
...and made him
fall into that horse.
Yes! That must be it!
But Soma has already
become the legal owner of Billy.
Billy and Maki
will never be together.
All right!
Under such circumstances,
St. Tail can get the horse back!
In addition, I'll reveal
Soma's evil intentions.
But Billy is already scheduled...
...to go to a ranch
in Hokkaido tonight.
And by train!
Train?!
It's the K-Express,
leaving Seika Station at 8:02.
We have only four hours
until its departure.
Please hurry.
What short notice!
Did he go home?
How can I send him
a warning note?
Hey, have you seen Asuka Jr.?
No, I haven't.
Didn't he go home already?
Really? Thank you.
There is no other way.
It may be a bit much, but I guess
I should use that method.
Tonight...
...I'll get Billy
from the K-Express train...
...leaving Seika Station at 8:02.
St. Tail?
It's a warning note...!
It's elaborate...
Dad! Let me borrow
your train schedule!
The one you always
use for your trips.
All right.
Here it is.
Thanks, Dad.
But why do you need it, Meimi?
Well... for something...!
Mom!
- Mom!
- What?
Is Meimi going on a trip?
Not that I know of.
I haven't heard anything about it.
I wonder if she's running away...
If so, she wouldn't borrow
the schedule from you.
That's true.
There are a lot of things
going on at her age.
It's a difficult age...
Let's see...
the K-Express departs at 8:02...
It will pass that point at...
All right!
SEIKA STATION
What did you say?!
St. Tail is coming to steal Billy?!
Yes.
We'll be aboard the train
to protect the horse.
Don't worry.
Here comes the train.
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
May the blessings
of God be with us.
There are no suspicious
persons on board.
All right!
Position yourselves
at each place.
No! Let me go!
Please let me go!
What's the commotion,
Mr. Soma?
Well, this young lady
was doing a bad thing.
She was trying to open
the door of the livestock car...
...and let Billy escape.
I beg you! Please return Billy!
You're going too far, young lady.
Billy is mine now.
You don't have the right
to even touch him.
Don't make me laugh!
I know you set us up!
There was no way Billy
would get upset like that!
You made him upset!
He made Billy upset?
What are you talking about?!
Don't say something
so stupid without any evidence!
Never come close to this horse!
Understand?!
Who on earth are you?
Billy...
Billy! Billy!
Billy!
Billy...
I see. I understand the situation.
I'm not doing anything wrong.
I suppose that girl
can't let go of Billy.
But St. Tail always has
a good reason for stealing things.
Rather than worrying about that,
how about your security?
Even that girl
was able to get close.
Don't worry.
We have one officer on each car...
...and two officers
in front of the livestock car.
I 'II be at the livestock car, too.
So it's impossible to break in.
I'm counting on you.
I know that!
First, check the car.
That must be Soma.
I wonder what they're talking about.
Darn! Why is Billy singled out?!
St. Tail wants him, too.
That means Billy
is a very good horse.
Of course he is!
That's the reason I fell in love with him.
He'll bring us a lot of money.
But that was a good idea.
You invented
Wild Bunch's broken leg.
You blamed it on Billy,
and then you got him for free.
The key was to use the fact
that the girl didn't want to sell him...
...coupled with your special talent.
It's like we thought.
That's how they did it!
Now that we know,
I'll take Billy no matter what.
The livestock car
is the very last one.
Naturally, Asuka Jr. is
keeping it under surveillance.
If that's the case...
How's it going?
Is there anything unusual?
No. Nothing so far.
Thank you.
This is Asuka! I've found St. Tail!
Everyone! Get up on the roof!
Bad news!
I was checking it out...
...and there's no officer
in the next car or anywhere!
What?!
What's going on?
What happened
to the kid, Asuka?!
I didn't see him, either.
Maybe something happened.
I'm worried about Billy.
Let's go!
Yes!
Don't move, St. Tail!
Give up now!
There's nowhere to run!
Wait a minute.
Isn't it strange that St. Tail...
...shows up in the front
when Billy is in the back?
It's...
...Show...
...Time!
Darn it!
Shoot! Someone's on the roof!
Like we thought, it's St. Tail...
What are you doing?!
Ignore him! Shoot!
Stop it!
Get off of me! Get off!
Asuka Jr.!
Duck!
St. Tail!
St. Tail...
One!
Two!
Three!
She was all right...!
What a stunt!
I'll definitely catch you next time!
I'll let you see
your lady pretty soon.
What's the matter, Billy?
Billy!
I'm glad...
...that Soma's wrong-doing
was revealed to the police, too.
So Billy is formally
returned to Maki.
Of course.
But it's terrible.
He made up the story
about the broken leg...
...and faked the medical report...
...and he upset Billy
by hitting him with a BB.
Really! I can't believe it!
I wonder if Maki is riding Billy now.
She looked very cool!
The boys shouldn't
be the only ones...
...to view her as an angel.