I'm so glad
it's nice weather, Seira.
You were looking forward...
...to this field trip very much.
Today let's forget about studying...
...and just have fun, Seira!
You're always forgetting
about schoolwork.
Why don't you make a wish
at the "Tree of Happiness"?
Like, "Please make me
a little bit smart!"
It's none of your business.
all the girls are there now.
What's
the "Tree of Happiness"?
What?
Don't you know about it?
It's a tree in this park
which is popular right now.
Really?
Yeah! Let's go see it!
This is it!
There's a rumor that if you
carve your wish on the tree...
...your wish will come true.
You can carve your name
along with the one you love.
There are a lot of scars...
Yeah... I feel sorry for it...
GET BACK
THE "TREE OF HAPPINESS"!
Good morning!
They seem in love!
What? What? What is it?!
Oh, Meimi. It's about
the "Tree of Happiness."
The "Tree of Happiness"?
Yes! Hanako of Class C
carved in the tree...
...and wished for a date
with a boy she likes.
- Then...
- Then...?.!
Then it came true!
Wow! That's great!
I envy her!
I'm going to go there again...
...and make more
and more wishes!
You have too many wishes.
That's not true!
I asked about Kosuke,
Kazuhiko, and Akio...
How about
Yasuhiro and Isshin?
Well... Meimi,
did you make a wish?
No, I didn't because
I felt sorry for the tree.
Meimi, you worry too much.
You shouldn't think too much
about this kind of thing.
You should just enjoy it!
I thought you had made
a wish about Asuka Jr.
Don't be stupid! Why would
I want to wish about him?!
What about me?
You talked mean
about me as usual.
No, I didn't!
Didn't you make a wish at
the "Tree of Happiness"...
...that you could
catch St. Tail?
Stupid! I don't have
to ask God about it!
I'll catch her by myself!
That's why
he can't catch her at all.
- That's right!
- You shut up!
Arborist?
Yes. I treat the trees...
...which are damaged
by disease and pollution.
You mean a tree doctor.
Yes.
About a year ago...
...in the grove on the hill
near Tachibana Nature Park...
... I found a white tree
which was dying from disease.
The disease had
progressed badly.
If nothing was done,
it appeared that it would fall...
...any minute.
Good... It still has a chance.
It took time.
But the tree fully recovered.
Your thoughts must
have reached the tree.
After that, I went there...
...to check on it
from time to time.
But when I went there today,
the tree was gone.
The tree was gone?
Yes.
The owner of Tachibana
Nature Park...
...took it out
by the roots. And...
Oh, that tree.
I want it to become the new
"Tree of Happiness. "
A new "Tree of Happiness"?
The current tree
has so many scars...
...that we can't
use it anymore.
We were looking
for a new tree.
I beg you, Mr. Tachibana!
Please don't
continue with this!
Trees are living, too!
You're hurting them!
It's none of your business
what I do in my park.
Or are the trees saying
they're hurting?
Yes, they are!
You just can 't hear them!
That's stupid.
The "Tree of Happiness"
is a money tree for this park.
Some come just to carve
their wishes on the tree.
So I have
no intention of stopping...
...no matter what you say.
It's best for trees to be
in their natural state.
But he's moving them
and carving them up...
Don't worry.
I'm sure your prayers
have reached God.
That's what the owner
of the park said?
Yes. According to Kudo...
...the tree will be planted
in the park tomorrow night.
Tomorrow night?
Yes.
So it's in time...
...for the opening
the day after tomorrow.
Then what will happen to
the current tree in the park?
It's terrible,
but it will be disposed of.
No way!
It'll be replaced because
it isn't useful anymore...
Trees are not an instrument
for humans to make money.
So, Meimi, I would like you
to steal the tree.
all right, Seira.
Count on St. Tail.
I'm home!
Welcome back, Meimi!
Whose voice is that?
Meimi! It's me! Me!
Ruby! You can...?!
Meimi, I'm Ruby!
Dad! What's that?!
Interesting!
It's a voice changer.
I found it at a toy store.
I thought I might
use it for my magic.
Meimi, your eyes
are like stars...
...of the first magnitude
in the night sky...
Oh, by the way...
...the park you went to
on your field trip the other day...
...was showcased on TV.
As you can see...
...nature remains
undisturbed here...
...and visitors can
observe rare plants.
Also, there are athletic
and cycling courses...
...and people of all ages
can find enjoyment here.
This is the owner
of the park, Mr. Tachibana.
Hello. I'm the owner,
Tachibana.
Over here...
...the "Tree of Happiness"
is very popular...
...because it can make
wishes come true.
I hope you can come
to Tachibana Nature Park...
...and carve your wishes...
...in the "Tree of Happiness."
He is advertising
the "Tree of Happiness " like this...!
But that park
has changed a lot.
Yes. It used
to be a small park.
Is that right?
Now we have to pay
an expensive entrance fee.
We often
went there on dates.
It's no longer
the park of our memories.
But you haven't changed
since that time...
...and you're
just as close to me.
Of course, Eimi.
And will be forever.
Oh, well... I guess we'll leave
these young ones alone...
...and we should get going.
Right, Ruby?
You're still here, Meimi...!
I'm going now!
What's this?
Is it a delivery?
What the...?!
What?!
"Tonight I'm going
to Tachibana Nature Park...
...to get the 'Tree of Happiness.'"
It's a warning note from St. Tail!
There's no time to lose!
Once more...
...I'm going to ask
Mr. Tachibana to stop.
Excuse me...!
That's strange. I wonder
if anyone is here.
We've got it at last!
We had
a tough time getting it.
Let the rich guy know...
...that we've got the flower
he asked for.
It's...?!
It's a...!
This flower is designated
a national treasure!
And so is this flower here.
I don't believe it!
all of these are plants
that are nearly extinct.
Why are these here?
This guy again!
What a persistent fellow!
He's seen too much.
What should we
do with him?
He saw the secret.
If he tells anyone...
...we're selling the national
treasure plants...
He can't tell.
Now that he knows our secret,
we can't let him go.
I'm going to
the "Tree of Happiness"...
...to watch its replacement.
Make sure you watch him
until I come back.
Yes, sir.
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Be careful, Meimi.
Count on me.
Nothing is
impossible for St. Tail.
May the blessings
of God be with us.
You're Mr. Tachibana,
aren't you?
Oh, welcome. I was
waiting for you, Asuka Jr.
Hello.
Anyway...
...the "Tree of Happiness"
that St. Tail is targeting...
...was planted
around here, I thought.
Oh, you mean the old tree.
It's over there
lying on the ground.
Why did you do that?
It has too many
scars to use.
So we're replacing it
with that new one.
Oh, then you're
returning the old tree...
...to its natural habitat.
No way we're going to do...
...something
so time-consuming.
We'll cut it up and make
benches or something.
What is he thinking?!
Is this something the owner
of a nature park would do?
St. Tail hasn't
shown up, has she?
I wonder if she gave up.
No. She'll definitely come...
...since she sent
the warning note.
All right!
Okay. The transplant
is almost done.
Well, St. Tail didn't show up.
What a pity!
What happened?!
Why didn't you show up, St. Tail?!
From now on, I want this
new "Tree of Happiness"...
...to make a lot of money.
To commemorate this event,
I should carve the first wish.
Let's see...
I wish that this park
becomes more prosperous...
What's that?!
Whose voice is that?!
What's that voice?!
Ouch! It hurts!
You hurt me!
I won't forgive you!
It can't be true...!
The tree talked...?!
Not yet.
The real show starts now.
It's...
...Show...
...Time!
Help me!
She has shown up.
Come out! St. Tail!
There she is.
She's up in the tree!
One!
Two!
Three!
Shoot!
I'm taking
the "Tree of Happiness"!
I won't let you leave!
I'm going to catch you
today for sure!
It's dangerous to run without
looking where you're going!
I'm going to catch you
next time for sure!
Mr. Tachibana.
Mr. Tachibana,
you're under arrest.
What... what are you
talking about?
Those two
confessed to everything.
What?!
You...!
Hello, Son!
Oh, hi, Dad!
What are you doing here?
Isn't that Mr. Tachibana?
He was using
the nature park as a cover...
...for selling
rare flowers illegally.
What?!
He's been
a suspect for a while.
We got the warrant
and came here, then...
You got a big bust.
No wonder. I thought
something was strange.
Oh, Mr. Kudo.
Are you all right?
Yes. Thank you very much.
What happened to you?
I came to ask Mr. Tachibana...
...to stop the "Tree of Happiness"...
...and I was suddenly hit.
Because he discovered
their secret...
...he was locked up.
But I'm glad that
your injury isn't serious.
Would you like the police car
to give you a ride?
No. I want to clear my head
by walking home.
Thank you very much.
That's what it is. St. Tail.
I couldn't get
the tree back after all.
Even though I come here,
the tree won't be here...
I'm so glad... It's safe.
Did you read
today's paper?
Yes.
The owner Tachibana
was arrested.
The City of Seika is going
to manage the park.
And Kudo replanted
the "Tree of Happiness"...
...and he's treating it.
It is now prohibited...
...to carve in
the "Tree of Happiness".
From now on it is a symbol...
...of the importance
of natural life...
...and it is to be
loved by people.
People's wishes
do come true...
...when they put
some effort into it.
That's quite a wise saying
coming from you!
I suppose so.
But if I give her any praise,
she gets snobby. So I won't.
What do you mean?!
Nothing.
Please put a little more effort
into getting better grades.
Mind your own business!
Such good friends...