It's nice to walk in the forest!
I've heard that trees produce
elements which relax people.
The girls who are tired
of the business of urban life...
...are resting for a minute,
I suppose.
Hey! Why don't we
race to that tree?
All right!
Are you ready? Go!
First place!
Man! I don't know if you're
tired from playing or what...
...but aren't you
missing the point?
We're on the mountain...
...behind the school
to observe nature.
But we are still in class.
Mr. Yamano is amazed, too.
A PRECIOUS
CREATURE OF NATURE:
SAVE THE BEAUTIFUL BUTTERFLY
It's like...
...when you put out cotton
soaked in sugar water...
...then different
insects gather.
Here, in particular, there are
many varieties of butterflies.
Beautiful!
I wonder what those
butterflies are called.
Aren't they swallowtails
or something?
They look a little
different to me...
They're called
Yamano Oomurasaki.
Yamano Oomurasaki?
It's the same name
as yours, Mr. Yamano.
As a matter of fact,
thirty years ago...
...I discovered that butterfly.
The first time I saw it was...
...when I had just come
to this school.
Here it is!
"Yamano Oomurasaki.
Discovered by
Mr. Ikutaro Yamano in 1966.
Found in a few small areas
like Seika City."
At that time there was
a lot of green around here.
But the groves
around here...
...have been
destroyed one by one.
Now we can only see
Yamano Oomurasaki...
...right here
in the forest of St. Paulia.
Poor things...
But it's not all bad.
A few years ago,
a law was passed...
...which prohibits taking
any insects from this forest.
Can you guys hear me?
Mr. Yamano has a butterfly
named after him.
He's great!
He deserves his position...
...as the special advisor
here at St. Paulia Academy.
He's super nice!
What's that? I heard
"great" and "super nice."
Is someone
talking about me?
Is it Haneoka or Mimori?
Hey! What are you doing?!
Start cleaning
like you're supposed to!
If you don't, I'll be scolded
as the group leader!
All right. I understand,
Group Leader!
Hey, Takamiya. You, too,
come here and help us.
All right...!
Bagworm...!
The bagworm scared me!
Asuka! I was scared!
Let go of me!
It's hard to believe
that Takamiya has...
...something she's afraid of...
Right, Meimi?
Hey, what kind
of insect don't you like?
I suppose... ants.
How about you, Kyoko?
For me it's a mantis.
I just can't stand that face.
What don't you like?
- Well...
- Yours must be this...
Here!
Oh, shoot...!
Asuka!
You boiled the pasta
too long today.
If you're going to complain...
...why don't you cook
once in a while?!
And what happened
to your face?
Nothing.
It's a girlfriend, isn't it?
No!
I remember when...
...great-great-grandfather
would tell us...
...that we're a family who
has trouble with women.
Shut up!
Oh, shoot. I did it again.
He must be very angry now.
Hey, Ruby!
Mr. Yamano...
Mimori...
You can't find a single
Yamano Oomurasaki?
Who would do
such a terrible thing?
I hate to accuse anyone...
...but I can guess who did it...
About a week ago,
two young men visited me.
So you want to collect
a Yamano Oomurasaki...
...in the forest of St. Paulia, right?
It's impossible.
This is a protected habitat
for the Yamano Oomurasaki.
The law prohibits
their collection.
So why don't you
give up and go home?
Mr. Yamano,
we already knew that.
That's why we came here
to discuss it with you.
How about just a few?
No one would know.
I won't do that!
Idiots!
Don't come back again!
I suppose they did it
as revenge for my refusal.
Mimori, no, Sister...
Will you hear my prayer?
What is it?
Could you ask God,
with me...
...that those butterflies...
...will return to the forest
of St. Paulia again?
Mr. Yamano...
That's terrible!
I investigated...
...and discovered that
Mr. Yamano was correct.
The two men,
Yoshiyuki Ishida...
...and Kenichi Kawai live in
a European-style building...
...on Seventh Avenue.
On the surface they pretend...
...to be regular
butterfly collectors.
But behind the scenes...
...they're selling rare butterflies...
...which are illegal to catch,
and fetch a lot of money.
Good job, Seira!
A wonderful investigation!
So what happened
to the Yamano Oomurasaki?
Don't worry.
The men are still hiding
the butterflies in their house.
Meimi...
For Mr. Yamano's sake...
...please get
the Yamano Oomurasaki back.
All right!
Those men are enemies
of the entire earth!
St. Tail will teach them
a harsh lesson!
NIKO NIKO MART
FRESH-MADE OMUSUBI
Shoot! It's a miss.
How about yours?
Mine, too.
Asuka, how about yours?
"Tonight I'll take
the Yamano Oomurasaki...
...from the Ishida residence
on Seventh Avenue.
-St. Tail"
It's a warning note!
I licked St. Tail's
warning note...
- Let me lick it, too!
- Me, too!
What are you doing?!
Eimi, can you come here?
What's up?
I've just had an idea.
For the opening
of my next magic show...
...how about this?
Oh, are doves coming out?
Not really.
Wow! Beautiful!
Really, Eimi?
Yes, really!
I'm sure your next show is
going to be another success!
Eimi...
Genichiro...
It's really embarrassing...
Oh, well.
It's a little early,
but I guess I should go.
Ruby, cover for me
while I'm gone!
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Meimi, tonight you're
dealing with butterflies.
Please be more
careful than usual.
Yes. You can count on me!
May the blessings
of God be with us.
Ishida, are they
that interesting?
They're just butterflies.
Just butterflies?
These are some
of the last in the whole world.
They're Yamano Oomurasaki!
Look at these beautiful,
colorful patterns and shapes!
They are jewels
made by the gods.
Sir, you have guests.
Who's here at this hour?
He said he's Asuka Jr.
Asuka Jr.?
Is it the Asuka Jr. ...
...who is the special
investigator of St. Tail?
Yes.
That means...
...St. Tail is after them...
Calm down.
Without any evidence...
...no one can do anything to us.
All right. Tell him
we'll be with him in a minute.
Yes.
If they discover
these here, I'll be...
Don't worry.
We'll hide them
in the usual place.
Are you Asuka Jr.?
What's the problem?
St. Tail warned us...
...that she will steal some
Yamano Oomurasaki.
Where are the butterflies?
That's strange.
We don't have those
butterflies in our collection.
Anything wrong?
Nothing...
It is true that our hobby
is collecting butterflies.
But it's illegal to catch
a Yamano Oomurasaki.
There is no way
we would have them.
So you're sure...
...that there aren't...
...any Yamano Oomurasaki
in this house?
I've had enough!
If you don't believe us...
...why don't you
search the house?
There's a pool...
They live in a mansion.
He inherited it.
How is your search going?
Well, Asuka Jr. ...
We haven't seen
a single butterfly outside.
I see. That's enough out here.
Please help us inside.
Yes.
I have to fiind the butterflies
before Asuka Jr. does.
Where on earth
are they hiding them?
I see!
Asuka Jr., we haven't
found any on the first floor.
There aren't any
on the second floor or in the attic.
Why don't you admit...
...that you've made
a mistake, Asuka Jr.?
It can't be right...
It's impossible...
...that St. Tail would send
a fake warning note.
Rather than listening
to the words of a citizen...
...you trust the words of a thief?
How rude! I told the truth!
St. Tail!
It's...
...Show...
...Time!
It's the butterflies' curse!
I'm not deceived
by this illusion!
Good evening!
I came to pick up
the Yamano Oomurasaki!
St. Tail! Battle with me!
One!
Two!
Three!
Yamano Oomurasaki!
We searched everywhere,
and we couldn't find them...!
There's a difference out here!
What?!
That's what I said...
...but I just saw the reflection
of the wings by the moonlight.
They're my butterflies!
Give them back!
Arrest these guys!
I'm taking these butterflies!
I won't let you escape!
Wait!
He definitely did a belly flop!
Are you all right?
Shut up! Next time
I'll definitely catch you!
All right!
God, thank you very much.
Good morning!
Oh, I wonder what it is...
"St. Tail shows up
at the butterfly mansion!"
Good morning, Haneoka!
Look at my big scoop!
So it was the same people
who damaged our mountain.
Besides the Yamano Oomurasaki...
...those men were selling
other butterflies, too.
Mr. Yamano must
be relieved now.
By the way, Sawatari...
...don't you have
some other big news?
Women's intuition
is very sharp!
As a matter of fact, although
I didn't put it in the article...
...the best scoop from last night
is this photograph!
You mean the real
identity of St. Tail?!
I wonder...
Let me see! Let me see!
What's this?
What is it?
An exclusive photo?
Let me see, too.
Saruwatari...
I didn't take that photo...
...but my acquaintance...
...happened to have a camera...
Saruwatari!
Boy...
Oh, a butterfly!
Ah-cho!
Wait a minute!