Your attention, please.
This plane will be landing
within 20 minutes...
...at the New Tokyo
International Airport.
Who's that woman?
Tomoko Nagata,
she's 28 years old.
A successful
detective in the U. S.
She's so good
that she solved a case...
...which even
the FBI couldn't solve.
So why do we
have to meet her?
The mayor himself
invited her.
This means you may
finally lose your job...
...investigating St. Tail.
She must be a very
old-fashioned, homely...
...and unpleasant woman.
I'm sorry that I'm
an unpleasant woman.
PHANTASMAL MASTERPIECE!
A WOMAN DETECTIVE IS BACK
Do you know...
...about the mysterious
thief St. Tail?
She uses magic freely...
...and she sends
a warning note prior to her crime.
No one knows her identity.
Right?
Impressive!
Then we can talk now.
I want to ask you
for your assistance...
...in catching St. Tail.
I've assured you
that I'll catch her!
Yes. I expect you
can catch her someday.
But in this case...
...I think it's better
to ask this lovely lady.
I'm sorry...
...but I came back to Japan
on a personal matter.
Can you make any
arrangements to help us?
Excuse me.
To-mo-ko!
I can give you a ride.
I'm sorry...
...that I can't assist you.
That's all right.
I definitely will
arrest St. Tail.
I'm the person
who will catch her!
Be quiet! This kind
of thing is done by age.
That's unfair! All of a sudden
you're motivated!
Tomoko has sparked
the detective fire in me!
It's nice to see a father
and son together.
By the way, Asuka Jr. ...
...you go to St. Paulia's, don't you?
What? How did you know?
Your uniform.
Say, could you show me
around the school?
Yeah...
The graph for y=2x
is a straight line...
...which runs through the origin.
I wonder what
happened to Asuka Jr.
He's healthy and has
never missed any classes.
He was summoned
by the mayor...
...according to Takamiya.
That means it must have
something to do with St. Tail.
Hey, Asuka Jr. is...
...walking with a really
beautiful woman!
What?!
She's really beautiful!
I didn't know that he
likes older women.
What's going on?
Go back to your seats!
Oh, Nagata...?
Do you know her, Sister?
Yes. She was
the smartest student...
...in the history of this school.
If I remember correctly...
...she went to a college in the U.S.
Do you know
about her, Seira?
I've heard rumors about her.
She was the famous daughter...
...of a rich family in this town.
On the hill from where
you can see the port...
...there is a big
European-style house.
You mean that
haunted house?
Yes. She used to live there.
But the people who
lived there are missing...
...aren't they?
That's the rumor, but...
I've heard she's
a famous detective now.
What?! A detective?
Just beyond here, I've found
a really cute trinket store.
Let's go, Meimi?!
Yeah,
but I have homework...
Just a little peek.
Oh, it's Tomoko!
I wonder where she's going.
Let's follow her!
What?! But...!
- Don't worry!
- Wait!
Where did she go?
Isn't this
the haunted house?
I've heard that a first-year
student in our school...
...heard a woman crying
in the middle of night.
Ryoko!
We met earlier.
Well...
Tomoko Nagata.
Nice to meet you.
Yes. I'm Meimi Haneoka.
A delicate
and beautiful hand...
People who have
hands like this...
...are often magicians.
Would you like to come in?
But...
Don't worry.
A lot of my memories
are from here.
In your eyes, this must
be like a haunted house.
Oh, no...!
They were
understanding parents.
When I said
I wanted to study abroad...
...they let me do it
without saying anything.
But...
Let's go upstairs!
It's beautiful!
I was always dreaming.
From here...
from this window...
...I wanted to fly away.
I wanted to go somewhere.
I didn't notice...
...my parents' love for me.
Your parents are...
Missing.
Since I went abroad.
Oh, I'm sorry.
There's no reason
to tell you these things.
Please forget it.
Excuse me...
I'm sorry
I came in without asking.
It brought back
a lot of memories, so...
Please stay
as long as you'd like.
To tell you the truth,
I don't deserve to be here.
Well, would you
like to tell me why?
Revenge?
Yes.
The person
who is responsible...
...for my parents'
disappearance.
I only came back here
to get my revenge.
My parents were
art dealers in this town.
Art dealers?
Those people
who sell pieces of art?
Yes.
My father was
strict but affectionate.
Mother was always
watching over me.
I was really happy.
The piece of art my parents
treasured most was...
...a picture titled
"Wings of Freedom."
But a man who wanted...
..."Wings of Freedom"
appeared one day.
Of course, my parents
turned down his offer.
But in the end,
they gave in to his enthusiasm...
...and they decided
to sell it to him.
My father though that
he would treasure the picture.
But the man betrayed
my father's trust.
He said the picture
he bought was a fake...
...and he sued my father.
No way!
Because my father
didn't have...
...any evidence
to prove otherwise...
...he had to pay a lot
of money and apologize.
Because of that he lost
credibility as an art dealer...
...and he lost everything.
That's why they disappeared.
As I was abroad...
...I didn't know what was going on.
But I have always believed...
...that my parents were innocent.
But in order to prove it...
...I didn't know what I could do.
That's why you
became a detective?
In order to become
strong and take revenge...
...I endured the difficult training.
I continued to investigate...
...the man who deceived...
...my parents.
And the man is...?
He's the owner
of Sugawara Industries...
...Ryosuke Sugawara.
She's going to steal?!
No way!
If she can prove
that Sugawara...
...has the real
"Wings of Freedom"...
...then she can prove
her parents' innocence.
No! She shouldn't do that!
Meimi...
I'll steal the picture.
I'll steal it
before Tomoko can...
...and reveal
Sugawara's crime!
Her revenge is meaningless.
No way...
Today I'd like to take you around,
away from the job.
Dad!
I don't think you've seen enough
with this boy as a guide.
This time I'd like to show you
an adult's hospitality...!
"I'm taking
'Wings of Freedom'...
...that's in the possession
of Mr. Ryosuke Sugawara.
-St. Tail"
- She is...!
- What's that?
The real "Wings of Freedom"
is in my possession?
Is that what you're saying?
You don't have it?
That's silly!
I've always wanted that piece...
Because of that,
I once bought a counterfeit.
So you're saying
you don't have it.
Of course I don't have it.
I'm the one who wants
to know where it is!
I've heard of
the mysterious thief St. Tail.
She must have
misunderstood something.
She is...
It's not like St. Tail to send
an inaccurate warning note.
You believe
that petty thief's words?
She isn't a petty thief.
What Asuka Jr. said is true.
According to my research...
...St. Tail has never sent
an inaccurate warning note.
Not even once!
If you let us search your house,
we can clear this up.
I must refuse!
Why?!
If you haven't done
anything wrong...
...it shouldn't be a problem.
Because it isn't necessary.
You don't even
have any evidence.
Chairman. It's almost time.
All right.
Detective Asuka.
I'll listen to your advice...
...and will let you
guard the outside.
Then we'll do so.
Isn't she that
art dealer's daughter?!
Yes. I had it confirmed...
...through an American
detective agency...
...and there's no doubt about it.
Apparently she's been
investigating you.
This isn't good.
If she finds out
I have the real picture...
Then...?
You don't even need to ask!
Yes, sir!
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Be careful, Meimi.
We don't know
what Tomoko will do.
Don't worry! It'll be fine!
May the blessings
of God be with us.
Asuka Jr., where is
Detective Asuka?
He told me
he had something...
...he needed to check...
What is he going to do?
I suppose she gave up...
Pretty impressive, St. Tail.
I can't let you interfere
with my revenge.
Over there!
She's up in this tree!
Oh, no! How?!
Asuka Jr.!
Darn it! Never mind!
Let's move in!
Yes!
What shall I do?!
What's going on?!
You saved me!
Thank you, Asuka Jr.
This is the "Wings of Freedom"
you were looking for.
The real one.
It's the one
your father sold to me.
I prepared the counterfeit
and switched them.
Now that you've seen the picture
you were looking for...
...you don't have
any regrets, do you?
The one who broke in
should have been St. Tail.
So, even if you disappear...
...no one will suspect me.
After the police leave...
...I'll decide how
you should disappear.
We've made the police leave.
But the media is making a fuss.
I guess it would be better
to give them an explanation.
Let's have a press conference.
This must be it.
St. Tail...!
Why?
You know that I set you up.
Oh, no...!
Let go! Let go of my hand!
Let go!
I can't do that!
You almost did it, didn't you?!
Wait!
St. Tail...!
I'm sorry, but I can't
give this picture to you.
Why not?!
You shouldn't steal!
Ever!
Asuka Jr.!
Where are you?!
Over here! Here!
It's...
...Show...
...Time!
Hold on!
A thief by the name of St. Tail...
...seems to have
been misinformed.
Both six years ago and today...
...I've been a victim.
You don't really have
"Wings of Freedom," do you?
Of course not.
If you have any doubt...
...please go ahead and search
my house or my company.
That's a nice touch, Tajima...
I, Ryosuke Sugawara,
swear to God...
...that I am innocent!
It's the real
"Wings of Freedom"!
- What?!
- Please explain this!
I don't know!
I don't know anything!
Mr. Sugawara.
Please come with us.
Have you discussed this
with the mayor?
Maybe you should
have a discussion...
...with your conscience.
We've uncovered
a few things about you.
The materials she
gave us helped a lot.
You'll have a lot of time
to tell us your story.
Thank you, St. Tail.
I heard that
Sugawara admitted...
...deceiving your parents.
My dad was quite pleased.
Thank you for everything.
Please thank your father for me.
I will.
Meimi...
Hang in there.
I'm cheering
for you from America.
What's the connection
between you?
We're best friends.
I didn't know... Hey!
You don't understand.
Guys don't!
Wait! Hey, Meimi!