Wait!
St. Tail!
I know your escape route!
I did it!
St. Tail.
Today is the day
I'm going to capture you on film!
What...? Saruwatari!
Hey... What are you
smiling about?
Stop it!
What's with this article,
Saruwatari?!
What do you mean?
I just reported the facts.
You call these facts?!
First of all,
if you hadn't interfered...
...St. Tail would have been...!
Ah, she escaped
from you again, Asuka Jr.
What a pity...!
Shut up!
I'll definitely
catch her next time!
How many times
have we heard that before?
St. Tail may already be tired...
...of dealing with Asuka Jr.
What are you saying?!
You just don't
understand St. Tail!
Don't talk like
such an authority.
That's right.
You're a loser.
Shut up!
If you know so much...
...why don't you
try to catch St. Tail?!
I'm glad you said that!
Asuka Jr. or the two of us...
Who can catch St. Tail first?
Let's have a competition!
That's what I want!
A BURST OF LAUGHTER!
THE DETECTIVE TEAM
DOES A GREAT JOB!
The Detective Team?
Yes! We've formed...
...the St. Paulia
Detective Team!
We're going to catch St. Tail...
...and hear Asuka Jr. say,
"I lost to you."
Wait... Wait a minute,
everyone...
Both Kyoko and Ryoko
are highly motivated.
But you can never beat Asuka.
Right, Asuka?!
What are you doing?!
Get away from me!
Calm down, Meimi.
What's with Takamiya's attitude?
Hey, Kyoko!
Meimi! Seira!
Let's join together
and catch St. Tail!
Because I'm serving God...
...I can't be
involved in a fight...
Seira...
I'm sorry!
All right then.
Kyoko! Meimi!
We three will do it!
Emerald... you said?
My husband is the captain
of a ship going abroad.
The emerald was...
...my present to my husband...
...who would finish his last trip
and come back home.
It was stolen...
...by a jewel thief who has
been active recently...
...and targets big houses.
The police worked really hard.
But they can't find any clues.
Before my husband comes back...
...I want to get the emerald
back at any cost.
I want to see my husband's
look of surprise...
Your feelings...
I'm sure God
understands them...
According to my sources...
...the thief is working
for a crooked businessman...
...Torabatake.
Torabatake destroys
all evidence...
...linked to the thefts.
He appears to be
hiding the jewels...
...in a bronze statue
of a dolphin.
A bronze statue of a dolphin?
You mean the one
at the All Sports Center...
...in the Port Area?
That Sports Center was...
...built by Torabatake
as a place to hide the evidence.
I'm sure Mrs. Ono's emerald...
...is in the statue of the dolphin.
No one would ever suspect...
...that the stolen jewels
are hidden in there.
I see.
It's your show time, Meimi.
With our power...
...let's get back Mrs. Ono's
important emerald!
Yeah.
All right!
I'm ready for anything!
We knew that
you'd come! Meimi!
What?
What do you mean, what?
You came to catch
St. Tail, didn't you?
Yeah...
In order to deliver
a warning note...
...St. Tail will have
to approach Asuka Jr.
We're going to catch her then!
What a brilliant plan we have!
Yeah, yeah.
What...?!
What shall I do?!
Now I can't send
a warning note...!
I'm sorry!
That boy is suspicious!
Kyoko! Meimi! Get him!
Wait... Wait a minute!
Are you all right, Asuka Jr.?
Ouch...
What are you doing?!
Hey, you two!
Now we've caught you, St. Tail!
Let's see who you are!
Hey! Stop it!
Both of you!
We won't let you
interfere, Asuka Jr.!
We're going to catch St. Tail!
Speak up, St. Tail!
Admit that the ball
was a warning note!
Are you saying he is St. Tail?
No! I'm not St. Tail!
He's right!
That boy is not St. Tail. Here.
See?
She's right.
It's a regular ball.
That's strange.
Bullies!
You brat!
Ah, ha!
What stupid detectives...
...thinking that child was St. Tail!
What did you say?!
"Tonight...
...at the All Sports Center...
...I'll take the bronze dolphin.
-St. Tail"
What's this?!
She got through
our surveillance...
...and delivered
the warning note.
- St. Tail is very impressive.
- Yeah.
What surveillance?!
I don't want to hear anything
from a stupid detective...
...who didn't even notice
a warning note in his own pocket!
That's right!
What did you say...?!
This will be a problem...
Meimi, how do you think
St. Tail comes in?
What?!
Why do you ask me?!
Your father is
a magician, isn't he?
So as a magician's daughter...
...I thought you might know
how St. Tail thinks.
You would think so,
but I don't know...
Are you okay losing
to Asuka Jr., Meimi?
St. Tail will probably
come this way...
We'll get you, St. Tail!
Watch us, Asuka Jr.!
I have to deal with their fight...
Please cover for me
while I'm gone, Ruby!
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Mrs. Ono's husband's ship...
...is arriving at the port
tonight, isn't it?
I have to hurry!
Be careful, Meimi.
Don't worry.
I know what Asuka Jr. is up to.
No. The ones you have
to be careful about are...
...Ryoko and Kyoko.
We know those two well.
They may do
something unexpected.
No need to worry!
May the blessings
of God be with us.
Oh, hello.
May I speak with Meimi?
Oh, boy, that Meimi.
Of all times,
how can she be late now?
Meimi.
It's a phone call from Kyoko.
Meimi...?
Meimi? Meimi!
Meimi?
Meimi!
I've got a cold...
If she's sick,
she can't help us.
All right then. It's just the two
of us. Let's catch St. Tail!
Mr. Torabatake.
You have arranged for your
company's security guards.
I appreciate your cooperation.
It's the proper thing to do.
This bronze statue
is an important asset.
But...
...why is St. Tail
trying to steal this?
Even St. Tail...
...can't discover the secret
of this bronze dolphin.
Mr. President!
We've caught a suspicious man.
Hey! Come on!
Sawatari! Why are you here?
What do you think?!
I came to take pictures of St. Tail.
What?!
Do you know him?
Well...
Yes...
Ouch!
What's going on?!
This is...!
I won't let you escape,
St. Tail!
St. Paulia Academy
Detective Team!
Here we are!
You guys...!
Here we come!
What's this?!
Those are raw eggs,
Mr. President!
Stop it!
This is St. Tail's magic.
Darn you guys!
What...?
The real St. Tail is over there!
Hey, hey! Wait, everyone!
St. Tail! Don't move!
It's...
...Show...
...Time!
What?! What's that?!
Jewels! My jewels!
Ouch...!
Is this an emerald?
Mr. Torabatake...!
You're Torabatake, aren't you?
You're under arrest.
Dad!
Good job, Son!
Torabatake was
suspected of stealing jewels.
But we had a hard time
uncovering any evidence.
This incident finally gives us
the evidence we need.
My perfect hiding place...!
Darn you, St. Tail!
Don't forget to cook
our dinner, okay?
Yeah...
St. Tail!
I won't let her go!
Stop! St. Tail!
Lock on target! Fire!
Roger!
Oh, no! The match is wet!
Good grief!
This is the escape route
I expected you to take!
No!
We're going to catch St. Tail!
Plan B!
We did it!
We've got you, St. Tail!
Now, show your face!
It's going to be my scoop photo!
Don't move!
Watch out!
Fireworks...
I'm safe...
Oh, where is St. Tail?
Over there...!
No way!
Cheer up, you two!
But...!
We prepared for so long...!
I'm always like that.
You did well, you two...
...from the St. Paulia
Academy Detective Team!
Asuka Jr.
Thanks for a good photo!
Did St. Tail do this on purpose
in order to get us to make up?
But how would she
know about our fight?
That's right!
What's up, Kyoko?
We have to go
to Meimi to report this!
I'm returning your
important emerald.
- So Meimi caught a cold?
- Is she all right?
Thank you for coming
all this way to see her.
Please come in.
Meimi. Your medicine is here.
Thank you.
But I don't want it right now.
Don't be that way.
You've got to get better.
Ryoko and the others
are here, too.
Open the door, Meimi.
Meimi. Answer me.
Oh, dear!
Something is wrong with Meimi!
Oh, dear! Hurry up!
You don't need to worry.
She must be sleeping.
What's the matter, Meimi?
You didn't answer.
Sorry! I must
have been sleeping.
See, I told you.
Oh, well...
I'm leaving your medicine here.
It seems like you're
dealing with the cold well.
Yeah. Sorry to worry you.
No, we're the ones
who are sorry.
To tell you the truth,
we let St. Tail escape.
Is that so?
I'm sorry to hear that. But...
...you guys became
friends again, didn't you?
Kind of...
But if Asuka Jr. hadn't interfered...
What are you talking about?
You're the ones
who interfered with me!
How can you say that?!