I'm happy! I'm happy!
Tomorrow is going
to be a fun Sunday!
And I have free
tickets to Aqualand!
All right! I'm going to ask
Haneoka for a date! Hooray!
I'm so happy...!
Haneoka!
Yes?
They're cute!
What's up, Sawatari?
What should I do?
There are two beautiful girls.
And they're stunning
in their summer school uniforms.
One shines like gold
in the summer sun...
She's like a sunflower.
The other sits quietly
in the heart of the forest...
She is like a white lily...
Oh, do I have to choose one?
Am I going to break up
their friendship?
No, I can't!
Lord, please forgive my sins.
And please show this
lost sheep the right way.
Five free tickets?
Thank you for getting enough
tickets to include me, Saruwatari.
That's right! I have five tickets.
So all three of can them can go...
Asuka Jr.
What do you have?!
Free tickets to Aqualand.
- Here.
- Wow! Thank you!
I feel bad taking these
from you, Sawatari.
What?
- What are you talking about?!
- Don't hang on me!
Wow! A free ticket to Aqualand!
If you're going, I'm going, too!
Hey! Hold on for just a minute!
First of all, there are
only five free tickets!
Wow, perfect! Did you
have something to say?
No... Nothing.
"WHITE DOLPHIN"
- RETURN TO THE SEA!
As usual, there's
a big Sunday crowd!
Everyone! This way!
They said the aquarium
is on the third floor...
...and we need to use an elevator!
All right!
I wonder if we could
get on the next one.
I guess we can get on somehow.
Here it comes!
We're going up.
Oh, wait for me!
We just made it!
Oh, no! How embarrassing!
Wait, Meimi!
We can easily
squeeze in one more!
What was that?!
Did I see...
What am I supposed to do?
My hand...!
Shoot! I didn't let go of her hand.
Hey! You two!
You're too close to each other!
Break it up! Break it up!
Don't be ridiculous!
It's just the situation!
Good grief!
Hurry up...!
Get there!
Come on, third floor!
Second floor.
Going up.
No! Wait!
It's gone...
Just the two of us...
What?! We lost Haneoka!
Asuka, too.
Oh, no! I thought we were going
to have an enjoyable day together!
She must be alone
and crying right now!
Asuka is with her.
Is this by any chance
a kidnapping...?
I told you, Asuka is with her!
Haneoka! I, Manato Sawatari,
am on my way to save you!
You're not listening...!
Don't worry!
If we go slowly now,
they'll catch up with us.
Right?
Yes! You're absolutely right!
He sure is quick
at switching his attention...
This is a great opportunity.
I want them to be alone.
I call this plan...
Seira's Love Love Strategy!
Isn't it great?!
Well, Mimori?
Let's go! Let's go!
You're right. Let's go.
Hey! Wait!
Don't leave me alone! Hey!
I guess they already went in.
It's because I forced myself
into the crowded elevator...
So you wanted to be
separated and all alone?
That's not what I meant!
Why do we always
end up like this?
Sawatari, what do you think of fish?
What?
I love fish!
Really? I'm glad to hear that!
- Sawatari.
- Yes?
Wouldn't you like
to breathe underwater?
Because it looks like
it feels good, doesn't it?
She's so cute!
All right!
I, Sawatari, for you, Mimori...
...will master breathing
underwater or anything!
You name it and I'll do it!
Wow, wonderful!
I can't wait!
Why do things turn out this way...?
Oh, no...!
- Well...
- What?
I spoke with St. Tail
up close the other day.
Really?
It's not a good idea
to bring up that incident!
I have to change the subject.
Why do you chase her
so passionately?
She's my dream girl...
What?!
Oh, no... I mean...
I want to see
if she's my dream girl...
I'm curious about
what she's normally like...
And many other things...
I'm glad...
I'm glad it is dark... But...
But I continue to hide my identity.
It's the same as lying to Asuka Jr.
Resemble...
I can tell because
it was dark then, too.
It's not her physical shape,
it's more her aura...
She resembles Meimi.
Asuka!
Hey! Asuka!
What are you daydreaming about?
You're late!
Of course!
If we don't watch the fish carefully,
it would seem rude to them.
There's a creepy one! Let's go!
- Hey! Don't pull!
- Hurry up! Hurry up!
Look, it's a white dolphin!
He looks like he's having
a conversation with the dolphin.
Seira...
Yeah...
Mana...
This is the Director's Office.
Director. That kid is glued
to the dolphin's glass again.
Again!
This is enough! Kick him out!
What an annoying brat...!
Then that white dolphin
is your friend?
Her name is Mana.
Do you know about Mana, Sister?
Yes, I do. I also saw you
at the aquarium the other day.
The director
of the aquarium said...
...that Mana was sick
and he could heal her.
He lied to me
and took Mana from the sea.
Mana wasn't sick...
He never had any intention
of returning Mana.
It's because Mana is a rare breed
called a Pearl Dolphin.
I've asked him many times
to return Mana, but...
He refused, didn't he?
Did you talk to the police?
It's no use, Sister.
Mana isn't my pet.
She's my friend.
I'm not her owner
so I can't go to the police.
The director tells me...
...to show some evidence
that Mana and I are friends.
But it's impossible
because Mana can't speak.
Cheer up, Hiromi.
I'm sure God will help you.
That's terrible!
Wait for me, Hiromi!
The mysterious thief
St. Tail will get back Mana.
Hiromi says Mana can do
a trick only when Hiromi calls her.
Well, then...
If he shows it to the owner...
...he can prove they're friends.
But Mana is...
...so shocked from being
taken away from the sea...
...that she has
become very depressed.
And she has been
in that tank for a while.
So it is impossible
for her to do the trick...
I see...
I heard...
...Asuka had a good time
on Sunday, right, Yasuhiro?
That's what I heard, Chiba.
I heard he had girls
with him, Yasuhiro.
I envy him, Chiba.
Boy! How pesky can you two be?
Sawatari had free tickets.
What was I supposed to do?
If you have a problem,
talk to Sawatari.
That's not the point.
Why didn't you at least tell us?
You're rude to us.
This is...!
"Tonight I'm going to Aqualand...
...to get the 'Pearl Dolphin.'"
It's St. Tail's warning note!
What's the Pearl Dolphin?
I don't know.
It's the white dolphin at Aqualand.
We've never been to Aqualand.
It must be a beautiful dolphin.
Right, Asuka?
You two are really
getting on my nerves...
I'm home!
- Hi, Meimi.
- Welcome home.
What's this?
What did you do, Dad?
Isn't it romantic?
It's the illusion I'm going to use
in the next magic show.
It's like we're really in the forest.
Dad, can you change it
to the sea next?
Of course. Here!
Wow! It brings back
memories of our dates.
Yeah. We went
to the sea often, didn't we?
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Meimi...
I think Hiromi will
probably be at the aquarium.
Be careful.
All right.
May the blessings
of God be with us.
This is our Pearl Dolphin.
Please protect her
from the mysterious thief.
- Yes!
- Put me down!
Put me down!
Return Mana! You liar!
That kid again.
Excuse me...
You're still here?!
It's way past closing time!
Director.
Like I've told you before...
...there's no proof
that the dolphin is your friend.
Mana will flip in the air
at my command. I'm not lying!
I don't believe it.
She hasn't been trained.
If you're too persistent,
I'll report you to the police.
It's true! Believe me!
Then have her do the trick.
If she does the trick,
I'll let her go back to the sea.
Really? Will you really?
Really.
It's a promise between two men.
But I don't think the dolphin
can do a flip from the tank.
That's not fair!
Kick him out!
- Yes!
- Asuka Jr.!
Bad news! St. Tail showed up
on the surveillance camera.
What?!
St. Tail...
Good evening, everyone.
The St. Tail dolphin show...
...will be starting
at the dolphin's stage shortly.
Tonight's special guest
is the Pearl Dolphin, Mana.
What?!
Move!
How could this be...?!
How did she open...
...the gate between
the tank and the stage?
- Let's go!
- Yes!
Here we are. Get off.
Hey, you brat!
Mana...
Return Mana! You liar!
Mana will flip in the air
at my command. I'm not lying!
Tonight's special guest
is the Pearl Dolphin, Mana.
Let's go, Hiromi!
Mana is at the dolphin stage.
Hurry up!
Mana looks depressed.
St. Tail!
Mana!
Hiromi!
Mana! Jump!
Asuka Jr.!
What's going on, Asuka Jr.?
Get St. Tail now! Otherwise...!
Otherwise... what?
The dolphin will do a flip?
I won't ask you again!
Mana!
Jump!
Jump, Mana! Mana!
If you don't jump,
you can't go back to the sea.
Where's the flip?
If she doesn't jump,
I can't return her to the sea.
It's your fault!
Because you lied
and put her in the tank...
...now she's really sick.
That's enough, brat!
Let go of me!
Mana!
Wait!
I'll make you keep
the promise with Hiromi!
What?!
It's...
...Show...
...Time!
Mana!
Open your eyes.
You're in the sea.
Mana...
Remember...
...the fun time you spent...
...with Hiromi!
Remember the sea!
Hiromi! Now!
Mana! Jump!
Mana!
Now you can go back!
You can go back to the sea, Mana.
I don't know about that!
I don't know anything
about the promise!
Take the dolphin back
to the tank immediately!
No, Director.
You definitely promised!
I am a witness.
It's not a pretty picture
you're painting.
Shoot...!
I have no choice.
Asuka Jr.! St. Tail is...!
Wait! St. Tail!
Take care of the rest, Asuka Jr.!
I'm telling you to wait!
I have to catch you
no matter what!
What? Why?
Because I'm your dream girl...?
If you say it just one more time...
I...
You resemble...
You...
...resemble the girl
I can't stop thinking about!