Because I'm your dream girl...?
If you say it just one more time...
I...
You resemble...
You...
...resemble the girl
I can't stop thinking about!
MOM'S SECRET!
A FEMALE THIEF'S VENGEANCE
You resemble the girl
I can't stop thinking about!
The girl Asuka Jr. likes...
He likes...
Meimi!
Oh, Meimi! Class is over!
You were like that
throughout the class.
That's why the Sister was angry...
...and gave only you homework.
Yeah...
But...
...Asuka Jr.'s words...
...keep repeating in my head...
I've got an idea! Asuka Jr.!
Why don't you help her?
You can finish it
in 15 minutes, can't you?
Don't be absurd!
It's worthless
unless you do it by yourself.
- Oh, no.
- They're going to start up again.
That's all right, Ryoko.
What...?
I'll do it by myself.
- What..?
- The fight didn't start...?
You resemble the girl
I can't stop thinking about!
Why did I say that?
Asuka Jr.!
You know the crown of the sun,
the Prominence Crown, don't you?
Yeah. It's showing
at the F Art Museum, isn't it?
Don't you think
St. Tail is going to target it?
What? What are you
talking about?
There's a treasure
lying at the end of the rainbow...
What's that?
The Prominence Crown
was owned...
...by the Astoria Royal Family.
These are the words
from the Royal Family's crest.
On this crown...
...there are seven jewels...
...which, people said,
were from the end of a rainbow.
Garnet...
Topaz...
Emerald and sapphire...
They are seven colored jewels.
How cool!
Only the ruby,
which was in the center,...
...has been missing for some time.
It's a famous story.
Some say it was stolen.
But no one knows
exactly what happened.
However...!
The ruby has resurfaced
after over a ten-year absence.
I've heard it will go on auction.
How would it be possible
for St. Tail to pass it up?
I've got the front-page article!
You did good research.
I've seen the crown.
Wow! I should go to see it, too!
Me, too!
Unfortunately St. Tail has
no intention of stealing it!
Sorry!
Hello!
Meimi's father!
Thank you for being
a good friend to Meimi, Seira.
Not at all. The feeling is mutual.
Today I came here to pray.
What?
Is something troubling you?
As a matter of fact...
The other day, all three of us
went to the F Art Museum.
But since we saw
the Prominence Crown...
...Eimi, my wife,
has been a little strange.
She seems depressed.
What can I do to cheer her up?
Let's pray!
I'm sure God will help us.
Thank you, Seira.
I see...
As I suspected, since that day
Mom has been depressed...
You, too, are depressed...
Your father said so
and is worried about you.
Oh, I'm fine!
See?
Enough about me.
I'll ask Mom to her face!
Leave it to me.
Meimi...
What?
Mom, tell me!
Does the reason
you're depressed...
...have anything to do
with the Prominence Crown?
Thank you, Meimi.
You've noticed it.
You're right...
Maybe it's about time
for me to talk about it.
Meimi.
You know I was once
a mysterious thief, don't you?
Yes...
It was in a town very far from here.
I was called
"Mysterious Thief Lucifer."
It meant a devil
that had fallen from the sky.
I was a mean thief.
I stole things from innocent
people time after time...
...and became
the talk of the town.
Did you say you wanted me
to walk in your footsteps?
Oh, no way!
The thing I want you to take
is my athletic ability.
You don't do bad things.
I know that.
Yes...
Originally I started to do it
to test my athletic ability.
But later I discovered
that I couldn't stop being a thief.
For what reason?!
Did you have someone who
pursued you with all of his heart?
- What?
- Oh, nothing! Nothing at all!
My rival showed up.
I still get irritated
when I think about it!
A despicable mysterious
female thief showed up in the town.
She enjoyed
doing things for spite.
She targeted whatever item
I was planning to take.
She was like a snake!
Oh, Mom.
You're so competitive...!
But one night...
...while I was trying to get away
from the police...
...I hurt my ankle because of her.
I was in a desperate situation.
Then someone hid me
without any questions...
It was Dad, wasn't it?!
He was living in a small
apartment and training...
...to be a magician.
I don't have it.
What should I do?
I'm poor and I don't
have any medicine.
It hurts, doesn't it?
It's none of your business!
But don't make so much noise!
If they fiind me, you'll regret it!
Oh, I've got an idea!
Hey! Are you listening to me?!
One!
Two!
Three!
I can only do something like that.
But it's good for hiding, isn't it?
Since then...
Whenever we met,
he gave me an armful of flowers.
Only flowers.
That's the only magic
he could do at that time.
I was happy...
...because he always did
all that he could do...
...and he tried to make me happy.
When I watched him like that...
...I started to think...
...of the stupid things
I had been doing.
And I stopped being a thief.
I planned on returning
all of the things I had stolen...
...to their rightful owners.
At least I was planning to do so...
But...
...the one thing I couldn't return
was the Prominence Crown's ruby.
On the way to return it,
that other woman took it from me.
And that's how it ended.
When I saw the crown...
...I remembered it.
Cheer up, Mom!
I'm not going to tell Dad.
Dad knows everything.
As always
he doesn't mention it to me.
Seira. I'm going
to get the Crown's ruby back.
The auction place is...
...the same place as before.
So this time...
...I don't think
you should go there.
Besides, I'm sure Asuka has...
...all of the information
about the place...
I've found the warehouse...
...where they're keeping
the ruby until the auction.
One!
Two!
Three!
"Tomorrow night,
I'm going to the R Warehouse...
...to take the 'Star Ruby.'
-St. Tail"
St. Tail?
As expected, she's coming!
Asuka Jr. is
in love with someone...
What should I do, Mom?
You haven't gone home yet?
Neither have you.
Excuse me, you two!
Hello! I've just opened
a fortune telling shop near this school.
Please come by
with your boyfriend.
Oh, my...!
How cute! You're blushing!
Hello there! I've just opened
a fortune telling shop...
Please come!
I'll be expecting you!
Hello, over there!
I guess it's better
if you're not seen with me.
I've never said that!
This is for your homework.
You can peek
only if you can't figure it out.
Thank you.
I didn't do it for your sake.
Practice... practice.
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Good luck, Meimi!
You can leave it to me!
It's for my dad and mom!
May the blessings
of God be with us.
There it is!
That must be the Star Ruby.
Where is Asuka Jr.?
Today is the day I'll catch her!
One!
Two!
Three!
Wait...
It's too easy...
Where is the security?
The owner of the jewel...
...refused the security
in the warehouse.
Are they outside?
I've got her!
You won't escape today!
One!
Two!
Three!
I'm sorry, but you're the last
person I want to catch me!
At last I've found you!
We've put the Star Ruby
on auction to draw you out.
The Mysterious Thief Lucifer...
We've discovered
the clue to finding you.
You're the last person
I want to catch me!
I wonder...
I wonder why I want to catch her.
At first, I just wanted to catch her...
When you showed up,
I was excited.
But then...
...I didn't want
anyone else to have you!
From that moment on...
There's a treasure lying
at the end of the rainbow...
I don't remember
which royal family it was...
...but the end of the rainbow
can't exist physically...
Oh, shoot! I'll be late for school!
At the end of the rainbow...
...is a treasure...
Asuka Jr.!
Don't tell me he spent
the whole night in the rain?
What's the matter?!
What about you?
It's pretty early...
I'm on duty this morning.
What happened to you?
You've got a high fever!
Wait a minute!
I'll call your home.
I love you...
I love you, Meimi.
It's the truth.
I'm happy...
...that you're here with me...
I AM RETURNING THIS.
-ST. TAIL
...that my hand...
...can reach you...