I never imagined
that this day would come.
That's right. I forgot
that girls walk slowly.
I'm sorry.
Oh, no. No need to apologize...
Well...
I love you...
By the way...
I'd like to make it clear...
...there won't be any
of that daily diary exchange...
...or using a beeper business.
Needless to say...
...there won't be any
matching clothes either.
And birthdays...
...Christmas, Valentine's Day...
...I don't...
Don't worry.
I don't want anything...
I love you...
A FORMIDABLE FOE?!
A MISCHIEVOUS PIXIE'S TRAP!
Again...
I discovered
that this is the house...
...of the Mysterious Thief Lucifer...
...who is Eimi Haneoka.
Since monitoring this house...
...Lucifer hasn't shown...
...any movement...
...but her daughter
sometimes goes out at night.
And every time she goes out,
the next morning...
...there's an article about St. Tail.
Does this mean...?!
Hey! Look! Look at the article
about St. Tail this morning!
She escaped
from you again, Asuka!
Because he has Meimi now...!
He doesn't care about St. Tail!
Ryoko!
Right?!
What kind of logic is that?!
Nothing has changed!
I will definitely catch her!
You want to impress Haneoka!
I see...!
Wow! Cool!
Why are you jumping
to all of these conclusions?!
How about this, Asuka Jr.?
It's the fortune teller.
I've heard she is pretty good.
A fortune teller?
Oh, yeah. I've heard that, too.
Yeah, why don't you ask her
about the location of St. Tail?
That's a cover story.
What he really wants to know is...
...how their relationship is going.
Right! This is great!
Let it go! Let's change the subject!
You guys...!
Don't get mad!
We're happy for the two of you.
That's right!
Finally you two got together!
Takamiya...
How could she, Haneoka?
How could she choose
Asuka over me?!
Why? Haneoka?
Hey! Get away
from me, Saruwatari!
What's wrong...?
It's unusual to see you here...!
Mimori!
I came here to see you!
Boy! I can't even have
a broken heart in peace...
What?!
Nothing...
I'm impressed, Takamiya.
What else can I do?
First of all, those two took...
...too long to get together.
Oh, I see. So half of it
was stubborn pride!
Oh, brother...!
I'm sure you'll have
God's blessings, Takamiya...
God's...
It hurts...
My beautiful face...!
When I'm hitting him...
...I feel good.
That's interesting...
That's terrible...!
So God's blessings...
...may not be necessary...
FORTUNE TELLING
We've found it!
This is the fortune teller's house
that Kyoko was talking about.
You aren't interested in this
kind of stuff. Let's forget it!
Why don't you ask her
about the location of St. Tail?
That's all right.
You want to go in, don't you?
Let's go in.
It's dark.
Welcome!
That's the girl...
Excuse me, you two!
Hello.
I've just opened
a fortune telling shop near this school.
Please come by
with your boyfriend.
Oh, my...!
Oh, welcome!
We've heard your fortunes
are very accurate...
You want to know...
...whether you are right
for each other, right?
What...?
When I see you two, I can tell...
Your names and dates of birth...
Meimi Haneoka,
born on September 29th.
And Asuka Jr. is...
Daiki Asuka, August 12th.
So he is Asuka Jr.,
special agent for the mayor...
What are you going to do
with the crystal ball?
Okay...
Well...?
A thick fog is
filling the crystal ball.
So I can't see you there.
I've never seen such thick fog.
And I can see a ring
around his finger.
This must be
about the secret promise.
It's a one-sided promise...
What? Is she talking
about St. Tail and Asuka Jr?.
It seems the ring can
never be removed.
His character
and straightforwardness...
...is indicated in this.
As a result, this relationship...
...is doomed to failure.
Why?
You're hiding something
very big from him, aren't you?
I guess I've hit the bull's-eye.
Let's go.
That's why I hate
fortune telling stuff.
She knew things
without getting any information.
Listen! That's nonsense.
Those who talk
nonsense and tell lies...
...are the worst!
Right?
Honest eyes...
Unremovable ring...
All right, then.
Let's go home.
I'm getting hungry.
That's the sign...
...that he can't forgive
people who deceive.
I'm sure he won't forgive
my being St. Tail...
I'm leaving!
That's a solid-gold statue of Mary.
Yesterday, a person
named Sakiko visited here.
She valued it a great deal.
But...
You know about Pandora...
...the fortune telling place,
don't you, Meimi?
Yeah...
Sakiko went there.
What?!
My statue of Mary?!
That's right.
That solid-gold statue of Mary...
...is bringing you misfortune.
No way...!
You can bring
the solid-gold statue...
...of Mary to us immediately.
We'll take full responsibility
for its disposal.
You've got to be kidding!
How could I...?!
Are you prepared
to have misfortune?
I can't do it...
Do you understand?
So did she give it away? Why?
I suppose
the fortune teller uses hypnosis.
Hypnosis?
So Sakiko can't go to the police...
Meimi?
- I went there.
- What?
I went to the fortune teller...
...and she gave me
a scary fortune...
If Asuka Jr. finds out I'm St. Tail...
You've been deceiving me!
Let's stop stealing.
Seira...
Meimi...
I appreciate what you
have done very much.
But you don't need...
...to see Asuka Jr.
as St. Tail anymore.
So let's end it.
I love you. I love you, Meimi.
No! We can't do it!
We can't desert those
people who are in trouble...
Meimi...
We have to get back
the solid-gold statue of Mary.
Now it's lunch time!
Lunch time! Lunch time!
You brought a lunchbox
today, Asuka?
Yeah...
It's been a while...
...since St. Tail
booby-trapped your lunchbox!
"Tonight I'll get
the solid-gold statue of Mary.
-St. Tail"
Oh, boy! She really
went all out on this lunch!
I envy you.
Hey, Haneoka.
Look at Asuka's lunchbox...
- Stop it!
- Then let us eat it!
Let me make lots and lots
of whatever you like...
Whatever happens
from this point...
COOKBOOK
...I hope I have no regrets...
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Meimi...
Please tell me
when things get too painful.
Please promise me.
If it happens...
If it happens, then I...
...will become St. Seira!
St. Seira...?!
One!
Two!
Three!
Thank you, Seira.
May the blessings
of God be with us.
A solid-gold statue of Mary?
We don't have any...
All we have are over there.
It's made of solid gold...
Our store doesn't have it.
I'm sorry...
SAKURAI JEWELERS
We don't have such a thing...
A solid-gold statue of Mary...
Our store doesn't have it...
Really...?
Darn it!
That St. Tail! Where is it?
Where is the location?!
Where in the world is there
a solid-gold statue of Mary?
Mysterious Thief St. Tail!
I'm sorry, Asuka Jr.
I didn't want you here...
where she is...
I came to get
the statue of Mary back.
You came here.
That's what I wanted.
I have several things
I want to ask you.
Now watch this.
Doesn't this smell nice?
Now take a deep breath.
What's going on?
This fragrance is...
The smell in a bathroom!
It's lavender!
Your date of birth?
September...
...29th...
I've heard it somewhere before.
What is your father's name?
Haneoka...
Genichiro...
And mother?
Haneoka...
Eimi...
Are you...
...the daughter
of the Mysterious Thief Lucifer?
Meimi Haneoka?
You're Meimi Haneoka,
aren't you?
You are
the Mysterious Thief St. Tail.
Stop it!
Meimi Haneoka...
Meimi...!
Are you St. Tail?
Stop it!
You...?!
Stop! Stop!
Meimi...!
Yes. I'm sorry.
I've been hiding it from you.
I was scared that you'd find out.
I was scared...
I was really scared...
Okay. That's enough.
I just wanted to know your identity.
You said some
unexpected things, too.
Ms. Meimi Haneoka.
What are you scared of?
I was hypnotized...?
Oh, no!
I can't have my secret...
...revealed either.
I wouldn't be able
to continue my business.
- Your business?
- That's right.
Stealing people's valuables?
Don't worry.
I'm not planning to reveal
your identity to the public.
Let me tell you what I'm thinking.
What?
I'm thinking of...
...taking revenge
on the Mysterious Thief Lucifer.
Lucifer...?
My mom...
On my mom?
Then I'll take the statue
of Mary, Ms. St. Tail.
You can't do that!
One! Two!
Three!
Oh, the statue of Mary!
It isn't hot...
Was it magic?
I'll take the statue of Mary,
Ms. Fortune Teller.
How dare you...?!
St. Tail...!
What...?
St. Tail!
I wonder...
...what will happen if she
continues with that business.
Her hypnosis...
You're Meimi Haneoka...
I have to stop her hypnosis...
At the time, my body got cold...
I thought the real Asuka Jr.
was asking me.
I'm scared.
The solid-gold statue
of Mary was taken.
I'm sorry, Mother.
It was the most valuable item...
...out of everything
we've gotten recently.
- Maju.
- Yes.
Lucifer is living a normal life.
It won't be fun to make her suffer.
Don't you agree?
What...? Yes!
And the daughter's pain
is her mother's pain.
Don't you think so?
Yes! I'm with you all the way!
Excellent.
We can have
more fun that way, Maju.
The Mysterious Thief St. Tail.
The battle is just now starting...