Then you also went
to the fortune teller Pandora...
Yes.
And when I came to...
...the ring, which was
a family heirloom, was gone.
It's the same trick as the other one.
But, Sister! I'm sure of this!
The one who stole
the ring is St. Tail!
There's no doubt about it!
MOM'S ENEMY!
ROSEMARY'S CONSPIRACY
SERIAL ROBBERY
BY SAINT TAIL CONTINUES
This is the longest
it's gone in Seika City's history.
I've heard that all of the victims
are saying St. Tail did it.
I don't know anything about it...
What a terrible thing to do!
My dad says
he can't sleep at night.
I don't know...!
There's no way that
she would do these things!
Asuka Jr. ...
A warning note...
St. Tail's warning note
hasn't been delivered.
We had an agreement...
...that she would give me
a warning note every time.
She's never broken the promise.
Promise...
Those newspaper articles...
I don't believe them!
Thank you, Asuka Jr.
It has to be hypnosis.
All of the victims are...
...made to believe
that St. Tail stole their things.
That's the revenge
on the Mysterious Thief Lucifer.
In order to get
revenge on my mom...
...she's giving me trouble.
Why?!
Meimi.
Even though I thought it was
disrespectful to your mother...
...I researched the old articles
about Mysterious Thief Lucifer.
This is...!
THIEF LUCIFER PUBLICLY
CHALLENGES ROSEMARY
It looks like
Mysterious Thief Lucifer's warning note.
Oh, Mom. What a showoff...!
In this article, Rosemary...
...seemed to be Lucifer's
opponent, I mean, rival.
Yeah. I heard
about her from Mom.
She was like a snake.
The person who resents
Lucifer can only be...
...this same person.
You're right. Mom returned
all of the items she had stolen.
But this Rosemary...
...has some connection
with that girl...?
I'm going to Pandora again.
I may find the location
of the victim's ring.
By the way, Seira,
how do you pronounce this?
FORTUNE TELLING
I'm really scared.
If the same thing
happens to me again...
But I have to go in.
For the sake
of St. Tail's reputation...
Excuse me...!
Welcome!
I've been waiting for you!
PANDORA'S ORIGINAL GOODS
MEDUSA CHAN
You don't need to be
that surprised! Right...
...Mom?
Mom...?
What...?
How cute!
Mom! You've got
to get rid of that habit.
You're so cute!
You look exactly like
Lucifer did at that age.
But cuteness is only skin deep.
Lucifer... She loved doing
things that people hated.
She always targeted
the item I was planning to take.
She was like a snake!
That's right! That's right!
I've heard that
somewhere before...
AIthough I don't have
any grudge against you...
...you have to come along with me
so that I can get my revenge.
Just curse the fates you were
born as Lucifer's daughter.
Excuse me...
Kabako...?
KABA (HIPPOPOTAMUS) KO
What did you say?
Oh, am I right?
You're Ms. Kabako Sendo,
also known as Rosemary, aren't you?
I learned how to read
your name from Seira.
Please don't address me
with my ridiculous real name!
Understand?!
That horrible
warning note from Lucifer...!
Because of that,
the public knew my real name...
...and people made fun of me!
That's right! That's right!
The humiliation...!
I've never, even for a second,
forgotten that feeling!
Like mother, like daughter!
How hateful! I'll never forgive you!
I didn't mean anything by it at all!
I just wanted to know
about the theft.
The stolen items are not here.
We don't know anything
about the items St. Tail stole.
Right, Maju?
Right, Mom!
This mother and daughter...
All right, then!
Sorry to have disturbed you!
Come back again!
How infuriating!
I'm not afraid of revenge!
Who do they think they are?!
Meimi, sorry to keep you waiting.
I checked for places
where a pair posing...
...as mother and daughter
have moved in recently.
This is the only place.
This is a monastery!
Yes. It's the old building
along the seashore.
It's not used now,
and it's supposed to be empty.
It's been for sale
for quite a while now.
But people thought it was creepy
and didn't want to get closer.
If those two are there...
...the stolen items
must be there, too.
I'm going to get them back!
And I'll clear St. Tail's name!
For the sake of Asuka Jr., too,
who believes in me...!
Darn it! Someone else
must be using St. Tail's name.
She must have been forced to be
involved in such a strange case.
- That blimp!
- Something is written on it!
"Tonight I'm going to the monastery...
...to take the rings and other things
which are in the possession...
...of Kabako Sendo,
also known as Rosemary.
-St. Tail"
What's that?
It's St. Tail's warning note!
St. Tail!
I used the same
warning note as my mom's.
Isn't it nice?
Meimi...
Oh, you're worrying
about the location, aren't you?
Asuka Jr. can figure it out.
It's not that.
Is it wise to show her real name?
Oh, no...!
I was only thinking about doing
the same thing as my mom did...!
She is indeed
Lucifer's daughter...
She has a lot of guts.
It doesn't matter whether
it's the mother or daughter!
I won't forgive you!
Your money's here!
Thank... Thank you...!
But who is Rosemary?
Her last few messages
have been difficult to understand...
What do you think you're doing?!
I am Rosemary.
How do you do, Mr. Detective?
You're so cute!
Rosemary?!
This is jade dust...
It's pretty, isn't it?
Don't take your eyes off of it.
What's happening?
I can't move!
You don't need to worry about
not understanding what's going on!
Cute little detective...
I'm inviting you to my house now.
So what are you
going to do, St. Tail?
Your weak point
is now in my hands.
You angered me.
You'll regret it,
and you'll wish you were dead.
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
One!
Two!
Three!
Be careful, Meimi.
Don't worry. I'll take care of it.
May the blessings
of God be with us.
See you!
I wonder why...
I have a bad feeling about this...
Meimi...!
Asuka Jr. isn't here...
Nor is his security staff...
They couldn't fiind this place?
You... didn't come...
The item you're looking for...
...is in here.
But no matter
how much you search here...
...the detective won't come.
Maju...!
What do you mean?!
Well...
You'll see...
Don't be misled, Meimi!
This is hypnosis!
It's an illusion!
One!
Two!
Three!
lllusion!
She created
a wind with her magic...
...and pushed away
my hypnosis...!
Are you awake now?
Where am I?
Oh, weren't you listening?
You're in my house.
Never mind that. Look this way.
Can you tell who is next door?
St. Tail!
This is a one-way mirror.
They can't see us
from the next room.
You'd better watch
closely from here...
...and see what happens next.
It's...
...Show...
...Time!
It's payback time!
Curtain ghosts!
Don't come near me!
What are you going to do to her?
Run!
I've gotten back
everything you stole.
Run!
Please run!
Now!
Everyone has something...
...that they don't want
other people to know...
You do, too, daughter of Lucifer.
That was loud.
It sounds like a storm.
Don't worry, Eimi.
There is always an end
to everything and every storm.
You're right.
There is an end to everything.
She's very near. Watch closely!
I'll do the same to you, St. Tail.
Until I catch you...
...don't get caught...!
All right!
You wanted to know
her identity, didn't you?
You're pleased, aren't you?
Why... Why...?!
Meimi!