I don't want anything...
...because you are my treasure...
...because your eyes
are my treasure...
THE FINAL BATTLE!
SAVE ASUKA JR.
What?! Sister?!
Asuka Jr. hasn't come home?
Is it true?!
He's been absent
for four days already!
Did he disappear?
Where did he go?!
Calm down!
Right now, the police
are looking for him, too.
Then he really is missing?
Sister! How is Detective Asuka?
Asuka's father?!
Asuka's father is on
a top-secret mission right now...
...and we can't contact him...
Anyway, calm down!
He'll be fine, everyone...
I ran for my life
from the monastery...
Asuka Jr. didn't come
to the place in my warning note.
At that time, he was already...
...missing...?!
Takamiya...
He probably
screwed up somewhere.
But still, Asuka is Asuka...
I'm sure he must be eating
when he needs to eat...
...and he must be sleeping
when he needs to sleep.
He'll pop up sooner or later.
Don't worry.
Thank you.
It's been four days since I was
locked in the top of this tower...
Why?
Why did you hide
the truth from me?
Were you enjoying teasing me?
What was I to you?!
What did you think of me?!
Really?
Asuka Jr. didn't show up
at the warning note's location...
Did he see the warning note?
I don't know.
But...
Maju said...
No matter how much you search,
the detective won't come here.
Meimi! Does this mean...
...Asuka Jr. was captured
by the mother and daughter?
They're punishing me...
...to get their revenge
on Mom and me.
It's not fair!
I'm getting him back.
What?
Oh, Lord, forgive me,
for I use no gimmick or trick.
Getting him back?!
You mean Asuka Jr.?!
One!
Two!
Three!
Meimi!
If you do that...
...it's the same
as telling him your identity!
It means that you'll get caught!
Then you two will...!
I'm sorry, Seira.
I suppose I can't be
St. Tail anymore.
But...
...he's an important
person to me.
Even though he may hate me,
or I may not be able to see him...
...I want him back!
It's no use trying
to stop you, is it?
Good luck...
Seira...
I'll be praying for your safety.
Ruby.
Please. This is
the only method I have.
Please deliver this.
Lord, until now...
...Meimi has never
stolen anything for herself.
But this time...
no, only this time...
...please protect
Meimi and Asuka Jr.
May the blessings of God
be with the two of them.
What's this?
It has something.
St. Tail...?
She's coming here soon, Mom.
Things are going as we planned.
I hypnotized the police
and sent them away.
No one will come to this
monastery and disturb us, Mom.
All right.
Everything is in order here.
Lucifer's daughter...
I want to see you suffering soon.
It's time to eat.
How long are you planning
to keep me locked up?
That's obvious!
Until Mom says so.
Don't worry about that. Here...
This is for you, isn't it?
A warning note?
Welcome to my house, St. Tail.
Asuka Jr. is here, isn't he?
Let him go!
You're a foolish girl.
Did you think...
...I would simply hand him over?
What a pretty picture.
This is a hallucination.
But I can't breathe.
Asuka Jr.
I have to find him!
How long is this hallway?
Keep running...
...until your heart bursts.
The end...
I can't find the end of the hallway!
Where is Asuka Jr.?
This thing delivered it.
She's a stupid thief.
She's deliberately come here
to be defeated by Mom.
"Tonight I'm going to
the monastery to get Asuka Jr.
-St. Tail"
Asuka Jr.?!
Give him back!
Give him back... Give him back...
How are you feeling?
Give him back!
Why don't you come with me?
It's a waste for your talent
to be stuck in such a small town.
That's how Maju joined me.
She isn't my real daughter.
Why don't you join us and grab
all of the treasure in the world?
You can get whatever you want.
Gold...
Jewels and art...
You can live in luxury.
I don't want it.
What is she talking about?
What I want is...
Give him back!
My jewel is...
So that boy is
your 100-carat diamond...
I guess you aren't very smart.
This is a hallucination.
It's not real.
Asuka Jr.!
One!
Two!
Three!
This warning note...
When did it come?
Warning note?
Are you stupid?
That's a love letter, isn't it?
Boys are so dumb!
Love letter?
The other notes until now...
All of them...
I want to get caught by you...
Don't play with me!
I am...
I am not a princess
locked up in a tower!
I won't stand by
without doing anything!
I'm going to get out of here!
Asuka Jr.! Where are you?!
Dear Lord...
Please protect them...
God...
...is telling me...!
Asuka Jr. is in that tower!
Butterfly powder is mixing
with my jade dust!
Ow! It's so loud!
Now's the time! Grab the keys!
No!
You idiot! There used to be
a bridge to the other tower!
But there's nothing there now!
Asuka Jr.!
One!
Two!
Three!
Now's not the time to save others!
My silk hat...!
I'm... sorry...
I'm sorry...
The truth is... I'm St. T...
God is...
...watching...
Surrender and go quietly.
I'm sorry I didn't notice.
Mom! Mom!
What about our revenge?!
It's all right.
If only I had met someone
like him 20 years ago...
What?!
If I had someone...
...who loved me no matter what...
Now let's go to the next town
and make some money, Maju!
Yes, Mom!
From that day...
...St. Tail disappeared
from Seika City.
After all, she had been caught.
And...
8 YEARS LATER
Thank you very much.
We were able to save
another lost sheep.
We owe it all to you.
Asuka Jr.
Oh, I shouldn't call you
Junior anymore.
You're a full-fledged
private investigator now.
- But I'm not used to it yet.
- Hey, you!
Asuka! Don't steal work
from the police!
He means to protect the peace
in Seika City, doesn't he?
Hey, let me get
the scoop next time!
Yes, that's right.
After all, St. Tail
protected this town.
St. Tail...
I wonder where she went...
Yeah...
She's in the chapel.
You parked illegally, didn't you?!
- What?
- Wait! Saruwatari!
Meimi!
The secret promise they had...
...will become
an eternal promise one day.
Yes, that day isn't far off.
THE END