I fell in love with someone
for the first time.
I met him when he was looking for my
grandma's wallet, not afraid to get his hands dirty.
I still remember his smile
when he finally found the wallet.
I will never forget him.
He was dressed
like a Buddhist monk.
I would like to meet him
again so much.
One more time.
Although connected to this world,
they do not belong to it.
Although connected to that world,
Anger, revenge, malice.
No matter what form evil takes,
they shall get rid of it in no time.
The guardian deities of the modern world:
the Pi-hyoro family!
The Guardian Deities of Our Time
The Pi-hyoro family!
You really can't stay
any longer, sensei?
It was my last funeral for today,
so I'll be on my way home.
Please don't be such a formalist.
If you stay, I'll make you dinner!
I'm afraid that when it comes to dinner, my sister
is already waiting for me at home with one.
Please stay.
Just a little longer, sensei.
Thank you for your
hospitality. Goodbye!
Ah, sensei…
What's with all those widows
that they're into monks so much?
An accident?
"A Maze of Snow"
Hōnenji Temple
Welcome home, dude.
By the way, do you already
have plans for Christmas?
You bet. I'm going with a friend from school
to the Christmas concert of Otometai.
And I think Kibatta-neechan
and Kyūta-niichan will go on dates.
Well, well. I didn't know
they had lovers.
I can understand Kyūta, but Kibatta-neesan?
Well, I guess she's in the right age.
So who is the chosen one?
Kariya-sensei.
You know, that guy
from Ruōgi Island.
Ah, Ikuhashi's doctor.
How about you, Kyōta-niichan?
Are you going on a date, too?
He has as much to do with dates
as chalk and cheese.
Have you ever seen him
to go on one?
But he is popular.
Really.
All the neighborhood women
have hots for him.
Well, but you know what I mean.
Our bro has never been with anyone.
He's just totally at odds with the girls.
Don't tease him like that,
Kyonta-niichan.
But it's all true.
Oh, Kyōta-niichan, I mean, as a manly dude,
you don't care about such stuff.
Ah, yes. I'm very sorry.
Gulp.
In the end I am at odds with the girls.
What do I know about love, right?
He took it seriously.
It's time for me.
I think I left the stove on.
Kyonta, that bonehead.
So what if I've never been on a date?
There are many other things
that excite me.
Something that excites me…
There is nothing like that!
Nakazato
Oh, it's you, Junko-san.
Have you come to pay respect to Shinobu?
When I saw you in that uniform,
I thought for a moment that it was Shinobu.
I am very sorry.
No, no, child.
I'm making a show of myself.
Please come in.
Introduce Kyōta-niichan to a girl?
What's with that?
Kyūta-niichan,
you know a lot of girls, right?
Even if I was to give each one of my limbs,
I couldn't satisfy everyone.
See? That's what
I'm talking about.
Our brother is a total loser
in that regard. Let's help him out!
Please.
It's a piece of cake for you!
I'm so sorry, Shinobu.
If I hadn't asked you to help me run this
stupid errand, you'd be still alive.
Junko.
Junko…
Shi… Shinobu?!
I want to meet him again.
I told you about him, remember?
The one I liked so much.
I'd so love to see him again.
To tell him how i feel.
Junko, we're best friends, right?
I don't think you'll be mad
if I borrow your body for a while?
Right, Junko?
Junko-san?
Junko-san,
is everything all right?
Junko-san?
I'm fine, ma'am.
Good. Please wait a moment,
I'll make us some tea.
Now I can go and meet him.
Kyōta-san.
Hey, Kyūta. Where are you
dragging me to, again?
Oh? Ah, yes.
How do I say it…
To a place where Christmas
starts a little earlier.
Hey, Kyūta!
You're here, my prince.
Hi, Kyū-chan!
I missed you!
Wait, Sayako.
– Oh, Kyūta-kun, I want one, too!
– You didn't forget about us?
And who is this boy?
Kyū-chan, is he your friend?
That's my brother, Kyōta-niichan.
Kyū-chan, that's your brother?!
– How handsome!
– Yeah, very much so.
Oh, something is
stuck to your hair.
I'll remove it for you.
Lean forward.
Thanks.
The first kiss belongs to me!
Victory!
That's not fair, Sayako!
Now, me!
What… what is going on?
What just happened?
That stupid girl…
She kissed him before my eyes.
She will regret it.
Wait up, boy!
Be nice!
Hey! Listen to me.
A m… murder!
You can still feel a tiny bit of aura.
Can this be…
Oh?
To Kyōta?
Not just that.
It's from a high school girl.
Holy moly!
It's a love letter, Kyōta-niichan!
Listen, Kyonta…
"I watched you all the time." See?
Our exorcist brother
finally got an admirer.
Give it to me.
That's her? Well, well.
Sister!
Show it, show it!
Hey, she's quite a looker!
What a cutie.
Continuing on…
"I would like to ask you something
and I hope you will agree.
If you have time in the evening of
December 24, maybe we could meet… "
Dude, she's totally
inviting you on a date!
On the night of Christmas Eve, on top of it.
You can't screw this up.
– Who said I was going?
– You have nothing to do anyway.
Apparently you've forgotten
that I got to help with the funerals.
Kyōta! Do you have any idea how much
courage it cost this girl to write this letter?
Isn't she cute?
Isn't she brave?
And you don't care
about any of that.
Go and have a little fun.
It'll be a good experience.
You've always been too serious.
It's a great chance for you to change it.
Right?
Awesome! Kyōta-niichan,
it's your first date!
I'll get it.
Hello?
Hey, how have you been?
We haven't talked
on the phone for ages.
What?
Sayako was murdered?
Shinobu.
My poor Shinobu.
Your anger was just.
But as long as Kyōta is alive,
more women will appear in his life.
I will kill them all.
I'll kill them, like I killed that girl.
There is a better method.
Kill Kyōta. Kill only him!
That way, he will
belong only to you.
Only to me?
Yes. No one else
will be able to have him.
By erasing him from this world,
you will protect him.
I shall kill him.
This necktie might be
a bit too flashy.
But it's your first date.
It's all right.
Thanks for your help, Kyūta.
After what happened to my friend,
somehow I don't feel
like going to parties anymore.
Was it one of those disco girls?
No.
Kyōta-niichan, this is your first date!
Don't think about anything else.
Yes. You look great.
Go get her, tiger!
How are things?
Is everything going well?
Yes sir. Our brother has already
come into contact with them.
Don't underestimate them. Although
they haven't regained their memories yet,
they are still incarnations
of the guardian deities.
I understand that perfectly. That is why
we must eliminate Kyōta before it happens.
Without him, their power
should drop significantly.
What a crowd!
I'm not surprised.
Otometai rock!
Let me give you the tickets
while there's still some space.
Oh gosh, instead of tickets,
I took Kyōta-niichan's love letter.
Only you could do it.
You'd mistake keys for an elephant.
By the way, my brother is around here
somewhere. It's his first date!
His first date?
He's a legendarily late bloomer.
It's kind of rare these days.
Do you wanna see his girlfriend?
Of course!
Here you go.
She's so pretty!
She has western beauty.
Her name is
Nakazato Shinobu-chan.
It's so relaxing when we sit here
and just talk quietly.
I think they call it "feeling
butterflies in the stomach".
Is everything okay on the island?
Yes. I told them
you said "hi".
And how are your brothers?
Annoying as always.
That means they're fine.
Uhm, Ryōko-san.
I think it may be a bit rude
to mention it so early,
but would you… uh…
Would you mind if you and I…
Would you like to date me knowing
that some day I'd like to get married?
What? That's Nakazato Shinobu?
You're kidding.
Why would I kid you?
Well, because Nakazato
Shinobu is sort of dead.
What?
She recently died
in a traffic accident.
Are you cold, Shinobu-chan?
Come again?
Ah, no, not at all.
I don't think it'll stop
snowing anytime soon.
I'm plenty happy just by
getting to meet you, Kyōta-san.
See, I thought that
you wouldn't come.
Is everything okay, Shinobu-chan?
I'm sorry.
I'm a terrible klutz.
I still can't believe
this is happening.
I feel like I'm dreaming.
Come on, let's get a bite to eat.
Hello? Ah, it's you, Kyonta.
What did you say!?
I'm sorry, Shinobu-chan.
I'm not very good at talking.
Aren't you bored with me?
Oh, knock it off. I'm the one
who keeps babbling all the time.
I wouldn't put it that way.
Besides, it's even better.
Thank you.
Kyōta-san!
What is it, Shinobu-chan?
Never mind.
I'm sorry to spring this on you, but
it's been on my mind since I saw you.
Kariya-sensei…
Uh…
Stampy!
Stamp…
I think one of my brothers
needs help. Excuse me.
Ryōko-san!
We'll talk about it again.
Slow down, Stampy!
I don't have wings!
Sister!
So you're suggesting that Nakazato Shinobu is
a ghost and she possessed her friend Junko.
We think so.
But somehow she managed to suppress her
aura and we were unable to locate her at all.
We also tried to sense where
Kyōta-niichan is, but to no avail.
Love is able to affect
the default aura.
But I don't think this girl's
ghost has such power.
Either way, we have to find Kyōta.
There's nobody around.
That's why we came here.
The pills should start
to work, Kyōta-san.
What's going on?
Are you getting hotter?
Can you feel your strength being drained?
What did you do?
Well done, Shinobu.
Now Kyōta is only yours.
Only mine?
Yes. Thus, you
fulfilled your goal.
I'd love to hear more
about these goals.
You drove a girl who was in love with my brother
to the point that she wanted to kill him.
You don't deserve anything.
It's over, demon!
You all are such fools. Your entire family.
What will you do without your beloved Kyōta?
What did you do to our brother?!
His soul is now wandering around,
on its way to the hereafter.
You're not just
any demon, are you?
Well done, Avalokita Ema.
I know that you are the chosen ones.
You know that name?
It means that…
I am one of five Ninshū
who were sealed long ago.
So you come from Chūkyō.
You are the last obstacle that
separates us from true freedom.
Open your eyes.
Open your eyes, deity.
Try to remember.
Remember who you are.
Remember the sword
that this hand held.
My… sword.
Yes. Exactly!
My sword! Aśarañtr.
The four of you are the future
incarnation of the guardian deities.
You are not a challenge for me.
Kyōta was the only one who could threaten me.
This is your end!
I wouldn't be so sure
about that, demon!
Who… Who is this?!
Although connected to this world,
we do not belong to it.
Although connected to that world,
Anger, revenge, malice.
No matter what form evil takes,
we shall get rid of it in no time.
That voice!
It's you?!
The guardian deities
of the modern world,
the Pi-hyoro family,
is ready for action!
Kyōta! You're still alive?
Go on, Shinobu.
Kill this worm!
This time do not mess it up.
Shinobu-chan, open your eyes.
He is deceiving you!
It's pointless. As long as I am here,
her soul cannot hear you.
I want to protect you.
I don't want to hurt you.
Shinobu-chan…
No.
From the moment I saw you
for the first time…
I've been thinking about you
over and over again.
Shinobu-chan.
No. I can't kill you.
I don't want to!
Do as I say, Shinobu!
No!
Shinobu-chan!
Run, Kyōta-san!
Stupid girl. That's what happens
to everyone who opposes me.
You bastard!
– Kyōta!
– Brother!
– Let's go.
– Yeah!
Damn it!
Haven't you had enough yet?
Lend me your energy, sword!
Aśarañtr!
How… Why?
How did you recover
your divine sword?
How?!
Kyōta-niichan!
Kyōta, you…
Their memories still haven't
fully returned, but…
He managed to recover his sword.
The rest is only a matter of time.
Yes. They managed to destroy one of Ninshū.
I don't feel the aura of the others.
They must've gotten the wind of his defeat
and ran away in fear of Pi-hyoro.
I am more than sure that they
will make their appearance soon.
I think Ema may not be
all that willing to help.
Excuse me?
Archbishop Galius?
I fear that a new battle
will break out soon.
I'm sorry, Ryōko-san.
I got held up by the patients.
I'm sorry.
Shinobu.
Junko-chan.
Hey. How are you?
I am Pi-hyoro Kyōta.
How did you like our show?
I am Shinohara Ryōko.
I'm a bit ashamed to break the fourth wall.
Howdy! I am Kyonta. I won't let
my brothers get too far ahead of me.
My name is Pi-hyoro Kyūta.
Thank you for your support.
We still have a lot to do, most of which
is about dealing with nasty demons.
The four of us will do our best.
Will you support us?