Brother… why?
I'm so jealous.
I'm so jealous…
I'm so jealous!
Although connected to this world,
they do not belong to it.
Although connected to that world,
Anger, revenge, malice.
No matter what form evil takes,
they shall get rid of it in no time.
The guardian deities of the modern world:
the Pi-hyoro family!
The Guardian Deities of Our Time
The Pi-hyoro family!
Kyōta, your part time job
brings us a lot of popularity.
Today, at the funeral ceremony,
the guests addressed me as "high priest".
Believe it or not, but back in the day
I even deserved that name.
Aren't you forgetting
something, Grandpa?
What are you reaching out
that hand for?
For my paycheck.
Ah yes, it completely
slipped my mind!
Guess what I got here!
A love letter to my handsome grandson.
Have you got no sense of humor, Kyōta?
It's the next order.
Order?
Yes. An old friend
of mine spoke to me.
He said that it is something that
only our Pi-hyoro family can handle.
Over the past year, four double suicides
have occurred on this island.
According to the old man,
our client, Mr. Ikuhashi Genpei,
is so wealthy that the people
literally worship him on this island.
And it was him
who invited us there?
Kyōta, I feel we've stumbled on
something noteworthy.
Right?
So do we take this order?
Of course we take it.
That's great. The next destination of the
Pi-hyoro family is the Ruōgi Island!
"Black Revenge"
So cool! Grandpa
has a nose for customers!
Sea and mountains as far as
the eye can see. Beautiful!
Awesome!
– Let's take a look!
– Yay!
Gosh, these goofs.
Strange… We were supposed to be picked up
by someone from the Ikuhashi estate.
The boat comes here only once a day,
so they couldn't mistake the hour.
Excuse me, are you from
the Hōnenji Temple?
Yes, we are.
You look amazingly young,
high priest Ryūnen.
"High priest Ryūnen"?
Are you suggesting
I'm that stinking…
For the love of Buddha,
where are your manners?
I apologize for the behavior
of my younger brother.
We are here on behalf of the high priest
and we will carry out the exorcisms.
Nice to meet you.
No, I apologize.
I am the personal doctor of
Mr. Ikuhashi Genpei. My name is Kariya.
And you, their doctor,
pick us up?
Please follow me to the car.
In fact, we're still waiting…
Kyōta, this car can fit
up to four people, anyway.
Is something wrong?
Ah, absolutely not.
We're getting in.
Ah, Kyōta-niichan!
Kibatta-neechan!
Wait for us!
We are not to tell anyone
that we are psychics? Why?
In fact, Mr. Genpei and I are the only
people who know about your visit.
What do you mean?
The grandson of the owner, Takahiko-kun,
hates any mentions of the supernatural.
I am very sorry.
That won't be a problem.
We don't mind.
I see that Mr. Ikuhashi trusts you,
his doctor, in many matters.
Actually, I am half his advisor.
By Buddha's loafers!
What a place.
A magnificent residence.
Who would have thought that this island
would hide such a beautiful mansion.
I heard that the Ikuhashi family built
their fortune in the arms industry.
This way please.
The arms industry, huh?
It won't be a simple job.
What was that nasty presence?
Did it come from the garden?
Or maybe from this property?
Thank you for coming
all the way here.
I am Ikuhashi Genpei.
I am Shinohara Ryōko, and this is
my younger brother, Kyōta.
Nice to meet you, sir.
I am pleased to meet the exorcists who
are recommended by Mr. Ryūnen himself.
Let us get to the point.
Please tell…
Grandpa?
Takahiko.
I heard noise.
We have guests?
Ah, these are my friend's grandchildren
who are visiting the island.
Meet my grandson, Takahiko.
How are you?
Takahiko, shouldn't you be
studying with your teacher now?
I fired him some time ago.
Excuse me?
This guy claimed that our island
is in the clutches of evil spirits.
He kept going on how these spirits
were to be behind these recent suicides.
I won't let anyone who talks
such nonsense teach me anything.
Anyway, I'm talking to our
guests now. Go to your room.
Grandpa…
Kyōta, kids like you.
Eh, you always push
everything on me.
Takahiko-kun, maybe you
could show me around?
Really?
I really can?
Yeah.
Awesome!
I'll show you everything.
Let's go!
Takahiko lost his parents early.
As a result, he grew very selfish.
I am sorry for the trouble.
Oh, please.
Takahiko, now!
Incredible, Kyōta-niisan!
Kiyohiko-niisan also liked to fish
and often went to this river.
Wait, you have a brother?
Yes. Unfortunately,
he died three years ago.
Everything on this island
changes beyond recognition,
but he had always
stayed the same.
Ready.
Awesome!
It's a real knife!
Do you always have it
with you, Kyōta-niisan?
A lighter and a knife
are a must for every man.
Holy cow!
Something happened?
Looks like he fell off the cliff.
And then what?
Bitten by a wild dog?
Terrible.
Oh, it's the Ikuhashi's boy.
Something horrible happened, lad.
Your private teacher…
I don't know. Maybe there was
some truth to his ghost stories.
Only a demon
could do such thing.
Get a grip.
Are you a man or not?
Kyōta-niichan!
Oh, it's you guys.
You got here faster than I thought.
Faster? Very funny.
How could you leave us
there like that?
Now, now.
Takahiko, these are my younger
brothers, Kyūta and Kyonta.
You should get along easily.
Younger brothers?
It was raining the day
you first arrived here as well.
Yes.
I still remember my disbelief when
you came and showed me the ashes.
My father was the only doctor on the island.
I wanted to redeem his guilt.
That's why I came to this island.
Your father was a great doctor,
like you are now, Kariya-sensei.
Ah, hell. Normally I am able
to sleep anywhere…
A child?
I can't move!
It's the same aura as before.
Takahiko?!
Serves you right.
What is it, psychic?
You can't move?
Takahiko has been possessed!
Kariya-sensei.
I am sorry to bother you at this hour, but
I would like to talk to you about something.
We will appreciate every hint.
Glad to hear it.
What happened?
I feel hostile presence.
It's in the room above us!
I will eliminate everyone
who threatens my presence.
Just like that stupid beak.
Stay away. Stay away!
Stay away!
Die, psychic.
Say hello to Buddha from me!
I have to summon…
Takahiko's guardian spirit!
Kiyohiko-niisan?
Takahiko!
Is it over now?
Kyōta-niisan, I made you a toast.
Thanks.
What is he buttering up for?
Would you like another coffee?
Sure. Thanks.
They seem to be have
become very close.
Who would have thought that such
an angel could be possessed by a demon.
Yes…
What did you want to
talk about last night?
Ah, nothing important.
I heard your father once
ran a clinic on this island.
It is true. Old times.
Time for a routine check-up.
I must excuse myself.
I don't understand
something here.
Why was it only the siblings
that committed these pseudo-suicides?
Why would the soul of an
innocent child hold such a grudge?
Mr. Genpei?
Are you all right?!
Please hold on!
I'll call a doctor in a moment!
I don't think that's
going to be necessary.
Who's there?
Kyōta-niichan?
Do you need something?
You look as if you got possessed.
Kyōta-niichan?!
What are you doing?!
Not good! Kyōta-niichan…
What's going on there?
Kyonta!
Kyūta-niichan!
Geez, put something on yourself!
He almost killed me.
Clothing is now least important.
What? Killed? But by who?
Kyōta-niichan.
You're kidding!
Listen, Kyonta.
We must join forces…
…and call Kibatta-neechan!
Kyōta! Or rather, the demon
who disturbs the peace of this island!
I came to get back the body of
my younger brother from you.
You stupid girl!
I think someone is
underestimating me here.
– Show him what Pi-hyoro can do!
– You can do it, Kibatta-neechan!
Don't play with me!
My brother is very strong.
You didn't choose your target very wisely.
Enough of this nonsense, demon.
Do you even have any idea
what you got yourselves into?
One more step and your sweet brother
will commit suicide right in front of your eyes.
Go ahead.
I'd love to see it.
Kibatta-neechan?!
Damn. Don't regret
those words later.
Kyōta-niichan!
You disgusting humans!
Who did he think he was?
Kyōta-niichan!
You must've been
worried about me.
But thanks to his possession,
I could freely browse through his memories.
– So you did it on purpose?
– And here I was, losing my mind.
I thought so.
It was very like you.
Tonight we will put an end to it.
I… I had a twin?
Yes. There is no doubt.
But… how is that possible?
There's more. It is his spirit
that plagues this island.
It was raining that night,
just like today.
My father was delivering you
and your twin.
It was a difficult delivery.
Your mother died right after she gave birth.
Soon after…
My father got possessed
by an evil spirit.
An evil spirit?
Yes. It was a ghost seeking revenge
on the Ikuhashi family.
My possessed father
strangled Takahiko's brother.
A moment later,
he regained consciousness.
Is that what you wanted
to tell me last night?
Yes.
When he came to his senses,
he couldn't believe the weight of his sin.
It wasn't your father's fault.
The responsibility lies
with the Ikuhashi family.
When I was young, I did a lot
of terrible things to create my wealth.
To achieve my goals,
I have ruined many lives.
It was the only way
to survive in post-war Japan.
In my youth, I was a very proud man
and never bothered to look back.
When Kariya-sensei came to
the island with the ashes,
when I heard about all this,
I finally realized.
This is a punishment
for my actions.
I lost my wife and my son,
and Kiyohiko soon joined them.
Now I have only Takahiko!
He's here again.
I almost had him.
I will not let these people
interfere with my revenge.
– Your haunting ends here!
– What?
Although connected to this world,
we do not belong to it.
Although connected to that world,
Anger, revenge, malice.
No matter what form evil takes,
we shall get rid of it in no time.
The guardian deities of the modern world,
the Pi-hyoro family is ready for action!
We've come to send
you to eternal rest.
Do you have any idea who
you're facing? I am a demon, fools!
Stop sinning any further.
Sinning?
I am but an embodiment
of Genpei's sins.
Try stopping me!
Take that!
Kyūta! Kyonta!
Kyōta, he may have a toddler's face,
but he's strong. Be careful.
Open your eyes, you moron! Who are you
actually trying to get revenge on?
What can you know?
Do you have any idea what it's like
to be killed without a chance to live?
How did I feel when I realized that it was
the fault of the Ikuhashi family?
And that's supposed to justify killing
your teacher and these innocent siblings?
Don't get close, Takahiko!
This baldie is not your brother.
I didn't know anything!
Since you're here, Takahiko,
I'll take you to hell with me.
Watch out!
Takahiko!
Ikuhashi-san!
Stop! Please spare him.
It's all my fault.
Takahiko did nothing wrong.
You want me!
What good will it do me
if you're dead?
No. I will rip everything
you love out of your life.
Takahiko!
Mr. Genpei!
You slimeball.
Please, stop it, little brother.
Takahiko…
I've envied you and Kiyohiko-niisan
so much for your happiness.
I knew nothing about it.
If I were in his place,
I'd probably do the same.
Takahiko…
This is the end.
Good that we have each other.
Yes. I hope Takahiko
will get better soon, too.
Don't worry.
He didn't look like a softie to me.
Right.
I took the liberty of checking
what you really can do.
I was not disappointed,
Avalokita Ema-sama.
How do you know this name?
This aura…
Are you from Chūkyō?
Is something wrong,
Kibatta-neechan?
No, it's nothing.
What is she doing here?
I showed up before Avalokita Ema-sama
and let her feel Chūkyō's aura, my lord.
Very good.
Five Ninshū will penetrate
their timeline any moment.
They will come after Pi-hyoro without a doubt.
I leave matters in your hands, Kyon.
Yes, my lord.
I am counting on you, Ema.
Next episode
Who would've thought?! It's Christmas Eve
and Kyōta is going on his first date.
We are so glad. He's about
to finally find his happiness.
However, it turns out to be
a nasty trap set for our family!
The trap was laid by the Five Ninshū who fled
from Chūkyō. Now we have to face them!
Next time on the Guardian Deities:
"A Maze of Snow".
If you miss it, exorcisms await you!