Chūkyō
Chūkyō.
A long forgotten
paradise on earth.
It lies between the world of the living
and the world of the dead.
It is here that the human soul wanders after
death for 49 days before going to the afterlife.
I report.
One of the long-sealed
elder demons got free.
There is no time to lose.
Archbishop Galius,
I am asking for orders.
I understand.
It seems that we must seek
the help of the guardian deities.
The guardian deities?
Very well. I will take care of
everything, Archbishop Galius.
Do not let me down, Kyon.
Although connected to this world,
they do not belong to it.
Although connected to that world,
Anger, revenge, malice.
No matter what form evil takes,
they shall get rid of it in no time.
The guardian deities of the modern world:
the Pi-hyoro family!
The Guardian Deities of Our Time
The Pi-hyoro family!
Hōnenji Temple
Hey, I brought you tea.
Oh, thank you, Mime.
Thanks, Mime-chan.
How's work?
Wow, so much money!
Not bad, huh, Mime?
How did you manage to
collect so much, Grandpa?
Our next order is just
a little bit bigger, that's all.
A million yen is a huge amount of money.
Who is our client this time?
A school headmaster, I think.
Money will always come in handy.
But that big of a sum
makes me a little nervous.
Come on, don't be so serious.
They should be getting to school by now.
We'll find out more very soon.
So you've already sent them
on a reconnaissance.
"A Visit from the Pi-hyoro Family!"
Private junior high school,
Seiwajō.
This is the place that the old man
told us to investigate this time.
Oh? It looks brand new.
Interesting.
Look over there, Kyūta.
I feel a strong cold aura
around the entire building.
This time we came across
something concrete.
Finally a demanding case,
right, Kyōta-niichan?
If I were you,
I wouldn't be so happy.
Okay.
We looked around as he wanted.
It's time to go.
Cool.
What is it?
Ah!
Kyōta-niichan, look!
She's wearing a Seiwajō uniform.
It looks like she wants to jump!
Hey, look what's behind her!
It's a demon.
She's haunted by a demon.
Just like we thought,
something is out there.
I didn't think that we'd come
across anything so soon.
I can't wait to see
what happens next.
Oh, right. I wanted to show
you something, Kyōta.
Hmm?
A school bus with children
goes off a cliff! There are fatalities
Do you remember the accident
from three months ago?
One week ago, the students of this school
got a massive food poisoning.
For years nothing was
happening at this school,
and lately their students have had
nothing but bad luck all the time.
Talk about nasty.
Even the most avid atheist would figure
that something was wrong.
I know, right?
Add to this the principal who is willing
to spend a million yen for an exorcism.
I knew there was something
behind this accident.
I'll go to that school
and learn more.
Kyonta?
No one is better suited for
a junior high school student.
Where am I?
I'm… still alive?
Yes. You are safe and sound.
Who are you?
Did you save me?
I'm not very good at swimming.
I am Pi-hyoro Kyūta.
Call me Kyūta.
I am Koga Maiko.
Everyone calls me Mai.
Mai-chan?
It'd be better if I died there.
I don't deserve to live.
I killed someone!
And she started crying, cuddling up to the
pillow like this. I didn't know what to do.
Women may be crazy about you, Kyūta,
but you don't know how to deal with them at all.
I just said that.
I don't know what she did there, but the part
about killing doesn't sound very good.
Doesn't matter.
Let Kyonta deal with the school.
Kyūta, the two of us will investigate the area
around the school tomorrow. Got that?
What kind of face is that?
But… I don't like doing this
and you know it.
We're going.
No complaining.
Exactly, Kyūta-niichan!
You're always doing great.
Yes. It's as if you were
born for this, Kyūta-kun.
– Shinohara-kun, you're so cute.
– Do you think we could be friends?
Hey, you said something interesting
when you introduced yourself.
That you're interested in ghosts
and the supernatural.
Library
Is it true?
You really like such stuff?
Well… yeah. Sort of.
Holy cow! I'm Shimomura.
I think we'll make good friends.
You have to join our club.
We protect people from evil spirits!
From evil spirits?
For now, uh, I'm the only member.
Let me get to the point. There's a nasty
shadow looming over our school.
Something has to be done about it,
or else soon no one will come here anymore.
Let's do our best, partner!
Shimomura? Are you still playing
this paranormal make-believe?
What do you want, Egashira?
I still remember how you yourself were
telling us ghost stories in this library.
I have grown up since.
There is no such thing as ghosts.
It's just a stupid superstition.
You'd better do something useful
while you're at school.
What's her problem?
It was Egashira Hisao. Our exemplary
student, although a total weirdo.
She used to like this stuff, too.
After her senpai died in the bus accident,
she changed completely.
Her senpai?
Some guy named Ōsaki Kōji-senpai,
a member of the tennis club.
He was going out with Mai-chan,
Egashira's best friend.
The four of us were friends and
we often talked about local ghost stories.
Dear residents, this is your
favorite waste paper servicemen.
We accept any waste paper,
from old newspapers to…
– Have you seen that guy in the store?
– I bet he can have any woman he wants.
Hey, girls! Look over there!
– What a hunk!
– So handsome.
Kyōta-niichan, I can't do this.
I'm going to go and die now.
Don't be so soft.
It's the fastest way to obtain information.
If you keep complaining,
I'll whack you in the head when we're done.
Okay, okay. I just have to stand here
and exchange the goods, right?
Dear ladies, we will exchange
your waste paper for new paper items.
We accept everything:
old newspapers—
Good morning, charming.
I have a whole box here.
Of course.
Please also take mine.
It sure is hot today, isn't it?
Kyōta-kun? Give these beautiful ladies
the best toilet paper we have.
Wow, he's sure into it.
Thank you.
Ah, don't mention it.
By the way, my ladies,
I heard that this school nearby, Seiwajō
or whatever, is cursed or something?
Do you think there is
some truth to it?
Ah, that's where the bus and
food poisoning accidents took place.
Yes, when I think of it,
I guess I've heard something similar.
Exactly. Grandma Nakajima
up on three should know more.
That old lady knows everything
that is happening in the area.
Oh? Grandma Nakajima, right?
Excuse me. Are you
Nakajima-san's grandmother?
Nakajima is me.
What do you want?
We were told that we could find you
in the park near the building no. 3.
Do you need anything from me?
We are brothers and study the history
of construction industry at Sakuraoka.
We have heard that you
know a lot about this area.
We would like to ask you about the land on
which the Seiwajō Junior High School was built.
I'll tell you, but it's a longer story.
Let's go to my place.
The land on which the school stands today
was once covered with thick forest.
In the past, it was a place of cremation
of the ones that fell in battles or catastrophes
or from contagious diseases, or finally those
who were executed for all kinds of offenses.
Over time, the place ceased
to serve as a crematorium.
The villagers, in fear for the anger of the dead,
eventually summoned many priests.
They conducted complex exorcisms
to calm down the lurking demons.
However, they met with something
well beyond their abilities.
The exorcism failed.
Despite the failure, the priests took measures
so that the demons could not harm the society,
and imprisoned them all
in a single place.
At least that's what I heard.
It must be one of those ghosts
that we have so many problems now!
Wait a second.
What do you want?
Personally, I have nothing
against you, buddy.
But someone complained to us
that you were a nuisance.
I'm afraid it'll hurt a little bit.
Physical education
Okay, that's enough.
What was that?
This aura…
They must be close.
Are you the one
who brought me here?
Yes. We hoped
for your cooperation.
Cooperation?
Regarding your recent transfer student.
We want you to give him to us.
If you do, we'll let you
become our follower.
Follower?
You barge in into my territory
and now you make demands?
So you refuse?
If you resist us now,
you'll regret it.
Get out of my territory now.
I took care of that boy long ago.
Get out. Understand?
You fool.
Kibatta-neechan, we learned everything
about the land this school stands on.
Good work. I'd love to hear
your findings over a cup of tea.
Stampy?
What does he want?
No idea. Maybe he wants
to tell us something.
Something happened to Kyonta?
We have to help him.
Yes. We're going to this school.
What happened here?
Doesn't matter.
I'd better get away from here.
Hop!
Piece of cake.
Wait, Hisao!
Listen to me!
We have nothing
to talk about, Mai.
Hisao!
Don't do this to me.
We can't leave it like this.
You know that if we don't do anything,
there will be only more victims.
If we don't do anything, the soul
of Ōsaki-senpai will never come to rest.
Senpai's soul?
I used to think that I should die
myself to pay for his death.
But now…
I still agree with that.
Excuse me?
You stole Ōsaki-senpai from under my nose.
It would be best if you died, too.
When I found out he had confessed to you
and you two started going out, I said:
"Congratulations, Mai.
I'm so happy for you!"
You replied, "thank you"
and laughed.
You never stopped to think
how it must've felt like to me.
I hate you. You were my best friend.
How could you do this to me?
I passed you at school every day,
hating you more and more.
You're are worth each other. He chose you by
your appearance alone. You both deserve to die!
It'll be better for everyone…
if you're dead!
Stop!
Egashira, what are you doing?
Stop! What are you doing?!
Stop right there!
It's you?!
You better not underestimate
Pi-hyoro Kyonta!
You brat!
Hey! Kyonta!
Kyonta?
Are you all right?
What are you doing here?
I think it's time for you
to tell us everything, Mai-chan.
Okay. It all started a week before that
accident with the bus three months ago.
Senpai!
Have you found the ball yet?
No. You?
Oh?
What's this?
Should we open it, senpai?
No. Let's leave it.
It may have something to do
with these ghost stories.
Listen, Mai-chan. Don't tell anyone
about what we've found here.
Senpai only aroused my
curiosity with these words.
It wasn't long until I told Hisao
and I went with her there again.
Then you opened the door,
breaking the seal that was upon them.
Please! Help us!
Calm down.
You can count on us.
Sister?
Have you seen the principal?
You won't believe what he said.
He told he didn't know us at all.
He doesn't remember at all
how he paid the one million yen.
This is ridiculous.
It was him who came to us and paid.
What's going on here?
I think I know.
Our client wasn't the principal,
but his daughter, Egashira Hisao…
I mean, before she got possessed.
How do you know this?
I questioned the thugs
Egashira had sent after me.
Apparently she also felt responsible
for breaking the seal.
So that's how it was…
Don't think you can get out
of here with life!
Damn. The other ghosts are already
pissed off. We'd better hurry up.
It's Mai-chan's voice!
Mai-chan, I'll help you
in a moment. Hold on!
I hate you.
I hate you, Maiko!
Mai-chan!
Let her go!
I won't let you do that!
In the name of all devas,
I command you to leave, demon!
I think I know where she escaped.
Such kids forced me
to retreat?! Unbelievable.
This is my land.
I won't give it to anyone!
It's time for these stupid humans
to learn what real pain is!
We can't let you do that.
Although connected to this world,
we do not belong to it.
Although connected to that world,
Anger, revenge, malice.
No matter what form evil takes,
we shall get rid of it in no time.
The guardian deities
of the modern world…
The Pi-hyoro family
is ready for action!
What a bunch of clowns.
Go, evil spirits of the rivers
and the mountains!
Dispose of our enemies!
You expect me die
from a few puny goblins?!
Kyōta, I'll take care of the small fry.
You get rid of the main demon!
Okay, sister!
You're not going anywhere!
Where are you going?
You ruined my robe!
I won't forgive that.
It's time to end it.
In the name of all devas,
I command you to leave, demon!
What's happening?
Why is it so cold?
Come back to where
you came from, demon!
Kyōta!
You got her, Kyōta-niichan.
I wonder if Egashira Hisao
and Mai-chan can reconcile.
I don't know. If they're
real friends, they'll be fine.
By the way, Kibatta-neechan. What happened
to that million yen? Did you give it back?
Of course I did. We couldn't accept it
under these circumstances.
So another job for free?
What matters is that
we have helped people.
You're forgetting something.
We did earn something, in the end.
Here! It's our paycheck from
the waste paper exchange service.
It may be not a lot,
but it's always something.
Congratulations.
Cool.
Let's buy some food!
A katsudon would be great.
Sweets for me.
I'm afraid it's already been decided
how we'll spend it. Right, Kyūta?
Ah, yeah!
Good evening, ma'am!
We bought a watermelon.
Let's eat together tonight.
Tasty as hell!
Kyonta, don't eat everything.
I think I won't bother them now.
Next episode
It's the end of the summer. On a distant
island, siblings commit double suicides.
We suspect that there's
more to it than it looks.
We go to the island
to investigate the details.
As we were afraid,
we come across a bad spirit.
I won't let evil act freely on my guard.
We'll show all demons their place!
Next time on the Guardian Deities:
"Black Revenge".
If you miss it, exorcisms await you!