Old Castle &  south wind subs
present Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Ma-a-da da yo! Ma-a-da da yo!
[Ready? Here I come!] Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta Yama Nezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta!
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na?
Where could the Green Forest be?
FABLES OF
THE GREEN FOREST
Dare ka ni dare ka ni kiitoite...
I keep asking everyone...
Hissori Matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne... Ano ne no ne,
You see... You see,
kin'iro medama no Fukurou ni
even the golden-eyed Owl
tachigiki saretemo shiranai yo!
won't hear you even if he tries!
Hissori Matsu tte doko darou na?
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dare ka ni dare ka ni kiitoite...
I keep asking everyone...
Spring Comes to the Green Forest
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
Hey, it's the South Wind!
It's Sister South Wind!
Hey, it's Sister South Wind!
Sister South Wind is here!
Hey, everybody, Sister South Wind!
Hey, Sister South Wind is here!
Look, Sister South Wind!
Chip! Chip!
Sister South Wind is here! Oh, I'm so happy!
Yeah! Sister South Wind is here!
Danny, get up!
Danny, come on!
Danny! Sister South Wind is here!
Sister South Wind is here!
Chatterer, Chatterer!
Hey, get up, Chatterer, Sister South Wind
is here! Get up, Chatterer!
Oh, it's still the middle of winter. Mm!
- Yeah, Sister South Wind is here!
- Spring is here!
- It's spring!
- Sister South Wind!
Hey, Granny, spring is finally here!
Well, aren't you glad?
Oh, that child!
Reddy Fox, dear.
Reddy,
close the door behind you.
Oh, what a child!
Ah, spring is here, at last!
Delicious looking goodies running about!
What a fish... big, what a fish...!
Hey, Bobby,
it's Sister South Wind, Bobby!
My fish,
where's my fish?
What's this about a fish?
Huh?
A fish?
Oh, Bobby, you're still half asleep!
Listen, it's Sister South Wind!
The South Wind?
Peter, spring is just around the corner!
Oh, boy, hey!
Spring!
It's spring!
It's spring, it's spring,
it's spring time in the Green Meadow!
It's spring time, spring time is here!
It's spring!
It's that mean old jay bird, Sammy!
No matter how mean they think I am,
it's still spring!
Yeah! Who cares?
I never asked you to like me.
I'm used to being disliked.
Peter!
And Bobby too!
Hey, hey!
Hey, tell me, where are you going?
Where are you going, anyway?
Come on, tell me, tell me!
Hey, come on, tell me, would you?
OK for you!
They're trying hide something
from me... why...
That's impossible!
I see you, I see you!
Heading for the Big River,
after crossing the Laughing Brook.
I know, to the Woodchuck's place!
Hey, Peter, Peter,
it's safe out there now, yeah.
B-But I-I'm r-really s...!
Yeah, Bowser and Reddy aren't out there.
We can go now, it's safe.
Gee, I'm afraid to cross the wheat field!
There's no place to hide out there!
Oh, Peter, don't you wanna learn the secret
of Papa Woodchuck, don't you, Peter?
Yeah, I'd like to know!
Peter, you're the one who started
talking about this, right?
Me... I'm such a want-to-know-it-all!
Why...
I... I just want to know everything!
So much that I can't help it.
B-But you know, it's a wonder
old man Woodchuck hasn't gotten up yet.
Yeah, that's probably part
of a little secret there, Peter.
A secret?
Secret?
Hey, let's go.
I just have to learn that secret!
IT'S REDDY THE FOX!
Hey, Peter!
Hey!
I wonder what the old man's secret is?
Father, do you suppose it's all right?
I think it might be better to go out later.
There you go again!
Can't wait any longer, Mother!
Keep on dilly-dallying,
and we'll miss the nest leaving event.
Now it's all right.
Come on out, everyone.
What?!
Here, here now. Don't go too far off.
That's it, that's it.
Now, get this, we're gonna learn
all about the forest,
there's mountains of things you must learn about now.
So...
...that's what the mistery's all about.
Hey-hey!
Listen up now. Which one of you can
tell me what this signal means, huh?
How about, Cook?
I know the answer, Papa.
That's a signal that an enemy is near by.
Right, good, how about this signal?
OK, Kiki?
It signal to run away.
Good.
Next.
Now, tell me, Rocky, what's this mean?
Rocky?
Rocky, where are you?
Where could that boy have gone to?
Rocky!
Here, here, I said stay here, Rocky...
What's so funny, Sammy?
But not to be able to follow such simple signals.
What's wrong with them?
It's none of your bussiness, you chatterbox!
What?! What did you say, woodchuck!
Why, you can't even teach
one little child. You big boy!
You impatient little meddler! See if I
speak to you anymore, you little runt!
Yeah, see if I ever talk to you again.
Remember that.
Peter, Peter, you know where Reddy Fox is?
I went to his den, but he wasn't there!
He's probably still sleeping,
not knowing spring has come.
But, Peter, I told you I was just there!
Ah, that's too bad, just when I had
some good news to tell him.
What's the good news, Sammy?
You wanna hear?
Yeah!
Tell me, tell me!
Ah...! You want to know?
Mm-hm.
Then I'll tell you.
This morning I went to old man woodchuck's
place and some cute little ones came out.
So, they have children!
Three of them.
R-Really?
Wow...! Let's go see!
Hey, let's go!
I bet they're cute!
However, that's not the news. There's gonna be
a duel between Papa Woodchuck and Reddy the Fox.
Come and watch.
It should be a lot of fun!
You mean... you're going to tell Reddy the Fox?
Ah, my heart's beating faster,
I can hardly wait!
Sammy!
Sammy, wait, wait!
What's the matter, Peter?
You don't look so good.
Spring is here.
Don't you want to play in the Green Meadow...
...or... are you afraid of me
and don't want to come out?
There isn't a slow bug anywhere
who can get caught by you!
Go home and go to bed, Reddy!
Well, let me tell you. I'm going
to old man woodchuck's house, right now.
I'm gonna try to catch him.
Not to mention three little woodchucks.
I heard it all.
Can't wait for them little woodchucks.
Hmm, spring certainly has come!
Oh, what should I do, what should I do,
what should I do?!
Listen to me.
Stand on only two feet, like this.
Remember you kids, never
get too close to him!
Uh-uh!
That's...
That's Bowser, the dog. Behind Bowser
there's always a man accompanying him.
Can't stay still, huh,
'coz it's spring out there.
I'll unleash you, but don't pick
on the weak animals of the forest.
See?
Now kids, come along.
Understand?
Yeah!
Let's try it one time...
Let's go!
Hey!
- Hey, hey, that's not fair! That's my hole!
- I got here first!
- It's mine!
- Hey, get out of the way!
Hey, get out of the way!
I'm going in first!
- I was here first!
- I am, I am, get out of the way!
- Oh, no, get out of there!
- Come on, Rocky, out of the way now, let me in there!
No, no, get out of there!
You guys, good thing this was only practice.
If Reddy Fox or Bowser were really here,
you'd be caught... yeah, all three of you!
OK, kids, now listen closely.
Now, let's take it again from the beginning.
What will I do, what will I do?
What will I do? I'd like to go warn them,
but with Reddy the Fox around!
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know!
Oh, what a mess! What a mess!
Oh, what a mess!
There he is, there he is!
That Reddy Fox is something,
he found out somehow.
Wrong, wrong! Did you forget already?
That signal means to stop, right?
Now, now, now, the fun is just beginning!
To think they're trying to scare me!
Not yet, not yet.
Be still now.
That's it. That's it.
Be patient. Be patient...
Don't move,
or you'll be caught, right away!
Hey, Reddy!
Reddy Fox, Reddy Fox!
That guy made a real fool of me today,
get him good for me, get him good for me!
That's right, Reddy, get the old man for me,
get the old man!
But... leave the kids alone, OK, Reddy?
Reddy Fox, Reddy Fox,
Bowser is close by!
Reddy, be careful!
It's the truth, it's the truth, Reddy!
IT'S REDDY! IT'S REDDY! IT'S REDDY!
Come on, run,
everybody hide, quickly!
Hide!
How wonderful, how wonderful!
Mama, we sure were scared!
Oh, Mama!
Thanks, Mama!
Gosh, thank you, Peter.
Rocky's life was saved thanks to you.
I-It was sheer luck!
Now that Reddy and Sammy know about our children,
we can't keep the secret any longer.
There's always much danger.
Bowser... Bowser!
Bowser, come on!
Come on home now!
That Sammy! Why did he have
to warn them in the last minute?
The three children must soon leave their nest.
To leave ones nest means
to part from father and mother,
and try to make it on their own.
Until such a time, father and mother
will teach their children
as much wisdom as possible, for them to live.
Nani ga aru no kana kono mori no oku ni?
What takes place inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana ano sora no mukō ni?
What takes place up in that sky?
Tashikametai kimi to futari de
I want to find out together with you
Porī!
Polly!
Tashikametai anata to futari de
I want to find out together with you
Rokkī!
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai, harahara shitai,
I want my heart to beat fast, I want thrills,
wakuwaku shitai... Mesomeso!
I want excitement... But, it ends in tears!
Dake wa gomen dayo!
Please forgive me!
Nani ga aru no kana asu ame no naka de?
Tomorrow, what takes place in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana asu niji no mukō de?
Tomorrow, what takes place beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica and Lordwen (initial subs
ep 06, 09, 14, 15, 31, 35, 40) & Gango (songs)