FABLES OF THE GREEN FOREST
02. Johnny grows up
Ready?
I found you, Kiki!
What?
How did you know, Cook?
It's time to find Johnny, now!
If it's Johnny, he's quit already!
- Uh?
- Yes, he's gone off, daydreaming again!
What? Again?
He's been gazing far off like that,
all day!
Oh, I'd sure like to go!
How happy I could be to run
around in the forest all day!
You never could go to a forest like that!
I will go, I will!
You'll see, I'll go!
There's something wonderful
awaiting for me far away!
I've got to find adventure, adventure!
Don't mama and papa say not to wander
out off the forest, Johnny?
That's right! They won't let you in the house
and they won't feed you anymore!
I don't care, I can find food myself!
And as for a house, I can build one!
I don't think so, Johnny, you've always been
a fumbler, isn't that right, Kiki?
What's so funny, you!
Why, you!
Oh, look out, look out!
Take care! Don't hurt us, Johnny!
Come on, don't take it out
on us, Johnny! No, no!
Chiiil-dreeen,
don't fight!
It's Sister Breeze!
- Sister Breeze?
The time has come for you to leave your nest.
Leave the nest?
By that I mean for you to leave your parents,
shift for yourselves and grow.
Now look at this big open field...
...how wonderful to run and jump
in that wide world!
I'm-I'm scared!
Papa and mama will scold us if we go there!
Now, don't keep relying on your parents!
Resolve to stand on your own two feet,
show your courage!
xxx
- Johnny, don't go!
- Papa will scold you!
Don't blame us!
I'm...
I'm scared!
Now, be brave and walk!
He's really going!
- Hey, what shoud we do, Cook?
- I don't know, Kiki, I really don't!
Mmm, so much clover, I love!
Whaat?! Johnny left the forest?
We desperately tried to stop him,
didn't we, Kiki? Huh?
Right!
Dear, after Johnny, hurry!
Yeah... Hmm...
Dear, why are you so unconcerned?
Johnny has left the forest all by himself!
What will you do if a fox
or a hawk gets him?
Mama, calm yourself.
The time has come for Johnny to leave the nest.
Johnny?
You and I had our time when we left our nest.
Just like Johnny is gonna do now.
But...
...the child can't do anything,
it's too soon!
Mama, from now on Johnny is gonna learn
by experiencing and thinking on his own!
Jooohnny!
Let's meet again!
Let's meet agaaain!
Sure I've come far!
Well, off for home.
Oh, here I thought it was a baby,
but he has sharp teeth and it's smart!
Since I'm not hunting for food
maybe I'd better retreat for now!
Bye-bye, little woodchuck!
Hey, what do you mean, "little woodchuck",
I'm a grown-up!
xxx
Aha!
I finally returned home!
- I'm home!
- Welcome back, Johnny!
Here, hurry and eat or it will get cold!
Uh... excuse me for... being late.
Well, Johnny... so you went to see
the outside of the forest today?
Papa isn't angry.
How was it outside of the forest?
Oh, papa, outside the forest
is so wide, so large!
There was fish swiming
and lots of animals and clovers!
I decided to go live in a forest that's...
bigger... larger!
Oh? Where are you going to live?
I'll find a good place in the Green Forest.
Oh, the Green Forest, is it?
Papa and mama, why don't you scold Johnny?
Yeah... well, the time will come
when you, kids, will understand.
I'm definitely going to that forest,
I'm gonna jump around to my heart's content!
Cook, Kiki, Johnny, now, now,
how long are you going to sleep?
The sun is already up, now get up!
- Oh, mama, oh!
- Let me sleep more!
Now, now, what am I going
to do with such children? Oh!
- Cook, Kiki, where is Johnny?
- I don't know!
Me either!
What happened so early this morning?!
Oooh!
Papa!
Oh, papa's gone too!
Sure is funny!
Johnny!
Papa!
Jooohnnyyy!
Papaaa!
Papa...!
Papa, where is Johnny?
Mama, Johnny has gone
and left home.
Whaaat?!
There's no need to worry, Mother.
Johnny is a grown-up and he can live
and survive well in the forest.
Oh! Johnny...!
Little bird, this morning I'm going far away
to the Green Forest to live! Bye bye!
- Well, I guess he's gone!
- Johnny...!
Johnny...!
Huh?
It's mama's voice!
Mama! Papa!
Forgive me, papa... mama.
Goodbye! Goodbye!
Goodbye!
Goodbye...!
Hi there!
Uh... uh...
Good day!
You're a woodchuck, like me.
Aren't you, huh?
Where did you come from?
Where are you going?
Huh? Wow, sure is fast!
Wonder what that is!
Well, well, well!
You, I've met you before!
Yeah, I'm Johnny Chuck!
Is that so? You must be the child
of old man woodchuck. And where are you off to?
I'm going to the Green Forest!
The Green Forest?
By yourself?
Oh, no, stay! But... but I still think
you should return home!
Oh, help me!
Give them back!
Give me back my clovers, please!
Don't bother me, I'm hungry!
Wait!
You?
What are you?
Return those clovers, you!
Huh, pretty brave for a little one!
Well, don't think too badly of me.
Well, I'd better go.
Oh, wait!
Stop it, come on, stop it, Johnny!
Oh!
Oh, I give up anyway...
Darn you, you pest!
Uh-hu, I got to see!
Oh, go, go, go! Yeah!
How's that you've had enough, you shrimp?
Had enough?
Who's giving up?
This could go on forever!
Let's go!
Shall we go too?
Here I come!
No, wait!
I give up...
Pretty tough shrimp, huh?
Say you...
...the day is almost over
and the Green Forest is still far-far away...
You better go home, right?
I'm going, of course!
Well... alright.
I'm going home. Bye!
It's still better for you to return home!
Papa...
Mama...
xxx
OK! Who's giving up?
I'm off for the Green Forest!
Let's see, he says that Johnny the woodchuck
is not yet appeared
and he's getting tired of keeping
a lookout so he's going to go home.
Why, was it too much to ask that woodchuck?
No use all of us waiting here.
Let's go!
What's there?
Hey, isn't this the guy I met yesterday?
Mister, hey mister!
Oooh!
Oh, the shrimp from yesterday!
Have a heart,
I'm finished fighting with you!
Oh, that's not it!
I mean, if you slept here,
the fox or a hawk might get you!
And please excuse me for yesterday!
Hey, I have an idea!
I'm going to the Green Forest!
Hey, mister, why don't you come along with me?
It looks so big, there we could find
enough food for both of us!
Mister, will you come?
What's the matter mister?
Yeah, Johnny, the Green Forest
is a wonderful place!
Everyone wants to live there, that's why
all kinds of people are mingled there,
likeable people and not so likeable people!
Fearful enemies and dangers are found there
but all are striving and living,
living cheerfully, pleasantly,
all bad things are soon forgotten.
That's how wonderful it is to be alive!
Yeah, that's right, it's the truth.
But, shrimp, that is a place
for young people like you to live.
Yesterday I lost to you.
I lost to your youth.
Me, I'll return to the pasture to live.
xxx
Subtitle: South Wind Subs