FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Johnny build his home"
Oh, my goodness, I can't oversleep this morning!
I've got to build a house!
My house!
My happy home in the Green Forest!
Hmm, now let's see,
where should I build my new house?!
Food's got to be fairly available
near by at all time!
Hmm, a place with lots of clover that I love!
Under an apple tree would be ideal!
A tree that will bear a lot of fruit in autumn!
That's the kind of tree to find!
It's got to be a place where one can nap in the sun
in front of the house! That'd be great!
Is such a... place easily found?
Huh? I just love to be able to sunbathe
in a nice sunny spot in front of the house!
Good!
Hmm, I'm going to check throughout
this entire forest and find such a place!
Ah, well, good for you!
Why, ah!
Ah! Well, this is it!
Lots of clover on this clearing!
I'll give it my best!
- Heey!
- What?!
Huh? So you're homeless, huh?
OK, well, go on, go on now, you better not
interrupt my nap again, do you hear?
Hmm...
Boy, I better build a home of my own!
Maybe I could try to widen the hole in this tree!
Hey, hey, hey, can't you tell
someone else's house from your own?
Oh, is this your house?
I'm Green the Snake
and you have no business around here, you know?
Oh, my name is uh... uh...
Uh, this is my territory, now you get out of here,
you hear?
Oh, I understand, I'll go find another spot!
Huh, serves him right!
Hey, you're Polly, aren't you?
The one I met the other day?
What?! Where?!
Hey!
Hey, Polly!
Can't catch me!
Polly!
- Yoo-hoo!
- I found you!
Hey, hey, Polly, wait!
Found you!
I'm sorry, Polly!
Oh, well, you're such a disappointment!
What?!
Oh, you, apologizing to that snake Green!
You... you saw that?
Well, that was a...
Oh, I don't think I want to know you!
Hmm!
Oh, hi there!
Is everything going OK, huh, Johnny?
Tell me, have you finished building
your house yet?
That's no good, playing around.
Why, let me tell you...
Johnny!
Johnny, please don't listen
to what Sammy's telling you!
What? What's that voice?
Who-who-who-who do you thi-thi-think you are trying
to tell Johnny not to listen to-to me-me-me! I'm gonna...
Johnny!
Come here!
Sammy is disliked in the forest,
so don't pay any attention to him!
You, you, what?!
Polly, I'm going to get...
I'm mad now, boy you gonna...!
Heey!
Hey, you...!
Aww!
- Oh, I'm sorry!
- Come on, Johnny, let's go, come on!
Sorry, Sammy!
Oh, oh, hey, hey, hey, now!
What a beautiful,
What a...
Oh... what... a beautiful... day...
Well, I sing pretty good, don't I...?
It's the woodchuck's children!
Oh boy!
Oh, gosh, it's Reddy!
What, it's Reddy?
Oh, darn it...!
Hi, Reddy!
Wow, what's up, Reddy?
Ah, look at Reddy spotting Johnny and Polly,
the woodchucks! Now, what a relief!
Look safe!
This tree is pretty soft
and no rear exit either!
Only one thing to do!
Almost tore my nose off!
You were so brave!
And you were such a little scaredy cat, Polly!
That's a lie, Johnny, I was not such thing!
You saved us, Johnny!
Oh, Johnny!
Oh, Polly!
Reddy is standing watch outside.
What are we going to do, beat him up?
You, Johnny, you could beat him up,
couldn't you, Johnny?
Polly! Come outside!
After all, you shouldn't be in an empty house
on a nice day like this! Come on out!
What is he saying?
Gee, Polly you sure are lucky!
To be friends with a guy like Johnny!
I really...
...never thought he'd be so tough!
Well...
Uh, say, Johnny, why can't we be friends?
I really think it will work...
Does he mean it?
Naturally, it's a big lie!
Honestly, Johnny, I respect you
from the bottom of my heart!
Well...
- Johnny, he says that he respects you!
- It's a lie!
Oh, boy, it hurts!
It hurts, I'm dying!
I'm dying!
Oh, it hurts, it hurts!
Oh, ah, it hurts!
I'm dying, I'm dying!
- Is it true?
- He's lying!
Should I go out and check?
You bit him twice, Johnny!
Even if he isn't dead,
there's nothing to be afraid of!
No-no-no, you just stay there and be quiet!
But I'm getting hungry!
Oh, ah, it H-U-R-T-S!
Hurts!
I'm dying, I'm dying!
All right, Polly, all right!
Oh, boy, Polly is curious after all,
she's come out!
Oh, it hurts, it hurts, help me, help me!
Aww! Aww!
Come a little closer!
Oh, I'm dying!
Help!
Gosh, I was worried so I came to check,
but everything's all dug up!
I wonder what happened to everyone!
- Hey, hey!
- Huh?
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
When Sammy the Jay cries out in that shrill voice,
you can bet there's danger near.
But Peter has a very bad habit.
He always wants to know where the danger is.
Should Peter be so curious?
Oh, help me, please...
It hurts, it hurts, hurts, hurts...
Polly, Reddy's pretending,
don't get too close, don't get too close!
Watch out, Polly, don't get too close!
It isn't so, I really can't move at all!
It's a lie, it's a lie
it's a lie, it's a lie!
It is the truth I tell you,
big mouth! Oh...
I'm gonna get you!
- Johnny!
- Huh?
Help me, Johnny!
Why you, take this!
Johnny!
Hey!
I got it!
I wonder who's the one that did this!
Oh, we're out!
That Reddy has gone, hasn't he, Johnny?
What's the matter, Johnny?
I can't be doing such things,
I've got to build a house!
Really have to watch for trouble
with guys like Reddy being around!
If I were to build a house...
...I'd want it to be far away from Reddy, where
I'd be safe, and I think I know the right place!
What?
Where is it?
Want to go see it?
Yeah, let's go!
- Hey, Johnny, isn't this a wonderful place?
- Mmm... uh-huh, Polly, it's great!
Hey, I'll build my house right beneath this tree!
Reddy, as we know, is quite proud.
If he knew that someone
had seen him in this condition...
...Reddy would really be embarrassed!
Who they're laughing at?
You know I'm Reddy?
You know I move on!
Stop your laughing!
In days of snow, rain, even storm...
...I'm going to build a house
that I can live happily in.
Peter!
That looks like a good house
you're building, Johnny!
Yeah, that' right!
This is it!
- Bobby, remember that little Johnny?
- Huh?
Yeah, from Papa Woodchuck's place!
How do you like that?
Hey, hey everybody, listen!
This is my new house and it's almost completed!
It will be ready real soon, real soon,
and when it is,
I'll invite you all over!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs