FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Huge tracks in the forest"
Hey, Polly, look at the pretty flowers I found!
- These are just perfect for you, so pretty!
- Oh, those...
Oh...
Oh... that's right, I remembered a spot
where the prettiest flowers are!
Oh, how pretty!
Mmm... Polly will be happy with these!
Better hurry home now!
Oh, my gosh! What was that noise?
Mmm what is this?
There's nothing there!
Oh, it's just my imagination!
Wow, a bigger footprint than this tree, you say?
Boy, yeah, it must be a big one, wow!
Honest, I really did!
I saw it with my own eyes!
- Then it's a ghost there?
- Uh-huh.
OK, then, come with me!
Surely that monster must still be around!
Oh... uh... wait here, Johnny.
Now, follow me!
- Oh...!
Uh... There's nothing around here, is there?
Uh... Uh... It ran off
after hearing Johnny's loud voice, Peter.
Aha...! Everyone come here!
Look at this, it looks like a giant footprint!
What a footprint!
Wow! Couldn't be an animal that big!
Well, I can see
that you still really don't believe me!
Oh, everyone, come and look at this tree,
look at that!
- Wow, look at that!
- Wow!
What, it looks like something left
from the scratch of a claw, what do you think?
Oh, look at that!
- Oh, wow, who could've done this?!
- Oh...
- Hey, look at that!
It continues on into the forest!
Oh, look at those!
Oh-oh! Looks like those tracks
go to my storehouse!
Oh, we better go help Chatterer!
Oh...! Oh!
- Chatterer!
- Oh, I better wait here!
Darn, darn, darn!
Who destroyed my storehouse? Oh, no!
The footprints!
It must be the monster, it must be!
It's all gone, all my hard work,
where I stored my berries and everything!
Oh, no, no, it's gone, oh, no!
Oh, no, this is terrible,
what am I going to do?
- This is awful!
- What's the uproar about?
No...
Oh, Uncle Billy, have you seen
a monster with great big feet?
Monster?
No, I didn't.
I met lot of folks on the way over here
but nobody mentioned anything about it.
Look at this, Uncle Billy,
this is the footprint that the monster made.
Oh... this is it?
That's funny, as far as I know, there aren't
any monsters in this area with such big feet!
This must be someone playing a trick.
Well, so long...!
- Hey, wait up, dad!
- Oh, my, excuse me!
Well, so long!
You hear that? There can't be such an animal
in the forest to leave such big tracks!
- Yeah, somebody playing a trick!
- That's right, because Uncle Billy said so!
I know, somebody stole my food and made it look like
the work of a big footed devil, darn, darn!
Then the culprit is...
...the one who claims to have seen
the nonexistent monster.
What? Are you saying
that the one who made the tracks,
fell the tree and stole Chatterer's food was me?
That-that's not...
Chatterer! Chatterer, surely you don't have
any doubts about me?
Oh...!
You've-you've got to believe me!
There really is a bigfooted monster! Really!
But... You've got to believe me!
Don't be silly!
Johnny couldn't do such a thing!
To doubt Johnny is cruel!
You can't fool us with tears!
Get out of this forest, thief...!
Johnny...! Cheer up!
But that's cruel to call me a thief...!
Oh!
- Hey, Joe, good morning!
- Huh?
Hey, have you seen a monster
with feet as big as this?
No. Hmm...
Grandfather! Grandfather Frog!
Say, you haven't seen
a big footed monster, have you?
Spotty!
Hey...! Danny, Chip!
Say, tell me, you two haven't seen a...
big monster around here?
- Uh...
- Mm...
Uh...
Uh, let's go home, Polly,
there's no one who will even believe us.
Oh, it's too early to give up...!
- Oh?
- Oh...
Finally Johnny has to leave this forest!
Well, I guess I'll just have to leave...!
Johnny, wait...!
You really saw the monster, didn't you?
You really didn't steal anything, did you?
Now Johnny, just listen to me!
Aren't you going to try
and find the real thief, huh?
Oh, Polly!
- Johnny...! Just the two of us could search...!
- Oh...!
Ah...!
OK, I'm not giving up!
- And I'll never think about leaving this forest again!
- Oh, goodie!
- Alright! Let's go find that monster!
- Yes...!
So now, Johnny and Polly
set out to search for the monster.
Polly! Polly...!
Hey...! Polly...!
Hey...!
Where did she stray off to?
Polly!
Ah...!
What are you doing there, Polly...?
I fell in the Laughing Brook...
How did it happen, Polly?
Oh, it happened when we crossed the river!
Your face!
Sorry!
My clothes are messy
and all you do is laugh...!
Uhm... sorry, Polly...
but I really didn't mean it!
Well, well, so here you are!
Well, Johnny, what happened
to your monster search?
My, my, Polly, how dirty your face is!
You keep trying so hard, but you'll never find it,
why don't you just give up?
- Oh, be quiet!
- Now, now!
The likes of you can never
understand Johnny's feelings!
He'd never do such a thing like this!
- You see, Sammy?
- Stubborn Polly!
No matter how you try,
what doesn't exist, doesn't exist!
It's a man, it's a man with a gun...!
- What happened?
- It's a bear!
It couldn't be!
Mm, yes, I saw it, over there
by the shadow of that tree!
Must be seeing things, there hasn't been
a bear born in this forest for a long time!
That's so...!
We'd better call it a day soon!
We should be out of the forest by sundown,
you know!
Could there really be a monster, Johnny?
- Mmm... Oh...
- Hey, Bobby!
So tired... I ain't get any sleep last night.
Oh... tired...
Oh... Peter, I'm so tired...
Bobby...!
Hey...
Hey, Bobby!
Uh... Peter, don't block my way!
I wanna get home and go to sleep!
I'm so tired, Peter!
So, you were up playing around
all night again, huh?
Hey...
You haven't seen Johnny, have you?
- Uh, I haven't seen him, Peter. Uh...
- I wonder what he's doing...
Hear this, hear this, hear this!
- Uh...?
- Uh?
Hear this, hear this, hear this!
- It's some news!
- Oh...!
Something's happened!
Peter, I'm going home to sleep, I'm so tired!
Sammy, did... did something happen?
Ah, Peter Rabbit, I was just looking for you.
Why, Johnny and Polly are in big trouble!
Oh...!
They're all muddy from falling in the river
and Polly is crying!
And to top it all off, there's a man...!
- A-a man...?!
- Man...?!
With a gun...!
- Oh... were they... hit?
- Were they hit?
Gosh, I-I don't know. I got so wound up, I didn't
even see what happened after that...!
Sammy, where did it happen...?
Are you going there...?
Yeah, Sammy, where did it happen?
Up stream, by the Laughing Brook!
That said, Peter, why don't you
just let him be!
- That's alright, Polly, I'll search by myself!
- No, no, I said I would help!
And I will help you!
But...
- Uh...!
- Oh...!
- Ah...!
- Hmm...
- Oh...!
- Oh!
- Hmm...
- Oh...! Oh...!
- Mmm...
A-a-ah...!
Wha-wha-what was that, just now?
- Boy, am I hungry!
- Huh...?
I sure am hungry!
- Oh...!
- Uh!
- Oh!
- Boy, I sure came a long way here!
I've been traveling a long time...!
I sure could use a full meal!
- J-J-Johnny!
- Peter...!
Did you hear the growling...?
What was that?
Oh...!
- Uh!
- Oh!
I sure would like a hearty meal of anything!
He must be hungry!
Having come from far away,
this bear unfamiliar with the Green Forest,
could not find enough food to eat,
and consequently, was very hungry.
The bear went further and further
into the forest,
until he finally reached the other side.
Mr. Brown's farm could be seen...
where his son, Tom is loading strawberries.
What's going on?
I'm Buster-Buster the Bear...!
Hey, everybody, it's me!
It's Buster, yeah!
The monster that everybody was afraid of
turned out to be Buster the Bear,
and he became friends with
everybody in the Green Forest!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs