FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"The monster of Poplar Hill"
No one is smarter than me,
No one is better than me,
No one is smarter than me!
Hello, Prickly!
How are you today, my friend?
What's wrong? You don't wanna talk to me?
Maybe you're deaf?
He's probably really deaf. He doesn't hear
anything and his mouth can't talk.
If so, then it's not a problem
if we talk bad of him. Because he doesn't listen.
I'll tell everything to the other animals.
I'm really gonna tell everyone in the forest.
Attention, everyone in the Green Forest:
Prickly is deaf!
But is it true? Maybe he's trying to trick me?
Liar, liar, liar!
Oh!
Aha, I see you're also a coward!
It doesn't matter if you raise your needles,
because you can't catch me!
I'm here.
Come on. I'm here!
You can't catch me! You can't catch me!
Goodbye, Prickly!
We'll play again another day!
Johnny, where are you going?
I'm going to see Polly.
She's waiting for me at Poplar Hill.
I feel so happy, such a beautiful day!
Hello, Johnny!
- Hi, Peter!
- You seem really happy today.
You're going to see Polly?
Yes. She's waiting for me.
Hey, Johnny, tell me...
Do you know a porcupine named Prickly?
I was told he came to live here.
He comes from a place with lots of hills, right?
Yes, from Canada.
I think they call him
"the Storm of Canada".
What's wrong? What do you have in your mouth?
- Oh!
- What are we going to do?
I'll help you!
We did it!
What an ungrateful guy!
He didn't even thank us
for helping him get rid of the bark.
This made me hungry. I'm going to eat.
How delicious! It's been a long time
since I ate something this good.
I forgot! I have to go see Polly!
Oh...!
Hello, Polly.
I'm sorry. Forgive me for being late.
The truth is that you don't care about me.
It was because Prickly was in trouble.
- I've been waiting for you for a really long time.
- Help!!!
- I-I-It's chasing me.
- What?
- There's nothing chasing you.
- Really?
What has happened, Peter?
I w-was calmly e-eating
when suddenly a-appeared...
What is that?
Huh?
Help! Help me!
Really?
Yes, it's true, Polly.
But if it doesn't have feet,
how can it run?
Well...
For example...
The Green Snake can run very fast
and doesn't have feet.
He's right, Johnny. Good point.
I wonder if that monster is still there.
Let's go see!
What?
- Huh?
- Huh...?!
How strange...
He was running here.
Now I don't understand it.
I've been living here for a long time now
and I never saw a monster like that.
But it's true, it's true, I saw it.
Come on, Johnny, please, tell him.
Of course, you always tell the truth, Peter.
Grandfather Frog, I went to the place
he told me, but it wasn't there.
It's the first time that there's something
in the forest that I don't know about...
Everyday I fly through the sky and there's
nothing that can escape my sharp eye.
I can't believe that there's
such a weird creature in the forest.
But if you say so, it must be true.
It's possible... But maybe you were
nervous and exaggerated a little.
Right now we need to make certain that
such a creature exists in the Green Forest,
although I'm sure I never saw anything
so weird in all my life.
Help me! I saw it! I saw it!
- Eh?
- Hm?
- Hmm...?
Peter! I saw it! It's exactly as you say.
Oh, I'm so scared! Really scared, Peter!
It's really incredible.
It's a monster without a head and feet.
It was running like crazy,
and I was almost petrified with fear!
My, my, my! I never saw such cowards.
I'm sure I would approach it
to see what it really is.
Tell me something...
Are you sure that Peter and Uncle Billy
weren't scared by their own shadows?
No. There's a monster, Reddy.
Both me and Uncly Billy saw it,
we can assure you!
But I don't believe you
and I don't fear anything in this forest.
Reddy, I didn't know you were so brave!
In fact,
I'm not sure if you really
don't believe in the monster.
Well, I don't!
I'll beat that monster, alone!
Who's afraid?
Hurray, hurray, you're very brave,
Reddy, you're very brave!
Now we have to find the monster.
Right now he's probably hidden in the bushes.
Today I have other things to do, but...
- ...I will do it tomorrow.
- Alright, we agree.
And I'll make sure that you will do it
because I'll be watching you from above.
Darn, if I don't do it,
everyone will see me as a coward.
What a fix...
Then you're really going, Reddy?
I'll take care of the problem!
You'll see...
Tomorrow you'll prove
that you're brave, Reddy...
I'm sure of it...
Now Reddy is sorry for what he said.
Would it be night forever?
But before morning came,
he had a great idea.
It could be the solution. That's right.
He will go to the farm,
make Bowser angry,
and when everyone sees him being pursued,
they will forget about the monster.
Granny, Granny...!
What's wrong?
He's leashed.
My plan has failed.
It's not my lucky day.
I knew it. Reddy won't be coming.
He's a coward.
I'm sure he's completely afraid.
Who knew? He's coming.
I'm not afraid. It's obvious I'm not.
Monster, are you there?
Come on, don't hide.
Coward!
C-come on, i-if you're s-so b-brave,
let us f-fight.
I'm not afraid of you,
and you know it well, you coward.
I wonder what's wrong?
What kind of monster is it?
Granny!
I saw it, I saw it!
Reddy is a coward!
I have news, I have news, everyone!
Listen up!
Reddy ran away from the monster!
As soon as he saw it, he ran into the woods,
he ran into the woods, the coward!
He was screaming for help, calling:
"Help me, Granny, help me!"
Reddy pretends to be brave,
but in fact he's a coward.
Maybe the biggest coward in the forest!
That's the truth!
News, news!
Reddy, when will you learn?
You shouldn't talk so much
or you'll get into trouble.
I told you many times
that in closed mouths flies can't enter.
But to tell you the truth,
I've never heard of a monster like that.
I wanna know if it really exists.
Otherwise I can't sleep peacefully.
Granny, will you avenge me?
Don't be silly. I just want to make sure
if that monster really exists.
That morning, Sister South Wind
delivered a message from Prickly.
He wanted to see Johnny and Polly.
So they went.
It's Johnny and Polly.
Where are they going?
Granny Fox, despite her age,
was still very wise.
Her plans are very different
from the ones she said.
She changes her course
and goes to the other side of Poplar Hill.
Then she finds Peter.
She knows that rabbits are very slow
at running downhill...
"I'll trap him", thought Granny.
Thank you for coming to see me, friends.
I want to thank you
for what you did the other day.
That was kind. Thank you.
You don't need to thank us.
By the way, is your throat better, Prickly?
That hurts! Ah!
It's a needle from Prickly. How it hurts!
I have to run!
Granny knows this is her great opportunity.
Now she will finally eat rabbit.
H-h-help me...
Help me!
Johnny!
Wait, it's dangerous!
Oh, no, it's the monster!
Help me!
Who knew?
It's Prickly!
Prickly, it's been so long.
Do you still enjoy going downhill?
Yes. I just arrived here,
so I don't have many friends yet.
But I wasn't playing.
I was just giving a lesson to Granny Fox.
Of course! She deserves it!
What's happened?
Hello, Sammy!
We discovered the monster's identity.
Really? Are you serious? Who is it?
Tell me, tell me, tell me!
The truth is that our monster is simply Prickly.
What? Prickly is the monster?
It was Prickly!
Peter will stay at Johnny's house for some days,
recovering from Granny's bite,
but for sure, everything will be okay.
Translation: Cyber Zero
Subtitle: South Wind Subs