FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Mischievous Chatterer"
I got news, I got news, I got news,
Read all about it!
Alright I shout it!
When the moles are excavating,
And the bears are hibernating,
And the hoot owl are debating,
That is news! Ah!
When the rabbits' multiplying,
I report it!
I'm a-tellin like it is,
I have no choice!
I am for freedom of the press,
I support it!
But when trouble comes to you,
How I rejoice!!
- I got news, I got news,
How the rumour's born as bubble!
I got news, I got news,
It's that Chatterer's in trouble!
Chatterer's in trouble!
When woodpeckers break the news,
I decode it!
When the bullfrog speaks a myth,
I exploit it!
I got news, I got news
Master in the major!
I got news, headline news,
Chatterer's in danger, Chatterer's in danger!
That is the end of the news!
Ah-ah!
Johnny! Polly!
You know why Chatterer's so depressed?
The reason Chatterer is depressed is because...
the Mean Weasel is coming home!
The Mean Weasel?!
Dear me, no wonder Chatterer is so glum!
Trouble, trouble, trouble,
a-ha!
When I told Chatterer the bad news,
he trembled like a leaf!
Isn't that sad?
- Oh!
- Hi, Chatterer!
Hey, we're big friends?
Just because it's not your problem,
you're all having fun on my expense!
That's not true at all, Chatterer!
Johnny's right, we're afraid
of the Mean Weasel!
You're lucky, Peter, you can hide
in that thorny mansion!
I've no place to go,
I can't escape from the Mean Weasel!
Now, we've got to do something!
Words, words!
There's nothing you possibly can do!
Wow, he's really petrified!
Ah, fascinating!
Extra! Chatterer faces disaster,
he runs fast, the weasel's faster!
Grandfather Frog?
Please, help me, Grandfather Frog!
Please, tell me what to do about this!
The problem is you're such a meddling busybody!
Someone sent the Weasel out to get you,
Chatterer!
Problems, I already have problems!
Give me solutions!
For your problem I have no solution!
Why don't you discuss it with
your friends in the forest, huh?
Friends?! With friends like that,
who needs enemies?
You're being ridiculous, Chatterer!
If you can't trust your friends,
it's time for you to leave the Green Forest!
I guess I'd better
leave the forest...!
How crushing...!
Oh, I've got it!
There's no need for me to leave by myself!
I've got it, I'll take someone with me!
So Chatterer decided,
he would heed his own advice.
He has a diabolical plan,
it doesn't seem quite nice.
My name is Reddy Fox,
I'm a very bold guy,
You're amazed by my IQ,
And my very sharp eyes.
I have a briliant brain,
And even red...
Oh, there you are, you crafty fox!
I'm not the only one that calls you crafty,
everyone in the forest calls you crafty!
Everyone? Even the birds?
That's right! Furthermore, they all shout,
"We don't dread, silly Red!"
I'll show them!
Run over to Lonesome Pine,
everyone who calls you silly is gathered there!
This is bad for my ego!
I'll show those animals how nasty I could be!
He fell for it!
They'll all be terrified, and some of them
will bid to escape from here with me!
Who could conceive such a frightful plan?!
Obviously, Chatterer can.
Well, don't just sit there saying nothing!
Let's do something!
Well-well, you sure are
an inspired looking group!
Why... it sure would astound me
if one of you had the courage
to face the challenge and chase
the Mean Weasel out of the Green Forest!
Oh, if there's one brave one among you,
my troubles would be over!
Alright, then, we'll fight!
Huh? Are you mad?
Why, there's not a soul amoung us
who can beat the Mean Weasel!
That's why we must all fight!
United we stand,
divided we perish!
When you say "we"
are you including me?
Why must we all fight
for a rascal like Chatterer?
He's always haunting us, insulting us,
calling us names!
I know that Chatterer persists
and annoys us continually, it's true...
...but... but he lives here in the Green Forest
with us, and we should all act neighbourly!
Hm... Thanks!
Well, even though he has teased us,
all he has hurt is our pride, yeah!
It is not that he hurt us, it's just that
he likes practical jokes, that's all!
If Chatterer leaves,
the forest will be a duller place!
You're right!
Chatterer can be quite amusing!
But how can we contend with the Mean Weasel?
We can fight and beat him too!
Remember, we've all got our secret weapons!
Hey, the weak ones will cooperate,
and union their strength!
- Yeah!
- Let's do it!
Oh! It's Reddy the Fox!
Alright, everybody, freeze!
Which one of you called me silly?
Was it you, Peter?
N-n-n-no!
Was it you, Rabbit?
No!
You, Sammy?
Who, me?!
Never!
Then it must be you, Johnny!
Oh, no-no-no!
No, I'd never offend you, Reddy!
Stop lying! I've got my information
from a very reliable source!
- You can't mean Chatterer?!
Chatterer?
Well... I... uh...
How could you lie to Reddy the Fox...
about us?
Why do you do such things like that, Chatterer?
Why, I was only jesting...
It really doesn't make any difference
because you're all gonna get it!
Oh! Look out!
Hold it, all of you!
Don't run away like cowards!
Didn't we all agree
to stand together and fight?
Where's all your courage?
I'm scared silly!
What's this?
All you can say is "Me-ow!"
Don't run away, don't panic!
Well, I... it just came to my mind
it's Sunday!
I never fight on Sundays,
it's against my principles!
I'm not afraid of you...
it's just that I'm very religious!
Phew! That was close!
- We did it!
- Thank goodness!
Hey, that's a signal from Drummer!
I think that he says...
...he says the Mean Weasel has been sighted
at the Laughing Brook and he's on his way!
Oh!
I'm getting nervous!
Bye!
Well, here comes the weasel!
Mercy me!
See who you're up against, squirrel!
Chatterer, I'm gonna get you!
I'm a mad-mad weasel!
V-v-very vicious,
F-f-field mice are tasty,
But squirrels are delicious!
Hello, Mr. Woodpecker!
It's me, Mr. Weasel!
I understand every peck!
SOS, Mean Weasel in Green Forest!
I just wanna... well...
wanna... ask... uh...
Wanna know where Chatterer is, right?
Yeah... yeah...
Well, I don't know anything about it!
So ask somebody else!
You don't have to tell me!
I already know!
Red alert! The Mean Weasel
has entered the Green Forest...!
Tension mounts, the river flows
When trouble comes, the river knows!
I'm going, the Mean Weasel's on the lose!
I hate to leave this behind!
Johnny, I'm worried!
- Uh, don't be!
- I was thinking about Chatterer!
Who gives a hoot! I don't care
what happens to that little troublemaker!
Polly, why is it that everything Chatterer
says and does upset me so much?
Polly is perturbed,
Still she keeps in mind,
Though he's acting grumpy,
Johnny still is kind.
I'm all alone in a friendless world!
I just can't leave the Green Forest!
Does Chatterer see the Weasel?
I don't think so.
Will the Weasel trap Chatterer?
Will Chatterer's friends defend him?
We'll have to see.
Johnny, how annoying digging a hole here!
I'm sorry, Peter!
Next time, think before you dig!
Hey, what's wrong,
you look so gloomy!
- Huh?!
- The Weasel's found Chatterer!
- Oh!
- They've converged at the Little Path!
- I've gotta go!
Not again!
How annoying!
Johnny, where are you going?
I'm going to see
if I can help out Chatterer, Peter!
Johnny, don't!
Stop, you'll get hurt!
That woodchuck, he's so fullhearty!
He doesn't stand a ghost of a chance!
Robber-robber-robber!
Thief-thief-thief!
Thief! Robber!
Everybody, get out!
Chatterer's in trouble!
Hey, everybody!
Come on, Chatterer needs your help!
- Everybody, come on, get out!
- Uh?!
Chatterer needs your help!
Hurry, hurry, come on with me!
- Chatterer needs your help...
- Uh?!
And despite the roaring din
The weasel keeps closing in.
Bounding through the tallest tree,
Chatterer darts crazily.
But the Weasel is so limber...
He just oozes through the timber.
Chatterer's petrified,
Searching for a place to hide.
Oh, I wish I could run faster!
- Hey, Johnny!
- Huh?!
You're OK?
Yeah! Hey, the Woodpecker reports
that the Mean Weasel has chased Chatterer
to the mouth of the river!
Let's take the shortcut!
I'll get you, Chatterer!
I'll get my hands on you!
I got you now, Ch-Ch-Chatterer!
It's all over for you!
Oh, where am I gonna go?!
Oh, run, Chatterer!
Yeah, nearly now, Chatterer!
Oh! Watch it! Oh, no, I just got you!
Help me, please!
Ah...!
I-I c-c-can't believe it!
Where did they all c-c-come from?!
Oh, no!
I hope Johnny and the others
come out of this unharmed!
Chatterer, wake up!
Oh! Oh!
Whe-whe-where am I?!
Look! They're all fighting for you,
Chatterer!
For me?! Oh my!
It takes more of you to get me,
I'll tell you! Yeah!
Oh, heaven, Polly, what can we do?
They're no match for the Mean Weasel!
It's Whitetail the Hawk!
Chatterer!
Hey, there, Mean Weasel, come up here!
I dare you to come up here! Hey!
D-d-darn it, Chatterer!
Coward, coward!
I double dare you!
Chatterer, you're in trouble,
I'll get you!
Oh, no!
What I'd do now?!
Help! Oh, no!
Somebody help me! Help me!
Help, help!
Help, oh, help!
What a day!
Oh heaven, a paradise!
Oh, my friendly pond!
My, oh my!
You certainly look happy, Chatterer!
Bliss! Pure bliss!
It appears that you decided
not to leave the Green Forest, huh?!
How could I ever leave my good friends?
All is well that ends well...
...knock on wood!
Despite Chatterer's mischief,
his friends save the day!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs