FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Paddy Beaver comes to the Green Forest"
Come on, sunshine,
what a beauty!
Sammy must have good news,
he's usually hullabalooing about trouble!
Oh, it's great to be alive!
What's going on, Johnny?!
Why are you yodeling?
Well, I guess I'm in love with my echo!
Johnny, wake up!
Wake up, Johnny, please!
Hmm. What?!
The Laughing Brook stopped
making the sound of laughter!
Huh?!
Johnny... now listen carefully!
You're right, Polly,
what's happened?
- It's really strange!
- Hmm...
It's eerie...
Ow!
Oh, boy, that hurt,
where is the water?!
Holy frog!
I suggest you not use my name in vain!
Look how big the waterlevel fell,
there were tonnes of water here yesterday!
Oh, smart as I am I simply can't figure it out!
Well, I'll be! What happened?!
The brook disappeared!!
How can we, creatures, exist without the brook,
Harry? I mean, we need it. What'll we do, huh?
When all is lost, Joe,
we can migrate to the Big River!
I don't think it's fair, we otters have been living
at the Laughing Brook and Smiling Pool
since my great-grandfather's times!
But you often make long excursions
and disappear for a long time, Joe!
You know, I love to travel,
it really broadens the mind!
It's exciting to explore a new river
or blue lake...
...but I've always returned here,
isn't that right, Harry, huh?
That's right, that's right!
It's said, "Home is where the heart is."
And my heart belongs
to the Laughing Brook and Smiling Pool!
To me it's almost like losing a personal friend!
Oh...! Oh, all this reminds me
of a beautiful saying.
"A true good friendhip is like the sun,
You never miss it till it's gone!"
Fathers, chapter 2!
Such a sparkling stream,
the Laughing Brook flows with happiness!
Johnny, wake up!
I wonder how could a body of running water
disappear over night!
Yeah, I'd sure like the answer to that question!
Oh, mother, there's an answer to every question,
just like every cause has an effect.
I mean, the whole things must follow logically,
just like summer follows the spring.
The spring?
The spring...?!
That's elementary, my dear friends.
But as I live, I wonder
at the balance of nature.
Every spring has its source,
in this case, the water from the spring
pours in the Laughing Brook.
- Make sense, Johnny!
- Let's go right to the spring!
That's a sensible idea, maybe the brook
reversed its flow and returned to the spring!
Boy, when I talk about water
I become very thirsty, so... pardon me!
So they shortcut through the forest,
And they headed for the spring,
They resolve to solve the puzzle,
Of the brook's meandering.
Then Harry was distracted,
By the sight of something cool,
And he made a hasty beeline,
To a tempting forest pool.
Strange...
The brook disappears downstream!
Yeah, why is that?
Let's go and find out!
- Yes!
Hurry, Johnny!
- Uh-hu, hurry, Joe!
- I am, fast as I can!
Through the forest and the lee,
Went the worried, puzzled three.
Flowers blooming everywhere,
Even water flowing there.
As they near the forest spring,
They heard its water gurgling.
Then all at once to their surprise,
A strange new sight came to their eyes.
What is that?!
Huh, what is what?
Where?
Can't you see?
By the edge of the pond!
No, I'm nearsighted!
- He is?
- So he says!
Somebody build this! This log's been cut!
There's no human odour!
I wonder who could've build this!
And for what earthly reason?
It's a terrible thing to do...
Look out!
Oh, help!
Dreadful... awful!
No one's safe anymore,
not even in the Green... Forest.
That is distressing!
How could such a strong tree tumble over?!
Greetings, good friends!
I'm Paddy, the busy beaver!
Welcome, folks!
- Thank you!
Oh, wow, I'm pleased with myself!
I cut this tree down!
- Oh!
- Look! Easy as pie!
- Amazing!
- It's remarcable!
This is a mouth made beaver dam!
- Beaver dam?!
That's right!
A genuine aspen beaver dam!
I'm going to build my home right here in the
Green Forest, and this dam is the first step.
How do you like my new home?
It's incredible!
- You did this all alone?
- Yep. Sure did. How do you like it?
What about this ridiculous dam, huh?
Just look at this brook!
I swear I'm gonna wreck
your dam right now, Beaver!
I mean, why can't beavers learn to let live?
I'm gonna wreck it, if it's the last thing I do!
And furthermore... uh... you...
you one jamming trouble maker!
What about the ecology?
Just look at this river!
And what's more, I don't think I like beavers!
The Laughing Brook is shedding tears,
The Smiling Pool is scowling,
The forest folk are filled with fears,
The frightened wind is howling.
Scoop, scoop, I've been scoop...
what big mouths talk about the beaver!
They don't call me Blabbing Blue Jay for nothing!
There are a lot of things
we hear about before you do!
I don't know about you squirells getting the news
first, but when you birds beat me to it...
Chirp, chirp, be quiet!
Now, watch this closely!
Oh, I'm scared!
Don't be afraid!
I've thought of practically everything!
Look, I've even build a canal!
I planned it so the tree will fall
in the canal and not on you!
- Oh, is that how it works?
- Where did you learn such things?
My mummy and my daddy taught me.
They learned it from my grandma and my grandpa.
I think it's something called heredity.
Aha... true.
You're right!
You, beavers, call it heredity,
but woodchucks call it instinct.
Tell me, if you didn't do
exactly as you were taught,
didn't your daddy give you
a nasty bite on the ear?
Absolutely!
I can still feel the pain!
- Not me!
- Ha!
- Oh, come on!
- My folks never bit me!
But when I forgot what they taught me,
I was spanked
and I'm embarrassed to tell you where!
I think I can guess!
We know too!
Well, I'm glad you're all here!
Now, I'm gonna make some straight poles.
Stand by and watch a genius at work!
Hey...! Duper, thief, burglar, bandit, thief!
What's wrong with you, anyway, thief?
- Thief!
- Mister Jay, who are you calling a thief?
Could it be you're referring to yourself?
That's right, laugh, you foolish animals!
You thief, thief, thief!
You bandit, thief, look what you've done!
You thief! Why...?! Thief!
- Thief, thief, thief, why, look what you've done!
- Oh!
- Thief... Why you...
- Mister Jay, you're crazy!
His behavior is for the birds!
Sammy always act that way,
he is happiest when he is miserable!
And when is miserable he's absolutely ecstatic.
Our friend Sammy is even-tempered,
he's contemptible all the time!
Thief, thief! Why can't you see what he's done,
look at this, thief, thief! Why...?
I am not a thief!
Oh, look what you've done!
You've stolen our trees! Thief! Look at that!
I insist, if he destroys our trees,
doesn't that make him a thief?
Hmm... hmm... true...
Joe and Harry!
- Sammy's right, I think he's right!
- Please, Joe, listen to them!
Wait a minute!
Don't you often do things
because they were taught to you
by your mother and father, don't you, huh?
- Oh!
- Well, do you agree or don't you?
I agree. I was soundly spanked by my father
when I forgot the things he taught me.
Oh, Paddy had his ears chewed seven times
till he learned how to cut trees
and build a dam!
But what will become of the Laughing Brook?
It no longer sings joyfully,
the silence is maddening!
Yeah, but without the Laughing Brook,
the Green Forest will become a desert!
We'll have to move far away,
to the Big River, and live there!
- I-I-I don't want to move...!
- Neither do I!
Return the Laughing Brook to us,
restore happiness!
That's right, return the water, restore the trees!
Thief, thief, you thief!
Joe, Harry!
Johnny, Polly!
Please, have faith in me! Don't worry!
I promise the brook will live as it did before!
- Really?! But how?!
You're not going to destroy the dam
after all the trouble you went through building it!
Certainly not!
In a few days, the dam
will be brimming with water
and the Laughing Brook will return
more joyful then ever!
It's-it's hard to believe!
I feel that Paddy is telling the truth,
aren't you?
Of course I'm telling the truth!
- Cross your heart?
- On my honour!
You're not a bad guy after all and we
won't have to move from the Green Forest!
- That's wonderful!
- How nice!
No... no... you're all wrong!
The nuts and the acorns
from the trees are our food,
and if we don't have the trees,
we can't eat,
and if we can't eat,
we're all going to die!
These trees aren't your personal property!
These trees belong to the Green Forest,
and the Green Forest belongs to one and all!
You all receive the necessities of life
from bounties of the Green Forest.
Well, the trees are necessary to me!
If you have the right to plot nuts,
so I have the right to cut trees!
But, tell me, why did you construct this dam,
and why is this pond so vital to you?!
I'm going to build my house
in the center of the pond,
it's going to be a kind of pondeminium!
Well, it sounds like a neat house,
don't you think so, Johnny?
I've decided that the Green Forest
is the place for me!
I'm going to plant my roots here!
After all, this is a free forest!
No-no-no, no one invited you to come here
and live in the Green Forest!
Get out of here, you thief, thief, thief!
- Hi there, Paddy!
- Oh, no, Paddy, he always speaks before he thinks!
Look what he's done to the trees!
Look!
Sammy's always been rude,
don't worry about what he says, Paddy!
Yeah, Sammy never did acquire
any of the social graces!
You know, I actually feel sorry for him.
There's gonna be trouble
and I'm gonna cause it!
Trouble, trouble, I'm gonna cause
trouble for you, big mouth!
That's right, trouble, trouble!
There goes big mouth!
Help, help! Help, help!
Help me!
That's not funny!
Oh, I've got to get busy!
Day by day, log by log,
On from early morn,
Paddy laboured at his dam,
Till a pond was born.
Great!
The Laughing Brook has been reborn!
Wow!
My, oh my!
Johnny!
- Yes?!
- The brook, listen to the brook!
- It is the brook! It's beautiful, Polly!
- Come on, let's go!
Hurry!
Paddy Beaver did his job,
A new dam he invented,
The Laughing Brook is back to stay,
And his new friends are contented.
Subtitle: South Wind Subs