FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Bob the Quail"
This morning, Mrs. Bob
has begun to move from the nest
in a familiar range to the Green Forest...
...because it would soon be time
to hatch her eggs.
Therefore... it was necessary to build
a nest in a good spot,
where there were many hiding places.
Mrs. Bob had her eyes on a place
in the outskirts of the Green Meadow,
near the Bramble Bush House
of Peter the Rabbit.
Hey, Bob,
good morning!
Hi, Peter,
Boy, you sure look cheerful!
- Yeah, sort of...
- That's good!
Hey, tell me, Bob, where you're going
to build your nest, huh?
I'm sorry, Peter, but I can't tell you that.
Hey, after all, since we're going to be
such close neighbors,
I'd like to come and visit you sometimes.
Sorry, Peter.
All the more reason I can't tell you.
What would you do if because of you
some accident befell me and my family?
You'd feel terrible.
Why, I'd feel sorry.
My gosh! Do you think
I'm going to bother you in some way?
I don't think that you would deliberately
try to bother us...
...but...
...all around us, taking aim at us...
...there are eyes...
...ears...
...claws...
...many things...
When you come to visit,
thinking that nobody sees you,
somebody, still... may be watching...
I see, I guess I didn't count on that.
Even I...
...If I told someone of our nest
and something happened,
- I could'n face my wife ever again!
- That's for sure, that's for sure!
But... if by chance, I...
Hey...!
If by chance I happen to find your nest,
you won't get mad at me, will you? Huh, huh?
Hmm...
Boy, you really are the curious one!
But please... be careful and don't talk too much!
See you later!
Don't talk too much!
Don't talk too much?!
Who does he mean?
He couldn't...
He couldn't possibly mean me...
Say, don't you think...
What? What is it?
I'm busy right now!
I-I just thought that isn't it a little
dangerous, so close to the winding path?
You needn't worry yourself
about such things!
But-but Reddy the Fox and the Mean Weasel
often use this path...
And Jimmy the Skunk, who loves eggs, also...
Let's stop building a nest
in such a dangerous spot!
Oh... You're a fool,
that's why this is safe!
Everyone always passes by,
so on the contrary, it will be unnoticed!
Is that so?
Maybe you're right.
Shh!
Be quiet!
Hmm...
Granny, are quails eggs really that delicious?
Sure, they're really delicious!
If Bob and his wife have moved here,
they will definitely have some eggs,
we'll move in on them!
Just like I said, isn't it?
You sure are smart, really!
If you realize that, then go off a little way
from here, and give your whistle!
Why, leave it to me!
No! If you fly from here and you're seen,
what are you going to do?!
That's right! From now on,
I'll walk in the shadow of the grass,
and from a spot further down the line
I'll fly off!
Remember, dear, it's very important
to do the same thing on your return trip!
It's up to you whether this place
will be safe or not!
I know, I know!
My, I wonder where Bob is going
to build his nest!
Now I know where it is!
I wonder where he landed!
I wonder where they built that nest, anyway!
Hmm...
It must be some place nearby, I know it is!
- Hi, Peter!
- Ah-ah-ah!
Oh, it's you, Johnny!
Don't scare me like that!
If you don't pay close attention,
Reddy the Fox or the Mean Weasel
will get you, Peter!
Be careful!
Oh, Bob!
Hi, you Johnny! Hi, you Peter!
How are you two doing today?
Hi, Bob!
Lately I have a lot of fans
for my whistling!
Look, even Jimmy the Skunk is coming!
Oh-ho!
Hi, Jimmy, did you come
to listen to Bob's whistling, too?
What do you mean, I'm just out for a stroll!
Oh, and just by chance,
you strolled up to my house, right?
Oh! What beautiful weather
it is today for a stroll,
and where did you built your home, hmm?
I've haven't seen your home anywhere!
There's no reason to tell you,
you might get hungry,
and I couldn't stand have my eggs taken!
Just one or two would do!
You do have lots of eggs in your nest,
don't you?
- You eat eggs?
Well, oh...
I think I'll go for a stroll that way...
It sure is ideal weather today...
Bob, it sure is rough for you
with everyone out to get you!
That's right!
Oh my, another guest is coming up the trail!
This time it's Reddy the Fox!
Huh, it's Reddy?!
Let's go, Peter!
Hey, Bob, how are you today?
Good, thanks.
Out for a stroll too, huh, Reddy?
Sort of. About to pay my respects
to you at the same time.
Well-well-well!
Peter and some friends were just here
to pay their respects, too.
Is that so?
Where did they go? Hmm?
I'd like to pay my respects to them, too.
Must be home by now.
Is that so? And you, Bob?
When are you going home?
Just on my way right now.
And how about you, Reddy?
Yeah, I thought I would leisurely
go home, you know.
Well, see you later!
Well, guess I'll go home!
Yes, that's him alright!
Now, one more worries cry!
Must be in here!
Everyone is searching everyday for Bob's nest,
but with no success at all.
No one could find it.
Then, one day...
Oh, look out!
Watch your feet, please, Johnny!
- Oh!
- Oh, Mrs. Bob, glad to see you!
Look who's here! Long time no see, Miss Bob!
How are you?
No-no-no-no-no!
Watch your feet!
Oh, they're little baby quail!
Oh, look at that...!
Oh, Johnny, aren't they cute?
We are now going to move
to Peter's thicket house nearby,
and when the little ones start to move about,
it might be dangerous in the old nest!
You're moving?
Alright then, I'll accompany you
to the thicket house!
Alright, everybody, follow me!
Huh? Is that so?
You people were that near?
Huh...
Sorry we had to fool you, Peter.
Oh, that spot! All the forest creatures
passed by there,
you picked a really good place for your nest,
didn't you?
Of course, my wife built it, that's why!
Now, all of you, follow your father!
Ah...!
Making fools of us!
Granny, we'd better hurry,
we won't be able to catch
the baby quails once they start flying!
Now we're going to practice how to hide!
What's up?
Aren't you going to hide?
- Seems so foolish!
- Look here, what did you say?
You'd better do like the others
and hide properly!
It's only a practice, when it's for real,
all that's necessary is to run away!
You don't understand, my son,
on the outside there's scary!
Fox, skunk, mountain lion, hawk, weasel,
right?
I know!
Look, see this?
He thinks he's grown up enough
by flying like that! I'm at a loss!
Sure would like to watch!
Must be making and practice
other things today... too!
- Oh-oh!
- Hey, you! You're Bob's child, aren't you?
- That's right!
- What's wrong with you?
Did you finish your survival training already?
I think this is enough training, Johnny!
Let's go play someplace wide and spacious!
But that could be dangerous for you!
It's OK! If you don't want to,
I'll go alone!
Oh... wait!
Bob's child, on arriving at this spacious place,
is jumping and leaping about
with all his energy,
and he began to think that it was a good thing
to train in such a spacious place.
Johnny!
What are you doing in this kind of place?
Well, I'm strolling with Bob's son!
Hey, don't you go too far away!
Don't worry!
Hey, he's going further and further,
isn't he?
- Oh! Oh, Johnny, look at that!
- Huh?
- Oh!
- Ah, you two better mind your own business!
I'm gonna tell everyone!
Wait!
Run, Polly, I'll handle Reddy!
My nose!
Daddy, daddy!
Bob!
Now you've really done it, you little shrimp!
I'm gonna get you this time!
Oh, I'll get you!
Mommy, mommy, mommy!
- My little boy!
- Oh, mommy!
Granny!
- Granny, Granny, please help!
- Reddy!
Reddy, you big coward!
Reddy, Reddy! Don't run away!
Sorry about that, Granny!
But don't give up and try again!
You won't catch us!
Forgive me, Mrs. Bob, for putting your child
to such an ordeal.
It's quite alright, Johnny.
Today's events surely must've been
very good medicine for him.
Hey...!
What good news, what good news!
I'll go tell everyone, right away!
Attention, everyone!
Now let's prepare for aerial maneuvers! Go!
Now hurry!
Return to base!
You made up your mind to go today?
From now on they can all
get along as grown-ups.
They needn't stick close to us any longer.
They're on their own!
Mr. Peter, you have to understand,
we're all grown-ups, grown-ups!
Yeah, I-I understand...
...but-but I'm going to be very lonely
if you all leave the forest!
Now, listen everybody.
It's almost departure time.
Everybody try and do their best.
- Yeah!
- Bye!
Bye, bye!
All creatures brought up under the protection
and love of their parents,
must eventualy part and become independent.
Johnny, Polly and Peter,
all went through this.
Now the baby quails
likewise are undergoing this.
There will be many dangers
and sufferings ahead,
but they'll all do their best to survive.
Subtitle: South Wind Subs