FABLES OF THE GREEN FOREST
11. Sammy's revenge
Chatterer, the red chipmunk,
chased by the Mean Weasel,
Now lives in a new house,
found on Mister Brown's farm.
I had better put something in my storeroom,
even a little at a time!
Looking intently at the already harvested
corn field of Mister Brown,
Chatterer is deep in thoughts.
Over there is Bowser the Dog...
Tom, too...
And that pesky cat, Blackie...
Nothing... Not a thing!
Oh, wow, here's a lot of corn fallen
where the field's not trampled so!
Hi there, Chatterer,
did you move over here now?
I was under the impression
that you lived in the orchard!
I'm busy storing food for the winter,
there's no food left in the orchard!
Ah! If it were me, I wouldn't be doing
what you're doing!
I'd just be using my head a little!
If you want corn, Chatterer, what you should do
is go to Mister Brown's house!
Why, he has all the corn that you'd
ever-ever want, believe me!
I go there often and just help myself.
I wonder if what Sammy the Jay
is telling me is true.
If it is true, I should be brave
and go check it out!
Hmm... Where is it? The storehouse where
the corn that Sammy mentioned is stored?
At that moment, Tom, Mr. Brown's son, came outside.
Wow, look at all that delicious corn
he has in those two buckets!
But Chatterer's afraid to steal the corn
because he's scared of Tom,
and Blackie, and especially Bowser.
I wonder how Sammy manages
to get food from there.
That's it! I'll come early tomorrow morning
and keep an eye on Sammy!
For the present,
Chatterer has decided to wait.
It's Sammy!
The usually noisy Sammy approaches
without making a sound.
Just like he came in, Sammy flies off quietly.
Hmm... I see how he does it!
What Sammy can do, I can do!
Now, today Blackie the Cat isn't here,
so my chances are up going to get
some food from that storehouse!
What a funny building!
???
The reason little Chatterer is slipping,
is the posts are made of stone.
Mister Brown also put kettles
upside down on the pillars
to further protect his grains
from chipmunks and field mice.
Oh, if I only had wings like Sammy!
Now Chatterer pondered.
He knows that it's useless to wish
that he had wings like Sammy.
But he wonders how he can do it
on his own strength.
What methods are there?
Ah! That's it!
Hey, Blackie, come over here!
Too scared to follow me?
Scared, you coward?
What's the matter? Hey, you can't
even find your own food in the farm!
You jumplike cat!
Yeah, nothing you are!
INSERT
I'm not afraid of you!
What's the matter, Blackie?
This... This is bad!
What are you making such a fuss about?
Huh, the mouse or something?
The field mouse
can't get into this storehouse!
It's alright.
You probably just seeing things.
Now I'll give you some milk.
Come on!
Come on, Blackie!
Oh, wow!
Amazing, fantastic!
This is it, the whole world is made of corn!
Wow, wee!
Hey...! That guy is sure putting
a lot of my yellow corn in that bucket!
Oh, all the nerve!
Chatterer began to think that all the corn
in the storehouse belonged to him.
So the next morning when he saw Sammy
approaching as usual,
he thought about getting even with him.
What are you doing,
what are you doing?!
Sammy was really in trouble.
He thought for sure
that he had fallen in a trap.
A trap! I know it was a trap
by Mister Brown's son, Tom! Yeah!
He's been trying to get me!
I've never been so scared in all my life!
Mister Brown's son is an awful guy! I better
be aware of him, he's out to get me, I know!
Reddy had just eaten three or four crickets
this morning and was therefore in high spirits.
Hey...! Hey...!
Wow! That bug smells so bad,
he doesn't want to be friends!
Bad news, bad news,
bad news, bad news!
Listen, listen, listen everybody! I've got
bad, bad, bad news! Everybody gather around!
Tom, Mister Brown's son is out to get me!
He's an awful guy!
Everybody listen! Come on!
Listen! Everybody, Mister Brown's son
is out to get me! I know it!
Hey, Chatterer!
You know what Tom did?
He's an awful guy!
He set a trap for me!
I think he's out to get me!
A trap!
A great big trap!
He set a trap, he tried to kill me
in the corn storehouse!
Having all that corn and he doesn't
even give me two or three kernels,
why, what kind of guy is that,
that stinking old minor!
And that big brat...
Why, it-it scared me so!
You better not go near there, Chatterer!
If I can get revenge,
why... I would...!
I'm gonna spread the word all around the forest
to be aware of Tom's traps,
and Chatterer, you don't go near that farm,
understand?
Something's fishy here. Tomorrow morning
I think I'll go visit Mister Brown's house!
How many times have I told you
not to go near any dangerous places?
That's the secret to long life!
Gosh!
It's Chatterer!
So that's it! Now, I've got it!
That thing that scared Sammy was Chatterer!
Chatterer grabbed Sammy still
from the inside and frightened him!
Hey...! You can't jump up this high and get me!
Bowser!
Here, boy, calm down!
What's the matter, is it Reddy the Fox?
Hey there, I understand, be quiet now!
Look here, it's your breakfast!
Nevertheless, Chatterer sure has grown blunt.
He'll make a good thief!
What a racket, get out of here!
Hey, Sammy!
You sure sound like you're in a foul mood!
Could be!
Actually, this morning I went
to check out something.
Don't you want to hear about it?
I don't want to hear about a thing
you've got to say!
Even about traps?
Traps did you say?
Oh, it's really insignificant.
I only thought you wanted to hear about
something I checked out this morning,
if you're not a coward.
I'm not a coward,
who said I'm a coward?
I did! Didn't you tell me that you were
so scared of Mister Brown's warehouse
you would never go there again?
I'm not a coward, I only said that there
was a trap set up there, that's all!
OK, then tomorrow morning can you go and
meet at Mister Brown's corn storehouse?
And do you have the courage to confirm
something that will happen?
You don't, do you? You're a coward!
Of course, I'll go! I'll go and show you
that I'm not a coward!
Good, then it's a deal!
Very early tomorrow,
before sunrise, we'll go together!
Good, of course I promise!
I don't know what's supposed to happen,
but I'll clearly show you that I'm not afraid!
Come tomorrow morning,
Sammy's face will be something to see!
Reddy's plan is working well.
Now it's the following day.
Sammy's scared? You're shaking!
Who... shaking?
I-I'm not shaking, I-I'm not scared!
Let's go, then!
Hmm... there's where the trap was set.
Now we should be able to find out what it was
that grabbed your beak the other day,
but regardless of what you see,
don't make a noise and don't make a fuss!
Hey, there he is!
Why, that's... that's Chatterer!
Why...!
I'll fix you, Chatterer!
Ah, never saw a face so like a masterpiece!
Serves you right, Sammy, you crazy fool!
DELETE Ah...!
Now, for Chatterer!
- I'll get you!
- Oh no, it's Sammy!
Darn you, Chatterer, you thief, you thief,
you thief! I'm gonna fix you!
Stop it, Sammy!
Huh?!
Thief, thief!
You squirrel thief!
Sammy, quit it! If you're not quiet,
Tom and the others will hear it! Stop it!
Thief, thief!
You squirrel thief!
I'll fix you, you thief!
That jay is rasing a racket!
The fox must be after a chicken!
Stop it, Sammy! Please quit now!
I'm gonna fix you,
you little robber, you thief!
INSERT
Bowser! Bowser!
Come on, Blackie!
I'll give you some delicious milk!
TRANSLATE
Hey, Polly, what are you doing, Polly?
With this soft grass,
I'm going to make a wonderful pillow!
It's going to be this big and fluffy!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs