FABLES OF THE GREEN FOREST
12. Johnny's secret door
All the little animals of the Green Forest,
know how to protect themselves
in case of danger.
Johnny too. In case of an emergency,
he has a secret rear exit.
There is delicious clover, growing
abundantly in this area.
No one would ever notice that a rear door
was located in such a spot.
There's not a single thing
that I don't know about!
I wonder what pranks
I can play today, anyway!
There's Polly!
How can that young lady eat so much?!
She'll get fat by eating so much,
if she gets fat, Johnny will be sad!
Shall I play one of my same old tricks
to make her quit?
Ah...! My tummy is full!
What a treat! Ah-oh...!
It's Reddy, it's Reddy, it's Reddy!
What's that...?!
I wonder if it really could be
what I'm thinking...
Why, that's a strange place for a door to be...!
I found it!
Why, that's Johnny's secret door there!
Hidden away in such a far away grassy field,
I wonder if anybody else has found it!
It's no wonder it was so hard to notice
Johnny's secret door!
Hey...Reddy!
Hey, Sammy, got some interesting news?
News?!
You're the one faster than anyone
on hearing news!
Reddy, there couldn't be any news from...
my side!
May be so, my ears are pretty fast,
comparatively speaking!
By the way, Reddy...
you know about Johnny's secret door?
Johnny's secret?!
Uh... sure, I know it!
- Why, it was just this morning that I found it!
- You did this morning?
Well, I found it yesterday morning!
Johnny's secret door... it's something!
I see he's found out the secret door...
Anyway, it opens right into
the middle of a clover field...
At first, I thought it was the front door,
but located at the rear
of the tree grove, out of sight!
You know, Reddy, nobody would ever notice that!
Hmm... I see,
I was only searching the front of the house!
Furthermore, Johnny thinks that nobody,
including you...
...knows of his secret door!
Oh, yeah?
Do you really think so?
Oh! I... found out something I had to do!
See you later, Sammy!
See you later, Reddy!
Go ahead if you feel so important...
Are you going to Johnny's house
and find that secret door, Reddy...?
He's really going there!
I can't stop playing tricks!
It's so much fun to play tricks!
But to have a trick played on you
it's really annoying!
But...
- Playing tricks is so much fun!
Johnny would periodically open the door
and smell the outside air.
One cannot be overly careful.
Johnny!
Jooohnny!
- Oh! Gentle Breeze!
- Shhh! Johnny!
- Reddy the Fox is nosing about!
- Reddy?!
Be careful!
Thank you, Gentle Breeze!
It's true! It's Reddy! He's roaming
around my secret back door area!
That's really funny!
Oh, wait!
Could it be that Sammy the Jay
was telling me a great big bib?
The woodchuck is an animal
found only in North America,
and is sometimes called a groundhog.
Related to the chipmunk,
its body movements are very similar.
Woodchucks have a natural talent
for construction projects.
First they dig a vertically straight tunnel,
fifteen to eighteen feet deep.
This section is built so then when it rains,
water running in will not be a problem.
The house that Johnny built is like this,
but let's leave that to our good imagination.
Let's call this long vertical tunnel,
a circular stairway.
In the horizontal section of this tunnel,
let's have another door.
And let's place the tables and chairs also.
Polly!
Maybe she went out the secret door!
Just as I thought!
Sammy fooled me again!
As long as I know that,
there's no use hanging around here!
Oh, what a day!
I just love this backdoor!
What Sammy said was true!
Mhm... good!
- Hey, Polly, watch out!
- Huh?!
Polly, come back!
- You spoiled!
- What's the matter, Johnny?
Oh, it's Reddy!
Darn it, if I've been just a little bit quicker!
Nevermind...
I can return at night...
Johnny, are you going to close the backdoor?
Yeah, now that Reddy knows about it,
it can't be used as an escape route!
Johnny, if you growled at him,
wouldn't he be scared and then run away?
I was thinking of giving up this old house,
and finding somewhere new to live!
Absolutely not!
What are you saying?
We're not going to give up
our home sweet home!
If Reddy knows, next, Granny will come,
all laying for us!
We won't be able to live quietly!
It was a lot of effort to make it like this!
OK, I'll make the rear exit in another place,
one that will absolutely
not be discovered!
From that day on, Johnny immediately
began working on another secret door.
Oh?!
What-what's that?!
I don't hear it now...!
Is it Johnny?!
That's funny that he would be way out here
in the middle of the Green Meadow!
I must be dreaming!
Johnny!
That really was Johnny!
That's funny, there's nothing
like an exit anywhere!
Well, it looks like Johnny
has dug a long-long tunnel
that reaches to the Green Meadow.
And let's hope that the secret rear exit
is one that cannot be readily discovered.
Sure is boring! All Johnny does
these days is dig in that tunnel!
I wonder if I should go for a walk!
Hello, Polly!
- Nice weather, eh?
- Oh, Peter! How are you?
Uh... real good!
By the way, where's Johnny?
Everyday, Johnny is digging a tunnel!
A... tunnel?!
Yeah!
Tell me, tell me, tell me!
Where, where, where?
Uh, say, where is he digging it?
Where?
It's a long tunnel that exits
into the Green Meadow!
That's amazing!
He does such wonderful things, Johnny does!
He's my very favorite friend when it comes
to building things!
Now that you mention it, I just saw Johnny
in the Green Meadow!
I was astonished...
He kept appearing and disappearing...
...but... I couldn't tell where
he was coming from!
Come on, Polly!
I'd like to know!
Come on, tell me,
you know I won't tell anybody
where he's hiding it, you know that!
Goodness, I just remembered
something I have to do!
Amazing, amazing, I never realized
how amazing his house was!
Who's there?
Peter!
I... I... I...
Johnny, I...
I thought once in a while
I should pay you a visit!
And then, the stairs were so steep I slipped
and fell all the way to the bottom...
...and... and... that is the true story!
Johnny, you were watching, were you?
It sure did hurt!
Boy, your curiosity sure is annoying!
Forgive me!
Have you seen Polly anywhere?
She went that way a while ago!
She went out, then!
It's Redtail the Hawk!
He's been flying around since yesterday!
I told Polly not to wander outside!
- Let's go look for her!
- Yeah!
Johnny!
Hurry!
You're so slow!
Oh, pooh, such a face isn't good at all!
My goodness!
I'm scared!
What will I do?! Oh!
About the time the evening sun
was setting in the Purple Hills,
the hawk finally gave up
and disappeared into the evening sky.
Johnny, separated from Peter,
is still wandering around in the forest.
She must've gone very far because
it's getting really late!
Polly!
What on earth has happened?!
Everything's going wrong for Johnny.
Now the desire to do anything is gone.
But the next day, Johnny sets out
early in the morning to look for Polly.
Polly!
Who is she, who is she,
get her out of here!
Who she thinks she is, barging into somebody's
house without a word?!
Today is the day my wife has to lay eggs!
So this is really annoying!
I don't want her here!
What place is this?
Hey! Hey-hey-hey-hey!
Get out of here!
Get out of the way!
Of all the nerve!
How nice!
Thank you, thank you everybody!
You're all wonderful, thank you!
Oh! That's right!
What place is this?
I need help, I'm lost!
Johnny!
Yes, Gentle Breeze!
What's the matter, Johnny?
So dejected?
- Well, Polly is disappeared!
- Oh...! Since when?
Well... since yesterday!
Oh, I'm sorry!
Gentle Breeze, I have this terrible feeling
that Polly is not coming back to me anymore...
My, such a thing...!
When I think about her being gone,
it makes me all sad inside...
How would you feel
if Polly is not too far away?
Polly is nearby?
Then I feel big and strong and brave
like a woodchuck should feel!
How wonderful to have such a friend!
When Polly is cheerful and happy,
I become cheerful and happy as well!
It appears that you, Johnny, have found
the most wonderful thing in the world.
Little birds, what is the matter?
Johnny!
What is it, Gentle Breeze?
They say that Polly is nearby!
By that tree, over there!
Thanks very much, little birds!
And thank you, Gentle Breeze!
Gentle Breeze?
What do you mean when you say that I've found
the most wonderful thing in the world?
Most wonderful thing in the world...
is for one soul to love another.
Polly!
Johnny!
Polly, if you run that way,
you'll be running further from home again!
Oh! That's right, isn't it?
Well, well!
Johnny, you found Polly!
Yeah!
Sorry if we worried you!
Johnny, I wasn't worried!
I knew you'd find her!
Yeah, well, so long, Peter!
Johnny has completely forgotten
the sadness of a few moments earlier...
...and is again the energetic, bright Johnny.
Never before, not even once,
has the Green Forest seemed
so beautiful, and so wonderful!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs