FABLES OF THE GREEN FOREST
13. A gun in the forest
Darn!
Robbed again!
Three chicks are missing!
This gets me! No matter how many traps
I set, he won't be caught!
Remember this, I'm not raising chicks
to make fox bait!
How terrible, how terrible!
Here comes Tom and he's carrying a gun!
How terrible!
Everybody, everybody!
Hide! Quick! Tom has a gun!
Here comes Tom to the woods with a gun!
Everyone! Quick, quick!
Hide! Look out!
Hey, Johnny, Johnny!
Hi, Peter! It's about Tom, isn't it?
I heard it from the birds, earlier.
That's right. Reddy can't continue having fun
by getting Bowser to chase him
all the time, we're gonna get hurt!
- Yeah, this time it's a gun and it's serious!
- Wow!
B-B-Bowser must have found
R-R-Reddy's track!
W-w-w-what do you think, Johnny?
Do you wanna go and see, huh?
Yeah, let's go!
That Bowser has finally picked up my scent!
Well-well-well, and just right!
I wanted to begin and go run anyway!
Well, I just want to see how far that
Bowser can keep up with me! Hmm!
INSERT 1
INSERT 2
INSERT 3
Just as usual, he's slow as ever!
OK, today I'll set the stage for a showdown!
Oh, Peter, Peter, look, they're coming!
Huh?! Are they?
Yeah...
That's funny!
Tom should be with them!
He should be close behind,
with that big gun of his!
There's Reddy, now!
Eh, Bowser isn't so much!
I wonder why everybody's
so scared of him anyway!
Y-you don't scare me!
How about... this next one.
Can you keep up?
INSERT 1
INSERT 2
INSERT 3
INSERT 4
INSERt 5
INSERT 6
I don't know why I'm trying to let Reddy know
that Tom is coming for him with a gun!
There's not one person
in the forest who likes him...
...because he's always mean to the weak
and always picking on
and scaring those younger than him!
Hmm... frankly, I don't like that
mean old fox either!
Oh!
But it'd be lonely not to see
that beautiful red fur...
I guess I'll let him know!
I feel sorry for him!
Hey, you noisy woodpecker!
If you don't be quiet,
the fox will be startled and run off!
Now you... get out of here!
Can't he hear me yet?!
OK, then I'll peck with all my might!
If he still can't hear me
then it's not my fault!
Here he comes!
I guess I'll make another run!
INSERT
INSERT2
INSERT 3
INSERT 4
Bowser! Bowser!
That's enough now! Let's go home!
I'm home...
What's the matter?
What happened to you in the forest?
Granny, I've been hurt!
What, you're hurt?!
Did you scratch yourself in the forest?
Did you catch yourself
on a wire fence at the farm?
Or did you run through the thorny bush?
Please, don't scold me, Granny!
It was just an accident!
Excuse me...
- Aw, it hurts!
- Lie still now and don't move!
You've learned your lesson, I hope!
What do you have eyes, ears and a nose for?!
To keep from having to suffer such
bitter experiences like this one, isn't it?
Aw, it hurts!
Sure is funny!
How did this happen?
If you only knew...
Come on, let's go see what happened to Reddy!
INSERT 1
INSERT 2
INSERT 3
INSERt 4
INSERT 5
INSERT 6
INSERT 7
INSERT 8
What a beautiful day...!
Oh... Hey... there... that's right, Reddy!
Hi, Reddy!
Hi, Peter!
Reddy can't walk!!
Are you sure Reddy really can't walk, Peter?!
Don't worry, don't worry,
he can't walk.
Right, Reddy?
Well...
INSERT 1
INSERt 2
INSERT 3
Oh, going home so soon, Reddy?
Aw!Yeah...
Really hurts!
Poor little fellow!
Oh, dear!
Poor thing!
Does she's thinking of giving those
three a severe licking, is she?
I won't let that happen!
Look out!
Granny Fox is behind you!
You always crawl home like that?
Ghastly old man,
stop your unnecessary medling!
Yes, yes, will do, Granny, will do!
Wait till I catch you on the ground!
- Granny!
- What is it?
Did you bring me something to eat?
No, there's nothing to eat!
Listen, Reddy, someone like you
has no right to eat.
What about using a little judgement
and a little common sense in what you do?
Isn't that right, Reddy?
INSERT
INSERT 2
INSERT 3
If you hadn't played games
with Bowser and Tommy,
this sort of incident wouldn't have occured!
You should be able to scrounge your own food!
Granny is going out...
Well, I guess I'll go over
and pay a sick call on Reddy!
Well, it serves you right!
I'm glad!
You're always showing off
for everybody all the time,
that's why these things happen
to you, you see?
Hmm, don't bother me,
get out of here, Uncle Billy!
I'm glad, yes, siree,
I'm really glad!
Now that you're hurt, I should be able to pay
a visit to Mister Brown's chicken house!
The eggs there... oh, so good...!
If only you wouldn't walk like that
for a long time it certainly would help!
Yeah, I'll be able to get up right away,
then I won't let anyone touch Mister Brown's
chicken house! Remember that!
I'm gonna eat up all those chicks
and those chicks eggs!
I'll eat to my hearts content...
Bad stuff, it seems like Reddy
really hasn't had anything to eat!
I'd better do something for him...
- Hey, Uncle Billy!
Hi, Joe, hi there, Harry!
- Have you heard about Reddy?
Just saw him.
You know that Reddy's stomach
is so empty he could hardly move about!
- Is that so? Alright!
Yep, you're right, you're absolutely right.
But have you guys ever been so hungry
that you absolutely couldn't bear it?
Have you really ever been so hungry
that you felt like you were dying?
- Sure we have, right?
Now, I've been thinking...
what would it be like to be so hungry,
but totally unable
to find anything to eat!
That would be painful!
Yes, it would...
Yes...
Where are you going, Joe?
Well, I'll tell you, Harry!
I'm gonna go catch a fish all by myself
and give it to Reddy! Yep?
That's what I'm gonna do! See you later, Harry!
Take care! Bye!
That's unfair! I wanna go!
You're doing a good deal all by yourself!
I'm with you, Joe!
Isn't that nice?!
I'll tell everyone in the forest about this!
Well, I'll be...
Isn't this the most beautiful deed
I've ever seen?!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs