FABLES OF THE GREEN FOREST
15. Old Mr. Toad
Peter!
Who is singing?
I don't know. The voice is coming from over there.
Peter, you'd be surprised!
You'd be surprised to know
who is singing!
Hello, Grandfather Frog.
You seem to know who it is?
Of course I know!
It's an old friend of mine.
He's known as the Singing Toad.
- The Singing Toad?
Oh, Peter, I think
he sings really well.
I would like to know
what kind of person Mr. Toad is.
I know him, although we've never spoken
because he is not very sociable.
Honestly, I find it strange that
such an ugly toad can sing so well.
You know what people say:
"Don't judge people if you
don't know them!"
That's right, Peter! Don't judge anybody
just for their looks.
- Oh!
Don't scare me like that,
what's the matter?
- What's going on?
- I, I...
Don't scare us like that.
How are you, Singing Toad?
So that's the famous singer?
I didn't expect it at all.
So, what do you think now?
It is really wrong to judge people
only by their looks.
Unlike Old Grandfather Frog,
The Singing Toad is no good jumper.
But now he runs fast, this Sir.
Wanna know why he's in a hurry?
The reason isn't funny!
He's followed by Green,
The snake who's long and lean.
Toads find no greater enemy on the road,
And now he's chasing poor Singing Toad.
Oh!!
Stop right there!
Don't interfere, Johnny!
Get out of here, cruel animal!
Johnny!
- Johnny!
- Green, what are you trying to do?
Just a moment, horrible snake, if you do anything
I'll bite your tail, I swear!
Well, it doesn't matter. After all,
today I'm not that hungry.
Don't you dare come back!
Thank you for helping me.
Be more careful the next time.
- From now on, we'll be good friends.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
If it wasn't for you, dear friends,
that evil snake would have eaten me.
INSERT
What a shame...
I'm so slow to escape,
so easy to be found,
that those little animals
had to rescue me...
Now I'm starving...
Oh, yes!
There are some worms over there.
I'm so hungry, too bad there's
nothing else around here.
Singing Toad, what do you think
about sharing my food?
Do you want to dine with me?
Why do you react like that?
The Singing Toad thought
the Bear was going to eat him.
When he heard his suggestion,
he thought he was joking.
But decided to pretend
he agreed with the idea.
That was the only way to survive,
and show off his courage.
I'll be pleased to dine with you,
friend Buster.
Huh?
I said that I'll be pleased
to dine with you.
Not too far from here,
there's a place where you can find
delicious food, follow me!
I'm coming!
We've arrived, my friend.
It's time to dine.
No-no-no-no.
I don't see food anywhere.
I'm not hungry anymore.
Oh!
I've never seen so many ants together!
Feel free to eat, my friend.
I've never eaten this much, I'm full!
- Are you satisfied?
- That was delicious!
In that case, you can come and dine
with me whenever you want to.
Seriously? I will, I will!
- Be careful on your way back, Singing Toad!
- Thank you, my friend, I'll be careful!
Hi, Singing Toad,
do you want to play with us?
Haven't you heard me?
I've just finished dining
with my friend Buster.
I don't want to know anything from you.
But how can he say that?
He's really ungrateful!
Really ungrateful!
In my opinion, that was
really rude from him.
What is going on, guys?
We're surprised at how ungrateful
the Singing Toad is.
Yes, that's it!
After dining with Buster the Bear,
he doesn't even want to talk to us!
And yet, he was so modest
when we rescued him...
I think he has a reason to act like that,
I'll go and find out!
Singing Toad...
...I'm Johnny, do you remember me?
Let me pass, please...
But, I'm Johnny!
We're supposed to be friends.
Oh, you don't say!
Don't make me waste more time.
Buster is my only friend
here in the forest!
Whoa, uugh.
Why are you laughing, you envious?
Did he call us envious?
I can't believe it!
I told you, he must have
a good reason.
That doesn't matter,
he's just showing off.
He's showing off that Buster the Bear
is his new friend.
I'm not really sure of that.
I have the best ears of the whole place,
and yet I'm not showing off for it.
Me neither. And I have the best
defense of the whole forest.
Nobody can climb trees as fast as I do,
and that's not a reason for me
to feel better than anyone else.
That's true, I wonder what is wrong
with the Singing Toad?
If he keeps doing this,
he'll lose the sense of reality,
and someone will end up
eating him some day!
Wait, I have a good idea!
Come closer and I'll explain it.
What we have to do is...
- I think this is a cruel thing!
- It's the only way to teach him.
I have an idea, guys, I can go
and tell it to the Singing Toad.
Meanwhile, explain to Buster what our plan is.
Wait for me here.
Time to tell it to all the
animals in the forest.
Don't do it, friends, please don't.
Singing Toad, Singing Toad!
Singing Toad, are you here?
Do you hear me?
I have news from Buster, the Bear!
Listen to me, Singing Toad!
Singing Toad, I bring news!
What do you say, Chatterer?
Buster is eager to see you, and is inviting you
to meet him to have a meal.
Oh, well!
Where is my friend Buster?
I'll tell you now.
He says he's waiting for you by the walnut tree
at the end of the forest.
Can you tell him
that I'll gladly accept his invitation?
I'll do that!
Buster asked me to meet him again!
I bet he likes my company...
Singing Toad, you better don't go,
it might be a trap!
Johnny, you're just jealous.
- Since he never asked any of you for dinner.
- Not true.
You try to make fun of me, right?
How dare you try to
make me doubt my friend!
I shouldn't keep him waiting.
All the animals started laughing
when they saw the Singing Toad
passing by.
The only one who didn't join
was Reddy the Fox,
since Peter was so scared of him,
he decided not to tell him.
All other forest animals
were ready to gloat
and make fun of Singing Toad.
Ribbit.
Oh, how are you?
You look tired.
- Why are you tired?
- I'm really hot.
Thank you for coming from
so far away, my friend.
This is a nice place to chill.
Oh, I feel flattered.
I accept your invitation to dine
with great pleasure!
To celebrate this meeting
I've decided to invite
another friend, as well.
- Oh, then, I'm not the only one.
- I hope he arrives in time.
Ah, here he is!
I'm leaving, I'm leaving.
I'm leaving.
INSERT
- What's wrong with the Toad?
- Poor Singing Toad,
he must be unhappy to see
everyone is making fun of him!
Let's follow him.
INSERT
Where did he go now?
Singing Toad!?
Singing Toad, where are you?
Here I am, help me!
Heeelp!
- Here, in this hole?...
- Help me...
I'll help you!
Here I come!
Try to jump!
Here I come, again!
Don't lose hope!
How funny!!
Where were you, Johnny?
You missed all the fun!
It's something terrible!
The Singing Toad
- ...has fallen into this hole!
- Oh!
And once again!
Oh...
Spending some time there
will teach him a lesson.
But if he can't get out,
he'll die!
Boastful Singing Toad, puff up your belly
and try to float!
Don't behave like that!
Help me!
Ah, yeah, that'll work.
Help me, I'm drowning, help me!
Hold on just a little longer...
Oh, that.
- Use that to float.
- Thank you.
Everything will be in vain,
I'm done for.
I can't get out of here.
Singing Toad, don't lose hope,
we'll save you!
Thank you, my dear friends,
thank you, my dear friends!
I'm really moved.
Singing Toad, forgive us
for laughing at you!
We didn't want you to fall in there,
we just wanted to teach you a lesson.
Peter, you should have thought
about the consequences.
I insisted we shouldn't have done it
from the beginning.
This is not the time or place
to be arguing!
Of course it's not
time to discuss.
Make them stop, Johnny.
I'm ashamed of you!
What's going on, fellas?
One second ago you were
happy and laughing.
Buster, could you save the Singing Toad?
He's fallen in there!
He's fallen?
Thank you, friends!
Wow, Buster, you're wonderful!
But what's wrong with you?
First you ask me to teach him a lesson,
and now you ask me to save him?
Sorry, I'm the one at fault.
That's not true,
if it wasn't because of my attitude,
nothing would have happened.
Buster is the best,
no doubt about that.
It's fine, it's fine.
Mother Nature is the one
that made me big and strong.
But I'm unable to hurt anyone.
I won't be a boastful toad anymore.
And we will never make fun of
you again, I promise!
Polly and I made that promise
a long time ago.
Why haven't you told me?
Why? Tell me!
Look, Peter is curious again and
that's what has caused all of this!
Getting involved in other people's lives.
It's fine, don't laugh.
The Singing Toad sings in the lagoon,
They say he does it
when it's full Moon,
He is the major,
He's is a tenor,
His music always present,
Because he's a good friend,
Because he's a good friend!
Nobody should show off,
or make fun of others,
just like it happened
with the Singing Toad,
that almost drowned,
and a great singer would've been lost.
Translation from Spanish: Lordwen
Subtitle: South Wind Subs