What a scare!
Oh my, what a terrible scare! Oh!
Oh, what a really unpleasant dream!
It's a terrible and unpleasant dream!
Scariest dream I've ever had!
Oh my, it certainly is!
If only I could wake up!
FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Bobby Racoon is captured"
Pfew!
What a terrible dream!
By chance I may still not be awake yet.
This is terrible!
Really terrible!
Oh, it's not a dream!
I'm really awake!
There's Tom and Bowser!
I'm not dreaming!
It's happening!
Just like in my dream!
- Johnny, I wonder what in the world Tom is doing!
- Yeah, I just can't figure it!
He must be going to catch Bobby, he must be.
That's it, isn't it, Johnny?
Since this tree was decaying,
and in order for the surrounding young
trees to get more sunlight to grow,
Tom thought that he would cut it down.
That Bobby's house was located
in this chestnut tree.
Tom could hardly be expected to know.
What should I do?!
What really should I do?!
My, oh, terrible!
What a terrible thing to do!
You think Bobby is alright?
What's the matter, Bowser?
Did you find something?
Here, Bowser!
Oh my, Johnny, this is quite a predicament!
Oh-oh, this means curtains for Bobby!
My-my, that's terrible!
No! Now, Bowser, come here!
It won't come out if you're standing there!
Nobody's here!
Hey, it's Bobby!
He's safe!
Hey!
Oh, my leg hurts, my leg!
Hurts!
I'll just have to tie this old hound dog up.
Don't know when to make noise
and when to keep quiet.
Walk over here and see how this
old raccoony fellow is doing.
What's the matter?
Oh, I see! When the tree fell,
you hurt yourself!
OK!
OK, I know!
Now just be quiet, Bobby!
Now just relax here, old fellow!
Come on, relax!
Bobby's been caught, hasn't he, Johnny,
I know Bobby's been caught!
Gosh!
It's alright, fellows, nobody's here!
B-B-B-Bobby!
Where in the world is he?!
Peter, I'll go see for you!
Johnny, Peter, everybody wait here!
It's very dangerous to wander out, you know!
Let just see, anyway,
I guess I'll start checking from here!
Sure is dark. Dark places are not for me.
Bobby!
Did you find him?
What a fright!
Oh, now, be quiet!
Probably a little uncomfortable,
but have a little patience.
Just until I get these bandages.
I don't want to be bitten, you know!
Bobby's here! There, see?
See where Bobby is?
Inside that little shack!
Tom has Bobby all tied up so he can't move!
There was also a knife close by!
- A knife?!
I think this just might become
something terrible!
Now try and bear it.
Now-now, little raccoony,
just a little patience!
This is terrible!
Tom is restraining Bobby and Bobby is crying!
Johnny, wait!
It's over there.
That's were Tom came out!
Let's go!
Go, Johnny!
Bobby!
Johnny!
Peter and Polly are waiting outside!
Hurry, hurry, let's go!
Thank you, Johnny!
Johnny, Tom is coming!
Tom is heading this way!
Bobby, can you stand up?
Now, let's go, Bobby!
Johnny, Tom!
Tom is coming!
Johnny, Johnny, Tom is coming!
Tom will be here any moment!
Tom is here!
Bobby, I'll be back!
For sure I'll be back!
Now little raccoony, it's time to eat.
Well, I'll leave it here.
And you better eat it later.
Boy, he can't fool me.
Who's gonna eat that food?
To ward off such an action, Tom had applied
medicines on the bandages.
Bobby was so unhappy.
He could hardly bear it.
Finally he began to cry.
Bobby had not eaten a single bite
since becoming a captive.
To live as a captive...
...better to die, he thought.
Well...
...just little might not matter!
Bobby was captured by Tom.
How frightened he must've been!
But now, everything,
but everything is changed!
He's starting to recognize Tom's footsteps,
and when he draws near, he's happy.
Well, good morning!
You almost got me, you little rascal!
Gee, I wonder what's going on in there!
Oh, you almost got me, but not quite.
Watch this!
I see, Bobby is playing with Tom
just waiting for the chance to escape!
But he can't bite through a steel chain!
Yeah...
That is impossible!
Better give up trying to save Bobby, Johnny!
I think just like Uncle Billy says!
Me too! I give up!
Huh! What a lot of fraidy-cats!
Fraidy-cats, fraidy-cats, fraidy-cats!
What can we do, Johnny?
I'll keep trying.
I promised Bobby that I would save him
without fail.
Really?!
Johnny, would you please
let me help too?
Yes, I will too! We must save Bobby,
we must rescue our friend!
But after a while, a change
is taking place in Bobby.
Everyday restlessness sets in.
In due time, his appetite had disappeared.
However, one day
Tom brought a fish for dinner.
The instant he saw that,
Bobby knew clearly what he wanted to do.
He wanted to return to the Green Forest!
There's the place!
Hey!
Bobby, Bobby!
Bobby!
Johnny!
It's alright, nobody's here!
Oh, Johnny's disappeared!
My, how fast!
Hello, Bobby!
Here we are, here we are!
Say, Bobby, sure missed you!
Say, Bobby, what type of guy
is Tom anyway, eh?
Johnny!
- Oh, Polly!
- Huh?!
We are in trouble, Polly,
if you don't keep watch outside!
Terrific!
What a terrific tap!
Oh, this is terrible, terrible, terible!
Oh, terrible!
Oh, Peter, cut out, cut it out!
Stop, Peter, stop it!
That Peter is cruel!
Oh, Bobby is being carried off!
They're heading towards the Green Forest!
I'll bite Tom's leg and the two of you
run around him real fast
and he may think that there are many of you!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs