FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Poor Mrs. Quack"
Laughing Brook...
...flows through the center
of the Green Forest...
...across the Green Meadow...
...and empties into the far distant...
Big River.
Polly, I heard the sound of guns again.
Do you hear it?
Wherever do you think it is?
Oh... that sounds like it's
really near the Big River!
Scary, isn't it?
Johnny, Polly, Peter too?
Since this morning at the Big River
seems that something terrible is occurring!
W-w-w-what kind of terrible thing is it?
What kind of thing?
I don't know, Peter, I don't know!
I just heard this from Blackie the Crow,
so I don't know any of the details at all!
But never before has there been
such continuous gunshots!
I don't know what to think about it,
but I'm scared!
It seems to me that the sound
is getting louder, Johnny!
I wonder if this forest is safe!
Sure it's safe, Polly!
Sure this forest is safe!
They won't come here!
Polly, even if they do come, I'll protect you
so it will be safe for you and all of us!
What's so funny, Sammy?
Eh...?!
Tell me...
Nothing.
Peter, what's so funny?
Why, now that you ask about it, I guess
there's really nothing funny about it, at all!
Absolutely!
Peter, where ar you going so fast?
Well, if I go as far as the Smiling Pool,
I might be able to learn something
about those gunshots!
Peter...
Are you trying to get there ahead of me?
Johnny...!
Are you going?
Johnny! Don't go!
What?
The gunshots may start all over again!
Polly...
I'm not going, Polly.
There they go!
The forest number one curiosity seeker, Peter,
and the number one news monger, Sammy,
racing again to be first to learn
about the situation.
What will happen?
Mrs. Quack, it's better not to overwork yourself!
Do your grooming when you've regained
your strength completely!
Yes... but to wash one's face in the morning
is just good personal hygiene!
How true, but...
Oh...!
Is it you, Spotty?
Fortunately, your wounds are light,
but you are hurt. You musn't overdo it!
And Father Frog is the number one well
informed person in this lake, you know!
And furthermore, you just made a long trip
and you should be tired...
Quite true, quite true...
That's right! And Grandfather Frog
is really considerate!
You should take a little rest!
That's enough flattery!
Usually you're talking behind my back
saying what a talkative old man I am!
Never... what?
That-that Spotty!
You...
you're a cheat, Spotty!
Eh, that's awful!
Who's there? Who?
It's me! Me, Peter!
Is everybody alright?
Oh, so it's you, Peter!
Oh, what's up?
I heard the sound of gunshots, so I came
to investigate. Is everybody alright?
That so! That Peter, he's the most
gentle guy in the forest,
and also the most curious, Mrs. Quack.
I can vouch for that, I'll tell you!
The most curious in the forest, you say?
Now that you mention it,
those long ears look like it, don't they?!
Well, I never...
Peter and Sammy stared amazed
at this strange bird.
It looked like a duck, but it was
the first time they've seen a bird like this.
Small in size, a brownish colour,
it presented a neat, trim, appearance.
So, you're Mrs. Quack, the migratory duck.
Peter, what in the world are you
so surprised that?
Well, I never expected to find Mrs. Quack here.
I thought that I would have to go
over there, to the Big River, to meet her.
Well... Peter, since you put it like that,
I feel at ease...
No one will ever think that
you're here, Mrs. Quack.
So, rest here until your wounds heal.
Eh...?!
Did something happen, Mrs. Quack?
Mrs. Quack has just fled from the Big River!
Just fled the river?
It's really sad...
Does that wound hurt you?
Yes... a little.
What a terrible wound!
You'd better not move around!
Actually, Mrs. Quack is on her way home
to the North from the South,
that's why she came here.
In order to rest and eat she made
a stop to the Big River.
Some men were waiting over there
and she was shot.
How barbaric!
While you're floating out there on the pond...
...why don't you tell us how all this
happened to you, Mrs. Quack,
we'd realy like to know.
I hurried my children together,
and as we were flying off, I was shot.
Oh my, what happened?
Therefore, I and my children
ran as fast as we could and then...
...a terrible pain ran through
the base of my wing
and everything turned black.
What a turn of events!
What a scary experience!
Then, I don't know how much later,
I had the feeling someone called me!
It must've been terrible for you, Mrs. Quack!
On recovering my senses, I found I have
fallen to the underbrush of the Big River.
It was Joe, the friendly otter,
who revived the lady!
Joe, eh?!
Uh-huh, uh-huh! That he was the one
who found you, was most fortunate...
Yes, Joe told me that going to Smiling Pool
would be the safest place.
And... is your wound alright?
Yes, if I rest a while.
Righto, better not move about.
Please, forgive me,
I've caused you great concern.
In this world...
...one saves and is saved.
Don't be apologetic!
OK! I'd better tell all our forest friends
about Mrs. Quack's predicament!
Take care!
That's the kind of guy he is,
all buttermilk, Peter!
Goodbye!
Take care of yourself, OK?
Oh, that's our news caster, Sammy,
the poke-a-nose jay!
News, news, terrible news!
That will never do!
To the forest people, I'll be one step ahead!
A disaster, a disaster!
Everyone gather at the Green Meadows!
After being called by Peter and Sammy,
everyone quietly assembled by the Lone Pine.
Here they all had a lengthy discussion.
And what do you suppose they decided to do?
As a result of this discussion,
everyone headed towards Mr. Brown's farm.
- It's Red!
- Uh-hm!
Mrs. Quack, quick-quick!
Go hide in those bushes over there!
Oh... alright!
What's up, Red?
Out for a walk out here, huh?
Sure is funny!
What is?
Something smells so good out here!
What are you saying? As you can see,
this is the same unchanging pool!
Something does smell very good!
Since when did your nose go bad?
What did you say?
Looks like you won't catch any game with
your lack of smell... Sort of feel sorry for you!
How about it?
I'll let you eat me if you like!
What a nasty old man!
No satisfaction eating the likes of you,
you wrinkled old frog!
That's very though!
What a relief!
He's gone, he's gone!
Come out, Mrs. Quack!
About that time, Johnny and his friends
had made plans about how to help Mrs. Quack.
It's OK, nobody's here, Peter!
So... that's it!
For the sake of the very hungry Mrs. Quack,
Johnny and his friends had decided
to sneak into Mr. Brown's barn
and take some of that corn
that Mrs. Quack loves so very-very much.
And the responsability
of sneaking into the barn...
- The coast is clear!
- Yeah, let's go!
- They've been spotted!
- What do we do?!
The-the-the jig's up!
What a relief!
But Tom had guessed that Peter
and Chatterer had come to look for the corn.
So he scattered the corn
in a conspicuous place.
And left... pretending ignorant.
Tom loved very much the animals of the forest.
One, two, three, four, five...
Oh, it's Bowser! Run, run!
- Yeow!
- Oh, my goodness!
Chatterer, hurry and flee!
Chatterer!
Take that!
- Chatterer!
- Johnny!
Johnny!
Johnny! Are you alright?
- Did you get him, Johnny, did you get him?
- Terrific, terrific!
Gosh, too bad it happened to old Bowser!
I should have confidence in my feet,
but I was so frightened
that I was petrified with fear!
- Yes!
- Mhm-mhm...!
That's how it is when one is frightened!
Is that so...?
But-but... look at how Johnny
was able to run!
Should I say how impressed I was
with Johnny's courage, or how amazed?
Yeah, and I always felt
he was such a simpleton!
We can laugh about it now, but I really thought
that Peter and Chatterer were caught!
I was scared!
Yeah, that Bowser is really scary!
Weren't you scared, Chatterer?
Uh, Chatterer, weren't you scared?
- Chatterer, were you scared?
- Not a bit, you sissy!
Thank you very much!
Just for me?!
Don't cry, Mrs. Quack,
we did what we had to do,
because we want you to regain your health.
It's nothing to make a fuss over!
You shouldn't be crying at all! Huh?
- That's right, that's right!
Thank you, everyone!
This is the first time that I have ever
received such a warm kindness!
I have mustered my courage!
I will not to be scared or sorrowful again!
I have feasted on the food from your heart,
and the hurt from my wound
has lessened thanks to you all!
I will muster my courage and try my wings!
I'm going to try to fly, everyone!
Please, watch!
She's flying!
Hey, look at her fly!
Hey hey!
Mrs. Quack, the duck, warmed by
the friendship of Johnny and the others,
flew gracefully upward over the lake.
There's no more beautiful soul
than one that is kind to others.
Johnny and his friends knew this,
and now, experiencing such a feeling,
they felt an acute joy
from the bottom of their hearts.
Johnny and all the forest animals
had protected Mrs. Quack
with their help and friendship.
Subtitle: South Wind Subs