FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Yes, I sing of the Forest,
A merry, merry song,
'cause in the Green Forest,
Life is good all day long!
Even singing doesn't help when you're hungry...
Okay... Alright...
There is only one solution...
And that is to steal a chicken
from farmer Brown's henhouse!
Don't go, Reddy, it is dangerous to go
to the farm in broad daylight!
Granny...
Yes, it's dangerous.
But if I succeed, I'll make you happy!
But what if the dog catches you?
Do not fear, Granny,
I'm smarter than Bowser the dog!
I'll get a chicken!
Huh?
Today's episode:
"Granny fox and Reddy"
What are they doing?
Remove your ear!
Look...
- Look how beautiful he circles...
- Whitetail the hawk!
That's an old acquaintance.
Keep your ear to yourself!
Amazing how high the hawk can fly...
Your ear, I can't see!
Oh...
Good...
This is the best chance I've got!
Terrible!
Terrible! Terrible!
Listen to me, listen...
Look... Sammy...
He's got some news.
Oh, I saw something terrible,
eh... eh...
It was something black and huge,
and there was smoke everywhere!
- Oh! Fire?
- No, no fire!
No fire, it was a black-smoke-making monster!
A black-smoke-making monster?
Yes...  near the bridge!
On the left side of the river, there...
It was terrible!
Gosh!
Why do you laugh, Peter?
That was no monster, it was a train!
That's a railroad.
That's funny! So, Peter, you know it?
Well, I couldn't believe my eyes
and that never happens!
It is a huge-huge black monster,
eh, Peter? And very ugly!
It makes more noise
than Buster the Bear,
and the ground shakes when it passes...
Gosh, you can't imagine!
What, what, what?!
Yes, and it goes really fast,
- ...nobody anywhere can be faster!
- That's right.
And as you know, I can run pretty fast!
Well, I'm not saying Peter is slow,
but that monster is much faster!
- That's right.
- Hey!
I was just listening for a minute.
But you are forgetting something.
What's that?
The fastest of all is me,
as you are well aware!
Monster or no monster,
if I'll race it, I'll win!
Hmm, really? I don't know, Reddy...
Oh... what?
If you are the fastest,
why don't you catch me
and Chatterer then?
Ah, pooh! I'll catch you later.
Now, me and my Granny we'll do an experiment,
and I'd prefer something better
than a scrawny rabbit, and a tough squirrel!
I'm off on a big adventure,
everyone in the forest will hear soon!
Well... got to go now...
You'll hear! Goodbye!
Huh? What does he mean?
Sammy, where is Reddy off to?
Hm, I'll go and see!
Huh? The henhouse on the farm?
In broad daylight?
I'm going to the farm,
to see what he's up to!
Could be fun!
See you!
Here he is! Of course...
Attention! Attention, sound the alarm!
Hurry up! There's a chicken thief!
There he is!
Reddy is stealing chickens!
He's in the chicken house!
Oh... where can I go?
Good! Get him!
Darn, I didn't lock the door!
That's not so nice of Sammy.
Fortunately Bowser can't keep up with Reddy!
Oh, dear, what will Granny say?
Oh, poor me!
Reddy Fox, you're a fool!
Going to the farm in daylight!
Granny, then you know?
Of course I know!
I saw everything, everything!
To go there in broad daylight,
well, it's the most stupid thing you can do!
If Sammy hadn't told...
Quiet! Was it Sammy's fault
you were trapped and acting like a fool?
If the door hadn't been open, then what?
Come along... then I'll show you
how you should catch dinner!
When do you finally learn
to stand on your own feet, eh?
How fast!
I was scared! That whistle!
And I never imagined that monster
could make so much noise...
What a horrible thing!
Horrible!
Well, wasn't it exactly like I told you?
And it's even worse up close!
Yes... that's true... it is a monster!
That's right!
Look... Reddy and Granny Fox!
What are they doing here?
They have no bussiness here?
Yes, what are they up to?
Well, Reddy, pay attention...
Watch closely and follow me!
B-b-but I'm scared, Granny!
I don't want to, please, Granny!
Why, you coward, are you afraid?
Look closely.
Stop trembling!
I don't dare to cross there... it's scary!
You can if you try! Follow me!
Don't force me, Granny!
Attention, Bowser is coming!
Behind you... Bowser! He'll get you!
Oh... save me, Granny!
Why are you laughing, Granny?
What happened, Granny,
why did you stop here?
Never mind!
Tell me, where is Bowser?
Argh. He was not here.
If I hadn't yelled, Bowser was coming,
you would not have crossed the bridge.
How mean, Granny, you lied!
You shouldn't have done that!
What's the meaning of crossing the bridge, then?
Reddy is a chicken!
He is a coward!
He's afraid of Bowser!
The son of Granny Fox...
...is afraid of Bowser!
- Reddy is a coward!
- He's afraid of Bowser!
He is a coward!
Reddy is a coward!
He's afraid of Bowser!
Son of Granny Fox:
Bowser is coming!
- Reddy is a coward!
- He's afraid of Bowser!
He is a coward!
Reddy is a coward!
He's afraid of Bowser!
Son of Granny Fox:
Bowser is coming!
Well? How did it go, Granny?
It went well this time, yeah?
Why was I so scared at first?
But, tell me, Granny...
Why are we here?
Why did we cross this stupid bridge?
Can you explain?
There is the smoke-making monster, Granny!
It will attack us!
Okay, Reddy, watch closely now to what I'll do!
What are you going to do, Granny?
Stay there and sit still, okay?
Have to jump!
Oh, Granny!
- Did you see, Reddy?
- Yes, Granny!
To stay safe you need
more than just fast legs...
What I did now was to use my brain,
and I hope you'll do that too...
You used your brain, Granny?
Yes, that's right. And Reddy: even you
can learn to use your brain!
Hm... yes, Granny, now I see!
Reddy is my name,
A crafty fox, that's right!
My courage is my fame,
I'll win every fight...
Why is Reddy singing like that?
Hello!
Hi, friends!
How are you?
Coward Reddy!
- Are you afraid to go to the farm in daytime?
- Coward!
You're much too afraid of Bowser!
Coward! Coward!
What do you say?
I'm no longer afraid of Bowser!
Oh, no?
No, I'm just smarter than him,
that's all!
Reddy, is that so?
- Yes, that's so!
- Don't believe it!
I don't either!
Okay, we shall see!
Tomorrow when the black monster arrives,
meet me at the bridge,
and I'll ridicule that stupid Bowser!
You'll see! Because my name is Reddy!
That's settled...
I'll tell everyone, okay, Reddy?
Marvelous!
Invite everyone who likes
to celebrate my triumph!
See you at the bridge!
Listen up, listen!
I've got big news!
Johnny, Polly! Tomorrow at the bridge,
when the monster arrives,
Reddy is challenging Bowser.
See you there!
Really, a duel?
- A duel?
- Hm-hm!
Chatterer and Peter poked up Reddy...
- ...that's why!
- Hm-hm!
Why do they meddle?
Peter and Chatterer are troublemakers!
The black monster is coming!
And so is Bowser!
Look, Reddy and Bowser!
Where is he now?
Did he fell into the river?
Well, fine, serves him right!
Reddy didn't expect this to happen!
Bowser is very near now...
Will Reddy be able to escape?
Because he is being chased,
he can't go directly home.
And Bowser doesn't give up easily,
and he has a sharp nose.
If Reddy doesn't shake him off,
Bowser is going to know where they live,
and Granny will not like that!
Hey, Reddy, you're so valiant,
prove your courage!
I thought you were no coward?
Well, go on, Reddy... Coward!
Get him! Get him!
Well, what's the matter, Reddy?
Show us!
Shame on you, Reddy!
What would Granny think?
Poor Reddy.
Reddy, go to the forest!
Over the hill!
Bowser can't catch you there!
You're faster than him!
Reddy!
Go to the forest, over the hill.
You won't get caught there!
To the forest!
- To the forest, over the hill!
- Bowser can't catch you there!
Thank you!
- Hurry, Reddy, don't get caught!
- Hurry, Reddy, run faster!
And with some help from his friends,
Reddy's story happy ends!
Translation: Peter & Edit: Mónica
Subtitle: South Wind Subs