FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Sammy gets mocked"
There it is! That's the Green Forest,
that must be it, where Uncle Billy lives!
I finally found it!
One day, a strange bird arrived
at the Green Forest.
It seems he is a southern friend
of Uncle Billy, the Possum.
Well... Good Day!
Is this the Green Forest where Uncle Billy lives,
I would like to ask you!
Yes, it is.
And who are you, please?
No, nevermind, it doesn't really matter now.
I'll meet you all formally later. I'll see you!
- That one, what is he, sure is peculiar!
- Yeah.
Undoubtedly, he's not a friend of Uncle Billy,
of that I'm sure.
My-my-my, but this is such a very large forest!
I don't know!
I just don't know where
to start looking for Uncle Billy!
Thief, thief, thief! Who is it that stole
my breakfast, who is it that stole my breakfast?
I've got a good idea!
Now, you should cut that out!
You should...
Oh, come on now, cut it out!
Dear! Instead of just playing with the children,
why don't you go out
and find something to dine on?
How about it?
I know, I know, I was just thinking
a lot about you, Mommy!
You always say I know, I know,
I know, I know but you never do!
Just like last night!
Oh, you don't have to nag me like that!
I know, I know, indeed!
Come on now, kids,
you go on back to the house now, go on back!
Well I'm going now, Mommy, bye!
Oh... shocks!
Really, I don't know what to do
with that stupid husband!
Hey, Uncle Billy!
Johnny! Polly!
Uncle Billy, that friend of yours seems
to have come a long way just to see you!
A strange one, isn't it?
My friend? Who?
Oh, haven't you met him yet?
It's that bird with the shrill voice!
No...
...I haven't met him yet.
But... My friend with the shrill voice, she say.
Wearing a very different brownish colored suit.
A brownish colored suit...
Hmm...!
What?! That guy?
Here, in the Green Forest?
Just a while ago, near the Clover Hill.
He was asking Polly and me about you,
Uncle Billy.
Oh, really?!
Why, that guy, well, oh my!
When Uncle Billy thought about his friend
from the days in the distant Southern Virginia,
and that he was here now in the Green Forest,
he became extremely excited by his memories.
I haven't seen him, but...
I'll look for him!
Sure is funny! Someone with sharp ears like you
not knowing about him!
Well, I'll keep it in mind and search for him.
But, tell me, what does this person look like?
Well, he's a friend of mine from long ago
in that good South country.
Well... please don't bother, Peter,
I don't think you can find him.
You see, Johnny and Polly
told me this friend of mine
from the South country
was up here looking for me,
but I can't find anybody else
who knows anything about it,
and I think they're just wrong!
Uncle Billy, you never told me
what he looked like!
Don't bother to ask,
I didn't see him around here!
Well, now...
if even Drummer doesn't know, I...
...it may just all be a big misunderstanding
but I guess I'll better keep looking...
Dear, where were you wandering
about until now?
Why in Heaven's name
did you not come back sooner?
Oh my...!
Oh!
You know we were all waiting for you
with empty stomachs!
I'm sorry, dear!
Oh, now, Mother, forgive me,
why, I was just looking for my friend
from the South country!
Really...?!
You can be so trying!
Uncle Billy was at a loss for a reply.
He felt absolutely terrible.
Furthermore, he was exhausted
from walking about all day.
Dear!
You're hungry... aren't you, Billy?
Oh, I sure am!
Why, I haven't had a bite to eat all day long!
If you've eaten, hurry up and go to bed!
The bed is already made up!
Hurry up and come to sleep,
you know the night wind is very poisonous!
Alright, Mother, I know, I know,
I'll be right up, good night!
My wife... her barks lot worse than her bite,
she tries to hide it, you know,
but her soul is really very tender
and I love her a great deal!
I'm off, Mother!
Well, good morning, smiling sun!
Today I'm gonna try find
my friend, Mocker, real hard!
Today...
Good old easy-going Uncle Billy
was eager to work hard
for the sake of his family...
...and he wasn't going to let himself
be side-tracked by a lot of little things.
Having eaten a hearty breakfast,
what a really pleasant morning it is,
it is, it is...!
Say, Sammy, what were you doing up
so late last night?
I heard you until all hours of the morning!
Ah, what are you talking about?
I wasn't up that late last night,
I'm telling you!
You know, Sammy, you really oughta
tell the truth every once in a while.
You kept me awake all last night
after the sun went down
making all that disturbance by the Green Forest!
What happened, huh?
I need my sleep!
I'm telling the truth, I went to bed as usual
and didn't wake up till this morning!
How can you dare accuse me of that?
Then you must've been talking
awfully loud in your sleep!
Liars, liars, liars,
liars, liars!
Darn, darn...
What's going on, anyway?
Hey, Sammy!
Wasn't that noise that you made
last night enough for you,
do you have to bother us today as well?!
Don't be funny, Peter! This is the second time
already this morning!
I slept soundly last night,
and to be told that I was causing
the disturbance, bothers the heck out of me!
Hmm... then you must sleep awfully funny.
Now, tell the truth, Sammy, why were you
flying about the Green Forest,
shouting "thief, thief" when all of us
were trying to sleep here?
Peter, you and Jimmy too must've
something wrong with your heads.
You're crazy! Now listen, I was asleep,
now why would I have anyone trying
to accuse me of something I didn't do?
I wouldn't mistake you voice, Sammy,
I know it very well!
If Hooty the Owl hears you,
you'll be finished!
Now, don't shout about and keep us up!
Sammy is furious,
but he doesn't know what to do.
Are they trying to make me angry,
or did I really shout out in my sleep?!
Sammy, the talkative jay, has never been
as angry as this before.
Although he doesn't remember
a thing about it,
most of the forest animals are complaining
that they couldn't sleep well last night,
because Sammy was making such a commotion
all night long.
But what's going on? Sammy wonders.
Am I going completely crazy?
There goes Sammy, the sleepyhead jay,
Shout all day long,
Not having enough during the daytime,
Sammy also shouts during the night,
And we can't sleep, no-no-no-no!
It's a lie, it's a lie, it's a lie!
Oh-oh, crazy Sammy,
he's asleep-eep-eep...
Sleepy jay Sammy,
Oh-oh, crazy Sammy!
It's a lie, it's a lie, it's a lie!
Please, let him sleep...!
Sleepyhead Sammy!
He's going to be very surprised,
- When we won't let him sleep!
- It's a lie, it's  lie, it's a lie!
It's the truth, really, I slept all night long!
Sammy, are you sure you don't remember
anything that happened?
But you may have been half asleep,
don't you think?
Johnny, are you going to doubt me too?
I don't dance and jump around at night
like everybody is saying!
Uh-huh, that is true, I don't doubt you!
That's funny, if I hadn't heard it myself!
Do you think everyone could be
making fun of Sammy?
It's the truth!
It's causing quite a commotion
throughout the forest!
- It's a lie, it's a lie!
- I assure you the one who's lying is Sammy!
It's just like Jenny said!
Hmm... I agree!
What is this?!
It's a lie, everyone's lying!
Sure is funny!
Sammy says last night he was sleeping,
and everyone else says
he was raising a ruckus all night long!
Couldn't it be that there are two Sammys,
couldn't it, huh?
That's it, that's it, that's it!
Everyone's mistaken someone else's voice
for mine!
Who would ever mistake Sammy's voice?
That "This is terrible, this is terrible"
was without a doubt Sammy's voice!
That's right, oh, I guess it won't work, Sammy!
- That's right!
But... but it wasn't me, it wasn't me!
Sure, sure...!
But sleep quietly tonight, Sammy!
What do you mean by that, huh?
Anyway, it's all settled!
OK, Sammy?
Now, you remember that!
Well, goodnight everybody...
Yeah, try to get some sleep now, Sammy...
Not true, not true, not true!
It's all not true, not true, not true!
What should I do now, Johnny?
Let's see...
Be sure you aren't half asleep tonight,
uh, Sammy?
It's a mistake, I keep on telling you it's a lie,
it's a mistake, I keep telling you
it's a mistake, it's a lie, it's a lie!
OK, this being the case, I'll see with
my own eyes. I'll keep lookout!
Better get plenty of sleep for now,
otherwise I'll be very tired tonight!
Sammy was worried.
He had never slept so late,
with the sun high in the sky...
Still can't sleep... Maybe I can sleep
in that dark spot over there...
Ah, Uncle Billy!
Oh, John and Polly, you're going for a walk too?
Yeah... that is there's something bothering me
and I thought of asking you about it,
Uncle Billy.
Oh, there's something you want to ask me?
Sammy...? All night long...?
Sammy insists that it's absolutely not him,
but everyone says that they
could not mistake Sammy's voice.
T-that's it!
Why, that's his voice!
You... you did say for certain
that a bird from the South
came to visit me yesterday, didn't you, Johnny?
I admit I did say that.
But what about it?
Well, that's the answer!
Oh my, oh my!
What a guy! He's really here!
Well, now Sammy's half asleep,
ruckus over the day,
just tell the forest people to sleep peaceful
tonight and leave the rest to me!
Uncle Billy! Billy!
I wonder what's really going on...
Not scared... not scared...
I will find out the truth...
not scared...
Not scared... not scared...
Not scared, not scared, not scared!
Aha, I'm sure that Peter the Rabbit is going
to eat the corn from Mr. Brown's corn field!
How lucky to be easy-going like Peter!
I've been watching and I haven't seen anything!
Was I really half asleep when I did what
everybody says I did if I did it?
This is terrible, this is terrible!
Oh, this is terrible!
This is terrible, this is terrible,
this is terrible, this is terrible!
I'm not really half asleep!
I'm right here completely awake!
This is terrible, this is terrible!
This is terrible, this is terrible...
If this is my voice...
...then who could that be?
Hmm... it was about here, for sure...
This is terrible, this is terrible,
this is terrible, this is terrible!
this is terrible!
That's my voice! I'm really over there!
Stop it! Stooop!
Stop it, stop it, stop it!
Stop it, stop it, stop it, stop it,
stop it!
- Stop it, stop...
- That's my voice for sure, I...
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop!
It's no use... I'm going crazy...
Out of my mind!
It's terrible, terrible, it's terrible!
This is terrible... this is terrible...
this is terrible... this is terrible!
U-u-u-uncle Billy... I'm absolutely certain
I'm going completely crazy!
This is terrible, this is terrible,
this is terrible,
this is terrible, this is terrible,
this is terrible!
Well, just follow me!
This is terrible, this is terrible,
this is terrible!
- Well, you can't fool me, I know his habits well!
- This is terrible, this is terrible!
This is terrible, this is terrible,
this is terrible, this is terrible!
Ah... well?
I'll introduce you my friend:
that's Mocker the Mockingbird!
Mocker the Mockingbird, is that what you're
saying, Uncle Billy, is that what you're saying?
Oh, that's enough fooling around for now.
So how about coming out here, Mocker?
Well, how you've been doing, Uncle Billy?
You've come a long way, Mocker,
welcome, welcome, I'm glad to see you!
But one thing for sure, you haven't changed
a bit, you still love to fool around!
After all, I've come a long way to see you again,
and I wanted our meeting to be a fun thing!
Well, so we meet again in the soft moonlight,
it's good to see you, Mocker!
Then my voice was his?
Are you sure, Uncle Billy?
Mocker is a real expert in imitations, you know!
Forgive me, Sammy, will you ever forgive me?
Are you kidding?!
That sounds just like my voice!
Darn, you fool, why imitate my voice,
why imitate my voice, why imitate my voice?!
It must've been because Sammy
is the noisiest one in the forest!
I apologise, excuse me, Sammy!
Do you think just apologising is enough?
Thief!
Nah-nah, you make such ruckus
all the forest people
are gonna wake up and chase you out of here!
For today I forgive you,
but someday I'll get my revenge,
of this you can be sure!
You voice thief!
I guess I really shouldn't have done
that to him, I guess it wasn't fair!
Ah, I'm saying sometimes it's good for him
to be punished!
Anyway, I want to introduce you to my friends!
Please do, Uncle Billy, I'd like to meet them!
Well, now, you just leave it to me!
You're going to come with me to my house tonight
and we're going to spend the whole evening
talking over old times!
I'd like that, I really would!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs