FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"The big commotion in the forest"
Momma, we are hungry, we are hungry!
We are hungry, oh, where is the food...
We are hungry, we are hungry!
- Momma, we are hungry!
- Momma!
My husband! How long do you intend to sleep?
Enough is enough, get up! Oh...!
I wonder where he went...!
What on earth are you doing there?!
Don't just daydream!
Hurry and go to work, can't you hear the children
crying with an empty stomach?!
How can you be nonchalantly viewing the sky,
there's no time to be wondering
about the weather!
Get this, there are five children waiting
with mouths open, don't forget that!
I know, Mother, I know!
Mmm...
Now, I wonder just where in the world
that Mocker could've got to...!
The big commotion in the forest!
I don't understand! Hey, what's happening,
what's happening, hey, what is this?!
I don't understand, what's happening?!
Well, good morning, Sticky,
what's the matter with you, huh?
What's the matter with Sticky,
something bothering him?
What's the matter, Sticky?
I wonder what's the matter with him.
Hey, Sticky!
- What's the matter, Sticky?
I can hear my voice,
I just don't understand it!
I'm not saying anything,
but I can still hear my voice!
I'm not saying a word but I can hear my voice
from the bank over there!
Don't be silly, Sticky!
Right, Johnny?
It's true, if you go with me to Laughing Brook
you'll see! I'm not lying!
This is the place!
From the bank over there!
I can hear it!
This is Sticky!
That's not true! I'm Sticky!
This is Sticky! This is Sticky!
I'm Sticky! I'm Sticky!
This is Sticky!
No, you're not, I'm Sticky,
I'm the real Sticky, I'm Sticky!
I'm Sticky, I'm Sticky, yes, I am,
I am Sticky!
No, you're not, I'm the real Sticky,
look at me, I am Sticky!
I'm Sticky, I'm the real Sticky!
Right, guys, you know I'm the real one!
I'm the real Sticky, right?
I am Sticky, I am Sticky!
- I am Sticky!
- Huh...?!
I am Sticky!
I'm the real one, over here!
I'm Sticky!
I'm Sticky! This is Sticky!
I'm Sticky! Over here!
This is Sticky!
Oh...
There are two Stickys!
I'm Sticky!
I'm going crazy, I'm Sticky!
That was funny!
You're really a genius in imitating!
I'm glad I've got a friend like you!
We can really have some fun now!
I've got it!
I can think of some really funny tricks, uh-hu!
Mocker, I've got some good ideas
for some funny tricks!
I'll tell you what we can do...
And we can do this... and...
This is genius...!
Oh, hey, Mocker!
Oh! Hi, Uncle Billy!
You know, Mocker, I thought I'll introduce you
to all the forest folks today, now come along!
Introduce?! No, no, no way!
If everybody knew about Mocker,
that would spoil all of our fun! Right?
Right, Mocker?
Come on, let's go!
See you later, Uncle Billy, bye!
He... He-he-hey wait, Mocker, wait, oh, wait a while!
Oh... Mocker is become... friendly
with a terrible guy...
Chatterer...!
Hey, Chatterer!
What's up, Peter, you have some business?
Why are you such a fool,
a blockhead and an idiot?!
What?!
Fool, fool, idiot!
What?! Oh boy...
Let's get out of here,
he's coming, he's coming!
Come out, come out, come out, don't run off,
where are you, Peter, come on,
come on, where are you?
Hmm... where is he?!
He's run off!
I can't figure it out!
I don't understand it... Oh!
Why, you better watch out!
Hey, you mean thing, calling me names,
that was awfull!
Huh...?!
I never said a thing!
Yes, you did!
Oh!
Oh, Chatterer, are you crazy?
Oh, get out of here, get out,
stop it, stop it!
That's cruel!
To say such bad things!
What, Polly?
What's the matter?
Well... after saying such cruel things...
Really!
Huh?! I didn't say anything!
You called me such mean things, bad and ugly
and oh, that's terrible,
I... oh... how cruel... oh...
You're so cruel! Oh...
You... of all the things, to call me
those terrible things! I hate you!
Polly! Polly, wait!
Don't follow me, I hate you!
Come on, Polly!
Hey, why did you called me all those names for?
You're the one that called me all those names!
It wasn't me, I was just sitting there!
It was you who called me all those names!
You're the one!
No!
Yeah!
- Take back, you first!
- You called!
You quit it! You quit call me those names!
Because of Sammy's and Mocker's mean tricks,
the entire forest creatures were arguing
and fighting among themselves.
Oh my, oh my, oh my!
That guy, Mocker, has really started
some trouble here in the forest!
Uncle Billy!
Between him and Sammy, he's going
- ...to have everybody in the forest mad!
- Uncle Billy!
Oh my... oh, hello, Bobby!
Uncle Billy!
Uncle Billy... do you think we could talk
for a little while...? I'm... very lonely...
Lonely? What in the world
are you talking about, Bobby,
you have a lot of good friends, don't you?
No good, no good, those guys are no good.
They all talk bad behind other people's backs.
The only trustworthy one is you, Uncle Billy.
You are the only one, believe me.
The only one?
Hey, it's Uncle Billy whistling!
How you're doing, Uncle Billy?
Hey, how are you today, Joe?
Fine, thanks!
How are you, Uncle Billy?
- Well, hello there, Harry, how are you?
- What a nice day, going out for a walk?
Yeah, I must've talked entirely
too long with Bobby.
Seems he had a problem
he just couldn't solve alone.
Hey, Uncle Billy, do you mind if I talk
to you about something for a while, huh?
Why, sure, Joe.
Uncle Billy!
I have something to talk to you about!
Will you come over here, please?
Hey, Uncle Billy! Uncle Billy!
Uncle Billy!
Uncle Billy, come here!
Hey, Uncle Billy!
Hey, I got this fish
especially for you, Uncle Billy!
- Why is that for me?!
- Mhm...
Hey, Uncle Billy!
I got this just for you!
I can't stand fish, but I don't want
to hurt his feelings.
- Goodbye, Uncle Billy, goodbye!
- Bye! Bye Uncle Billy!
How are you, Uncle Billy?
Hi, Chatterer!
Hi, Uncle Billy!
- Hi, Uncle Billy!
- Hi, Uncle Billy! Hi, Uncle Bily!
- Hi!
Hi, Uncle Billy!
- Hi, Uncle Billy!
- Hi!
- Hi, hi!
Uncle Billy has become
the popular one of the forest.
Everyone is fond of Uncle Billy.
That is because Mocker has not said
any bad things using Uncle Billy's voice.
Johnny...!
Johnny, you fool!
What a fool you are!
Uncle Billy, is that you?
An idiot and a fool like you
will soon be caught up
by Granny and eaten up!
Fool, fool!
But... what are you saying, Uncle Billy?
Fool, I said you're a fool!
Why are you saying all those
nasty things about me, Uncle Billy?
What's wrong, why are you saying that? Oh!
Feel sort of bad for Uncle Billy!
Uncle Billy said it was OK to play tricks,
didn't he?
No problem, no problem!
You're troubled when's come,
You're lonely when's come,
Come to Uncle Billy,
The popular one in the forest,
The only one to be trusted,
Uncle Billy, Uncle Billy...
Uncle Billy!
Just a moment ago,
why did you say such a thing?
Huh...?!
What?!
Didn't you say that I was a fool and an idiot,
I heard you!
Oh... I did...?!
You said I was a fool and an idiot!
I said such a thing?!
I'll bet it was that Mocker!
Serves you right, hm!
Serves you right, really!
That's what happens when you start feeling
good because everyone is flattering you!
Hey, Uncle Billy, how come you said
such nasty things about me?
Uncle Billy, why did you say
nasty things about me?
Why?!
Uncle Billy the fool, Uncle Billy the fool!
- Yeah, he's a... yeah, fool!
- Fool, fool!
- Yeah, he's a fool!
Listen to me, you troublemakers!
Enough is enough, or I should have
to become very angry!
Hey-hey, good for nothing!
So that's what happened!
What should I do?
If things are left just as they are,
the forest people will never forgive Mocker!
We've got to do something!
I've got an idea!
And a good one at that!
Listen, Uncle Billy! We'll get
all the forest people together,
we'll get them assembled and tell them
what Mocker's been doing!
Is that a good idea?
How about it?
Might work?
Might work! What next?
Now, Uncle Billy, you go to everyone's house
and get them to assemble!
But where... do you think it'd be
a good place for us to assemble?
The Lonesome Pine it'd be a good spot!
People of the Green Forest and Pastures...
...thank you for coming here so willingly!
There is something that is really
gonna startle you folks, today.
OK!
Now listen carefully to this!
I got the news!
It's a fake, it's a fake!
I know all the news!
It's a fake, you don't know,
I got the news, it's a fake!
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
you should understand, that that's not me,
that's someone else who stolen my voice,
now listen up there in the tree!
- Sammy's a liar!
- What?! I'm the real Sammy! What do you mean?
And that's the way it is, ladies and gentlemen!
I'm Sammy, I'm Sammy, I'm Sammy!
I'm Sticky, I'm Sticky!
Just had to imitate your voice, Sticky!
Excuse me, Sticky!
I'm Sticky! Remember Sticky?
I'm Sticky!
Johnny, why did it turn out this way?
I can't understand it either!
Listen, Peter!
Yoo-hoo, tell me, Peter!
It is something that's not my concern,
but really this is a problem!
Who would've thought
that to be alone would be so lonely?
That's my voice!
Croack! That's right, what in the earth is this?
The tranquil Green Forest
has completely become a noisy one!
It's become... like a big commotion!
Why...? Why...? Why...?
Who is in there, anyway?
You don't know who I am by now?
Listen...! Maybe some of you already know,
but the reason for having you
all assembled here
is to introduce you to a new friend!
He'll be living here with us in the Green Forest!
The Mockingbird!
Mocker!
Uncle Billy, introduce me to everybody,
do you mind?
Ladies and gentlemen,
I would like to introduce you
to an extraordinary artist and my old friend:
The Mockingbird Mocker.
Mocker has the world's most wonderful voice!
Furthermore, he can imitate anyone!
By that reason, he has bothered you,
for which I would like to apologise.
If all of you will permit me,
I would like to live here,
with all of you, in the Green Forest.
Altough Uncle Billy and Mocker
were asking for forgiveness,
there were some
who were not inclined to pardon them.
Johnny, what should I do?
I think I may have overdone it!
Oh, it's all right!
Remember, you've got a beautiful voice!
Why not let everyone hear your song, Mocker!
My pleasure!
Everyone's feelings have been soothe
by the beautiful singing
of Mocker, the Mockingbird.
It was so wonderful
that Mocker made many friends.
And he could stay in the Green Forest
for as long as he desired.
Subtitle: South Wind Subs