FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Peter plays a prank"
Oh! Johnny is here already!
Hi, Johnny!
Hello, Polly!
Oh, Johnny, forgive me for being late!
You could've taken your time, Polly,
you didn't have to rush so!
Look, it's not even time for the meeting yet!
I came too early, you see?
Oh, then Peter is not here yet?
That's right.
Peter is a sleepyhead
so I hope he won't be late!
Rest assured!
Remember how yesterday
he told us he would show us
a field of delicious clover!
Yeah...
But I sure am hungry...
I better hurry or I'll never make
my appointment in time!
I wonder who it is!
Why, it's my friend, Jimmy the Skunk!
How lucky Jimmy is!
He needn't be afraid of anyone!
My stars, if only I had a smell bag like Jimmy,
I wouldn't have to be afraid of Reddy
one little tiny bit!
It's Reddy the Fox!
Oh...
Oh... did he notice me?!
Hmm... no, not yet.
Well, what Granny always says to me
is appropriate right now...
Wait! Just wait!
I never expected Reddy to be stalking
at such a place!
What a scare! What do I do,
Johnny and Polly must be waiting!
What a fix! It's already
the appointment time!
Johnny and Polly will be worried!
Oh... And it's already time for me
to be there!
But if I can't go that way,
I'll have to take such a long detour!
If I'm real late
it's like breaking a promise!
What in the world am I ever going to do...?
That's it!
Hey, Peter, hey, Peter,
hey, Peter, hey, Peter!
Hey, Peter, where are you off to?
That's right!
Sammy is quick tempered, if I get him angry,
it might work!
- What's the matter, Peter?
- A-ha...
Be quiet! It's nothing for you to stick
your beak into, you... you gossipy jay!
What?! What did you say?
- You long eared moron!
- Don't bother me! Quiet!
What did you said, you cowardly rabbit?
Sure I said it! No one's as gossipy
as you, pea-brain feather face!
Good...! Now's a wonderful time for me
to catch him!
So he's coming, huh...
OK.
Reddy is in the shadow of that rock.
- OK, Reddy!
- Got you!
Oh, come here!
Hurry, Peter, run, run, run!
Hurry and run away!
Peter, you're pretty far away from home!
Help, help!
- Help!
- What's this?
Sounds like someone's inside!
Who can this be,
I better go find out! Hey!
No...!
Hey, wait for me!
- Help! Help!
- My-my!
Help me! Help me!
Help me!
Help, help!
Help!
Who is the one that played such a trick?
Who, who?
Why, Jimmy...!
So you're the one who played that trick on me!
You know what will happen to anyone
playing tricks on me!
Don't, I beg, I said you're making a mistake...!
Oh, no, it wasn't me!
Oh, no... no-no! Hey-hey stop it!
There, that's what you get!
No-no-no, I told you the truth,
it wasn't me...!
I did it!
Oh, the look on Reddy's face!
Feels like nothing's broken.
But that Reddy...
...he almost broke my neck!
He didn't do it on purpose.
Reddy was...
Eh...
What did you say?
Reddy didn't do it on purpose.
I was watching.
He was chasing Peter, then ran into the keg.
Oh, really...?!
Yeah, Peter jumped over the keg but Reddy
ran into the keg head first!
That's funny...
What's the matter?
Maybe Peter deliberately headed towards
the keg, you see...
Come to think of it, that usually quiet Peter
tried to pick a fight with me...
...very peculiar...
Well, what does that mean, Sammy?
Wait a minute...
It's funny, we haven't seen Peter
after that time, you see.
I've got it!
What did you figure out?
Peter knows that you were inside the keg
taking a nap, you see.
Then, he lured Reddy and made him
play that trick on you!
And then had Reddy punished by you,
do you understand?
Surely Peter wouldn't do such a thing.
No, there's no mistake.
It was Peter's doing!
I'll see Peter and ask him if this is the truth
if this is his doing...
...I'll have to teach him a lesson.
Peter should be around here somewhere, hiding,
so be on the alert.
As a precaution, I'm gonna go check
his briar patch house.
I'll rely on you.
Oh, I never ever thought
that it would be so dangerous...
...and it wasn't just a trick either!
Oh, won't Jimmy ever understand?
Oh, what should I do?
Jimmy is keeping a lookout for me!
Oh, like this I can't escape,
I can't meet Johnny and Polly
at the meeting place...
Oh... what can I do?!
Important news, important news,
I've got important news!
Sammy, what is the important news?
Peter tricked Reddy
which almost got Jimmy killed,
which I believe is terrible!
- What?
- Oh...?!
That guy is really going to get it from Jimmy,
so come and watch!
Really?
Yeah, the top of the Crooked Little Path
is where it's going to start! More fun!
That guy, Peter, isn't anywhere!
No, he should be hiding somewhere close by,
I've searched all over!
Is that so?
Hey, Johnny Chuck!
I'm glad you and Polly are here!
Find him?
Peter that is?
No, not yet.
Help us, please.
Sure we will.
But I just can't believe that Peter
would do such a thing,
he's never done that before...
Are you still saying that?
After all that happened?
No mistake.
Peter planned it.
For example, if a friend has problems,
he will talk it over with Peter,
and in his opinion... he would try to help him.
I understand, Johnny.
I won't try to find Peter anymore.
Really, Jimmy?
Thank you, Jimmy, you're nice.
Yes.
It isn't that I can't understand Peter's feelings,
of using me to get back with Reddy
for all the times Reddy has persecuted him...
...but such things, my...
...it's a small thing when compared to
Johnny's loyalty to his friends.
- I'm glad.
- Yeah, me too.
Oh... What a foolish thing I've done!
Jimmy, Johnny, can you ever forgive me
for this terrible thing?
Fool, fool, fool,
Peter's a big fool!
Oh, that's Peter's voice coming from the cave!
Seems like it!
Here it is, Polly!
It's like he's being attacked by yellow bees!
I'm sure this has taught Peter a big lesson!
Hmm, excuse me, Jimmy, but it seems like...
...I was very much mistaken!
It's OK, Johnny, you weren't wrong,
and now that Peter has been taught
a lesson by the bees,
perhaps he won't be nasty and mean
and play tricks on his friends!
Peter!
Forgive me, Jimmy,
forgive me, Johnny...!
Polly, forgive me!
Ow-ow!
I'm sorry!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs