Mr. and Mrs. Condor, who've come
from a country to the South,
have temporarily decided
to live here, in the Green Forest.
Altough scary looking in apearance,
the condors have not done anything
like atacking live animals...
...and they become great friends also
with Johnny and the forest people.
FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"The secret of Mr. Condor"
He's finely flown over here from
the distant country to the South, hm!
How wonderful!
I too would like to fly high in the sky
with the wind!
Me too, Polly!
But flying up so so high
won't one get dizzy?!
Hmm, he's not like you, Polly!
I'd sure like to go and see
at this country to the South!
That's funny,
usually he's flying with Mrs. Condor!
I wonder if anything has happened
to Mrs. Condor!
Or has she become tired of the Green Forest
and returned to her homeland?
They were always flying together harmoniously
in the past!
That's it! Let's have Mr. Condor tell us
all about the country to the South!
Yes, let's!
Yeah, that's it!
Mrs. Condor must be building a nest,
so that she can lay her eggs
and hatch her family!
All of my bird friends are building nests
all through the forest!
Why didn't I think of it sooner?!
Take the case of Bob, the Quail,
or Tommy, the Tit,
or even old man Northly, all of them
are building nests and brooding their eggs!
The condor couple must have a nest somewhere!
Sure would like to see it!
Boy, would I like to see it!
I've got to see it!
A big bird like the condor couple
must have a large nest,
so it should be simple to find!
And I've got to find it!
Just find a new nest high in a tall tree,
it should be simple!
Nope, not here!
Blackie!
Blackie, where are you?
Hey, Blackie, come here!
Hey... Peter!
Have you seen a large nest around here?
Haven't seen any. Why do you ask?
Oh, no reason.
Just... wondering, that's all.
What's the matter with that guy, Peter?
I never dreamed there were so many trees
in the Green Forest,
I think I'm getting a stiff neck
from looking at them!
What are you doing, Peter?
Hey... Peter?
Hi there, Johnny, pal!
What's the matter, is something wrong
with your neck?
I was looking up at the tops of the trees so much
that now it won't bend!
What on earth are you doing, Peter?
Oh... uh... just looking for something...
How strange!
To have Johnny find Mr. and Mrs. Condor's nest,
would spoil all the fun that I'll have
when I find it!
Now, where did Mr. Condor go to?
Now, why I was so stupid?
Why didn't I noticed this before?
I didn't have to punish my neck searching.
All I had to do is watch Mr. Condor
from a distance.
Sure would like to know...
What do you want to know, Peter?
A nest!
I want to know where the condor's nest is!
Oh, it's around here someplace, I believe.
Around here someplace?
Well, you're a big help to me, Sammy!
Go sit in a tree!
Well, I believe it's around here somewhere,
as I told you a little earlier about
the Condor's nest.
But there's nothing that I can do about it.
I've been flying over the forest,
but I can't possibly pick out that particular
spot for the condor's nest.
Thanks, Sammy.
Look, Peter, I've flown all over the forest
and looking down it's very difficult
to find the condor's nest, I tried!
Oh, I've got it!
Sammy, uh...
...wouldn't you like to know what a great
big bird like a condor has for a nest?
It must be quite a large one!
If you find it for me,
and I know you can, we could...
Yeah-yeah, OK, I'll try to find it.
But Peter, you keep searching for it too, OK?
With Sammy helping,
I know I'll find it now!
Like the clear blue sky that's above,
a wide expanse of water continues far out.
An ocean is so immense.
It's so immense that one cannot see any land,
one looks around and sees nothing but ocean.
- Oh, I'd love... to see an ocean...
- Wow, sure I'd like to see an ocean!
It's not only an ocean,
large cities, cities with lots of humans
living there.
I've lived in those cities
inhabited by those humans.
The cities where the humans live?
Isn't such a scary place very dangerous?
We don't attack any living thing, do we?
So humans don't do anything
against us either, understand?
No matter how well hidden,
if it's there, I know that I'll find it!
Oh... I was sure it was around here...
Oh! Peter! Peter!
It's not under the bush...
It's not behind the tree...
Oh, Johnny, Polly...
Oh, Mr. Condor...
Wh-What are you doing?
What are you all talking about with Mr. Condor?
We were listening some interesting stories
about the country to the South.
Won't you hear it with us, Peter?
Which is bigger, the cities of the country
to the South or Mr. Brown's house?
Do you know?
No comparison, it's many,
many-many times bigger!
Like the Lookout Pine?
Yeah-yeah, such things don't matter.
Mr. Condor, please, tell me
where is your nest, tell me!
Stop it!
Lookout Pine?
Nothing like that! Taller, taller.
Anyway, there are houses and houses
piled on top of which other,
such large houses are called buildings,
and there are many many such buildings!
Oh... Who cares how many buildings there are!
Mr. Condor, you just got to tell me
where your nest is!
- It's not necessary to search.
- Eh?
What?!
We just don't have a nest!
It's a lie, it's a lie that a bird
doesn't have a nest!
All of my friends have built nests,
layed eggs and hatched them,
that's why, Mr. Condor,
you must also have a nest!
So tell me!
Come on and tell me where it is!
Well...
We really don't have a nest.
Oh, come on, Mr. Condor, tell me.
Why not tell me where it is?
I'm not going to do anything bad!
I wanna see, I just wanna see!
Eggs were layed already, right?
How many? Big, I'll bet!
Oh, come on, Mr. Condor, your wife is keeping
them warm! Let me...
Peter!
In the first place, we haven't seen your wife
flying around with you.
Oh? You even noticed that, haven't you?
I thought that the Mrs. must
be brooding the eggs.
Now, to brood eggs a nest is necessary.
Please, tell me where your nest is,
I promise not to tell anyone else where it is.
I'll be the only one to know!
Nobody else will know where the nest is,
just me!
Hey, you two, move away!
- Huh?!
- Well...
We didn't built a nest, that's all!
We just didn't built a nest!
Come on!
Then where is your wife?
What happened, huh?
Surely she hasn't returned
to the country to the South!
She's here, she's definitely here,
busy with the family chores!
F-Family?!
The wife is warming two eggs.
Today or tomorrow,
the two most good looking babies in the
Green Forest should be hatched!
I'm really very excited about it!
But you said you didn't have any nest,
didn't you?
Exactly!
Exactly, absolutely true!
Condors don't have nests at all!
Oh... now you're making fun of me!
I don't mean to!
Then something is odd!
Brooding eggs, no nest...
I would like for you to tell me why
I can only believe half of your story!
Something is very strange here, Mr. Condor!
Believe what you will!
This is the first time
I have ever been doubted, rabbit!
B-But-But...
I told the truth because of your
ridiculous persistent questioning!
Now, if you're still not satisfied,
then you better not ask!
No nest, but his wife is brooding eggs...
Strange...
I just can't believe it, no nest.
OK, I'll solve this puzzle yet.
Just you wait and see!
Peter's curiosity really
is a problem now, isn't it?
Wanting to find out things
that others don't want you to.
Isn't that right, Peter?
You should not try to invade the privacy...
...and the lives of others.
Wow! What a beautiful
weather again today!
Oh, it's Mr. Condor!
Look at Mr. Condor!
Good morning!
Johnny, there is no way that he can hear you.
Look how high he is!
It doesn't matter if he can't hear me.
Hey, Mr. Condor!
Good morning!
Beautiful, isn't it?
Johnny, let's ask Mr. Condor to tell us
more stories about the country to the South!
Yeah...
Ah, he's coming down!
OK, today for sure I'm going to find
Mr. Condor's nest!
Peter, Peter!
Oh, Sammy! Did you find it?
The nest, was Mrs. Condor there?
Ah, I've met her! Mrs. Condor that is.
Really?
Wonderful!
That's Mr. Sammy for you!
But, you know, there weren't any eggs.
Huh?! But that's crazy!
What?! Do you think that I'm lying, do you
really think I'm lying about those eggs?!
Do you really think so?
No-no, but Mr. Condor definitely said
that there were two eggs!
No nest, but two eggs.
Peter, do you know about the hollow log,
near the large spruce tree in the Green Forest?
Do you know what I'm talking about? Do you?
Yes, I know the log. But...
...w-what's so special about it?
What's in it?
Go there and take a peak inside the hollow log.
You'll find something there
to make you very-very happy.
But go there quietly
and don't make any noise, alright!
Well, see you!
I wonder what I'm going to see...!
That's it!
In a city where the humans live
there are long things called chimneys.
And for some reason, they are really warm.
And beyond the city what is there, Mr. Condor?
A big valley.
The valley continues way out.
And what's beyond the valley, Mr. Condor?
A huge lake.
Fish are plentiful, and many birds flock there.
And what's beyond the lake, Mr. Condor?
Mountains, steep mountains.
Your species are there also.
And beyond that, what's it like?
A city. Another city and another city.
I wonder what on earth is in there...
That Sammy! Do you suppose
he could be trying to scare me?
It doesn't snow in the country to the South,
does it?
No, no such thing!
In the winter there are areas where it snows.
At such a time,
grab a chimney and warm your feet!
What's goin' on around here?
I'd like to know!
Surely Reddy couldn't be waiting
inside that log!
But that Sammy likes to play tricks!
Everything's OK, I wonder...
Oh... Well...
What will I do?
Sure would like to see inside...
Whatever is in there,
I might not like it!
Sammy knew that I was scared off and then
he followed me to see what I would do!
What a mean guy that Sammy is!
Mean!
But who was that in the log
who said "shush"?
A voice like that could...
...could only belong to a snake.
That must be it!
Mrs.! It's alright, Mrs.!
Sammy!
Mrs.!
Peter, looks like you were startled!
You are "the" Mrs. Condor, aren't you?
Yes, that's right.
And when I looked in the log a moment ago,
that was you who made that noise?
Yes, that's right.
However, you startled me
so that I yelled "shush".
However, your feet are sure real speedy,
that was a very fast getaway!
But, Mrs. Condor! What were you doing
inside that log in the first place?
I mean, why in the world would a condor
be sitting inside of a log?
For a short while, it is serving as my home!
What did you say?
And Mrs. Condor, whatever in the world
were you doing in there?
Now you understand, eh, Peter?
It was true what Mr. Condor said
about not having a nest, you see?
Were two eggs and now baby condors!
Hey, that tickles!
Now is the time!
- Reddy!
- Shoo!
Shoo! Shoo!
Shoo!
Shoo! Shoo! Shoo!
This is terrible, terrible!
The baby condors will be caught by Reddy!
- This is terrible, terrible!
- Shoo-shoo! Shoo, shoo!
Shoo-shoo!
Shoo!
Shoo! Shoo-shoo!
Terrible, terrible, this time Peter's out!
Terrible, terrible, this is awful terrible!
Peter, are you really OK now?
Did you understand, Peter,
to have two eggs, but no nest?
They have become babies.
They are our babies!
Peep-peep!
Are these really baby condors?
But how? Without a nest or...
Oh, Peter...
It's alright, it's alright!
My father, grandfather, great grandfather
and further-further back,
all came this way!
It wasn't because they didn't liked nests!
Doing it this way, is the best way for us!
But-but without a nest,
you can't warm your eggs, can you?
I mean...
I was in the log, warming my eggs all the time.
There are various species of condors,
but the one in this story
is known as the South American Condor,
and as you all just seen,
they really do not build a nest.
Now I understand!
But wait, wait Mr. Condor,
I have one more thing
that I wanna ask you!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs