FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Reddy Fox keeps home"
Well?
- What?
- I'm going!
Alright, Reddy.
Do a god job of caretaking now.
Granny, just set your mind at ease and go.
I wonder if it's really alright.
Recently, I've been feeling a little weak,
so I'd like to eat something tasty.
So I thought I would revitalize myself
catching the field mice on the farm
that I noticed last year.
A little thing like caretaking
I can do easy.
Really?
You don't say.
Don't worry.
Go and take your time.
Is it really alright, Reddy?
Now, you listen to me again.
I'm telling you not to get close
to any stranger.
If you do that,
you won't get into any trouble.
Yeah-yeah-yeah!
Do you really understand?
Carelessness is to be avoided!
Caution is surpassed by more caution!
Well, I'm going!
Granny's going on a trip, eh?
Are you sure of that, Sammy?
Yeah. Should be gone for two weeks,
so we can spread our wings without any worry.
What's so funny about that?
I'm sorry.
We don't have any wings to fly and fly...
So? I'm just supposing, that's all!
Still... How nice, eh, Polly?
Yes. Say, Johnny, now that we know,
why don't we assemble everybody
in the forest and play?
Let's have a stupendous party!
Hey! Let's all go play hide and seek!
- Yeah
- Yeah!
Oh! That's not fair!
But I'll quickly find where
everyone's hiding!
So, Bobby, you consider yourself hiding?
What the deuce was that?
I never heard that voice before.
Huh, can't scare me!
Chin up, chin up!
I'm not a weakling!
What will I do?
Everybody's left me!
I'm gonna hurry home and go to bed!
How boring! They're all
a bunch of silly weaklings!
Everybody's gone! This is no fun!
I might as well go home!
Well, so long!
So long!
- I'm scared!
- Let's hurry!
- Good night!
Must've been my imagination!
What a wonderful day!
I am carefree and free, there's nothing
in the world that I'm afraid of!
And with Granny relying on me
to take care of things,
I will handle the situation!
Don't you worry, Granny, ev...
Well, Granny said not to get close
to anything that's unknown!
This has not been a good day
for Reddy the Fox.
His stomach was so empty
that it's begun to hurt.
Finally...
...he decided to go out
and look for something to eat...
...and left his house.
Despite the early time of the morning,
Red was to hungry to stay at home.
So, stopping often... silently.
But with all his might,
he sniffed the wind blown air.
I hope I don't hear that again.
It's too scary.
Reddy's famous nose
really is able to distinguish things
that the eye cannot see
nor the ear can hear.
I smell some kind of baby bird!
It's chicken meat!
Now hear this, Reddy:
when you want something so much
that you can't stand it,
turn around an go home.
If you stay there, you'll be caught,
but if you go home,
you won't be hurt.
What a pity!
And there isn't any way to check
if there's is a trap or not,
I just don't know what to do!
That's it!
I thought of a good plan!
Hi!
Hey, I'm so glad to see you!
Got something up your sleave again, hey?
You sure look smart magnificent today.
No... not that much!
No, it's true, it's true,
no one is as brave as you,
we, who tremble every night
hearing that strange voice,
just cannot be compared with you.
That's true! That's true,
I'm not afraid of anyone or anything,
really, I am!
By the way, Jimmy, I found
a half eaten piece of meat!
Meat?
If you don't believe me, come with me
and see with your own eyes!
But I don't care to eat meat that much!
But... aside from the meat,
I thought there might be
some fallen eggs that you like so much!
Really?
And, Jimmy, that meat might be left
by the stranger who scared the...
Well, naturally, I wasn't scared...
...but all the others were, of course!
Oh, really?
Look, beneath that tree!
You're right!
Well, who would you think brought it?
Say, let's go closer and look!
Then we'll be able to see who left it!
That's a good idea!
Let's do it!
Say, Jimmy, to avoid any danger
wouldn't it be better
if someone stood guard over here?
That may be!
Then let's do this:
I'm-I'm taller than you
and can see beyond the grass field,
so while you're checking,
I'll stand guard for us.
How's that for an idea?
That Red, he wanted me to check if there is
a trap or not. What a cheap guy!
Hey, Jimmy, is that OK?
Yeah. That's OK.
Well, well, how was it?
The teeth marks and tracks
closely resemble yours,
although he's much larger.
Oh... Have you ever seen this guy?
I can tell without seeing,
at it's teeth marks are on the meat
and in the sand its tracks remain.
And maybe it's this stranger
that we're hearing.
- Why, if you think I'm lying, come and look!
- No, it's alright!
You're the one who wanted
to check, wasn't it?
You know...
...really, I just remembered
something important...
...that I have to do.
If you find out anything more about it,
let me know, later.
What foolishness! Thanks to him,
I've wasted a lot of time.
Yeow! Wait, wait!
Wow, that was too close for comfort!
My gosh, I thought for sure
it was that unknown stranger!
That's it! I'd like to know about
that thing also!
So we decided we'd go to
Digger the Badger and ask him!
A good idea!
But... uh...
...Jimmy, since you have a weapon
that makes you afraid of no one...
So...
Well... uh...
You... you know, you aren't afraid
of the unknown stranger, are you?
No, that's no good. I don't have this bag
just for the sake of quarrelling with others!
I still think that you oughta go see Digger!
He's from the West, and he would know
something about the stranger!
And what is it, fellows? You want
to know about that voice, you say?
Guess we'd ask you, Digger.
We thought you would know who it was.
Well...
I...
You see...
Usually, he doesn't associate with others,
so it's a little hard for him to converse...
In short...
...he's come from the Great West
and he's a friend of mine.
A friend?!
In short... yeah, yeah.
A coyote. Old Man Coyote,
who's come from the Great West.
Old Man Coyote?
Coyote?
Jimmy and Johnny quickly told everyone
what they had heard from
Digger the Badger about the coyote.
What they should do to avoid being
caught by the coyote
or if they did meet up with him,
what they should do.
All this had been learned, now,
and everyone was a little bit more
at ease than before.
Hi!
Well, why is everyone so jumpy
about that nothing Old Man Coyote?!
You're nothing but a bunch of cowards!
Me, I'm not the least bit scared!
Yeah, you're really not scared?
That kind of guy, if I meet up with him,
I'm thinking of giving him a scare!
Yeah, is that so?
Well, show us some of your strength!
In due time!
Terrible, terrible, terrible!
That coyote is out in broad daylight!
It's been a long time, brother badger!
Hey...!
If i-it isn't Old Man Coyote!
I thought it was t-t-time for you
to make an appearance!
I sure did miss your voice!
You're about the only one who
would say something like that!
And how long will you stay?
Such a nice forest, I thought
I'd look around and stay a little while!
Well, in any case I'll have to pay my respects
to my immediate neighbours,
but it'd be nice if they are pleased.
You have a mean streak!
You know full well
that they are all afraid of you!
Speaking of that...
Reddy,
R-R-Reddy the Fox is saying
that when he meets you,
he's going t-t-to get you!
Reddy the Fox. That one!
I better check for myself to see how much
courage that Reddy the Fox really has.
Judging by the voice, he's over at the ranch!
OK, now is a good time to go look for
some field mice!
Good evening...
...brother fox!
Coyote!
Why are you here?
Is it wrong for me to be here?
No!... No-no-no-no-no!
No-no-no-no-no-no!
I don't mean that at all!
Well, I understand that you want to live
in the Green Forest, yes-yes...
...th-then we could be good friends, yes!
By the way, is it true that you
are not afraid of anything?
Yes...!
I'm not afraid of anyone!
Although everyone seems...
to be afraid of me!
And you're not afraid of me, right?
Yes, I'm not afraid of anyone at all!
Got a lot of courage, eh, Reddy?
Yes, that's right,
I'm not afraid of anyone at all!
Then what about this?
Mean Old Man Coyote!
Anyone would run, so I did just
what anybody else would do,
so I am not a coward!
My Granny said,
"If you wanna live long, you've gotta run"!
But if you flee you're laughed at,
and you must live in hiding, live in hiding!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs