FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Coyote is the smartest"
Ever since Old Man Coyote
came to live in the Green Forest,
Reddy the Fox was always hungry.
Reddy was afraid of Old Man Coyote,
so he couldn't go out hunting at night.
Everything would be fine if Granny
were here, but...
...unfortunately, two weeks before,
she left for distant pastures...
...and is not at home.
Therefore, during the safe daylight hours,
Reddy would catch grasshoppers and beetles
and try to appease his hunger.
Hey, Reddy?
Well, Sammy, 'mornin!
Reddy, poor thing,
I understand that recently
you don't go out hunting at night
and that you're always so hungry.
Yeah...
Well, Granny isn't here, you know,
and there's so much to be done.
Truthfully, isn't it that you're
afraid of Old Man Coyote?
No, that guy, I'm not a bit afraid of him!
Oh, really? That's funny...
Then, I wonder who it was that hastily fled
the moment he ran into Old Man Coyote.
- Anyone would run if he bumped into Old Man Coyote...
- But, isn't it amusing?
I sure would like to tell Granny
that kind of a story.
Sammy, you aren't gonna tell Granny, are ya, huh?
Oh, aren't you supposed to report everything
that happened during her absence?
Well, mmm.
Reddy, there's nothing to worry about.
If you can't tell her, I'll speak in your step,
dont worry!
Uh, well, it's-it's okay, don't worry,
I'll tell her all about it.
Well, now, I think I'll pay a little visit
to Mr. Brown's house.
Ah, Granny! Weren't you supposed
to be back tomorrow?
If you have something to tell me,
tell me.
It's like this, Granny Fox:
The other day there came...
- You big mouth Jay, just you get outta here, huh!
- Reddy!
This I'd like to hear.
What kind of a story is it?
Well, Granny, in short...
Actually, during your absence,
Old Man Coyote has come to live
in the Green Meadows.
Old Man Coyote, you say?
That is correct.
Everyone in the forest
is afraid of Old Man Coyote,
but your grandson, in short, Reddy,
keeps insisting
that he is the only one not afraid of him.
However, one particular night...
- Huh?
- Hmmm...
- Oh!
So you're not afraid of anything?
Oh, help, forgive me, oh, save me!
Oh!
You... sneaky coward! You call yourself
a grownup? Shame on you!
Oh, Granny, forgive me.
I'll never brag again.
- Is that the truth?
- It's the truth! I promise, Granny!
Mmm... The problem is to get rid of that coyote.
- There must be a way.
- Huh?
The coyote is a relative of the wolf.
Perhaps, such an animal living here
means that there is less food
for you and me.
Hmmm...
If you and I take him on, Granny,
it wouldn't be any problem!
You're really a fool.
You do stupid things and that's why
you get in trouble.
Huh?
Reddy, look at your opponent
before you open your mouth.
He's an opponent that even
ten of us foxes can't beat!
You should know that much.
Try to use your brain!
Ah!
Huh?
Reddy,
your Granny is thinking of arranging a fight
between the coyote and Prickly the Porcupine.
Huh, with old Prickly?
That's right. You know all about
the sting of Prickly's needles.
Uh-hm. Prickly could take care
of Coyote, couldn't he?
But, what if he... loses, huh?
Then, so be it.
Someday we'll get our revenge!
I see, Granny. You've got a good head.
But how are Prickly and Old Man Coyote
going to be convenient and fight each other?
That's where my good thinking comes in.
I've got a plan...
Anyway, wait and see.
Oh, my goodness, if it isn't Mr. Prickly!
Well... if it isn't Old Granny!
That's mean, calling me old. Especially
when I consider myself young.
Reddy, doesn't Prickly look braver
and handsomer than ever?
Oh, he does. That he does.
Yes, indeed he does, oh, yeah.
Reddy, that story we heared
can't possible be true!
Especially not about our brave Prickly!
I don't believe it! Mr. Prickly
is not that kind of a person.
Hey, what's this nonsense all about?
Well, I heared from Harry that Old Man Coyote
is bragging that everyone,
everyone is afraid of him.
Oh, that silly story.
No, the problem is after that, Prickly.
When Old Man Coyote was asked
if Prickly the Porcupine was afraid too, well...
Hmmmm.
And what did he say then?
Mmm. Then that guy, Old Man Coyote, said:
Prickly's afraid and he's a coward
and he's always up a tree.
That's what he said...!
I don't believe that, no...
But others listening may take it for the truth.
Not only that, but Coyote...
Did he say anything else?
- That he did.
- Uh-hm.
But if I tell you, Mr. Prickly,
you'll get angry.
That's alright. Tell me, anyway.
Well... if you really insist...
Oh...
That mean Old Coyote said: if he meets
that porcupine on the ground,
- ...he'll make an evening meal of him!
- Oh!
Mr. Prickly, what are you intending to do?
Not a darn thing!
I'm gonna let that bragging bum
see if he can make a meal out of me!
I don't think he's around now...
Well, where can I find that bum?
Well... the story goes...
...that Old Mr. Coyote said
he was going to catch you
when you went for a drink of water
at the Laughing Brook.
Huh?
He said that, eh?
Well, now, wait till then!
- Hm...
Going out, you say?
Yeah, I apologize.
Specially since you came for a visit.
But I have some business to attend to.
I'm sorry to hear that. I was so
happy to become friends with you.
You, who must be twice as well
informed as anyone.
This doesn't mean we'll never
meet again. I'll be back by evening...
That so, isn't it? Well... take care!
Thank you. Bye!
Happy to meet you, Mr. Coyote!
I had heared that you build
a home in the Green Meadows,
and I wanted to greet you
and welcome you!
I hope that we can be very good friends?
- Yeah, that's right.
- Huh, as if you cared.
In the first place, I wouldn't
be friends with you for anything.
Uh, what did you say?
I was thanking you. I think we
can definitely become friends.
That is for sure!
By the way, Mr. Coyote,
for someone to be as brave
and strong as you are
and to be afraid of someone
is something I cannot understand!
Hm.
What nonsense! I'm not afraid
of anyone at all!
Oh my, then, was Prickly lying?
And who is that one?
He is a porcupine.
According to the rumours, you are
terribly afraid of the porcupine
and when he is there, you don't dare
- ...enter the Green Forest!
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Where can I meet him?
- Why, whatever do you intend to do?
Naturally, I'm going to beat him up!
Well, if that's the case, you want to go
to the Laughing Brook in the evening.
The Laughing Brook, you say?
Yes, Prickly should be going
for a drink of water.
Evening is it? Can't be helped.
I'll just wait.
How about that? Just like I said.
Uh-huh, Granny, you've got a good head!
Between Sammy, the talkative jay,
and Peter the Rabbit,
the news that Prickly and Coyote
were going to fight
spread quickly throughout the Green Meadows
and the Green Forest.
As you know, everyone in the Green Forest
was afraid of Old Man Coyote.
So everyone naturally hoped
that Prickly would be able to
chase Old Man Coyote away.
Peter and some of his friends,
gathered in a clearing in the Green Forest,
to talk things over.
Gee, I'm worried! Can Prickly win
over Old Man Coyote?
Me too, that's what I'm worried about.
For sure, Prickly is strong.
But Old Man Coyote seems to be strong too.
I think Old Man Coyote is stronger.
I wonder?
N-No one can stand up to
Old Man C-C-C-Coyote!
He's got a g-g-great head.
And extraordinarily fast legs.
If you wanna beat him, you g-g-gonna
have to p-prepare a d-d-day early.
A-A-And you c-can't let him know, either.
As the time for the eagerly anticipated fight
between Prickly the Porcupine
and Old Man Coyote drew near,
everyone in the forest
who could possibly be there
was out to see what would happen.
Hey, Granny! Prickly and Old Man Coyote
are gonna start to fight soon!
Yes, yes, I'm coming!
Have the spectators assembled?
Yeah!
Everyone's assembled at the Laughing Brook.
Ah... progressing very well...
That I was the one who manipulated
this fight, no one will notice.
A-ha! I heard, I heard, I heard, uh-uh!
Prickly versus Old Man Coyote was Granny's idea!
Sounds like something she would do.
I must stop the fight.
- Ah...
- Hm...
Ah...
Prickly had, many times in the past,
beaten dogs and foxes,
so a coyote gnashing up teeth
didn't frighten him in the least.
But from Coyote's standpoint: He never battled
with anybody like Prickly before.
He just couldn't figure where to attack.
- Oh!
- Ah...!
Watch out, watch out.
It'd be rather serious if I'm stabbed by
those quills in a careless moment.
If I grab him from the back,
I can get him.
Hm... Hmm...
I can't figure it. Why does he
keep running around and around?
Better hurry, better hurry!
Better hurry!
- Why are they circling like that?
- I know.
Old Man Coyote is circling to
try and make Prickly dizzy.
Then we should quickly tell him!
That's right. That guy, he'll never
realize it until he becomes dizzy.
But even if we wanted to,
there's no way!
Hm. This is very silly.
I can't continue doing this all day long.
I wonder, what sort of plan will
Old Man Coyote come up with?
- Huh?
- Eh?
If I think carefully,
there has to be a way of attacking
without being pricked by those quills.
- Ah...
- Oh...
- Well...
- Uncly Billy, what are you impressed with?
Well, right now,
Prickly can only rely upon his ears.
So if no noise is heard,
he'll think everyone has left
and he will expose his face,
so Coyote thinks.
Oh, I see.
Well, then, shouldn't we tell Prickly
about that right away?
Now, I'd really like to that,
but after all, to aid Prickly only
wouldn't be fair.
- They should settle this themselves.
- Yeah.
- Oh!
- Huh?
- What?
- Oh!
- Ow!
Coyote did not know a thing
about Prickly's tail,
but there's no animal
more cautious than a coyote.
- Ah!
- Oh!
Hm. As long as he's all rolled up,
there's nothing to worry about.
But until I can figure this out
a little more, I better not do anything.
- Huh?
A-ha...!
Well... So you intended to fool me
with such a strategy?
What a blessing this is!
Oh...
Ah...
Look, Granny... Coyote is just too smart.
And there's not a thing Prickly can do about it.
Yeah, this is no time to be impressed.
On the other hand... If Prickly gets it,
I'll never back into him again.
Oh, oh!
Oh-oh-oh...
Ah-ah-oh-oh...
Oh...
- Ah!!
- Hey, you two, stop fighting!
Stop. Stop. Stop. Stop.
Oh-oh... Huh?
Well, if it isn't the Old Mr. Toad.
Now, both of you stop this silly fighting.
Just the two of you stop fighting. Find a way!
That's very kind of you, Old Mr. Toad.
But it's a rule not to interfere
in a fight between two fellas.
That Old Granny Fox has fooled
both of you two nitwits.
- Huh?!
- What's that you're saying?
And that you were going to kick me out
of the Green Forest... That was a lie?
Of course not. I only heared that you
were going to make an evening meal of me.
So there was not much else I could think.
That was crazy! Who said such a thing?
- Oh!
- Ah!
Prickly Porcupine, it looks like somehow
that we've really been had.
It certainly looks that way, doesn't it?
You big liar!
- Oh, aw...
- Wait!
- Old Man,
it's better to ignore that type of people.
Ah, that maybe right.
Yeah!
Granny Fox has always thought
that she was the smartest one
in the whole Green Forest.
But actually, Coyote has been shown
smarter than she is.
Now, that it's been proven that Granny
isn't as smart as she thinks she is,
maybe she won't brag so much.
Subtitle: South Wind Subs