FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Bobby & Blackie Crow"
So sleepy...
The first time in my life
I've ever been so sleepy...
Polly, Polly!
You guys are here!
Isn't it wonderful?
The weather is so beautiful,
and the flowers are blooming,
there's plenty of clover,
oh, it's wonderful!
So, so, isn't that so?
Well, Johnny, isn't that so?
Peter! He's hopeless, that Peter!
Say, Johnny... uh...
Johnny, just a minute.
Oh my...!
I wonder what's the matter...!
Bobby!
I said, Bobby!
Bob?
Bobby? What's the matter?
What happened?
So sleepy, so sleepy, so sleee...
Why doesn't he go home to sleep?
He can't do that.
Don't you remember, a short while ago,
his home was cut down by Tom.
That's right.
Since then, he's just been playing around
and didn't have time to look for a house.
Say...
Say, I said...
Bobby, where are you going?
I just got to find a place to sleep...
That's very true.
That's rough, Bobby,
I'll search for you also.
It's alright, isn't it, Bobby?
Alright, alright.
I said, leave me alone!
Think I'll be of any help, Bobby, huh?
Don't bother me, eh, don't bother me!
My feet are as fast as Reddy's!
My eyes can see farther!
I'll be of some use!
Be quiet, eh?
Be quiet, get out of here,
get out of here, go!
I'm so sleepy I don't know what I'm doing!
You come closer, I'll bite you!
I'll bite you...
I'll bite...
I can finally sleep!
Yes...
Oh, Bobby's gone into
an awfully dangerous place!
How noisy! Be quiet!
- What?
- What-what-what... what-what?
This is my house! Get out!
Sure is noisy, please, be quiet until I finish...
- ...my nap...
- Get out of my house, get out, out out!
How noisy... I am not moving...
This is my house, get out of here
or I'll be forced to take action!
Not moving...!
I absolutely will not move!
- I'll not anew ask for it!
- No!
No, I will not move!
Not one step more will I move! I wont...!
This is my home, no matter what anybody says!
Now... I'm gonna sleep now...
Hey-hey, now, Bobby, just you get out of here!
What do you think you are, get out!
I'm so sleepy. It's really irritating.
Let me alone...!
This is my house,
and you just get out of here!
For a change, it could be my house,
so, Uncle Billy, please, move elsewhere!
Move? What do you mean, move?!
Mrs. Billy...
My, what a rude racoon!
- How does someone become so rude?
- Yeah, he's a terrible disgusting person!
I know, forgive me, I apologize!
Against the two of you, I can't win...
Ah, I finally found one!
Now, no matter what anyone says,
I'm going to sleep!
I'm going to sleep,
That was fun!
Bye-bye!
We came thinking that this might be amusing,
but it really isn't any fun at all!
Never mind!
The fun will soon begin!
Be quiet!
Get out of here!
Polly!
Come here, Polly!
What's happening with
all the crows over there, Peter?
Bobby's over there, in the tree stump!
Buster the Bear has not had
anything to eat this morning.
His tummy is completely empty
and he can't find any food.
Poor Buster!
What's happening?
Maybe there's something to eat in that place!
- Now Bobby can finally sleep!
- Yeah!
That's wonderful!
That's an old tree stump!
Usually, there's a lot of beetles
and beehives in a place like that!
Wow, it's Buster,
wonder what he's doing!
Oh... it looks like he's pretty hungry!
Don't bother me, Buster,
go somewhere else!
What are you so mad about, Buster?
Boy, I'm hungry so I'll eat you for lunch!
When the tummy's empty,
anyone it apt to be upset.
But even so, why is Buster acting
like a rash blundering fool?
Misunderstanding and losing his temper.
Hurry, Johnny, hurry!
Bobby? Bobby?
It's... B-Buster!
- Peter, grab that side!
- Right!
Hey, wait!
Where is this, anyway?
Sure slept good...
Wonderful!
It's somebody's house!
In such a place,
I wonder who lives here...
B-B-B-Buster's house!
Oh, it is Buster's cave!
Who’s that, standing there?
Bobby! It's Bobby!
Oh, no, no use, no use!
What should I do?
Bobby!
Why are you in my house?
Johnny!
Help, oh, Johnny, oh!
Johnny, help me, Johnny,
this is terrible!
Hey, Bobby!
Bobby!
Hey!
Hey, Johnny, I gotta see Bobby!
Yeah...
Unlike all of you, I've got to get my hands
on that little guy,
I've got to see him!
Uh-huh, I've got to see Bobby right away!
Bobby!
Buster wants to apologize to you, Bobby!
Apologize?
Oh, Bobby!
I was wrong, I was wrong!
Please change your mind and move in next to me!
I apologize...
Buster, is that the truth?
Now, that's the truth,
I always tell the truth.
That's what makes it too difficult.
Yesterday you said you were going
to eat me for lunch!
Oh, is that still on your mind!
Then I was so hungry I felt like dying,
so my head was funny...
But it's different now, my tummy's full,
so I'm back to my usual self.
And when I'm my usual self,
there's no worry!
OK...
Oh, Bobby...
Did it hurt, huh?
Sorry...
Buster, you seem to be apologizing
all the time today, huh?
And so, Bobby, at last was feeling
in good spirits again.
And off he went...
following his good friend, Buster...
...to live with him in his new home,
deep in the forest.
Subtitle: South Wind Subs