FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Grandfather Frog leaves the forest"
Well, good morning!
Have you finished your breakfast
already, Grandfather?
Huh?
Well, I've finished already...
...but, uh... Why do you ask, Joe?
No reason. But if you hadn't,
maybe a small fish I caught...
Although, if you finished,
you wouldn't want to have this.
Oh!
Joe, if you're going to divide that,
I'd be happy to give you any assistance.
But, with such a friend like you,
Grandfather...
I... I can't present you with such
a dinky thing. I'll throw it away.
Oh... What a waste!
Hey, Jerry, have you ever seen
such a greedy one?
Boy, that fish sticking out of his mouth...
Tried to swallow it up whole, I guess.
Hey... What's so funny? What's going on?
Why, Grandfather...
Huh?
Oh, what a greedy Grandfather!
Oh...
Geesh...
I'm grateful!
I'm really grateful. A little while longer,
and I would have lost my breath and died.
That's so. Grandfather is so greedy!
Now, Grandfather Frog
is a very wise old grandfather,
and that's the way that everyone
has thought of him.
But now, he's been seen by everyone
making a very foolish mistake,
and his reputation is down to zero.
Well, Grandfather Frog.
I've come again to gossip with you.
What's the matter, Grandfather?
You've been gazing at the sky for quite a while.
What are you thinking about?
Here, Grandfather, it's me!
What is it?
Oh, it's you, Old Mr. Toad.
What do you mean, "What is it?"
Well, I just came to see you.
You're not our Old Grandfather Frog today.
Whatever's happened?
I no longer want to live here in this pool.
That's right. If you knew more about
this Wide World like I do...
Huh?
You'd know that Joe the Otter
wouldn't just give you a fish.
Old Mr. Toad, you'd better return
to that Wide World of yours
and learn that it's best not to meddle
in the affairs of others.
Better not pretend to know,
when you haven't even seen any of it!
Ever since you've been able
to hippity-hop around...
...you've been in this Wide World.
But what good things did happen to you?
I'd like to hear about it.
Sure. Sure. I'll tell ya.
Listen! Farmer Brown's son is coming.
Be careful. When that boy comes to the Smiling
Pool, he carries a pocket full of pebbles.
Grandfather Frog was completely astonished.
His cousin, Old Mr. Toad, was really friendly
with the human child.
Huh?
Because he saw him smiling happily...
...Grandfather Frog had been taught
a good lesson.
Hm...
Grandfather Frog spent a sleepless night
thinking about his problem.
Finally...
...it is morning.
Okay. I'll do that and show 'em!
What are you doing, Grandfather?
- I'm taking off.
- Where... where to?
I'm thinking of going to see for myself
just what the Wide World is like.
Eh? Don't do it, Grandfather.
It's such a foolish thing to do.
Really, Grandfather. It's just too much
for an old frog like you
to go out into the Wide World!
If cousin Toad can go out into the Wide World
and stand up alone, I can too.
Old Mr. Toad is only half as smart
as I, you know...
I'm going out there also.
I'm going... There...
I MUST go.
This is terrible news!
Terrible, terrible, terrible,
terrible news!
Well, Sammy, another one of your
"big-big" events?
No kidding, this time it's really a big event.
Grandfather Frog has left
in a big journey by himself.
- Eh? Grandfather Frog has...
Let's go.
Sure miss that water...
Huh?
Oh!
Oh-oh!
Hey, hey!
Hey, hey! Hey, wait a minute,
wait a minute, that's not polite!
Wait a minute, wait a minute,
let's talk this over!
Oh...
Oh!
Go chase a stick or something.
Leave me alone, eh? Oh....!
This is it!
Didn't buy that, huh?
Oh, here we go again!
Bowser the Dog thought that
he'd killed Grandfather Frog.
Bowser hadn't intended to hurt him.
He'd only been playing around.
He's here! He's here! Grandfather is here!
Grandfather... What's happened? Is he dead?
I'm still alive.
What a frightening experience!
My gosh... You really, really scared us!
By the way, why are you here?
My, we really rushed here, Grandfather,
hoping to stop you from taking
such a long journey.
That's right, Grandfather. After all,
travelling alone is too much for you.
Never mind. Please go home.
But... Grandfather...
Until I see the Wide World,
I will absolutely not give up my journey.
Then, don't blame us if you have
another frightening experience.
What's there to be scared of?
There, just a little while ago,
I was careless, that's all... I'm off!
Nothing we can do. Whatever happens.
Here's a nice shady spot.
Huh, huh, huh....
Huh?
Hm. This spot seems a lot cooler.
This was a trap, set up by Tom,
to rid the fields of wild rats.
Huh? Hey, hey, let me outta here!
This is an edible frog that I always see
at the Smiling Pool...
To be caught in a mouse trap...
Now, Tom was really just only playing around.
He simply wanted to show everyone
the frog that he'd caught
in the place of a rat.
Oops!
Hey!
Hey! Wait a minute, come back!
You can't just leave me like this!
I gotta get outta here.
Even a frog has rights, you know!
Funny... The mouse trap is gone!
Huh?
Grandfather! What on earth happened to him?
It's very unlikely that, with Grandfather's legs,
that he could come all the way this far.
Johnny, look over there.
Oh... Grandfather's been caught!
What are we gonna do, Johnny?
Bowser, Bowser! Bowser!
So, it was you...
Hey... Hey... Huh... Hey!
Hey... Oh... Hey... Oh...!
Huh, water?!
Mmm, it's wonderful!
Water. My own private pool.
Hmm.
It's too slippery for me to climb out.
All sides of the barrel were
too high and slippery to climb.
Grandfather Frog now realized,
with a sinking sensation,
that it would have been better if he
had not wanted to see the Wide World
and left the Smiling Pool.
- Well, Johnny, what are we going to do now?
- Hmm...
Johnny, did you find Grandfather?
Well... Find 'em we have, but he's caught in there
and we don't know what to do about it.
I'll just go and look over the situation!
Well, Grandfather, what is it like
to live in the Wide World, huh?
Hm...
- You got business here?
- It's nothing. I was just passing by.
But everyone seem worried and was searching for you.
Hm. Listen, Sammy. Don't tell anyone
that I'm caught in a fix like this.
Caught in such a place...
Are you sure you are okay?
Don't worry about it.
I won't cause any of you any trouble.
My!
Grandfather is quite stubborn...
If it's said that we saved him,
he'll probably loose face, you see?
Sammy, it still is a secret
amongst us, isn't it?
Of course. But how are we going to save him?
Bowser, the watch dog, and Black the Cat
are both still there, you see?
Hm. Maybe we can call a meeting
and decide what to do just then.
I shouldn't have spoken so strongly to Sammy...
Huh? Hey... what's going on?
Hey, what is this?
Must be the wind around here...
Hm. A few more of these sticks
and I'll be able to climb right out.
Hey...
What a shame! Just a little bit more to.
You weren't discovered by Grandfather, were you?
Of course not.
He thought the wind was playing tricks.
It was quite an idea of Johnny's.
If all goes well, we can save Grandfather
without hurting his pride.
Uh-oh!
Hey!
Wait a minute...
Let's talk... talk things...
...over... I'm sure... we can be friends...
Oh...!
Oh, just died.
Dumb cat.
Uh-oh, oh... oh... oh... oh!
Oh! Rudest bunch of people I ever met!
- Oh!
- Terrible! Grandfather will be eaten up!
Well, Black, did you find something good?
Come here and show it to me.
Oh! This is the frog that yesterday I...
Whap happened? Is he dead?
Oh...
Well, it's still alive. Black,
I'm going to take this.
Huh?
Hey! Hey!
- Oh!
Terrible!
Oh...
Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh...
Grandfather Frog had, by now,
given up all hope.
I'll never return to the Smiling Pool.
Never see all of my friends again.
Then, after a considerable time
had elapsed...
Oh... Oh!
Oh.... Hmpf!
The whisteling stops. All is silent.
Grandfather waits, listening intently, but...
...not a sound is heard.
Huh?
Oh. Uh. Uh.
Oh!
Uh... Isn't... Isn't this the Smiling Pool?
Huh?
Hurray!
I'm home...!
This is...
...won-der-ful!
Great!
- Oh...
- A-ha!
Well, Grandfather, when did you get back?
Why... just this minute.
You must have suffered a lot.
Everyone was very worried.
They shouldn't have worried.
The Big World is just fine!
Not as bad, really, as I thought
it might have been.
- Huh?
Something wrong?
Uh... I-It's nothing!
Hm.
Well... Any questions?
- Huh?
And so, Grandfather Frog's pride was restored,
and he was able to return to the Smiling Pool
and live amongst his friends again.
Subtitle: South Wind Subs