FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Granny Fox and the coyote"
I have an excellent voice,
Open your eyes and wake up calmly!
You want to win from me,
But you won't win anything!
To do that, you have to wake up
Early in the morning!
Eh?!
I have an excellent voice...
Granny is talking to herself,
did she go crazy, or is she in trouble?
Tell me, Granny, what's the matter?
None of your business, you fool!
If you want, I can help you
by giving a good advice!
Hm. Hollow words.
You just want to tell everyone
what is wrong with me.
Oh, Granny, what are you saying?
It's true that I'm bored lately,
since there's nothing interesting to tell.
I don't care.
Why don't you stop talking so much,
and just go away?
Granny, I always told you that
it doesn't matter what you say,
- ...a silly person keeps doing silly things.
- Hm.
Well, I'm going to look for news,
goodbye, Granny!
Granny, Granny!
Oh, it's you, Reddy.
Oh, Granny, oh, oh...
If you have something to say, just say it.
Listen, Granny.
I just discovered the place
where Coyote takes his naps.
- Coyote?
- Uh-hm.
Yes, he always takes his naps
in the same place.
Hm!
I saw him sleeping in the same place
many times.
Are you sure of that?
- So, where is it? Come on, tell me!
- Follow me.
Over there, Granny.
Reddy, is it true that you
saw him sleeping here before?
As you see, I'm telling the truth.
Now everything will turn out OK.
Granny, I don't understand
what are you talking about?
Listen, I thought of a way
to get rid of Coyote.
Really?
This time we won't fail!
Tell me, how are we going to do it?
No-no. Your curiosity will have to wait.
You won't tell me?
The most important thing to do is
to confirm if Coyote really sleeps
in the same place every day.
Yes, I can confirm that, but...
Just because you saw him there
two or three days, doesn't mean a thing.
I want you to spy on him everyday,
until I say enough.
What? Every day?
- Yes, I want to check and make sure.
- Oh...
I already told you, Reddy,
"Never believe what others tells you."
- You have to see it with your own eyes.
- Oh, yes, of course.
I want you to understand this clearly,
don't let anyone know what you are doing.
And be very careful to be sure that
Coyote doesn't know what you are doing.
Of course, Granny.
- Granny...
- Good night, Reddy!
Good night...
Johnny, Polly, where are you?
- Wake up, Johnny and Polly.
- Is that Peter?
Come here, come here!
You have to hurry if you want to see, come!
To see what?
Don't ask questions and just come with me.
Let's go, a suprise!
Both of you!
- Let's go!
- Alright!
What a delicious aroma...
Johnny? Johnny!
- What's wrong, Polly?
- This flower has a strange smell.
- Let me see.
- Polly, Polly?
Johnny, Polly, hurry, hurry!
Wait just a moment, Peter.
I told you to hurry!
- Smells so good.
- Come, Polly!
It's Reddy?!
- What is he doing?
- That's just it. I don't know, Johnny!
- Oh...
- Do you think we should follow him?
- Hm?
He must be up to something...
- Shall we go and see, Polly?
- Uh-huh!
It's Coyote!!
Ooh!!
Don't you think there's
something fishy about all this?
Hm? What?
I don't know, but there's something strange.
- I'm here, Granny.
- And...?
Today he was there again.
Hm... Hm...
He was sleeping in the same place
like the other times.
Now, there's no mistake.
Good... But, please, go there again tomorrow
and see if Coyote is still there.
Hm? What!?
Yes, do you understand?
Yes, but why do I have to do it again?
When the time arrives, I'll tell you about it.
Until then, just do what I say,
without asking why!
OK...
Hey!!!
Huh?
Come here! Run!
Hurry up!!!
- There he is again.
- You're right.
I'll tell you again that this is very strange.
- Why is Reddy doing that?
- I don't know, Johnny.
By seeing Reddy doing the same thing
the next day, and the next,
and the next day once more,
Johnny, Peter and Polly,
were very puzzled, because
they didn't know what was going on.
And the more they thought about it,
the more it puzzled them.
Something is going on,
it doesn't matter what you two think,
- ...it's strange.
- Yes, very strange...
That's true. The question is,
why is Reddy doing such a thing?
Hm...
That's it! Why don't we ask Coyote about it?
- Huh?
- Ask Coyote? Oh...
Yes, if we do that,
who knows what we'll discover?
That's not very safe, Peter.
- There's no way we could do such a thing.
- Yes, true.
I know, we'll ask him about it this night
when he drinks his water.
That way, there won't be any problem!
You're right.
Johnny has a great head on his shoulders.
Is that true?
M-Mr. Coyote?
- Hm?
- Oh?!
Just look who's here.
Johnny, Polly, and aren't you Peter?
How are you, Mr. Coyote?
As you can you see, I'm in good health.
M-Mr. Coyote...
What is it?
W-well... we saw Reddy, a-and...
Reddy? You mean, Reddy the Fox?
Me and my friends were wondering
if you could tell us
why does Reddy watch you sleeping
during your naps everyday?
If you don't mind, Sir...
What? What are you talking about?
Well... to tell you the truth, Mr. Coyote...
And so, Coyote learned about
everything that was going on.
One after the other,
they told all they had seen,
and Coyote listened to everything
carefully, but...
I thank you for telling me this.
One day I'll show you my gratitude!
Goodbye!
There he is.
But, why, Reddy? That guy...
In any case, he is up to no good.
To come here to see me every day,
he has to be planning something,
but what is it? I would like to know.
Hm?
What are his intentions?
I don't understand...
If Reddy and his Granny are planning
to attack me during my sleep,
they are more stupid than I thought.
Much, much more stupid!
I'm back!
- I'm so tired...
- Yes, you must be, thank you for your work.
Don't worry, Granny, but for how long
do I need to watch him?
We shall see.
Watching him every day, it's so boring.
Coyote doesn't sleep anywhere else.
Uh-hm.
But go see him again tomorrow, and see
if he's still sleeping in the same place.
Oh, I don't want to do that again.
He's always there.
Do you ever listen to what I say to you, Reddy?
- Tomorrow. Tomorrow is the day.
- Really? Are you telling the truth?
- Yes. So, listen carefully to me.
- Alright.
Tomorrow, after you've again
made sure he's sleeping,
then run away quickly
and scare all the birds away.
Alright, but...
Why do I have to do that?
Just do as I say!
While you do that, I'll go to the farm
to make Bowser angry and bring him with me.
- Bowser!?
- Yes.
I'll bring him to the place where Coyote sleeps
and make them fight each other.
Oh!
That's why you wanted to make sure
if Coyote sleeps there every day!
If Bowser sees him,
he will probably attack him.
But Granny, won't that be dangerous for you?
Well, I won't let him catch me, so don't worry.
What a great idea, Granny,
this time Coyote will pay!
Don't party before the time comes.
I'll make sure they fight each other.
And I'm also thinking of
taking the opportunity to steal a chicken.
A chicken?
After that, I'll return to the forest.
Don't wait for me, and just go back home.
And then, later in the night,
we will eat and celebrate Coyote's defeat!
Alright. Goodnight, Granny!
That's some kind of signal.
I'll wait and see what happens.
You're still sleeping?
Then I'll wake you up.
Reddy, the rest depends on you.
Extra, extra, I have news for you.
- What is it?
- What is it, Sammy, tell us!
Bowser is chasing Granny right now.
What?!
Run, Bowser, run!
Granny, don't let him catch you!
Let's get out of here.
- Yes.
- Let's go.
Granny Fox led Bowser to the place
where Coyote sleeps every day.
Oh?!
- Oh.
- Oh?!
But being smart, Granny
didn't lead him directly,
because Coyote would have noticed,
and would have fled
before Granny could reach him.
You will have to run just a little more.
Now it's your turn, Coyote!
One, two, three!
Oh, he's not here!
Aah!!
Where did Granny go? Bowser doesn't have
a clue, but he's not giving up.
If he could get a scent,
he would be able to catch her.
Good, he went away.
Coyote was able to get away.
But it doesn't matter.
Even if Coyote got away,
Reddy and I will still have a feast
with the nice chicken we caught.
I'm home again!
Reddy...
Where is the chicken?
Eh?
Well...
Reddy, say something!
Please, forgive me, Granny.
I couldn't bring it.
What? You couldn't bring it?
No...
What happened?
You are not playing tricks on me, right?
- For sure.
- Then, why didn't you grab it?
Oh, but I did grab it, Granny,
but when I was returning home...
- ...it was taken away from me.
- Taken away?
Yes...
Who? Who did it?
Tell me who did it, come on!
Well... it was Coyote.
It appears that Coyote is better than us.
And if we can't make Coyote
go away from the Green Forest...
...then we don't have a choice but
to try to live with him the best we can,
and try again another day.
- Don't you think so, Reddy?
- Eh?!
We were tricked so foolishly.
- We lost to him.
- M-hm.
Coyote was thinking
exactly the same as Granny.
He liked the Green Forest very much,
and became friends with the animals there.
Goodbye, guys!
Goodbye! Until next time!
See you again! Till next time!
Goodbye!
Goodbye! Goodbye!
Let's go!
Translation: Cyber Zero & Edit: Mónica
Subtitle: South Wind Subs