FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Who's a coward?"
Oh? Oh... hmm...!
Oh... oh... Oh!
Huh?
Oh!!
Oh... Oh!
Oh.
Ah!
All the fruit has started to turn red!
Maybe in three days they should be edible.
Hm... Oh... O-o-oh...
Oh.
- Danny?
- Oh!
Oh...
Danny, what are you so scared of?
It's me, Johnny!
Huh?
Oh, it's you, Johnny!
- I thought, for sure, my heart was gonna burst.
- Wow...
Danny, you're sure some coward, aren't you?
That's right, I'm a coward because...
- Oh... Oh...
- What's the matter with you, Danny?
Be quiet!
- Huh?
- Oh.
Is that a hawk flying over there?
Yeah.
There's one flying over there.
But... He's going now.
Oh... Oh, I'm going home now.
Wait, we're returning to the forest too.
Let go together.
Huh?
Oh...
- Oh...
- My, how shocking!
I'm relieved. Now that I've made it to here.
Thanks, both of you!
Thanks to you, the return trip was real fast.
Now, why do fraidy-cats like you venture
so far to such a strange place, huh?
Johnny, Polly, I went to see when the fruits
growing there would be ready to eat.
Those fruits are available much closer.
But I love the fruits over there!
I just must have them, Johnny.
I want to eat them.
Are they that good, those fruits, huh?
Well, if I say it's good, it's good.
I'll just dream about them
and my mouth really waters...
Huh?!
- Oh...
- Hey!
- Do you see something?
Yeah, Polly, the hawk is flying again.
- Uh-oh!
- Oh...
Bye-bye to the two of you!
Oh, Danny is really a coward,
isn't he, Johnny? Come on, let's go.
Then, when Johnny said, "It's the hawk"
and turned around,
Danny had already disappeared!
That's the way it was. That Danny
would be scared of his own shadow!
O-ho...!
Anyway, there's no one as cowardly as that guy,
but in my case, I'm not afraid of anything.
That's right. Even I have too many days
passed without being chased by Reddy,
believe me, I get lonely.
A man without courage is to be pitied.
If I was that scared, I'd better be off dead.
Only yesterday, I risked my live
on a hazardous adventure...
...and it was fun!
What kind of an adventure was it?
Oh!
- Well, come on and tell us?
- What's the matter, Johnny?
You can't help being upset and ashamed
when people make fun of you.
So you try to laugh and say
"Sure, I am a coward!"
Hey, Chatterer, hurry up and tell
the story of your adventure!
Well, come on now. Don't be so impatient.
I'll get to it! I'll get to it!
Ah...!
Today, it must be ripe enough to eat.
If I was smart, I would control myself
and not eat those fruits...
It's such a lot of trouble to get them.
But those are especially tasty!
Oh, oh!
Oh!
Ah!
Oh!... Oh!... Oh!...
Oh, I can't win by speed alone.
I'd better use my head.
Oh.
Oh-oh-oh...
Wonderful, I can get out of here!
Oh.
Oh...
He'll start noticing pretty soon.
If he comes chasing me, he'll think
this time I've fled the other path.
That was scary! But I should be safe now.
Now, about Danny the coward:
since meeting with such a frightening adventure,
one would think he would go home.
But Danny proceeded towards the spot
with the fruits.
Look at those fruits...
I hope Green isn't around.
Oh!
Danny must really like those fruits!
Oh, how boring.
Isn't anything amusing happening?
Oh?!
Oh! There's Danny, the coward.
I'm gonna go and...
...tease him a little!
Danny... It's me.
Huh?
Why you did that, Chatterer? I think
my heart would leap from my mouth!
Well, maybe I overdid it a bit.
But what's a coward like you
doing in a place like this?
I'm going to eat some more fruit.
Oh... you better not bother...
It's different for a brave person like me.
But for anyone timid who, at the smallest thing, would
think that his heart was falling through his mouth...
...he doesn't stand a good chance of survival.
But, Chatterer, more than anything
I want to eat that fruit!
Hm?!
Then, I will take you there.
I, Chatterer, who fears nothing at all!
No, it's okay. I want to go by myself.
Huh?
Well, see you!
So be it.
Well, take care and get home
before it gets too dark!
Oh, my gosh!
Oh!
Ah!
Oh...!
Huh?!
Hm...
What in the world is he doing?
Uh-huh, he tried to grab something
and failed.
My chance. My chance,
I'll get it in his place!
Oh...
My, oh my, my life is saved!
But I'd better not leave yet.
Oh...
Oh!
It's Reddy! What a fix!
If he only doesn't notice
that I'm in here. I'll stay quiet.
That's funny. That hawk...
What in the world was he chasing?
There's nothing around...
Hm?
Ah... So that's it, he's in this can.
Oh! So he really found me.
Well, Danny, what a funny place
for you to be hiding.
You know you can't escape from me in there.
- Oh... Oh... Oh...
- Now, are you ready, Danny?
And how would you like to be eaten?
From the tail first
or would you rather head first?
Or shall I take one leg at a time
and eat it?
The front or rear leg, which do you
think is tastier, Danny?
Oh!
Mm.
- Grrr...
- Ow! Oh-oh... Alright...
...I'll drag you out there!
Come out of there!
Ah!
You come outta there. If you don't,
I'll crush you and the can together!
Oh...
Uh? That's funny...
The sound is strange.
Hm.
It's empty!
Oh, that was close.
That's the most frightened I've been
all my life. But I must eat those fruits!
Goody!
Hey, Johnny!
Johnny!
Huh?
Johnny, Polly!
Hi, Chatterer, what's happening?
- Oh, nothing. I just teased Danny a little.
- Huh?
- Who, Danny?
- Right. That fraidy-cat!
Saying he's going to get some fruits,
he was wandering about on the Green Meadows.
So I snug up at him and "Roar!"
Oh, Chatterer... That's going too far!
For a courageless guy,
that's the only way to make him brave.
- Now, that I wonder about...
- Huh?
Hi, Grandfather Frog!
Chatterer, you mustn't do
such terrible tricks.
What is just a little thing to you,
is a matter of life or death for Danny.
Furtermore, I don't consider Danny a coward.
And, what happened to Danny?
Went after the fruits.
Huh? I'm gonna see!
Wait, I'll go too!
It was wrong to scare him...
...but I can't believe that Danny has courage!
- Huh!
- Oh!
- There's no fruit!
- Danny... Danny...
- Danny's eaten all the fruit!
- Oh?!
Furthermore, I don't consider Danny a coward.
Johnny felt that he now understood
what Grandfather Frog had said...
...that Danny is not a guy without courage.
You see, all the animals in the forest
live in a life-and-death struggle.
And the small ones have nothing to fight with.
All they have to survive...
...is their quickness of reaction
and their ability to get away from danger.
Just their living is an act of courage.
Oh!
Oh.
Subtitle: South Wind Subs