FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Lost in the Green Forest"
Here in this lovely place, deep within
the Green Forest, lies Coyote's home.
The morning sun shines brightly.
A beautiful morning begins...
Hm. But what's that?
Why, it's Whitetail the Marshhawk!
Oh-oh, I'll bet he hasn't had his
breakfast yet and is out looking for it.
Sure would like to find a tasty breakfast...
Well, now who in the world is this child?
A hungry marshhawk is nearby.
Will he be safe?
A-ha, a feast, a feast!
Hm, too late to struggle.
I'll take you home and leisurely feast on you.
Hey... don't struggle so much!
Hush now.
Hush.
Boy, you're sure a bother, little one.
That old hawk, he's gone.
Does it's evil, I think? He was constantly
circling around over us.
Seems he was laying in wait, doesn't it?
But... from his manner right now
it isn't us.
Oh, either way it's good.
He's given up and gone, Johnny.
- Now... let's eat, let's eat.
- Let's!
Mm.
What's that, Polly?
Did you say something?
- Huh? Huh?
- Oh? Huh...
- Huh? Oh!
- Hi, you little one!
- Who are you there?
- Huh?
Little one?
Over there. It looks like
she went that way.
It was just for a moment
while resting after eating.
Little one, little one?
- Oh...
- It's a small dog.
Small dog? Then it's Bowser's child.
Did Bowser have a child, Polly?
Hmm. That's wrong. They hardly look alike.
But it's no mistake that it's a small dog.
It seems that Johnny and the others
still don't know the little one is a coyote.
Coyote pups are very much
like the puppies of dogs,
and especially they're almost identical
of the German Shepherd pups.
- Well, good morning!
- Huh? Peter, you've come at the right time.
Say, do you know him, that little one?
Oh... It's a dog. Who's? From where?
It's gone. The little one's scent
disappears right here.
That's strange, that the scent
should disappear...
- Little one, where did you go?
- The scent continues up to here, absolutely.
I'm sorry! Just because you came
to visit my forest.
No! No, no, it's our fault, all our fault.
We took our eyes off and we'll have
to search the entire forest.
Please, just wait for us
at Coyote's house, mother.
Yes, that would be better.
Uh, you have another coyote, you know.
But he's my child.
We'll find him and bring him home without fail.
It'll never do if you lose your son
because you visited my forest.
Please, leave it up to the two of us.
In all likelihood it could be a dog
brought to the forest by a hunter.
Furthermore, where there's a puppy,
there's a parent.
It could be one more frightening
than Bowser.
Yeah, in any case, we better not get involved.
Shht. It'll be bad if he notices and follows us.
Okay, this should be far enough.
- Uh-huh.
- I wonder if he went home by himself?
- Huh?
- Oh!
- Ah!
- Let's run away!
Oh!
Ow...
I'm the Number One newsman of the forest,
There's nothing I do not know,
Ask me anything and I'll tell you the answer,
Kind, polite, smart me,
the most popular guy in the forest!
- Hey, Sammy?
- Well, Coyote, what's your business?
- You've come at just the right time.
- Eh?
- We want you to help us.
- Eh, what do you mean?
- Help you, Coyote?
- You're the Number One in the forest on news
and for finding lost ones, am I right?
Famous? Such news has reached
your ears, Coyote?
Well, I don't wish to brag,
since actually it is a fact.
And, as everyone knows,
but that's very embarrassing.
Thank goodness you're famous for finding
those who are lost. We ask your help!
You're looking for something, father Coyote?
Actually, my dear Sammy, this is my old friend
who lives in the forest of the Purple Hills.
He's been visiting me since yesterday,
but this morning...
...his youngest son suddenly disappeared.
Son?
Yes, and we been searching around
trying to find his scent.
Strange, but that scent suddenly
vanishes, disappears.
- Well, well!
- Sammy, will you please try to give us a hand?
So, a lost little coyote? Huh...
During this time,
the hide-and-go-seek chase between Johnny,
the others and the little coyote
was still going on.
Oh...
Oh!
He's here.
Uh-oh!
- Oh-oh.
- Oh!
Ah...
Oh!
Oh... It's King!
Huh?
Little one, wasn't it wonderful?
I bet you were scared!
My, my, my...
Somehow, this little one has become cute.
We run off and off, but he keeps following.
Well, we won't anymore. Little one, tell me,
where in the world do you live?
Oh...
Wait. It's not Johnny or Polly or Peter.
It's an entirely different scent.
Well, let's see now.
Huh?!
Hmm.
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
I would say he's a puppy dog.
Hey there, puppy dog, where is
your home, where is your home?
Tell us now!
Don't bully him, Chatterer.
Huh?! Oh!
- Hear! Hear, hear!
- Hmm?!
News! I've got news!
Sammy, something happened?
Lost child! Lost child!
Coyote's son is lost!
What? Did you say Coyote's son is lost?
Uh-oh...
- Huh?
- Oh...
Just. Just. Just might be that he...
Just might be?!
What's the matter, Grandfather,
something happened? Huh? Huh?
Who's that? Who's that over there?
Uh, I-I found him and brought him here.
He was being chased by King Snake,
so I saved him.
Who's child he is we don't know.
No mistake! This child is Coyote's boy!
This is the lost boy that Coyote
is desperately looking for!
If Coyote sees it, he'll get mad.
- Oh...
- Oh!
- My, Peter...
If Coyote makes up his mind, it's pretty scary,
everybody had better flee!
Hey, little one, excuse me for
what I said earlier, I didn't mean it.
- Jimmy, are you going too?
- Hm?
Yes. Bye-bye!
That's mean, to go off like that.
That's right. All of you leaving,
that's mean!
When they learned who the pup really was,
everyone started to sneak off.
After all, they all knew how bad
the coyote's temper was...
A-ha!
- Huh?
Oh!
Huh?
R-R-Reddy!
That's the boy's scent.
It's Johnny's house. If that guy...
Okay,
he won't get away so easy!
Don't worry...
Terrible, this is terrible!
Hear! Hear, hear!
Terrible! This is terrible!
Sammy, what is it?
Coyote, he's been found.
The boy has been found!
Johnny kidnapped him, didn't he?
Where is he, tell me?
No, no... Not so. It's Reddy!
What... Reddy?
Now there's no one around here,
I can take my time.
You, thief of a hawk!
You don't know how though I am!
- Where's the pup?
- Huh?
Oh...
Little boy...
...come with me.
It's your father, it's your father,
little coyote, your father is here!
Huh? Here boy, hurry and go.
Oh!
Huh?
Argh, what a day...
...wounded and hungry, just no luck!
Good that he could return to his momma
and pappa without harm.
Yeah, cute boy, wasn't he?
- Johnny?
- Peter?
Forgive me for running away.
But when I learned he was Coyote's son...
- It's alright.
- ...I just got scared.
At least, that boy is going home
in one piece. And am I happy for him!
My little boy!
- How nice, eh, Johnny? Now we can breathe.
- Yeah.
Boy, Coyote was sure mad.
I've never seen anything like it.
He was mad?
"That Johnny! Next time I see him,
I'm really going to get him!"
What?!
"To learn what happens to those
who steal other's children,"
"I just have to really teach them
a good lesson!"
Sammy, t-t-that's wrong.
You yourself know all about that!
Well, Johnny, it's okay.
I'll forgive you this time.
The truth is that I'll forgive you because
you were so kind to the little boy, see?
My, Sammy, you're mean!
Johnny, it looks like we can
somehow become good friends.
Well, brothers of the Green Forest,
farewell, farewell.
Sammy, Sammy, it's the hawk!
The hawk is stalking you, Sammy! Sammy...
Ah...!
Ah, tricked me, eh, Peter?
The incident of the lost Coyote
pup in the Green Forest ended...
...without harm to anybody.
Tonight, that pup,
held in the paws of his mother,
will surely have some happy dreams.
Subtitle: South Wind Subs