FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Reddy Fox and the sheep"
Peter, run a little slower, will you?
Beetles!
Beetles! Wow-ee!
This is the first time I've seen this many!
Johnny, Polly, hurry!
- Amazing!
Isn't it?
If Jimmy saw this, he'd sure be happy!
That's true, shall we tell him?
OK, then I'll go tell him!
With my fast feet, it will be but an instant!
That guy, Jimmy, should be very happy!
Whatever the case,
beetles are his favorite food!
That guy, Reddy, napping right in my path...
Hmm, this is bad...
If I pass by real quietly,
maybe that Reddy won't notice.
Wait a minute!
That Reddy is pretty shrewd,
so he may just be pretending sleep,
waiting for me to pass by and then...
...budge...
which I woudn't appreciate...
What an unexpected bit of bad luck!
And all because of that Reddy!
All because of him,
I've wasted a lot of my time!
Boy, I'm hungry!
I better go see if I can find myself
something to eat around here someplace...
Hey, Jimmy!
Jimmy, I just found a place around here
where there's oodles and oodles of beetles!
Eh, did you say "beetles"?
Yes, and it's not just one or two beetles,
it's two hundred maybe,
or three hundred!
Where is it, Peter?
Please, tell me-tell me, please!
Follow me!
I'll take you there!
Gosh, you're sure slow!
Can't you run any faster?
Sure is impatient that Peter!
How awkward!
What's the matter, Peter?
There, there, beyond that tree!
Eh, beyond that tree?
Is that where the beetles are?
Peter suddenly felt like playing a trick.
Eureka!
Reddy was always frightening him
or chasing him,
so now Peter thought...
...how can I pay him back?
That's right, Jimmy!
Beyond that stump there are
tasty looking beetles
just swarming all over the clearing!
Really?
No, no! If you go at it recklessly,
they'll run away!
Go quietly up to that tree,
and then I'll signal "Go!"
And then you leap out from this side of the
tree, do you think you have all of that?
Oh... Go!
I did it!
Aw, my arm!
Oh, what, who...?
What the... Jimmy?
Wha-wha-what are you doing?
I was sleeping so restfully,
why did you do such a thing?
Forgive me...
Why did you do it?
Pardon me.
There was supposed to be a lot of beetles here,
Peter told me,
but when I leapt,
instead of beetles it was you!
Peter did?!
Oh, so it was you, Peter!
You, Peter!
Peter sure did a mean thing tricking me
that there were beetles.
Next time he won't get off so easily!
I'm not one to be caught by you, Reddy!
Once I crawl in the Bramble Bush House,
Reddy won't be able to enter!
I'll stop you from blatter!
That Reddy, today he's pretty sticky!
Peter is sure late, Polly!
- "My feet are fast, you know", is what he said, too.
- Huh?
- He's the fastest one in the forest.
- Oh, yeah?
- Here he comes!
- Hm!
Really, that Peter, what a liar
saying that there's a mess of beetles!
Jimmy!
Hi, Johnny and Polly!
Listen to this:
Peter's a terrible guy!
He lured me out saying
there were a lot of beetles,
then he tried to set up a fight
between Reddy and me!
I don't think that's very nice!
Eh... really?
- But the beetles... it's true!
- Uh-huh!
Then there...
then there really are some?
No doubt.
Peter decided to play a trick.
Well... is that so?
Well, no matter.
Rather... quickly tell me where the beetles are,
please, tell me where they are!
Yeah.
But now... I wonder if Peter's alright.
Peter's alright because
Peter has fast feet.
But... please, you got to tell me
where the beetles are,
please, tell me where they are!
Oh, what do I do if Bowser's around?!
That's it, I just got a good idea!
Well, completely forgetting about
how he was chased all around by Reddy...
Oh, I can't see them...
Peter couldn't stop himself
trying to find out
how the chase between
Reddy and Bowser was going.
Good it's quieting down now, I'll wait
here till night fall, then return home!
Get this, Reddy:
when chased by Bowser,
don't do such a stupid thing
as running straight home!
- Why?
- Because, Reddy, you're not thinking carefully!
That's just like telling him
where our house is located,
and we won't be able to live here anymore!
OK, Granny, I'll try to leave
Bowser in the lurch!
I'm scared, I'm scared!
Reddy!
Sammy!
Reddy, looks like you're in real trouble!
Say, Sammy, please, please don't perch
out there so conspicuously like that,
I'll be in trouble!
Oh, I see!
But Reddy, didn't you know that...
...Bowser's nearsighted?!
You should! Anything in the distance
he sees as a blur!
So that's why he relies on his nose!
Scared, eh, Reddy?
No matter where you flee to,
he'll absolutely smell you out!
Bowser's nose is really something!
Are you nervous?
Well, Reddy, aren't you afraid?
What, me, afraid?
Who's afraid?
Well, Reddy, keep in there pitching!
If you only had wings like me, Reddy!
Sammy...
Were you watching too?
Yeah! I just came from talking to Reddy,
and looks like this time,
he won't be able to run away!
No matter where Reddy hit,
Bowser smelled him out quickly.
Oh, dear!
Well, this means that he'll certainly be caught!
Is there no place in the entire
wide Green Meadow,
in which he can hide,
that Bowser won't find him?
This should not be far off!
Poor Reddy!
Finally, he started crying.
By the time Bowser located the sheep,
he had completely lost Reddy.
- Peter!
- Are you alright? What happened to Reddy?
Here, here, here is where we're different!
That dumb Reddy!
Trying to catch me!
About now he should be caught by...
...Bowser.
I wonder...
Well, with this, the Green Forest...
will... be peacefull.
I mean, everybody has been hurt by Reddy and...
Hey, guys, at least you could do is
to say "Thank you",
I mean, Reddy won't be coming
around here anymore and...
If Reddy really doesn't come anymore...
Johnny!
Don't you believe what I'm saying?
Of course I believe what you're saying, but I just
can't believe that Reddy won't come anymore!
Oh, it's Reddy!
Reddy's not one to be caught
by the likes of Bowser!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs