FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"The big boast"
Is there anyone smarter than I?
I'm the smartest one under the sky!
- Good morning, Chatterer!
- No matter when we meet,
you're always in good humour, aren't you?
That's for sure!
I always have enough food...
...so I can do anything I wanna do,
any way I wanna do it.
Bragging again, huh?
But it's the truth.
Though I may not be very strong,
my head is very sharp, right?
What I lack in strength, I can cover
more than enough with my intelligence!
There's a lesson to be learned in that.
- Oh?
- Uh?
Chatterer, let me ask you:
compared to Sammy, who's smarter?
That guy? He doesn't even reach
the bottom of my feet!
Smartness may be similar,
but his is a crafty kind of smartness.
Oh, Chatterer, I'm gonna GET you!
What are you planning to do, Sammy?
You'll see, you'll see. When I get through,
there'll be no doubt as to who's smartest!
Do you mean to tell me, Sammy, that you're
gonna teach Chatterer a real good lesson?
Don't you think he's a little too smart for you?
Hmm.
I can think much smarter than him,
with one wing right behind my back.
That's our Sammy. A smart bird,
but a little bit feather-brained!
Huh? Hm?
- Sammy, how are you going to trick Chatterer?
- Yeah. Sammy, how are you going to do it?
Never you mind. You will all find out
just as fast as Chatterer does.
And when he does, he'll be sorry.
I just saw a weasel, just now.
I talked with him a little.
Oh?! W-w-where?
- Oh, by your storeroom Number One.
- Huh?
On the outskirts of the forest. The weasel
said he's not leaving until he catches you.
You didn't tell him that
I was here, did you Sammy?
Yeah, at least for the present.
But y-you're so conceited.
Sometimes I think that your type of guy
should better be caught
by a weasel, Chatterer.
Sammy, don't scare me like that!
I beg you, please, don't tell the weasel!
- Then, will you listen to my request?
- I'll listen to anything!
- Well, then...
- Well, then?
- As for my supper...
- Your supper?
From today, for one week, every day, you will go
and get some corn for me from Mr. Brown's house.
From Mr. Brown's house?!
Oh...
How about it? If you can promise me that,
I won't tell the weasel.
- That's ridiculous!
- Why?
Because in the daytime,
Black the Cat and Bowser are on guard.
But you're real smart, aren't you?
That's true, but...
Then I would think it would be extremely simple
to fool Black's eyes, do you understand?
Okay, Sammy.
Well, I'll be waiting here.
So hurry and go get it!
And please, make it the most
delicious looking ones!
Oh...
Uh-oh!
Wow!
Ah! Ah! Ah!
Blackie, you foolish black cat, yeah.
You can't even jump up till here!
Oh... Oh...
Oh... What a predicament!
It went smoothe today. But it doesn't mean
tomorrow will go smoothe too.
Oh... Isn't there a good solution?
If I could get the corn without
going to the corn field,
I wouldn't be chased by Black.
That's it! Eureka, I've got it!
Yeah, Sammy...
Too bad you're not gonna have
the satisfaction of seeing me scared.
Gosh, I've got such a smart head!
I'm overwhelmed,
even if I do say so myself.
Today is another beautiful day!
Good, good! It sure is great to be alive!
Who's the smartest one under the sky?
Say. Say, Chatterer, tell us,
what did you think of?
You'll be surprised when
you find out what I thought of!
Then you will find out
how smart I really-really am!
Yeah-yeah-yeah!
Sammy, exactly how long
are you gonna keep me waiting?
Unless you get here on time,
it's very awkward.
Oh, well, somehow I didn't think
that you'd be here so early.
I'm always an early riser!
Well, I'll be running off!
That's funny, he should be more hesitating.
That Chatterer was enthousiastic.
But did he say something to you?
He would just smile and laugh,
and not say a word.
Hmm.
Aha!
That Chatterer, he's late.
Well, maybe he was caught
at Mr. Brown's house, Johnny?
In spite of that, he left here
full of confidence, Polly.
But there's always the unexpected.
Anyway, Sammy's wrong in making
such unreasonable demands!
That's not so.
He's run off quietly giving them up.
- Oh...
- Hm. Hey! Chatterer!
- Sure took a lot of time...
- Well, maybe...
We were really worried whether you
had been seen by Blackie.
I'm not so stupid as to be caught by that guy!
- My, how disgusting!
- But it's the thruth!
Still got any complaints, huh?
Here! Still got any complaints?
This corn today doesn't taste very good.
- Is that so?
- Did you really get this corn from Mr. Brown's shed?
Uh-huh, uh-huh, from his fence storage!
Huh, a fence storage?
Yeah, but it's still corn from Mr. Brown's house.
How's that? Can't you realize
how smart I am, from all of this?
Well, tomorrow I'll feast you again all you want.
I'm sure Chatterer intends to go to his
storehouse Number Two, tomorrow again.
If he can't enter...
Sammy, Chatterer was one step better than you.
Now, why not end it altogether?
Hm. Never happened.
Who is the smarter, we'll know tomorrow.
Help!
Have you thought of a way to cut him down?
Well, I'm really gonna make him realize
that he's not very smart, Peter.
Say, tell me. How are you going to get him?
Get over here.
Get over here, I'll tell ya.
- Oh?!
So, that's how it will be.
Well, see you later!
Now, the next day, Chatterer set out
enthusiastically, for his storeroom in the fence.
Oh!
Huh?
Help!
Chatterer. Nothing happened, huh?
Hardly. Had a little excitement.
But it went fine.
Hm. Liar. Look, you're still shaking like a leaf!
I am not shaking. I ran out of breath
and I haven't got it back, that's all.
- Huh?
- Oh!
Hm. You sure don't lark for words.
However, you didn't bring the corn, did you?
Uh...
What? So you did run off scared!
Well... I better have you hurry and go get it.
Oh... That is...
If you don't want to, that's fine.
As for promise...
- ...I'll just tell the weasel where your house is.
- Ah...!
I understand. As long as I go,
it's alright, isn't it?
Again, Chatterer decided to go
to his storehouse by the fence.
But Whitetail was still guarding it,
so he couldn't get near.
Huh?
Oh...
Huh-hm.
That's strange.
What's Whitetail doing over there?
- You failed, huh?
- Oh...!
Yeah, I'm sorry to say.
- Escaped you, huh?
- I'm really sorry, specially since you told me.
Now, now, you needn't be so dejected.
Sammy will probably be complaining.
So when he does, I'll tell you.
- I'll rely on you.
- I'll see you later!
Oh... So that's it! Sammy used Blacky
to tell Whitetail about it.
I'll definitely have my revenge!
All day long,
Chatterer wondered and wondered...
How could he get even with Sammy?
Whitetail will probably be waiting
in an ambush tomorrow. With only Whitetail...
That's it, yeah!
The very next day, Chatterer acted on his idea.
Right at daybreak, before anyone else was up...
...he went to Mr. Brown's corn storehouse...
...and followed his own secret way inside.
Once inside, he gathered some corn.
Then he hid it in a safe place in the fence.
By doing this, he felt
he could give the corn to Sammy.
This plan went very smoothly.
Well, see ya, bye-bye!
Sammy, not knowing anything of the plan,
didn't know what to make of this situation.
He got very discouraged.
Nuts.
- Oh!
Sammy, just because you can't cause any
trouble, you don't have to make such a face!
I'm the smart one. To try and think
of getting me is a big mistake!
Well, till tomorrow!
How mortifying! How mortifying!
As matters stand,
Chatterer will be considered
the smarter one. How mortifying!
Isn't there something that I can do?
How mortifying! How mortifying!
Just a minute...
That Chatterer, he'll probably go
again to the stone fence for more.
From the stone fence...
If Reddy leaps out...
Wow! Save me!
- Reddy?
- Huh?
Yeah, I'm thinking of telling Reddy
about Chatterer...
...going to the stone fence for corn.
How about that, gang?
Isn't it a good idea?
When he sees Reddy the Fox hiding
in the stone fence,
Chatterer won't hide the corn
there anymore.
Then, even if unwilling, he'll have
to go to Brown's house for the corn,
you understand?
Sammy! You must stop that!
That's right. To let Reddy catch him,
notwithstanding, is too pitiful.
Huh. You guys really, really,
don't know me at all, do you?
- Oh...
- Huh?
I just want to scare Chatterer, that's all.
If Chatterer is really in danger,
I'll raise a ruckus and let him know.
So don't you worry, okay?
How is that? No complaints now!
You sure are a weird old thing.
Yeah, I think so too.
Huh? If you yourself say so, no worry!
Hm. This must be the place
that Sammy spoke of, huh?
Well, I'm going!
Ah...
- Huh?
Oh...
Thanks for waiting!
Now, don't be bad. Full eat up, eat up!
If you want more, I'll get more.
Thanks, but my stomach
is not feeling too good.
Next time, I'll accept your treat.
Sammy, actually thinking
about apologize to Reddy?
- Possibly, nothing will clear your throat.
- Chatterer, how did you know?
Some things are very obvious.
If you're going to think of some way to bother me,
you better think of a way better than that,
because I figured out your plan!
This morning, I saw Reddy.
Reddy! There's no point in hiding
because I saw you this morning!
- You better hide better than that!
- Huh? Darn.
Hm, I'll remember you for this!
Sammy, all the trouble you went through
to have Reddy waiting in an ambush...
I'm sorry that I didn't fall for it!
Hm. Don't worry about it.
- Huh?
Serves you right!
Now, do you see why I say that there is
no one around with a better head than me?
Are you sure of that?
What do you mean?!
But Chatterer...
That the weasel was just looking for you,
that was just talk on the part of Sammy.
Don't you understand?
Huh?
And you, swallowing that story!
It can't be said that your head is that good!
Oh...
Furthermore, Chatterer, you think you're smarter
than Sammy and that you outwitted him.
But when you were about
to be caught by Black the Cat,
Sammy deliberately raised a ruckus
and distracted him, and helped to save you.
Oh, that's right.
If you think that you were able
to escape on your own,
well, I don't think that's being smart!
- Oh?
Sammy doesn't stand out now,
after all that big talk.
Bragging is the most useless act in the world.
Because of his bragging, Chatterer
ran into many frightening happenings.
Sammy also was humiliated.
Hm, a person's nature
is hard to change, isn't it?
And the two, after this, will always, until
the day they die, probably continue to brag.
Subtitle: South Wind Subs