This is the tallest pine tree
in the Green Forest.
You probably noticed it before, right?
It's called the Lookout Pine.
Those who can climb to the top
can see a complete panoramic view
of the Green Forest
and it's extensive Meadow.
FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Todays episode:
"Johnny's adventure"
How scary!
Was that a ghost?
Who-Who-Who's there?
Johnny? Polly?
Johnny!
Hello, Chatterer!
You scared me, Johnny.
I didn't know you could climb so high?
Tell me, Johnny,
how did you get here?
Chatterer, look at that cloud.
Where does it come from?
It floats so softly and quietly,
there...!
I don't know, but it will surely
arrive at some place, right?
Oh! How wonderful!
Look, so many birds!
- They are surely going back South.
- Goodbye!
Goodbye!
Oh...!
For some reason,
my heart is beating really fast,
and I feel kinda nervous.
I'm sure there's something wonderful out there,
and I would love to see it!
I want to see it!
Although woodchucks are land animals,
sometimes they like to climb
to the top of the trees.
So, at this moment,
Johnny could see the vast land
spreading beneath his feet.
Be careful!
Yahoo!
What's the matter Johnny?
You seem to be in a hurry.
Hello, Sammy. For some reason
I can't stand still.
Johnny, you're always so clever, Johnny.
If you continue that way,
you'll end up in the river.
It's better if you change direction.
I know what I'm saying.
Hey, hey, Johnny!
He's so strange.
- Hello, Johnny. What's going on?
Hello, boys, how are you?
He's acting very strange,
don't you think?
Yes, that's true.
I'll continue to watch him
with my own eyes.
Do as you wish.
Look here. Let's have some fun.
Tell me how. Tell me how.
We will play a prank on Gandfather Frog,
now that he's taking a nap.
What a good idea!
Well, I'm finally home.
Huh? What?
What happened?
The door fell out,
just by touching it.
I'll have to fix it.
Oh, no!
The stairs are also very old.
I'll fix the chair too.
Oh, what's that noise?
Oh!
This house is too old.
That's it!
I'll do that!
I'm going away from here!
I'll look for another place to live,
a place I've never seen before!
How delicious fruit!
What's this?
The door of Johnnys house
is on the ground?
This is getting really interesting.
Here he comes.
Let's see what will happen.
I'll go away from this forest,
I'll go on a journey through the world,
and see things that I never saw before!
Am I hearing right?
Hello, Sammy!
Stay outta trouble, alright?
Why would I be in trouble?
Hey, Johnny, wait a minute, Johnny!
Tell me where you are going.
Tell me, tell me!
I don't know, Sammy,
but I have the desire of leaving
this forest and see the world!
Huh?!
Johnny?
This is terrible!
Really terrible!
Attention!
I have news, news!
Johnny decided to leave the forest
without telling anyone,
not even his closest friends,
Polly and Peter.
He knew that if he told them,
they would try to stop him.
And even if they asked him
where his next house would be,
he didn't have an answer to that.
So, he decided not to tell anyone.
What a shame...
Hey, Peter, Peter, Peter!
What did you say?
Johnny did what?
That's what I heard.
Sammy told everything he saw.
Oh, I'm so disappointed!
Johnny told Sammy and not me?
Hey!
What is it, Peter?
- Where is everyone?
- At the Great Pine.
How rude! He left me here alone.
I'll see what's going on.
To sum things up, not even Johnny
knows where he intends to live.
And why is he being all secretive?
This morning I saw him in the Lookout Pine.
I saw him there, I saw him there.
- In the Lookout Pine?
- The Lookout Pine?
- Hello, Peter, how are you?
Hello, Chatterer!
Hello, friends!
Hello!
Tell me, Chatterer, so Johnny was
in the Lookout Pine?
Yes, and all he did was watching
from above, it was all he did.
And then? Then he did what?
Then he descended and
started walking away fast.
And then he decided to
pass through the river.
He jumped into the water.
And when he crossed the river
he went home.
After that, he came out again and
told me that he was going away.
And can you guess what he said next?
He said "Goodbye!".
- Goodbye?
Huh?!
Johnny, you're an idiot!
Polly, Polly, you still
wanna hear the news, right?
Why don't you mind your own business,
you useless bird!
What did you say?
Be careful what you say to me!
If you could have stopped him,
why didn't you?
Now that you mention, you're right.
Why didn't I stop him?
The truth is...
that wouldn't have mattered.
Because in that moment,
if someone tried to stop Johnny,
he would have failed.
For he had made a decision.
His spirit had joined
with the spirit of adventure!
Yoohoo!
Where did that sound come from?
I want to know him.
My name is Johnny
and I'm brave!
It doesn't matter the distance,
I will arrive there.
Help...
- Help...
- Who's asking for help?
Help me!
What's wrong?
Who are you?
Help me!
Help!
It's Mrs. Swallow. What happened?
Oh!
It's the Mean Weasel!
It's useless trying to escape,
in a few moments you won't be able
to fly anymore!
What can I do?
Come here! I'll get you!
What to do?
No, no!
Help! Get me out!
Mrs. Swallow, do you think
you can fly over here?
I'm not sure, but I think I can.
I'll apply a little mud and you'll be
alright in no time.
Thank you.
Soon I'll be able to fly freely.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Of course.
- I never thought you would travel so far.
- Well...
I was bored at my home and...
I wanted to look for another place to live,
where I can build a new house.
Let's see over here. It looks great to me.
How lucky, it has a lot of dry wood.
That's great.
Here you go, Mrs. Swallow.
Eat a little.
No, thank you. I'm not hungry right now.
Well, then if you'll excuse me...
- Johnny.
- Yes?
So you abandoned your house
and came here?
Uh-huh.
I want to discover new places
to build a place to live.
But Johnny, how can you leave your place
where you've lived all your life?
Don't you think you should
think it over?
What about you?
Don't you go every year to the Far South?
You don't get it , Johnny...
The reason why I fly to the warm South
is because I can't survive in the cold.
What?
I see that you don't understand.
In other words, If I wanted to live
in the Green Forest
I would freeze in the winter!
So, as you see, Johnny...
I still think you made a big mistake
to abandon your house,
that protects you during winter.
- Good night, Johnny!
- Good night!
Where did Johnny go?
Hey, Sammy!
Tell me, Sammy. Did you try to
find Johnny?
Not now, but... I don't know
where should I look.
In that case it's useless for the others
to look for him,
if not even you know how to do it.
You're right.
I tried to look for him, but I just
can't find him, I give up.
- Well, goodbye.
- Wait, Sammy!
Where has Johnny gone to?
- What a problem!
- That's right, it's a big problem.
I'm just gonna look once more
and see what's happens.
After ten days...
the wing of Mrs. Swallow had healed,
and she was able to fly back
to total freedom.
Finally, the door is perfect.
And I can fly to the other side of the world.
If it wasn't for your help,
I wouldn't be alright.
You're ready for the journey?
Yes, thank you. I can fly again.
Thanks to you, Johnny.
My wing is healed like new.
I'm happy for that.
Well, I'm ready to leave.
But what about you?
Well... I will continue my journey.
It seems a good idea.
You're very brave.
But, I understand well
what you told me, Mrs. Swallow.
I reached a conclusion.
If one can't feel new experiences,
and see new horizons,
one will never be an understandable being.
I think it's a very great conclusion, Johnny.
So you will know what to do
the next time, right?
What?!
I promise you that I will see you again
in the Green Forest.
Mrs. Swallow, I...
I will miss you, my friend. Well...
Good luck.
Mrs. Swallow!
Goodbye!
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Mrs. Swallow!
Hurray!
Finally I found it!
Hurray, hurray!
In this forest
I'll make my new home!
Finally I found it!
I won't permit you to
come close to my property!
I already decided to live here!
The forest doesn't belong to anyone,
so everyone can live in it.
Thinking otherwise is very selfish.
And when two selfish beings face each other
the logic result is a fight.
Now, you know I'm the strongest.
Only I will live here,
so you better go away from here.
Wait a moment!
You can live here if you want.
I can't stand living here in this place.
After that, nevertheless,
Johnny felt victorious.
Hurray!
I won, I won!
Huh?!
But, it's the Lookout Pine.
I returned, I returned!
Attention, attention
I have big news!
Johnny has returned to the Green Forest!
Attention, attention,
I have big news!
Johnny has returned!
- He has returned?
- Johnny has returned!
Johnny has returned!
What great news!
Johnny!
Hello, everyone. I have returned!
- Where were you? Where did you go?
- Tell us!
Your head and your body are dirty!
Oh... and you're hurt!
It's nothing.
Tell us what happened, Johnny.
Oh, goodness!
But... What...
Johnny, Johnny, Johnny,
don't you dare do this again!
- Oh!
Poor Johnny was exhausted.
Do you think he learned his lesson
after this?
Well...
In reality...
We all sometimes feel the urge
to meet new places,
and have new experiences.
Translation: Cyber Zero
Subtitle: South Wind Subs