FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Uncle Billy regrets"
Beetle-dum and beetle-dee,
Beetles taste real good to me!
Beetles come and beetles go,
Where beetles are,
I do not know!
Yummy beetles, one by one,
I wanna put you in my tum-
-my...
Always doesn't rhyme.
There are none here, there are none there...
Hm, there are no beetles anywhere. Hm.
Mmm...
- Oh...
- Oh my, that hurts.
- Hi there, Jimmy, at it I see?
- Oh. Hi, Uncle Billy.
Why you all got yourself such a gloomy face
there, Jimmy boy? Got yourself some troubles?
Oh, I guess you ain't found
your breakfast yet, huh?
From the size of your tummy, Uncle Billy,
you appeared to have had a good breakfast.
Well, I only found one very small grasshopper.
Why, then... you're just like me.
Hm? Oh.
Uh, well, yes, that's so.
Yesterday there were some delicious
beetles around here.
Yes, beetles should do.
- Huh?
- And so...
- Huh? And so?
- And... egg!
- So yummy!
- Right, right.
- So round!
Slurp, slurp...
Oh, swallow 'em down!
So good! Oh my, but I haven't eaten an egg
in so long. I almost forgotten how it tastes.
- That's no yolk, Uncle Billy.
- Oh, my....
Mm, that was delicious!
Oh, my tummy is full...
- My, what a beautiful afterglow!
- That means it'll be another beautiful day tomorrow.
Hey, where is Johnny?
- Hey, I'm over here!
- Well, I'll be...
What are you doing?
Amazing!
What is it?
- Wow! Oodles and oodles!
- Look!
My...
Oh, if we tell Jimmy or Uncle Billy,
they'll sure be happy.
Uh-huh, yes, let's hurry and tell them.
- Hungry, hungry!
- You just ate a little while ago. Now wait just a moment!
Hungry...
Really, how far did he go anyway, huh?
Mrs. Billy, is Uncle Billy here?
I'm hoping that if you come across that
deadbeat husband of mine, you tell me.
Inside.
He isn't here?
- I just don't know what I'm gonna do with him.
- What?
Said he was going to look for dinner,
- ...and he's been gone since.
- Johnny!
Did you tell Jimmy, Peter?
I just went to tell him, but his house
was empty. Where is he?
Jimmy's not here, either.
Oh, how disgusting!
Having a worthless husband means
nothing but worthless happenings.
Oh, it's irritating!
Now, go to sleep. Dinner's over,
there is no more.
- I'm going home.
- Me too.
- Yeah?
- Uh-huh.
Good night!
Hm.
Oh. Ah...
It looks like Bowser ain't 'round right now. Ah!
Oh.
Huh?
Uh... oh...
Huh? Oh!
Wasn't there a crack near the entrance
wide enough to enter?
Hm... yeah...
Oh...
Oh, here it is.
- I should be able to enter through here.
- Huh?
Oh!
Oh...
Oh my, did he frighten me!
Huh?
Eh!!
U-a-ah... ah...
Ah-ah-ah-ah-ah....
Ah!
Woo... Oh!
Oh. Jimmy, stop please, I'll die!
Huh?
It's me. It's me. I said, don't do that.
It's Uncle Billy.
- Uncle Billy?
- Yes.
Oh my, I'm so sorry to disturb you,
but eh, excuse me if I don't accept
your customary greeting.
I was scared of your tail,
because I thought it was a snake.
I look though,
but I'm really a softy!
My tail frightened you?
And I've thought you were Bowser!
Well? What's funny?
Well, don't you see? Each of us
was afraid of the other one.
I guess today neither of us is very brave.
Well...
You-you've just got to understand that
I'm not myself today, not myself at all.
Hm, I think.
Sssht, Bowser will hear you.
Huh? Oh. You were thinking exactly
the same thing as me.
That's why we're acting strangely tonight.
Yes, well, I guess so.
By the way, Uncle Billy, did you come out
before or after you ate the eggs?
- Oh, I am afraid that it was before.
- Yeah?
Now...
Well, now, after all this digging,
we should be able to enter very easily.
Now, please, brother Skunk, after you.
- Please.
- Oh, no, never happened,
that I should go before you?
Please, I insist.
My, my, I never realized you were
such a very polite skunk, Jimmy.
- You must've been brought up right.
- Nothing like that.
No, no, you have a good bloodline, Jimmy!
Your family, it has a beautiful soul,
I'm telling you, there's not a stink in the lot.
Uh-huh.
I could never ignore the dignity
of your family line. You go first.
Hm...
Uncle Billy, even though
I have a beautiful soul,
I think that you should go first.
Because society says, "Age before beauty".
So please, I insist, you first, not me.
But your family... After you.
No, no, Uncle, after you.
Now, maybe it seems to you like each one
is being terribly polite to the other,
but actually it isn't so.
You see, there's always a possibility
that some kind of a trap
has been set inside the chicken house,
and neither one wants to go in first.
But my admiration for your
courtesy and politeness
has no limits. After you, sir.
Uncle, out of respect for your age
and infirmity, I insist. You first.
- Jimmy.
- After you, Uncle. When Bowser comes...
- Uh, oh, it's Bowser!
- Bowser?!
- Ah!!
As you said, the elderly must go first.
That's not very polite of you, Uncle Billy.
- You're pretty fast for an old guy.
- Uh? Uh, yeah.
- Hm?
- Hm? Eh?
Oh, my Lord, have mercy, mercy, mercy!
You be quiet, you hear?
Go busy yourself on some other branch,
you fur-brained owl!
If you got all that time to go hooting around,
you just go and find my husband for me.
Thank goodness, Bowser's gone!
Well, well, onward and off for two eggs.
Yes, downwarding nestward for eggs.
Oh my, when I think of all these chickens
carrying eggs...
Oh...
And this time we do it like the friends we are.
All the eggs we find, we split equally.
Sounds messy, but I'll do my part.
Then I'll take the second and third shelves.
I may not have a gas attack,
but I'm awful good at climbing, I'll tell ya.
Uncle Billy, have you found
any of the eggs yet?
No, not yet.
But I'm sure still a-looking.
Ah-huh.
Eggs, eggs, eggs...
There must be an egg.
There's got to be an egg here somewhere!
Eggs. Eggs, eggs, eggs, eggs.
Oh! None! None!
I haven't found any, either.
None, none, none.
Oh, where are those eggs I can...
Ah...
An egg!
My, that's just one of those hard,
miserable little badden eggs.
A-ha! Another badden egg...
- Darn eggs.
- Stinky egg!
Uh!
Oh...
Eggs, eggs, eggs...
- Uncle Billy? Hey, Uncle Billy?
- Eggs... Eh, what is it, Jimmy?
- Eggs, eggs, eggs...
- You threw that egg on purpose, Uncle Billy.
Eggs, I can...
Hm?
I hit that egg at you, Jimmy?
You did that purposely, aiming at me below you,
isn't that right? Isn't that?
That-that's not so, Jimmy!
That just not so!
Just sweet words...
- But it was only an accident, Jimmy.
- I don't believe you. You're just making that up.
It's not a lie! Upon my very honor!
I don't believe you! You did it on purpose.
Now, come on down
and we'll fight this out square and fair!
Oh!
The situation is very tense.
Jimmy, after all, is very hungry
and hadn't found any eggs.
So when he got hit on the head by one
and had it wasted, he became furious.
Now, come on down!
Well...
Just because I'm a peace-loving soul,
you don't have to get smart.
If you wanna duel,
you can just come right up here!
Oh... You sneak, you know I can't climb!
Then, why should I go through the trouble
of climbing down, just for a gas attack?
Okay, then, Uncle Billy! I'll keep waiting
right here until you come down.
Maybe not until next year,
but I'm gonna wait as long as I can!
Go right ahead, go right ahead.
No one is gonna stay quiet
after getting hit by a hard egg.
So I'm gonna stay here as long as I can!
Why, you just do as you please.
I think I'll take me a little nap.
Ah!
Good. Please do, please do.
I'll reward you without fail.
Hm-mm, okay.
Go to sleep. It's alright,
I'll still be here tomorrow-night.
Ah!
Hm.
Coming down?
What do you think? After all, it's morning now.
We'd better leave this place pretty soon.
I don't mind, really.
What are you saying, Jimmy?
You know Tom will be here
to feed the chickens, soon.
When he'll find you here,
there's gonna be trouble.
- I'm not a bit afraid.
- Oh...!
Uh... Eh...
Oh... Jimmy...
I don't mind. I don't care
how much noise the chickens make.
Huh...
Oh... Huh...
Eh... Oh. Oh!
Jimmy, if you're gonna get outta here,
now is the time.
When he opens the door,
I'll run off. Don't you worry!
Hm... Oh, my...
What?!
I thought the chickens were making too much
noise. You little black-and-white thief!
What a sneak...
You didn't find a single egg, did ya?
Last night, I moved them to another spot.
Uh...
Uh, okay, Bowser, it's alright.
Look at that self-confidence, Bowser...
You'd make a poor opponent against his gas.
I'd have to wash you for a week!
Well, let's go feed the chickens.
It's breakfast time! Oh...
That's funny... this is the egg
that I put in the top box!
The roosting chickens
couldn't have kicked it over...
Now, I wonder if that skunk
could've climbed up that high?
No, couldn't be. Oh?!
Oh... uh...
This tail must belong to a stupid possum.
A-ha!
Look, it is!
Bowser, we had one more visitor last night.
Look.
Bowser, what do you think of Mr. Possum?
When Johnny and the others heard
the full story from Jimmy, they were startled.
And they began to run to a place from where
they could see Mr. Brown's chicken house.
They didn't have any idea
what they could do to help him,
but Uncle Billy's problem worried them.
Uh-huh! Jimmy, whatever the reason,
that was mean to leave Uncle Billy.
- That's right.
- Uh-huh.
No, no, my husband is at fault.
Oh...
Running from us, and doing this.
Last time he was saved by playing dead.
But this time nobody wants to leave him.
If he could only run away.
Ah!
Bowser? You think this possum
is dead, don't you?
Now, look here, you pretending possum...
I haven't done anything to you. How can you
be dead when I haven't done anything?
You can't fool me anymore!
Hey, you talented actor-Possum, you.
Now come on. Come on.
Now, watch Bowser. I'll show you
if he's really dead or not.
Oh!
- Uncle Billy...
- Is he alright?
Oh, my dear...
Bowser, you're really fooled.
This one is just good at playing dead.
But he's pretty good, playing dead for this long...
But, Bowser, if he can play dead
after this, I'm gonna salute him.
Ah!
Bowser...
Stop, Bowser!
Bowser. Bowser, let him escape.
It's alright. Let him escape!
Now, come back here Bowser.
Come on...
Now do you understand, Bowser?
Every animal has something that can teach us.
This animals taught us how it survives.
You all saw that? I'm ashamed...
I'm the real cause.
I should not have become angry.
Let's not go on with that story, Jimmy.
We're just gonna shame each other some more.
- Important thing, Johnny:
- Eh?
That my tummy is so empty
that I'm getting dizzy...
Ah, you wanna know where
there are lots of beetles.
And this time don't forget the kids
and my portion, do you hear me now?
I-I-I-I know...
Let's go, Uncle Billy. It's close by.
Oh, dear, don't rush so.
I can't run, you know.
You were running fast just a moment ago?
I would never forgive you if you'll forget!
Oh, I know, honey lamb.
Don't you worry!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs