Chickeroo, chickeroo,
No one's more smarter than you!
Chickeree, chickeree,
There is nobody smarter than me!
FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Captive Chatterer"
Yeah... Yeah!
Ah...
Mm.
To Chatterer, Mr. Brown's grain store house
was almost a dreamworld.
But gradually, he began to feel that this
was not Mr. Brown's but his very own place.
And soon he began to act recklessly,
without caution.
Oh...
Hey, I'll pick it up later.
Now, that my tummy is full, I'm sleepy.
Guess I'll go home.
Now, this is terrible. For carelessness
is the greatest enemy of a little animal,
and, unintentionally, he's been noticed.
Chatterer, not knowing this, came again
next day to the grain storehouse.
Heh? Oh...
Oh, what's that?
It wasn't here yesterday...
Well, well. Something to eat in such a place!
A-hm...
Just leave it alone. Don't play with such a thing!
But I wanna touch it, and find out
what it is, and how it works.
But, being caught by something unknown
in the past has never done any good.
Yeah, but nobody's gonna get hurt.
What's wrong with just taking a look?
Hm.
Hm. Smells of mice, I think.
The barnyard type, that is.
I wonder, what is it?
Huh?
Hm.
Well...
What a delicious smell!
I wonder how it would taste?
Sure would like to know!
Hey, stop it!
It's better to stay away!
Ah, who's scared of something like this?
All I have to do is to leap in quickly,
and grab it, and back out.
Oh, stop it. Haven't you got all that corn
without eating such things?
But I wanna eat it to see
what kind of flavour it has.
Ah...!
Ah, I'm gonna end up as this guy's dinner.
But, don't worry.
Tom did not eat Chatterer up.
Help! Help!
Fool, fool, fool! Ending up like this
is your own fault, sick tummy!
Captivity can be an awful thing
for a wild animal.
And realizing he couldn't ecape from this prison,
Chatterer thought it would be better to die.
He resolved to stay there.
Unseen by anyone.
Eating nothing, until he was dead.
Huh? Hm.
Oh... I'm so hungry...
I'm not going out to eat. I just wanna see...
...if there isn't some other way to escape here?
Hey, don't overdo it. Over there,
a mountain of corn is waiting for you.
Hm, I wouldn't even touch it.
Hm...
Ow!
Oh...
It's a walnut!
Hey, don't be so stubborn.
Why don't you eat just one
before you starve to death?
Maybe I'll just have another one.
Before he realized it, all the walnuts
and all the corn had vanished.
But he was so full and feeling so good...
...that his idea of starving to death
was gone with the wind.
Hm. As long as I'm going to be staying here,
I might as well make myself comfortable.
Well... Now that that's decided,
I'd better make myself a good bed.
And from that day on, Tom brought tasty food
to Chatterer, many, many, times.
At first, when he saw Tom coming, Chatterer
would flee into the hole of the tree stump.
But, gradually, when Tom appeared,
Chatterer would leap out of his hole,
wondering what kind of delicious
food Tom was bringing.
And finally, he would start to eat
without fear, right in front of Tom.
Hm... Mmm.
Huh?
Oh...
Oh, what is it? Some new kind of a trap?
But, I'm already captured?
So, why is another one necessary?
I don't get it?
Hmmm.
Hm.
Tom had made this wheel just for Chatterer.
And finally, he realized that
he could run as much as he desired,
whenever he wanted to.
Chatterer began to feel happy.
For him, half the pleasure of living
was in being able to run about.
I thought this man was to be feared,
but now I see he is my friend.
Yeah.
All three of you with serious faces,
what seems to be the trouble?
- Oh, Sammy, so glad you're here!
- Have you seen Chatterer anywhere?
Who did you say, Chatterer?
We haven't seen him around anywhere recently.
So we've been out looking for him.
Now, that you mention it: I haven't seen
Chatterer for quite a while.
That so? Then, if you, the newsreporter,
don't know,
it wouldn't be of any use to ask anyone else.
Wait. Chatterer was always going
to Mr. Brown's grain storage.
It may be that he met up with
some scary incident there.
- Oh...
Uh-oh!
Well, I wonder what's going on?
- Chatterer!
- Huh?
Hi...
Huh? What's so funny?
The guy who thought he was so smart,
has finally been caught!
Quiet! Can't your eyes see my predicament?
Look, I've got all this corn
and all of those nuts over there!
Delicous... Would you like some?
You've got a smooth talking mouth,
but remember:
I'm gonna hurry and tell everyone,
and make you look rediculous!
News, news, news, I've got news:
Chatterer is a fool, has been captured!
News, news, I've got news!
- Can't be?
- It's true I'm telling you, it's true!
But that's rude. Chatterer should be caught
so shamefully, I simply cannot believe.
That's right. It's just like Uncle Billy said.
- Right, Danny?
- Uh-huh. Right, I never believe it.
Is that so? Well, whether you believe it
or not, I couldn't care less.
If you all go to Mr. Brown's house,
and see with your own eyes,
you'll understand what I'm saying.
News, news!
- Oh...
- What do you guys think?
No use just thinking about it here.
Let's go and see!
Oh!
- Peter!
- Huh?
- Oh!
Why, Johnny and Polly!
And Uncle Billy, too!
You're all here! Hey!
What Sammy said, it was really true.
Yes, that's why we told him to be so careful.
Retribution, because he wouldn't listen
to what we said.
This is no time to say such things,
rather we must do something
to save Chatterer.
Johnny, that's just impossible!
That's right. Because once you get
in a prison, it's impossible to be saved.
Oh, our poor Chatterer...
Oh... They're gone!
They must all be laughing over me.
Well, wise one, wise one, oh,
and how are you feeling?
Huh? Hm...!!
Well, well, Mr. Chatterer.
And is your nice new home all comfortable?
Hm, none of your business!
That's good, that's good.
Oh, wise one, oh, wise one,
Oh, how are you feeling today?
The weather is delightful...
Won't you take a walk with me?
Ah, fool...!
Stupid, idiot! A guy like you
oughta be caught by the coyote!
Oh, wise one, oh, wise one,
And how are you feeling?
Yeah, come out here if you can!
Wise one, wise one, Chatterer is a wise one...
Why is our usually eager and bouncy Chatterer
suddenly become so sad?
For Chatterer is a captive.
And the good comfortable house,
the plenty of food that he has now,
does not make up for the freedom
that he's lost.
And, by now, Chatterer realized it.
Hm.
Uh-hm.
For a while, Chatterer had been
very active and happy.
But now, Tom,
watching Chatterer's forlorn little face,
realized his squirrel is very unhappy.
After catching a glimpse
of Johnny and the others,
Chatterer began yearning for the Green Forest,
the Green Meadow and freedom to run in them,
until he felt that his heart would burst.
- Chatterer, I wonder what he's doing now.
- If only he's in good health.
Oh!
Huh?!
Oh...!
Ah, it's the Green Meadow!
It's the Green Meadow! It's the Green Meadow!
It's the Green Meadow!
Huh?!
Wow!!
It's the Green Forest! The Green Forest!
Yeow!
But, how did you ever escape
from that strong prison?
Huh?
Well... I'm pretty smart, you know.
And I fooled Tom pretty good.
- Oh!
- You sure really smart, Chatterer!
Eh?
- Oh...
- Shame on you! You should tell the truth!
Oh, Chatterer, you really have courage,
don't you?
Hm...
Chatterer, suddenly you're dejected.
Something wrong?
- Everybody: what I just said, it's a lie!
- Huh?
Huh?
Oh...
This is what really happened:
Tom deliberately opened the door,
and he set me free, deliberately!
- Oh...
Tom is but half the scary person that you think.
Rather, he is a very good person.
All during my capture he treated me
very good. We became good friends.
And now there's a lesson for all of us to learn.
And that is that Tom does not wish
to hurt any of us.
- He's lying!
- No, it's not a lie!
Then, just like Tommy the Tit always does,
can you eat from Tom's hand directly?
That's right. If you're really not scared
you should be able to do it.
Eh...
See? That he's not afraid,
isn't that a lie?
No, it's not a lie!
Alright. I'll show you myself,
accepting food from Tom's hand.
I'll show you all, about Tom!
I just hope Tom doesn't blow it.
So, hurry up and go, okay?
I'm going, guess what!
I'm not afraid, I'm not afraid,
I-I'm not afraid...
Hm, guess I am afraid!
You're a coward! Big coward, coward!
Eh, no way, I'm not afraid!
Just watch me, you'll see!
Hey...
I did it, I did it.
Huh, you couldn't do it one more time.
Uh-huh, too can do it!
Huh?
- Oh...
After taking the second walnut
from Tom's hand, Chatterer lost all fear.
He thought that if he'd
only felt this way long ago...
...he and Tom could've been friends
much sooner.
So now, Chatterer's statement,
that he was not afraid of Tom, was true.
And Johnny and the others saw that fact.
Yeah...
Subtitle: South Wind Subs