FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Peter changes his name"
Oh! I hate it!
Peter Rabbit, Peter Rabbit!
Oh...! Peter Rabbit, Peter Rabbit, Peter Rabbit,
I'm so tired of that name!
Why did I have to wind up
with such a crummy name?!
Gee, really gosh!
Hey, Peter Rabbit!
Well there, Rabbit, how are you, huh?
Hey, Peter, let's play!
Peter Rabbit, Peter Rabbit,
Peter, Peter, Peter, Peter...
Oh... I hate it, I hate it, everyone teases me!
If only...
If only I had an outstanding name...!
I detest it, I detest it... a name like Peter!
It's not polite to listen to someone
talk to themself!
Oh, excuse me, but you don't know
very much, do you?
Hm... what don't I know?
Even a name one considers bad,
is only as bad as one makes it.
Any name can be good
or any name can be bad,
depending on what one is and what one does.
You should remember that, Peter,
that when you're around your friends
your name is only as bad as you make it.
Depending on such things does a name
become good or bad.
Jimmy, I hate sermons.
This isn't a sermon,
I'm just telling you something
that you should know
without being told by someone.
Furthermore, if you don't like
to be called Peter Rabbit,
just change it to something else!
What?!
What was that?
What was that, that you just said?
I said, if you don't like it, why don't you
change it to something else!
Yeow, what a simple solution,
I could just change my name!
I could change it to...
Well, I could call myself, uh... uh...
Oh, what could I change my name to...?!
From this time, Peter completely lost
his appetite for food.
And when Peter forgets to eat, now that's when
he has something important to think about.
Anyway, Peter's head was full,
thinking over something
that, at least to him, was very important.
That's it!
I'll ask Sister South Wind to give me a name!
Sister South Wind!
Oh, Sister South Wind!!
Peter! Did you have some business with me?
- I have a request to make, Sister South Wind.
- What is it?
Uh... yeah. I want to change the name
Peter Rabbit, to something more suitable.
Can you think of a good name for me?
My, Peter! With a name
especially given to you by God?
Oh, yeah, but I don't like it.
Everyone makes a fool of it.
I want to have a more magnificent name,
and surprise everyone.
Please, I ask you like this.
You are a problem.
Must you absolutely change it?
Yeah, no matter what anybody says,
I've made up my mind.
So please, please...
Oh, please...
Just because you changed your name,
no one is going to think
that you are any greater,
if your conduct is not righteous.
Oh, rest assured, that from now on,
I will never play any mischievous tricks.
Alright then...
Since you have a tail like cotton...
what about Cottontail?
Cottontail?
Cottontail... Cottontail!
Thank you, Sister South Wind!
Cottontail!
Cottontail, Cottontail!
Cotton-tail! Tail!
Cottontail!
Hey, Peter!
What are you mumbling about?
Well, Uncle Billy!
Please, stop calling me Peter!
What's that?
I'm not Peter anymore!
From today, my name is Cottontail!
I don't want you to call me Peter Rabbit anymore!
Well?
- See you!
- But, Peter...!
Uh, no... that is... Cotton-Cottontail.
Yeah, I'll be...
Well, what is it?
Now, that you have such a magnificent name,
why don't you refine your language a little?
Huh...
Hardly concerns you.
Oh, dear, for two or three days he doesn't say
a word and now he comes out with all these...
...strange things...
That's right.
Evidently, what Uncle Billy said
is prying on Peter's mind, and he can't sleep.
Now he's practicing very hard how to speak.
That's terrible.
Wait a minute, I think I've got it!
Mhm. Ladies and gentlemen!
Everyone! Hello, it's the new... me!
And how are you?
I've changed... and so have you!
It's good to see you all!
Everyone!
Good morning!
Yes!
This is Peter, now Cottontail!
I am no longer the fun loving
mischievous rascal of yesterday.
Your understanding, please!
Hey, Peter, I heard from Joe, yesterday,
but did you change your name?
- Did you really change your name? Oh, OK.
- Hi, Sammy! No, Sammy!
You are correct.
From today I am called Cottontail.
- Did you say Cottontail?
- Yeah, what a great name!
No, that's correct, I'm no longer Peter,
so please, relay that
to our forest friends!
- I will no longer respond to the name Peter!
- Oh, even your language has changed!
I've got it, Peter! No Cottontail,
that's what I'll say, no Cottontail!
I'll report this to everyone, immediately!
News, I've got news, I've got news!
Everbody ought to be very surprised!
What did you say, Cottontail?
- Cottontail!
- It's really a funny name!
- I don't know...
- Even his manner of speaking, huh?
He said, "Please relay this to our
forest friends", that's what he said.
Sure would like to see him soon!
- He's coming...
- Huh?
Putting on airs!
Well, everyone, good morning!
Chatterer, Chatterer, I said!
Oh, he's funny, Peter!
To burst out laughing at someone
is very impolite!
Say, Peter, Chatterer didn't
really mean anything bad.
You're not any different.
I just told you my name but you
deliberately used the name Peter.
I'll have none of it.
Ah, excuse me, excuse me, my mistake.
Well, now is a good time.
If I associate with you, unrefined people,
my new name will be dirtied.
- Huh?
- From now on, please refine your language!
Until you can do this, please
do not associate with me!
Well, then, everyone...
Adieu!
Just a moment, Peter...
Cotton...
- Cottontail!
- That's it, Mr. Cottontail, that's it!
Oh, bad upbringing cannot be
easily overcome, it seems.
Too bad. Goodbye!
Uh... Mr. Cottontail?
Johnny, that's no good,
I told you a thousand times, didn't I?
Gosh, excuse me, I've made Peter mad!
Getting angry about changing a name?!
Hi, Peter, how are you? I've heard
from Sammy you've changed your name!
That's correct.
Yes, that's correct, Mr. Paddy.
From today I will be known as Cottontail.
Please, do not refer to me as Peter again.
Oh... Cottontail is it?
That's right, good name! Uh?
- Isn't it a good name...?
- Are you sure, Peter?
Is there something wrong with my face?
Oh, no, when I look at your face
it's still the same old Peter.
Old Peter, that name seems more appropriate.
Hm, my face may look bad, but what are you
trying to do, make me look like a fool?
Oh, that wasn't what I meant.
Darn, everyone is trying to make a fool out
of me, saying my voice doesn't match my face.
Maybe they're just jealous because
I have such a beautiful voice.
Help me, help, help me, help, help, help!
Help, help me!
Help, oh, help me, somebody, help...!
- Help me!
- Say! That voice! Isn't it Peter?
Really? What happened, Polly?
Let's go see!
- Ah, this is terrible, this is terrible!
- Help, help!
This is bad, we can hardly reach him!
That's it!
- Sammy, hurry and go call Joe Otter!
- OK, got it!
Peter, hang on!
Help... help... help!
Help...!
- Uh, come on, grab it, Peter!
- Johnny!
- Come on... Johnny! Oh!
- Peter, grab it!
Johnny...!
- Johnny!
- Peter, reach...
No good.
Hurry...! Hurry and save me!
- Peter, buck up just a bit more!
- It's no use!
Oh, Peter!
Gosh, it's Joe!
Joe did it!
He did it, he did it, he did it, he did it!
- Yes, he did it!
- He did it!
You're alright?
Peter, wasn't that swell?
I'm not...
I'm not Peter.
Peter, don't be so persistent!
I am Cottontail!
Now, hurry home and dry yourself out,
you'll catch cold like that!
That's right, I'll go with you, Peter.
Come, let's go.
C...Cottontail.
I'm OK, leave me alone.
What a guy, he didn't even say "Thanks" to Joe!
That's alright, I don't mind.
But with that attitude, the time will come when
no one will help him when something will happen!
Yeah, if he's always so angry, I'm sure no one
will tell him even if Reddy is near!
- Then I bet he'll be caught quick as a flash!
- Huh?
We'd better do something quickly!
- That's it, let's ask Reddy!
- Uh... ask Reddy?
What you're gonna ask of Reddy, huh?
Ask Reddy to chase after Peter!
If we do such a thing, he'll be captured!
No, we'll have him chase Peter
in a place where we can watch,
and then maybe Peter will realize
how important friends are!
I see, then you're saying to have Peter return
to his own self as quickly as possible!
- Exactly.
- But will Reddy accept those conditions, huh?
Well, what if he really is captured?
No problem. If things go wrong,
I'll just give Reddy a good squirt.
Strike while the iron is hot. Let's try it!
I wonder if it's alright.
Oh, yeah?
Then why should I help you anyway, Jimmy?
Well, if you ask me, I can't say, but...
this time help.
- I refuse! I don't have the time!
- Reddy! Agree to do it!
Oh, but, Granny...!
Oh, be quiet!
Aren't you a member of the forest family?
Do as you're told, and make everyone happy!
- I... Granny!
- Rest assured, Jimmy!
No matter what Reddy says,
I will be responsible and accept your request!
Really, Granny?
- Oh, but, Granny, that's...!
- Be quiet! What an unreasonable kid!
Just leave everything up to me!
- Is it no deal?
- Oh, he's coming back!
How did it go, Jimmy?
Success! Granny convinced Reddy to do it for us!
- Is that so?
- But... will they keep their promise?
Don't worry, Johnny.
If anything goes wrong,
just ask Sammy let us know,
and we'll step in and do something about it!
Now, let's go and report this to everyone!
What a fool you are, Reddy!
Oh, why is that?
Just because. When someone says something
like that, accept it and shut up.
Then, at the right time, you can catch him.
Understand?
Oh, is that all?
Oh-oh! Tomorrow,
what's going to happen to Peter?
Hey, Peter! Peter Rabbit!
Well, good morning, Peter,
we meet at a good time!
Hey, Peter, I've got some news!
Huh?
What are you saying, Chatterer?
This person isn't Peter, he's Mr. Cottontail!
Oh, is that so? Well...
I have some important news for Peter Rabbit!
And if I don't tell him,
there's gonna be big trouble!
Then, you better hurry and tell him!
Yeah...!
- Excuse me, I've made a mistake, Mr. Cottontail!
- Huh?
Chatterer!
Wait!
Important news? I wonder what it is!
- Mr. Cottontail, good morning!
- Good morning!
Reddy?!
Oh!
We did it, we did it!
Oh, that's right, I supposed to be on watch,
I almost forgot that!
Chatterer's news must have been this!
Oh, boy, today I'm gonna have a feast!
I shouldn't have been so obstinent!
Somebody, help me!
I guess I'd better try to save him this time!
Peter, go towards the Smiling Pool!
Reddy, thank you, that's enough!
Reddy, that's enough, thank you,
- ...that's enough, that's enough, that's enough!
- Don't be a fool, I'm not giving up this kill!
Ah, but that's not according
to your promise, Reddy!
This is bad, I'd better let Jimmy
and the others know right away!
That Reddy, he fooled us!
This is terrible, this is terrible,
Peter got it towards the Smiling Pool!
Well, pretty soon, Peter will be coming
and gasping for breath!
- But really, I wonder if everything is OK, huh?!
- Oh, you're still saying that!
Terrible, terrible!
Terrible! That Reddy,
he really means to catch Peter!
- Come again?
- And how's Peter, huh?
Right now, gang, he's fleeing this way!
Here he comes!
Stop, Reddy! Stop!
- Jimmy, OK?
- Hurry, let's chase them!
Help... me!
Peter... get on my back!
Darn, just a little more and I would've caught him!
Hey, Joe, come over here!
Come on, Joe, I need ya!
Reddy, if you don't get out of here,
you're gonna get a good squirting!
Oh, no, you cut it out!
Oh... not that! Uh!
Oh, for a minute I wondered
what was going to happen!
It's OK now.
Joe, thank you! Thank you, everyone!
You've all saved me!
That's not so.
We were really at fault, Cottontail.
That's enough with that Cottontail.
I was very wrong.
After changing my name, I finally realized it.
Is that so?
But, Peter, actually, we...
Jimmy! Nothing more need to be said!
Peter has been saved and he found out
that a name is not what a person is...
...it's what he does and what his friends
think of him that make him what he is.
Is that right, Peter?
That's right. If I hadn't thought
all of those strange things,
none of this would've happened.
I'm sorry!
Good, that settles everything!
Now, all of you go off and play someplace,
like real friends should!
Shall we go to the Lonesome Pine?
There's lots of wild berries there!
- Yeah, let's all go!
- Yeah, follow me!
Cottontail, you're in a good mood.
- Did something good happen?
- Oh, Sister South Wind!
I've decided to go back to
my very own name of Peter.
- And you wanted to change it... so much.
- Yeah...
But Peter is still better.
- So you finally realized it then, Peter.
- Oh, yes, Sister South Wind.
I realized it full well.
See you later!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs