FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Sammy learns a lesson"
Mmm, tell me why am I so beautiful!
And why is this coat I'm wearing
so pretty!
And my style so smart, whether viewed from
the front or from the rear, it's truly enchanting!
Why, I'm probably the No.1 beauty
in the Green Forest, no, no?
I'm the No.1 beauty in the world...!
Yes... how beautiful!
Hi...!
Good morning, Sammy!
Well, so it's you, Johnny and Polly, hmm...!
You know, Johnny, all year round Sammy's coat
is always so beautiful, I really envy him!
In the Green Forest, you're No.1,
with the prettiest coat!
- Maybe No.1 in the world...!
- M-hmm...!
You know, Sammy, grooming yourself is fine, but
maybe you might try a little winter preparations!
Why, I don't hibernate in winter like you do!
And besides, underneath this beautiful coat,
I wear warm underclothes!
So I stay warm all winter long!
But... in the winter it does get very difficult
to find food in the snow!
That's right, Sammy! I think it might be better
if you stored just a little bit of food away!
- Oh...!
- What are you laughing to yourself about?
Oh... because I've already made
arrangements for food!
- No worries!
- Is that really so, Sammy?
What... of course!
I have business to attend to,
so if you'll excuse me, please...!
It's certainly unusual about a lazy guy like Sammy
would make preparations for the winter
without being told to by anyone!
That's true! He might have
really suffered in the cold last winter!
Yeah, that must be right, Polly!
I can eat my stomach full of this marvelous corn!
Ah...! Nuts!
Why why, what happened to the corn?
What... what... what happened...?! Oh!
What happened, what happened
to the delicious corn?! What?!
Say, you thief,
what do you think you're looking for?
No matter how much you search,
you won't find the corn in there!
- I moved it yesterday!
- What, what did you say?!
Boy, are you mistaken, Sammy, if you think that
I didn't know you had an eye on my storehouse!
You may have meant to hide and watch me,
but the coat that you boast
so much about was clearly visible!
Hey, quiet down, quiet!
What...?! Trying to take other people things,
what do you mean, "be quiet"?!
Hey, hush up, be quiet now, hush up!
What?! You blockhead,
you try and make me quiet?
Now you've done it, Chatterer,
you've insulted me!
- What, I-I've insulted you? You've insulted me!
- Leave me alone, leave me alone!
Are you crazy?!
You leave me alone,
you're always picking on me!
What? That's my corn,
you thief, get out of there!
I don't want your corn, you just leave me alone,
why you little... shrimp!
- Shrimp...?! Oh, who are you calling a shrimp?!
- Quit picking on me!
Oh... my! Oh, look at how beautiful my coat is,
and how lovely my wings are,
I love it, I love it, I love it!
Oh, look! And look at how beautiful my tail is!
Such a pretty tail! Would they look suits
everywhere, but never find such a tail!
Could you even believe it's mine, how charming!
Sammy is beautiful, Sammy is smart...
That's so true!
It's on the outside, not on the inside!
What's on the outside, is not on the inside!
What's on the outside,
- ...is not on the inside!
- Hey, quit picking on me,
knock it off, knock it off!
Sammy is pretty, Sammy is smart,
But he must remember, to have a heart!
What, what? Who made up
that song about me, anyway?
I did...! Sammy, if you like it, why don't you
join in and sing along with us, huh?
Ah, what do you mean?
Peter, I know that Sammy may be shameless,
but he could never do that!
That may be so.
Well, boys, let's hit it just one more time,
slowly from the top, one, two and three...!
Sammy is pretty, Sammy is smart,
But he must remember, to have a heart!
What's on the outside, is not on the inside!
- Leave me alone!
- Sammy is pretty,
Sammy is smart!
But he must remember, to have a heart!
One more time!
- Sammy is pretty, Sammy is smart,
- Why-why, don't you know who I am?
- But he must remember, to have a heart!
- Leave me alone! Leave me alone! Uh...! Why?
- What's on the outside, is not on the inside!
- What, what? Quiet...! Oh...!
Sammy is pretty, Sammy is smart,
- But he must remember, to have a heart!
- Quiet!
- What's on the outside, is not on the inside!
- No, no!
The song Peter wrote,
quickly become popular throughout the forest,
with the exception, of course,
Sammy the Jay.
Sammy is pretty, Sammy is smart,
But he must remember, to have a heart!
What's on the outside, not on the inside!
Sammy is pretty, Sammy is smart,
But he must remember, to have a heart!
What's on the outside, is not on the inside!
Sammy is pretty, Sammy is smart,
- But he must remember...
- Hey, stop singing such a song!
No matter what he's done,
that's hard on Sammy!
Hmm, but Sammy was trying
to steal some of my food...!
That's right, to call a thief a thief,
why, what's wrong with that, Johnny?
What's wrong with that...?
Well, I'll tell you:
Maybe Sammy is at fault this time,
but haven't we at one time or another
all been saved by Sammy's news reporting, hmm?
Yes. That's right. You know,
if Sammy hadn't raised a ruckus,
we might all have been caught already
by Granny or Reddy.
So thinking about that, couldn't we be
a little generous, don't you think?
Hmm, but that and this are two different matters!
Sammy is pretty, Sammy is smart,
But he must remember, to have a heart!
What's on the outside, is not on the inside!
Sammy is pretty, Sammy is smart,
But he must remember, to have a heart!
What's on the outside, is not on the inside!
Sammy is pretty, Sammy is smart,
But he must remember, to have a heart!
What's on the outside, is not on the inside!
How mortifying, how mortifying, how mortifying!
How could Peter write such a song
and make the laughingstock of me!
Why, some day, someway, I gonna get revenge
on those guys, how can they do that?!
Why, it's Whitetail?
Ah, that's it! I know how
I'm gonna get revenge on Peter, why...!
He's going to be crying!
Today, why don't I go down to the Smiling Pool,
and I can teach them my new song!
What's on the outside...
Sammy is pretty, Sammy is smart,
But he must remember, to have a heart!
What's on the outside, is not on the inside!
Sammy is pretty, Sammy is smart,
But he must remember, to have a heart!
What's on the outside, is not on the inside!
Hey, Jerry, are you there?
Jerry, Jerry! Hey!
Joe! Hey, are you here? Hey, Joe!
It's Whitetail!
Peter, hearing the horrifying screech
of White Tail, flees for his life.
Terrified, he runs for cover.
Peter knows he's no match for such an enemy.
Peter!
Why are you such in a hurry about, Peter?
Huh?
This... This sure funny... Why... I-I-I...
Were you the voice right now?
How did you forget, Peter, that I'm good
in imitations, why, how could you?
I wanted revenge from yesterday, Peter,
so I've been watching you since morning!
Peter Rabbit is the No.1 coward in the forest!
Watch him run, and watch him hide,
Watch Peter run, and watch him hide!
Peter Rabbit is the No.1 coward
in the whole Green Forest!
You tricked me, you tricked me!
We're even now, Peter!
You tricked me, you tricked me, you tricked me!
Peter, you coward!
You tricked me, you tricked me, you tricked me,
why did you trick me?!
Sammy, having taken revenge on Peter,
now wanted revenge on Chatterer,
but, no matter where he searched
in the Green Forest,
he could not find a trace of Chatterer.
Johnny and Polly didn't know.
Grandfather Frog didn't know where he was.
Nobody knew.
Well, that's to be understood.
For Chatterer, every morning, without fail,
would rise with the sun,
and go merrily to Mr. Brown's corn field.
There, the harvesting was carried out,
in preparation for the coming winter.
And the leftovers scattered about,
Chatterer would collect for the winter storage.
Want some milk, Blackie?
Here you are!
- Johnny, over there! Isn't that Chatterer?
- Where?
Yeah, that's right!
Hey-hey, what's wrong,
what happened, anyway?
Hey, it's Chatterer!
We thought he wasn't in the forest,
and there he is, ah!
Right!
No wonder Sammy couldn't find him,
no matter how hard he looked!
Shouldn't we tell him that Sammy
is aiming to get revenge on him?
We'd better!
That Chatterer, I wonder
where he disappeared to!
There's Chatterer!
In such a place?
Hmm...
Looks like I might get my revenge after all...!
That's right, he was pretty persistent
with his questions!
No problem, I won't be taken in
by the likes of Sammy!
But Sammy can find you from the sky!
Then seek his revenge!
On a time like this, I'd usually warn them,
but this time, mm-mm, not a chance!
And then I ran with all of my might, oh...!
Why you, coward!
You shouldn't laugh so much, Chatterer!
Look out, Chatterer!
Johnny, Polly, you'd better run too!
Chatterer, keep it up, run faster, faster!
Chatterer, run this way, this way!
Chatterer, inside the rock wall,
quick, hurry, hurry, quick!
- Chatterer, here, here, here we are!
- Hurry, hurry!
Who do you think you are, Blackie?
Nobody's afraid of you!
No creature in the forest
can be caught by the likes of you!
How about that?
- Silly! Silly cat!
- Meow!
That was close, too close!
Serves you right!
OK, everyone can come out, now!
- Yeah, it's true, he's gone!
- That's good!
Everyone OK?
Yeah, Sammy, thank you for saving us!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs