FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"A gift Buster left behind"
Winter will soon be here.
Guess I'd better soon preparing
for my winter hibernation.
M-hm...
This being my first winter
in the Green Forest,
If I should waken, I'd better
eat more than I have up to now,
so that I'm not hungry.
Bears call it hibernation.
When winter comes, they have to find
a warm cave and sleep continuously,
without eating, until spring comes.
Therefore, in order to have
plenty of nourishment,
bears must eat many times before hibernation.
Huh? Such delicious looking munchies!
There's a lot to be eaten here, uh-huh!
Oh... hmm... Mm.
Hey! Hey!
Oh! Hey! Wait! Oh... Oh...
Hey, Buster, what are you doing?
Stop, I'll fall! I said, stop!
Hey, hey! Darn, he's trying to hog
all my winter supply.
Hey, come on there, Buster!
Hey! Whoa! Whoa!
Wait! Oh! Oh!
Hey! Oh! Hey! Oh!
Hey! Stop it! Hey, cut it out!
Oh! Hey! Oh! Oh...
Oh, some of my chow
must have fallen in the brook.
Oh... What a waste!
Help! Oh, oh, oh! Help!
Somebody, save me! Oh, oh, oh...
Hm? Chatterer, wait!
I'll rescue you in a jiffy, here I come!
Oh-oh-oh-oh, it's cold...
What in the world are you doing swimming
in the brook like this on a cold day ?
What? You're kidding!
I was gathering nuts,
when Buster shook me into the water.
I'm freezing!
Oh, Buster! Look at that!
He intends to eat
all my winter supply by himself.
That can't be? Buster isn't that kind of a guy.
I'm not lying, look there!
He's eaten them all.
Well, Joe, how are ya?
And Chatterer, I see that you're here too, huh?
Hm!
W-whatever happened to you, little fellow,
you're soaken wet?
Huh? You, crazy bear, you're the one
who made me fall!
Huh?
- Who, me?
- That's right, you! Hey...
Oh!
Say, Chatterer, you better take care
so you don't catch cold.
Quiet, you bum, I'm freezing!
Well, see ya, Buster, I'm leaving too!
I don't understand...
What can Chatterer be so mad about?
Hm. Hm. Oh!
This cave is cold. Yeah.
If it's cold here now, I'll hardly
be able to pass the entire winter here.
Tomorrow, I'd better find
another, warmer, cave.
How I miss the old forest!
It always really so warm.
First of all today, I'll fill myself with fish.
Then I'd better find a cave, right, quick.
- Hey, Harry, what are you doing?
- Who could just ignore that? Look!
Look what Buster's doing!
Huh?
I've never seen anyone catch so many
at one time. This is awful!
Yeah. Yesterday, Chatterer and Johnny got taken,
and now today looks like our turn.
Something's gotta be done about that, Harry.
Hey! Chatterer! Chatterer! Get up!
You're still asleep in there?
What is it, Sammy? Please, be a little quiet,
I've got a fever!
A fever? Did something happen?
Yesterday I got thrown into the brook by Buster,
so I've caught a cold.
Ah, I heard about that incident.
About Buster, we've all decided
to have a discussion,
and we're going to assemble today.
Eh, Buster?
Yes, that's why I came to get you, Chatterer.
Come on.
I'll go.
Say, listen now. No matter how big his body is,
eating sumptuous like that
will cause problems for the rest of us.
Listen, friends. In order to get through
the winter, we all need food, don't we?
Yep. That's right. That's right.
Buster isn't the only one that
hibernates in the forest,
isn't that true, Johnny?
Yeah. It's necessary for me too.
But then, what should we do?
I think... I think somebody
had tell Buster about it.
And who's gonna tell him?
Uh... Hm... Uh... Oh...
Huh...!
But we have to be careful. If we say something
boundlessly and make Buster mad,
it will be trouble. Just the other day,
he chased Chatterer up a tree.
Yeah.
The likes of Buster
should get out of this forest!
- Did I do something?
- Huh?! Oh-oh...
Bus...
Buster!
- Oh!
- Ah!
I see so many of you assembled here.
Well, just what's the discussion about?
It's nothing. Just, uh...
Chatterer, it seemed like you just
called my name, I mean, didn't ya?
I-I didn't say a thing, Buster.
I-I think you misheard me.
- Isn't that right, everyone?
- Yeah!
It's okay if that's the case.
Uhm... By the way,
does anyone know of a cave
that'll sleep someone like me?
A cave?
Uh-huh, the one I have now is really so cold,
I'd kinda like to find a little
warmer cave before the snows fall.
Hey! Hey, Buster! I know of just such a cave!
Oh, really?
Yeah. Go up there by the large tree.
And there's a big, big, cave.
Just right for you, Buster!
Gosh, thank you, Peter.
You're a life-saver!
Wow, was I frightened!
I thought I was a goner.
But, Peter, is that story
about the cave really true?
No, I told him about Reddy's house.
Oh, what did you say?
On behalf of everyone, I took revenge.
Clashing with Granny and Reddy oughtta be fun.
Wow, Peter, that's smart!
- Ah, let's go and see!
- I'm not!
I'm not either. That's really mean!
He's really frightening
when he gets mad. I'm leaving.
Me too.
It's safe.
I say we can watch him from afar.
- Chatterer, aren't you going?
- Huh?
Okay, it's settled. Forward, march!
Peter's really becoming a troublemaker,
which is causing a lot of problems.
Let's hope nothing serious arises from this.
Hmm... Now, where is it?
Buster, look, can you see that large
spreading tree over there by the rocks?
Now follow the trail to the right.
It's beneath that tree.
Ah, is that it, Sammy?
Well, thank you.
Looks like the fun's beginning!
Now, where could the entrance be?
Is this it? But it's such a narrow entrance...
Guess I'll just look inside.
Don't make so much noise.
Someone's trying to sleep!
I'm not feeling so good, lately.
Don't bother me. Enough is enough!
This is a little too narrow.
What could that be?
Wow!
Pfew... Oof...
What's the matter with you? Peeping into
other people's houses without permission?
What? Other people's houses? Huh?!
That's right. In any case,
this house is Reddy's and mine.
B-B-But... Peter told me
about this house, you know.
One of Peter's tricks again.
You must've done something wrong.
It's to pay you back.
But... But I haven't done anything wrong,
to Peter or anyone else,
for crying out loud.
No matter who told you, this is our house.
Isn't it, Reddy?
We've been living here for years.
So, hurry up and get out of here, please.
That Peter tricked me, huh?
But I've never done anything to hurt him!
He was so funny.
Boy, was he funny!
Buster was so funny when he came out.
He came out real fast and he tumbled on.
Serves him right! Boy, do I feel beter!
Somehow I feel sorry for him.
Say, Johnny, why not tell him
of that large warm cave near Chatterer?
Now, that you mention it.
There was one there.
Hey, nothing doing.
If he moves in close to me,
I wouldn't have a good night's sleep.
My, everyone's assembled again?
Somebody like Buster, who eats
everything selfishly by himself,
oughtta hurry up and leave
this forest, don't you think?
That's-that's right!
He eats so many fishes at one time,
it means there will be
no fish left for Joe and me.
Right! Buster is a kind of guy who
looks after his own welfare.
Mm...
So that was it?
I'm so big and eat so much
that everybody is angry with me.
But, unless I eat a lot,
I'll be in trouble.
If I wake up during my hibernation...
Oh, anyway, I'd better find a warm cave.
From that day on, Buster searched
all the time for a cave.
But a cave that Buster could sleep in,
cannot easily be found.
Furthermore, the animals of the forest,
day by day,
became colder and colder towards him.
I can't find a cave.
And everyone is so cold towards me.
Should I return to my old forest?
But... But, at this late time,
I couldn't reach it before the snows come.
Hey, Harry. It's really hard to catch
these fish today. They're fast!
At this rate,
it's gonna take us a little time. Hm.
Hey, Harry, Joe!
Hey, Buster! What are you gonna do?
I got an idea, I think you'll like.
Watch me.
Hey...
What the heck you're trying to do?
Huh, Buster?
I don't even understand
what you're doing, Buster?
Yeow!
- Watch. I'll catch a bunch of fishes for ya.
- Huh?
Wow, this is tremendous!
- Hm.
- Wow...!
That's my little gift for you,
- ...for all the inconveniences caused you.
- Huh? A gift for us?
Yeah. As of today, I'm leaving this forest.
Stay healthy!
A gift?!
Yeah. He said something like he's
leaving the forest today.
What did you say?
- Johnny, what do we do?
- Let's go over to Buster's place!
Chatterer! Chatterer!
What's the matter?
Well, er... gosh... Look!
Chatterer, look at all the fallen nuts!
Look at there, Chatterer!
So, those are Buster's going away presents.
Huh?
That's right. For Joe and Harry,
he thaught them how to catch fish,
because he felt so badly he had taken so many.
I can't believe that greedy guy
would do such a thing.
But, here are the nuts for you.
Oh...! Then, did he leave something
for you and Polly too?
I bet he did. Let's go see!
- Oh!
- Hm!
Let's go and see!
- Ah, it's here...!
Amazing!
Alright. This time, let's go
to Polly's house. Come on.
- Oh...!
- Oh...!!
It's here. It's Buster's present!
Buster really isn't a greedy fellow.
He just has to eat a lot,
because of his hibernation.
Oh.
Yeah!
Say, Chatterer, let's tell Buster
about that warm large cave he can live in.
If we don't do anything, I don't think
that Buster will stay in the forest.
Uh-huh...
But I think he's already left the forest,
hasn't he?
Well, we'll chase after him!
Sammy can fly after him,
and he'll be here in no time.
Ah! If that's your desire!
Mm... Now that I think of it,
maybe we were the greedy ones.
Why, thank you, Chatterer!
To tell the truth, Johnny and I
discussed this yesterday.
And, without telling you,
we were going to ask Buster to stay.
Oh, well, never mind such things.
We'd better hurry and chase after him.
- Sammy, we're relying on you!
- Okay!
Hey, Sammy, he's got to be
on the Crooked Little Path. Hurry up!
Got it. You guys hurry and come too!
This is the last time I'll see the Green Forest.
But, even if I return to the other forest,
I hope I can find a cave to live in.
- Buster, Buster!
- Someone calling me? Huh?
Ah, Buster, glad I caught you in time!
What on earth's the matter, Sammy? Huh?
Johnny and Polly and all of us want you
to come back to the Green Forest. Come on!
What are you saying? If I stay,
everyone else's food will be gone.
That's wrong! We've been talking and we think
that the greedy ones were really us!
We want you to come back
to the Green Forest, Buster!
Huh?
Oh, I don't know.
And my present cave is so cold
that I won't be able
to pass the winter.
Don't worry. We're gonna show you
where there's a warm cave!
What? What did you say?
Is that the truth?
It's no lie. Everybody's gonna be here soon.
Huh?
- Buster?
- Hey, Buster!
- Wait!
- Come on back now!
- Come on back!
- Come on back, Buster!
- Buster!
- We want you Buster!
Oh...
Hey!
Yahoo!
- Hey, Buster!
- We want you Buster!
- Hey!
- Buster, come back!
All creatures of the Green Forest
finally realized that Buster was their friend.
Buster's appetite was big,
but so was his heart.
We always must remember,
never to jump to conclusions.
Subtitle: South Wind Subs