FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Peter and the peach tree"
It will soon be winter.
In preparation for their hibernation,
Johnny and Polly must eat a lot.
Hey, Johnny, Polly! There he is...!
- Hi, Peter!
Hey...!
Come on, Johnny!
Let's go play, huh? Hey, hey!
Everyday, always eating!
Move out of the way!
Move, I said!
Boy, really, just when I'm so busy!
- Danny, wanna play?
- Nothing-doing, I'm too busy!
See you later. Bye!
- Bye-bye, Peter!
- Bye, Peter! See you later!
Hey-hey-hey-hey-hey...!
Wow, it's snowing!
Hey, Johnny, Johnny!
Johnny! Good morning!
The snow is falling! Johnny!
Oh... Not in, is he?
There!
Wow, who is there, playing such tricks?
Excuse me!
Johnny is a coward, he doesn't like the snow.
Danny, Danny, come on out!
The snow has fallen...!
Ah, so the snow has fallen!
Hm... Come on, I can't be dilly-dallying
around, for heaven's sake.
Move, move, I haven't finished
my winter preparations, oh!
Hey, Tommy, well, hello there!
- Hey, hi, Peter, good morning!
- Good morning!
You're in good spirits today, Tommy?
Did something good happen to you today?
Yeah... Do you know about
Mr. Brown's peach orchard?
- Huh, Peter?
- Yes, I know...
On his peach trees there are a lot of worm eggs.
So I wanted to take a look at those eggs.
Boy, are they good for you, Peter,
really good for you!
I'm just feeling so good...!
The peach trees, yes,
in Mr. Brown's food orchard!
Hearing about the peach tree,
Peter could not stop himself from going there.
He just loved the bark from the peach tree.
Mm-mmm, sure would like to eat some right now.
I guess I could run over there, huh?
- Mm...
- It's too dangerous.
When the snow falls, Granny
will be prowling the Green Meadow.
The hawk and the owl will be halfway too!
I already know those things, Danny.
You don't have to tell me.
And when you're near Mr. Brown's house,
Bowser will be there.
If you're smart, I don't think
you'd go near such a dangerous place!
Since hearing about the peach tree from Tommy,
Peter could not stop thinking about it.
Whenever he thought about
that soft bark of the peach tree,
his mouth would water.
Finally, Peter decided to go there.
Uhm.
I'm so brave! I'm gonna jump
and I'm gonna play!
I'm so... brave...
I'm gonna jump and I'm gonna play!
I'm so brave! I'm gonna jump...
What a fool!
Going to such a dangerous place.
And the Bramble Bush House
is such a good home, too.
Why is it Peter just can't stay still?
Hey... Let's go!
My ears are long, so I can hear!
My legs are strong, so I can jump!
Jump! Jump, jump, jump!
Eh...!
My ears are long, so I can...
Mm-hmm!
Mm... Wow! Great!
Wow, look at all of these beautiful peach trees!
Peter, unknowingly,
was doing a very bad thing.
If Peter ate all the bark of the tree,
the tree would wither away.
Huh?!
What will I do?
If I knew things were going to turn out
this way, I never would have come here.
- What a terrible thing to do!
- Yeah, sure. Sure is, son!
The trees with the bark eaten off
will just wither away!
Nothing to do but to cut them down.
Must be that rabbit from the Green Meadow.
Sure would like to fix him!
It's Mr. Brown and Tom.
I wonder what they're doing there...
What are they doing anyway?
Hm.
Hm. Now that's more like it!
Might teach him a lesson, that scoundrel!
Scoundrel? I wonder who Tom's talking about...
For the time being,
Peter was safe where he was.
But he decided to wait for nightfall
before going home.
Wait, now! Mr. Brown and Tom
were putting something on the peach trees.
I wonder what they were doing...
What a waste!
Why didn't I stick around to see?
Hm, I sure would like to see,
I sure would like to see...
Just a little peek,
just a little peek!
Hm. Ah...!
Oh?
What is this?
Huh? Hm.
T-That hurts?!
With this I can't eat the peach trees.
Hm.
Oh, that's cruel, that's cruel.
That Mr. Brown sure does cruel things!
Wow, that's cruel!
Peter, realizing that he could not eat
the peach tree,
now wanted more than ever
to eat the bark of the tree.
If only a little.
Furthermore, he completely forgot
about going home.
I don't believe it!
Look at that! There is one tree that Mr. Brown
forgot to wrap in that odd stuff.
Boy, am I lucky!
Oh?... Hey!...
Let go of me!
W-What is... What is this then?
Come on now, let go of me.
Oh!!
What is this thing?
Oh!
Hey, let go of me!
Peter now has become caught
in a trap set by Mr. Brown.
This is what Tom meant when he said,
"I'll punish him!"
Why... Why...
Especially after I came all the way back
to the Green Meadow?
Why? Why did I go back there?
Why did I go back?
I'm so dumb.
Ah...! Oh...!
Oh!
Ah! Oh! Oh!
Oh... Oh...
Oh...
Oh-oh-oh-oh.
Ah, ah, ah, ah, oh, ah.
Oh, ah, ah, ah, oh!
Ah, oh, oh!
Ah, oh, oh, ah!
Oh, ah, oh, oh!
That's strange!
What is it?
Oh, Peter, oh!
Peter! What happened, Peter?
- M-My foot.
- Oh...
- That's terrible!
- I know, I know.
Peter, I'm going to take you
to your Bramble Bush House.
The night is almost gone,
we'd better hurry!
Can you walk?
I-I-I think so...
Ah!
Look! Look, Peter, how wonderful!
Oh, Danny...
Thank you! Oh, you saved me!
Danny, what's Tom doing out there?
This is terrible, Peter. It's a trap.
Tom is setting a trap around
this Bramble Bush House. Scary, isn't it?
Danny, you'd better stay here for a while.
Besides, I have plenty of that grass that
you like to eat here under the brambles.
You better do that, right?
Yeah...
Huh?
After three days have past,
Peter's foot is completely healed.
Peter?
- Huh?
- Where are you going, Peter?
Well, I, uh, I...
Peter, you aren't going
to Mr. Brown's place by chance, are you?
Say, Danny, I'll show you something good.
I wanna show you that I'll be okay,
even if I go to Mr. Brown's place!
Oh! Watch out Peter, it's a trap!
Yeah, well... Look at this!
Hey!
Watch this!
Oh, I know where they all are!
Here we go...!
Wow! Hey! What's this then now?
Eek!
When the winter comes...
...this is my domain!
When it's covered in snow,
I will joyfully play!
Hey-hey-hey-hey...!
Tom should know this is my domain.
Hey!
When winter comes, this is my domain,
because everyone is hibernating for the winter.
Hey-hey-hey!
Oh...! Oh-oh..!
Johnny! Johnny, gone to sleep already?
Oh?
Hey, it's snowing!
Hey-hey-hey!
Oh!
In winter times, this is my domain!
Hey, Peter!
Hey! Hey-hey!
That Peter... What a guy!
Even though Peter got into deep trouble,
he was back to his playful ways.
But he learned, if you hurt something valuable,
you sometimes hurt yourself.
Subtitle: South Wind Subs