FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Johnny's hibernation"
Johnny and the others are winter hibernating!
Winter hibernating,
Soundly sleeping in a warm bed,
Johnny and the others are winter hibernating!
Winter hibernating,
Soundly sleeping in a warm bed,
Johnny and the others are winter hibernating...
Hey, Harry!
Let's play!
Oh, yeah, Joe!
Uh, slippery, slippery! Oh, oh!
Let me try that!
Hey!
Wow, sorry about that, Harry!
Hey, look out!
- Look out!
- Watch out!
Joe! Harry!
Yes!
How are you, Peter?
Oh!
Yeah, hi, Peter!
Say...!
I wanna talk to you!
Do you have a minute?
M-hm.
Buster and Johnny and Polly,
they don't like the cold weather,
so they are going to winter hibernation soon!
Haven't they started yet?
Grandfather Frog went to sleep long time ago,
he was one of the first!
- Hey, Harry, yoo-hoo!
- Hey, cut it out!
Hey, listen to me!
You slipped well, Peter!
Johnny and Polly are going to hibernate!
Understand...?
- Yes, so what?
When those I-hate-the-cold-guys,
go into hibernation, we won't be able
to see them until next spring,
so I'd like to give them a party!
Hey, listen!
So, day after tomorrow,
I'm thinking of having a farewell party
underneath the Lonesome Pine,
will you guys be there...?
Well, come on, hey!
Can't you understand?
Yeah, we got it there, Peter!
Make sure to be there...!
Why, Peter, a farewell party, you say?
That's right, by the Lonesome Pine!
Well, Peter, we'll all be there!
- Yes, yes, yes!
Uh, got it!
I'll be there for sure, uh-huh!
- Bobby, did you hear, Bobby?
- I heard!
- Did you understand?
- Yeah... tomorrow... right!
Hey, that's wrong, it's the day after tomorrow!
Oh, you understand me?
Aw... aw...
OK.
Jimmy, come on now, come on now.
Yeah, yeah, I'm coming, it itches, it itches!
Come on, now, Buster, for sure!
Uh... I sure will...
- Hey, knock it off, Chatterer!
- Oh!
Hey, you cut that out, Chatterer!
Oh, if it isn't Peter,
don't scare me like that!
You're the one who scared me!
Excuse me, but I didn't do it on purpose!
Chatterer, you have a storeroom around here too?
Yeah. Yeah, could be!
By the way, Chatterer, how many do you have?
Storerooms that is?
Come on, Chatterer, tell me, tell me
about how many storerooms do you have!
Huh?
Huh, huh?
Oh....! Peter, for heaven's sake,
I would just like to warn you...
Oh...! That how many storerooms I have
is of no concern to you!
Above all, you're such a gossip,
I don't wanna talk about
how many storerooms I have!
A gossip?
Who's he talking about, anyway?
Couldn't possibly be me, could it?
I'm a blue jay, chi-chi-chi,
Open your eyes wide and see,
Magnificent blue jay,
That's me,
If you intend to fool me,
Listen closely!
You better get up early
before the break of day,
I'm the magnificent... blue jay,
Chi-chi-chi!
Well...! What are you two whispering about
in such a place...?
Uh... Well, it's Sammy!
Gosh, we were just gossiping
that you're the most beautiful in the forest!
Ah, well...
Could be... huh!
Ah...! By the way, Chatterer, are you trying
to hide something behind you, there?
Uh, no, no! Uh, by the way, Sammy, did you know
about the big farewell party tomorrow?
At the Lonesome Pine,
the day after tomorrow at noon?
I know, I know, I know!
Oh, Sammy, you always know everything!
Hey! Very well, then!
The day after tomorrow, at the Lonesome Pine!
See you there!
My...! My stomach is very full!
- Uh-huh...
- Johnny?
Sleepy?
- Uh-huh...
- Don't... don't go back to sleep right now!
Didn't you say you still had
to get ready to hibernate?
- Uh-huh...
- Oh, Johnny, you're a good-for-nothing!
Uh! Oh, look, it's Peter!
Uh, look!
Johnny, look! Oh, come on!
M-hm...
- Hey-hey-hey-hey! Hi, Johnny and Polly!
- Good day, Peter!
Hey-hey-hey-hey!
The farewell party has been set for noon!
The day after tomorrow, so be prepared!
Johnny, Johnny!
Seems like... you've become fat
since the last time I've seen you!
- Johnny...! Johnny!
- Uh... oh...
- Oh, hi, Peter!
- Johnny...! You can't go to sleep quite yet!
Mm... Yes, I know...
Oh, I still have some work left to do,
to enlarge the bedroom a little.
- Keep it up, Johnny!
- Yeah... Keep it up, Johnny...
- Uh...!
- It's Reddy!
- Oh...!
- Yeah, keep it up, keep it up!
Keep it up
all you hibernating forest creatures!
Well, Polly and Peter,
you needn't be startled!
I'm really not as bad a fox as you might think!
The Green Forest has changed completely
to a winter scenery!
So all the forest creatures will be hibernating!
By the way... Could you, please,
include me too...? Could you?
- What do you mean...?
You know, that-that farewell party.
- Uh?! Really, you at the party?!
Uh... Yeah!
What's wrong with that?
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
- No...!
Peter, Peter!
Uh... Sammy!
Peter, Polly, I think Reddy really means it!
Yeah, I'll look forward with pleasure!
Till then, goodbye!
The falling leaves will soon be replaced
by the snowfall.
Reddy! Bye, bye, regards!
In short, Reddy's tummy is full.
Rumor has it that there was a chicken missing
this morning from Mr. Brown's chicken house!
But...?
What's the matter, Polly?
Won't Reddy become hungry again
by the time the party comes
day after tomorrow?
Dry leaves, dry leaves...!
Say, Jimmy, how are you going to pass
the long cold winter this year, huh?
Oh... I suppose...
...if it's nice weather, I'll probably
just go for a walk,
but... if it's cold,
I'll probably just pass the time at home.
W-what do you mean?
Y-you're going to lock yourself
in your house, too?
That means it's only Prickly...
Sammy and myself, huh?
Hey, hey, Peter, there's one person
that you forgot to mention, remember!
Uh...? Who-who's that?
Uh, tell me, Sammy!
Reddy!
Reddy?!
Hmm...
Hmm...!
All the hibernating folks are so sleepy,
they can't help it!
- Shall we wake 'em up a little?
- Huh?
Uh...
It's Reddy, it's Reddy,
Reddy is here!
Sammy!
Sammy, you frightened us!
Excuse me, excuse me, but I just wanted
to wake you up a bit!
There are some of you
who aren't frightened a bit, you know!
Ah, that Sammy guy really isn't any good.
To tell you the truth, he isn't honest!
That's why he's not liked by anyone.
Uh-huh.
Move over.
Oh...!
- Huh?
- Hey, Buster, wake up!
Buster!
Urgh?
- Boy, is he heavy...
- Sleep more!
Get up, Buster, get up...!
Hey...!
Hmm... What's going on there?
It's the weasel, Shadow the weasel!
Help! Help!
What are you doing, you Mean Weasel?
Get out of there!
Yeah...! While they're busy with the weasel,
I'll move in!
Buster, I said, wake up!
Buster! Wake up, Buster-r-r-r!
P-P-please, wake up!
- Hey...!
Give it to him, Sammy, that's right, you show it,
give it to him, get that Old Mean Weasel out of here!
That's right, come on, Sammy, yeah, Sammy,
come on, give it to him, more, more!
Yeah, Sammy, you teach that Old Mean Weasel,
that's right, Sammy!
Oh, boy! Yeah, Sammy,
come on, yeah, Sammy!
Look out, look out, Peter! It's Reddy,
it's Reddy, it's Reddy! Look out!
- Oh...!
My-my-my, that here sure is a good fish,
eh, man, he sure is now!
I'll eat half... and I'll take the rest...
home to Granny...
Thank you, Sammy!
No, not me!
Sammy, you saved us again,
thank you!
Really, Sammy, you saved us!
Oh... give your thanks to...
Buster!
Hmm, Buster must really be sleepy!
Buster, Buster!
Buster, I've got news, I've got news!
Buster, you scared off the weasel
and Reddy the Fox! You scared them off!
Yeah...
When was that?
- Uh...!
- My, Buster, didn't you even notice?
Don't you remember being bitten by the weasel?
Yeah... Yeah, if you say so, someone might
have bitten me, I don't know...
Feel that I...
Yeah, I wanna start my winter hibernation,
let's call the party to an end...
Hey, hey!
Buster, Buster, tell me about
your winter hibernation!
Well, I'll tell you this,
hibernation is hibernation,
but to everyone it's completely different...
Yeah, yeah...
Johnny and Polly, without anything to eat,
sleep soundly until spring.
I mean, they really sleep like they're dead...!
Well, Uncle Billy, once in a while...
...wakes up and goes out,
and I do that too, sometimes...
Mmm... Boy, to be able to... sleep like that, mmm...
Hey... Johnny, tell me about
your winter hibernation, how is it, huh?
Well, Peter, I'll tell you:
during our winter hibernation,
we don't eat a thing...!
We don't touch a thing,
not until spring...!
Oh...!
We do nothing but sleep...!
During that period, our body goes cold,
and our heart beats very slowly.
Almost as if we were dead,
it's really sort of frightening!
This is my first winter hibernation,
but I don't think there's anything to be afraid of!
My mother and father made their preparations
for hibernation, when winter approached!
And when the snows came, they're in their houses,
passing the time, until spring came!
My grandfather, great-grandfather, all woodchucks
pass the winter the same way!
That's why, Polly,
there's nothing for us to be afraid of!
M-hm!
Huh, it's snowing!
Well... Yeah...
I guess I'll start my sleep very soon.
- Bye, everyone, see you next spring...!
- Bye, stay healthy!
Well, goodbye, everybody!
- Bye, bye!
- Goodbye!
- Bye!
Good night! Pleasant dreams!
Goodbye!
Goodbye, everyone!
Goodbye, everybody!
Bye...!
Oh!
We finally arrived at my house.
It's time to part, isn't it?
Yeah. Pleasant dreams while you sleep!
Yes, I shall.
I shall think of all the wonderful things
that happened during the year, while I sleep.
Yeah, I will too.
Wouldn't it be nice
if our dreams were the same...?
- Oh, yeah, I hope so. Well, good health!
- Yes, thank you!
Goodbye, Polly!
Goodbye, Johnny...!
Hey, hi, Peter!
Hey, hi, Johnny!
Hey, Peter, didn't you go home?
Johnny, until I actually see you enter your house
for the winter, I just can't settle down!
- You certainly haven't changed!
- Hey...! Let's go, let's go!
Johnny, faster, faster!
Well, Peter, I guess this is where we part!
If something interesting happens during
the winter, I'll sure let you know!
M-hm. Thanks, Peter. Bye...!
Oh! See you next spring...!
Goodbye, Johnny!
Oh, get out of here!
Oh, for heaven's sake,
aren't you leaving, blue jay?
For heaven's sake, get out of here!
I'll tear your feathers out!
Get out! Get out! Get out! Mh!
Huh! Chatterer, I'll take a walk
- ...wherever I please, why you...
- What?!
You looking around my storeroom?!
Those two they won't be bored all winter long!
Goodbye! Goodbye! Until next spring!
Goodbye! Goodbye! Goodbye...!
Johnny, Polly, Buster the Bear,
Uncle Billy and his family
have all gone into winter hibernation.
Johnny must be soundly sleeping,
dreaming in anticipation
of the coming warm spring.
Now then, everyone,
until spring arrives, take care!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs