Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
I'm Joe the Otter,
I live in the river contentedly,
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
My fur is like a butter,
That's the way Mother Nature invested me!
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
What a yummy looking trout!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Hmm?!
Look at all those delicious looking fishes,
swimming all over the river!
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hey... where are you going?
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Wow, he's voracious! If I hadn't left that
trout, he would've come after me for sure!
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Say, Mr. Otter, isn't this your trout?
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Mr. Otter!
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hey!
Mr. Otter! Mr. Otter...!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Hey, Mr. Otter!
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hey, there! Mr. Otter!
Isn't this your trout?
I found it lying there, on the rock!
Don't be afraid, I'm a gentle bear!
The Commotion over the Big River
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
Yeah and I'm a-a-a....
f-f-f-fearless otter!
Aren't you hungry?
I think I'll fill my tummy with yummy trout!
Oh, yeah!
Thief! Robber! Fish taker!
Poor Joe, unhappy otter,
Is Buster a friend, or just a robber?
Can he trust the bear,
Or should he beware?
I feel like dessert. I think I'll have
some sour ants. All abode!
Hey, stop it!
Pushing over my tree!
Hey! Hey, knock it off of this!
What the heck happened?
Almost shook up. Who the heck...?
I'm getting out of here while I can!
This is my idea of living!
This is Paradise!
That bear eat all my trout,
didn't even leave me the bones!
Yeah, not even the bones!
That bear is a hog!
I can't bear that bear either!
I was rudely awakened
from my nap this afternoon,
that big bear doesn't have
any manners at all, right?
Remember we're all entitled to the fish
in the Laughing Brook, right, Harry?
Hear, hear! That's right, Joe!
It's share and share alike!
It'll never happen!
- Why, Grandfather Frog?
I'd like to know why!
Well, in my opinion...
if you... you'll heed my word...
I think we need action not words...
It's time to teach that bear a lesson.
All those in favour say "Aye"!
I-I-I've got a cramp in my leg.
OK, then it's settled.
Let's go, right, Harry? Huh?
Yeah, yeah!
Hey!
Wait, wait!
Onward!
Wait!
Oh-oh, leg cramps!
I can't help you, Harry and I
are gonna give Buster the Bear the business!
By tomorrow morning,
we're gonna get him, you'll see!
Yeah, yeah!
You two better be careful!
Hey, hey!
Joe and Harry were all aquiver,
as they went to the Laughing Brook,
they turned and churned and wooled and swirled
and completely muddied the river.
OK, Buster! There's mud in your eye!
Aha, here he comes, yep!
Ah, the river water is muddy...
and fish couldn't survive here!
Yes, I'll go upstream!
Now, for the next step!
Joe and Harry's plan is working.
And now, it is morning, one week later...
Rocky, Rocky!
Hey, Peter, why are you in such a state?
Rocky, Rocky, something terrible has happened!
Terrible? Terrible...?!
Why... what's terrible?
Buster hasn't eaten anything
in the whole week...!
- And, and, and...
- Huh...?!
And he's ravenous, and he's unbearable!
Oh! Now what's gonna happen?
It is going to be terrible,
I can hardly wait!
I smell trouble! Trouble!
And I love every bit of it!
Let's follow Sammy!
Rocky, come on, hurry up!
Will you, please, hurry, Rocky?
Trouble, trouble, can't miss trouble!
Help! Help! Oh!
So... you're the one
that's been taking my food...!
I didn't! I didn't, I swear, I didn't do it!
I cross my heart,
you're growling up the wrong tree!
- Go on!
- Oh, yeah?
For that I'll eat you for my breakfast!
You're the one who muddied the river
and drove the trout away.
I-I didn't, Buster,
I'm telling you the truth!
That's another lie.
That makes me even angrier!
Oh, no, what do I do now!
If I can get to that tree,
maybe Buster couldn't climb it!
- Oh, boy...
- I-I-I hope I can make it that far! Huh!
A kangaroo couldn't have jumped further!
Oh... Help, help!
Help!
No! Oh... Help me!
Oh, no!
Oh, no, poor Bobby, he's out on a limb!
Hey...! Somebody help me! Help...!
Help! Help!
Oh, I sure wish Rocky could run faster!
Hey...!
Rocky is already on his way,
running as fast as he can.
I'm exhausted...
Meanwhile, back at the branch...
Ah, what a lovely predicament!
Oh-oh, this is getting serious,
I'd better help Bobby!
I've got a good idea!
Buster...!
How about a nice juicy rabbit?
They're much tastier than raccoon...!
Huh?
Don't you like delicious rabbit?
Come here, my chubby yummy little friend!
I may be chubby but I'm not your friend!
Peter may be a rabbit,
but he'll out fox the bear! I made a joke!
I... I can't keep on much longer than this!
Huh?!
Huh... Peter made it out of that one alive!
Oh!
Buster! Hey, Buster!
May I introduce myself?
I'm Rocky Chuck!
Just what I need! A pushy woodchuck!
All you small animals make me really nervous!
Now why is everyone so mean to me?
Tell me, Buster, in what ways
have I been mean to you?
That otter and raccoon have been
treating me miserably.
I'm so hungry I could eat my own shadow!
Everyone in the forest is up to pranks
but they only do it for fun!
I'm all for fun but when it leads to hunger,
well, it's more than a bear can bear!
It's a matter of survival!
Joe and Harry think that all the fish in the
Laughing Brook are their personal property!
If a huge bear like you eats fish everyday,
they'll all be gone in no time!
That's a fish story! There's enough trout
in the Laughing Brook for everyone!
I've got an idea!
Why don't we play some pranks on them?!
Pranks! This situation calls for dirty tricks!
This is top secret! Lend me your ears!
- Well, I... I...
- You aren't afraid, are you?
Oh...! Just a little!
I'm beginning to like you!
Let's you and I be friends!
Come on!
Come up here and sit on my shoulder!
From Rocky's mouth to Buster's ear,
A plan of action, bold and clear.
Was put in motion by the bear,
At the Laughing Brook, so let's go there!
I'm a proud and bushy bear,
To my buddies I am better known as Buster,
I'm about to fill my snout,
With a mess of yummy trout,
So fishes are so delicious...
That robber... That wolf in bear's clothing...
Those are not his fish, sure!
Those are our fish, right,
my spotted friend, don't you agree?
O-o-o-of course...
Well, on the other hand...
That brown devil Buster the Bear!
That snake in the grass...
See that fly over there?
Now, tell me, who's fly is that?
Nobody's!
Why compare that fiddle fly to our fish?
Say something, Harry, there's no comparison!
I wasn't intending to make a comparison
just hoping one would fly by me!
He's flying towards me now.
If that delicious fly doesn't come
near me it couldn't be mine!
Now's my chance to get him!
Now to make it obvious, if Buster the Bear
came by and snatched this fly
could I watch and clear conclude
that he stole my delicious fly?
It's senseless, my friend, but senseless!
Doesn't make sense, Grandfather Frog,
I just don't understand it!
Well, tell me, Joe, what's the difference
of the fish you have caught,
and the fly I haven't caught?
Now, Joe, go ahead
and tell me the difference if you can!
You'll be better off if you listen to me, Joe!
If you're smart, Joe,
you'll make friends with Buster the Bear!
If I may suggest, you should make friends
with everybody you live with!
Here's a word of wisdom, Joe,
from an old frog!
"A stranger is just a friend
that you haven't met!"
Who needs wisdom, I want revenge!
Hey, Joe, don't do that!
If you become that hateful,
you'll poison your good character!
Joe swam home to go to sleep...
...and started dreaming
about ol' Buster the Bear.
He just could not outdo him,
He trell to chase the fish way,
But only drove them to him!
Hey, that will never change!
But Grandfather Frog was right!
I should make friends with Buster,
who needs enemies?
Oh, Rocky!
Look, it's Joe!
What's that...?!
It's Buster!
I wonder who is kind enough to leave
this wonderful breakfast here
for poor little undernourished me!
That was me!
I caught that fish especially for you, Buster!
Joe, this looks like the beginning
of a beautiful friendship!
If I may philosophies,
who needs enemies, eh, Buster?
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango