Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
The Monster of the Poplar Hill
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
…no one is smarter than me!
No one is better,
no one is smarter!
Oh?
Hello, Prickly!
How is my old blockhead
friend Prickly today?
What's wrong?
You don't wanna talk to me?
Maybe you're deaf?
He's probably really deaf. He doesn't hear
anything and can't talk back, either.
So I can talk bad of him all I want,
he won't hear me, anyway!
I'll tell about it, I'll tell about it!
I'll tell everyone in the forest.
Huh? Well, well, so you did hear me.
Then why have you been ignoring me so far?
Oh, wanna fight?
It doesn't matter if you raise your needles.
You'll never catch me, anyway!
A slowpoke like you wouldn't
catch me in a million years!
Come on. I'm here!
Catch me if you can!
Good, keep trying.
Almost there. Almost there!
That's all you've got?
Alright, we'll play again
another day, Prickly! Bye-bye!
Rocky, where are you going?
To see Polly. She's waiting
for me at Poplar Hill.
Good for ya!
Hey there, Rocky!
Hi, Peter!
You seem awfully happy today.
Going to see Polly, I bet?
Yes. She's waiting for me
at the foot of this hill.
Hey, hey!
Hey, hey, Rocky?
Do you know a porcupine named Prickly,
living somewhere around here, at Poplar Hill?
I heard he came to live here
from far away.
Yeah, from Canada, I think.
They call him "Canadian porcupine".
It's Prickly.
I think there's something
stuck on his fangs.
What do we do?
Heave-ho!
Heave-ho…
We did it, we did it!
Gosh. What an ungrateful guy!
He didn't even thank us.
You know, this whole thing
made me hungry.
Delicious!
So delicious, it's crazy.
It's been a long time since
I ate something this good.
Ah! I forgot,
I have to go see Polly!
Polly…
I'm… I'm sorry
for being late, Polly.
You just don't care about me.
But Prickly was in trouble.
I had to save him!
It's just, I've been waiting here
for a really long time.
Ahh!
I-I-Is there anything chasing me?
What?
No, there's only us here.
Uh… Really?
What's going on, Peter?
I-I was eating in peace,
when it suddenly a-appeared…
I don't know…
I'm speaking the truth!
But if it doesn't have feet,
how can it run?
Well…
Maybe it's…
Green the Snake can run very fast
and doesn't have feet!
Oh, you're right… Good point.
Maybe that monster
is still out there.
Let's check it out, Peter!
What?
Strange…
It was right here, I swear.
I don't get it.
Croak-croak!
I've been living here for a long time now
and I never saw a monster like that.
But it's true, I saw it.
Come on, Rocky, please, tell him.
I went to check that place
with Peter right away…
But by the time we got there,
it was already gone.
It's the first time that there's something
in the forest that I don't know about.
Everyday I fly through the sky and there's
nothing that can escape my sharp eye!
I can't believe that there's
such a weird creature in the forest.
But if Peter saw it…
…we ought to believe him. Right?
True, maybe he was nervous
and exaggerated a little.
Nonetheless, we should confirm whether
such a creature exists in the Green Forest.
I-I-I saw it!
P-P-Peter! I saw it!
It was exactly as you said.
Oh, I'm so scared!
Really scared, Peter!
It's just incredible!
It has neither head nor feet.
I managed to run away somehow,
but at first I got
petrified with fear!
My, my!
What a bunch of cowards.
I would never run away from it!
On the contrary, I would wait and
approach it to see what it really is.
Tell me something…
Are you sure that Peter and Uncle Billy
weren't scared by their own shadows?
No! There is a monster, Reddy.
Both me and Uncle Billy saw it,
we can assure you!
But I don't believe you
and I don't fear anything in this forest.
Reddy, I didn't know
you were so brave!
Maybe you could really find out
the identity of that monster?
Alright!
I'll beat that monster, alone!
As if it could scare me.
Good, good, Reddy!
So when are you heading out?
Right, Reddy!
Why don't you go right away?
It might be still
somewhere around here.
T-Today I have to take care
of a few things, still…
But I'll go first thing tomorrow.
Alright. And I'll make sure that you'll do it
because I'll be watching you from above.
Now if I don't do it,
everyone will see me as a coward.
Then you're really going, Reddy?
Darn right I am!
Reddy Now started to think that
maybe it was a mistake to boast so much.
Oh, how good it would be
if this night never ended!
But before morning came,
he thought of something great.
That's right! He could go to Mr. Brown's farm
and provoke Bowser to start chasing him.
Once everyone sees him being pursued,
they should shrug off the whole affair.
Darn, looks like
my plan has failed.
It's not my lucky day.
Strange. Something happened?
Reddy should have been here long ago.
He must've chickened out.
Oh! He's here, he's here!
I'm not afraid. Why would I be?
It's obvious I'm not scared.
Monster! Are you there?
Come on, don't hide.
Y-You coward!
Come on out, monster!
I-If you're so brave, I'll fight you.
I'm not afraid of you,
and you know it well, coward.
I saw it, I saw it!
Reddy is a coward, yeah!
Oh, Mrs. Jenny?
Please listen to this news I have!
Reddy ran away
from the monster!
As soon as he saw it,
he ran into the woods, the coward!
But I have to say that
he's very good at escaping.
He didn't even forget to properly call
"somebody save me" in a big voice!
Reddy pretends to be brave, but maybe
he's the biggest coward in the forest!
Can you believe it?
Reddy, when will you learn?
It's because of your bragging
that you're always getting in trouble.
I told you countless times
that no flies enter a closed mouth.
But to tell you the truth,
I've never heard of a monster like that.
I'd like to know if it really exists.
Otherwise I can't sleep peacefully.
Granny, you'll avenge me, right?
Don't be silly. I just want to make sure
if that monster really exists.
That morning, Sister South Wind
delivered a message from Prickly.
He wanted to see
Rocky and Polly, so they went.
It's Rocky and Polly.
Where are they going?
Granny Fox, despite her age,
was still very wise and agile.
Her plans were very different
from the ones she revealed to Reddy.
She changed her course
and went to the other side of Poplar Hill.
Granny Fox found Peter.
She knew that rabbits
are very slow at running downhill.
"I'll trap him", thought Granny.
Thank you for coming
to see me, friends.
I wanted to thank you
for what you did the other day.
You don't need to thank us.
By the way, is your throat better, Prickly?
Owie!
What's this? What's this?
What's this? Gosh, ow!
Ah! I know! I'm getting smarter.
It's a needle from Prickly.
Granny never lets
such an opportunity go to waste.
Rocky!
Rocky, Rocky!
Wait, it's dangerous!
Oh, no, it's the monster!
It's the monster!
It's Prickly!
Prickly, it's been so long.
Still enjoying
rolling downhill, I see.
Yes. I just arrived here,
so I don't have many friends yet.
But this time I wasn't playing.
I was just giving a lesson to Granny Fox.
I see.
Of course.
What's that?
Hello, Sammy!
We've discovered the monster's identity.
Really? Are you serious? Who is it?
Tell me, tell me, tell me!
Our mysterious monster
was just Prickly all along.
What?
Prickly was the monster?
It was Prickly!
Peter will stay at Rocky's place for some days,
recovering from Granny's bite,
but I can assure you
that everything will be okay.
Chatterer the Squirrel
always loved to play pranks.
Everyone became
so annoyed with his antics,
that when the Mean Weasel came back
to the forest and started to pick on him,
they decided to turn
a blind eye to it.
Only Rocky and Polly work hard
to help out Chatterer in his time of need.
How is this going to end?
Next time:
"Mischievous Chatterer".
Be there to watch!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango