Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Ready?
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
I found you, Kiki!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
What?
How did you know, Cook?
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
It's time to find Rocky, now!
If it's Rocky, he's quit already!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
- Uh?
- Yes, he's gone off, daydreaming again!
Fables of the Green Forest
What? Again?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
He's been gazing far off like that,
all day!
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Oh, I'd sure like to go!
How happy I could be to run
around in the forest all day!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
You never could go to a forest like that!
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
I will go, I will!
You'll see, I'll go!
There's something wonderful
awaiting for me far away!
The Green Forest is Calling Me
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
I've got to find adventure, adventure!
Don't mama and papa say not to wander
out off the forest, Rocky?
That's right! They won't let you in the house
and they won't feed you anymore!
I don't care, I can find food myself!
And as for a house, I can build one!
I don't think so, Rocky, you've always been
a fumbler, isn't that right, Kiki?
What's so funny, you!
Why, you!
Oh, look out, look out!
Take care! Don't hurt us, Rocky!
Come on, don't take it out
on us, Rocky! No, no!
Chiiil-dreeen,
don't fight!
It's Sister Breeze!
- Sister Breeze?
The time has come for you to leave your nest.
Leave the nest?
By that I mean for you to leave your parents,
shift for yourselves and grow.
Now look at this big open field...
...how wonderful to run and jump
in that wide world!
I'm-I'm scared!
Papa and mama will scold us if we go there!
Now, don't keep relying on your parents!
Resolve to stand on your own two feet,
show your courage!
xxx
- Rocky, don't go!
- Papa will scold you!
Don't blame us!
I'm...
I'm scared!
Now, be brave and walk!
He's really going!
- Hey, what shoud we do, Cook?
- I don't know, Kiki, I really don't!
Mmm, so much clover, I love!
Whaat?! Rocky left the forest?
We desperately tried to stop him,
didn't we, Kiki? Huh?
Right!
Dear, after Rocky, hurry!
Yeah... Hmm...
Dear, why are you so unconcerned?
Rocky has left the forest all by himself!
What will you do if a fox
or a hawk gets him?
Mama, calm yourself.
The time has come for Rocky to leave the nest.
Rocky?
You and I had our time when we left our nest.
Just like Rocky is gonna do now.
But...
...the child can't do anything,
it's too soon!
Mama, from now on Rocky is gonna learn
by experiencing and thinking on his own!
Rocky!
Let's meet again!
Let's meet agaaain!
Sure I've come far!
Well, off for home.
Oh, here I thought it was a baby,
but he has sharp teeth and it's smart!
Since I'm not hunting for food
maybe I'd better retreat for now!
Bye-bye, little woodchuck!
Hey, what do you mean, "little woodchuck",
I'm a grown-up!
xxx
Aha!
I finally returned home!
- I'm home!
- Welcome back, Rocky!
Here, hurry and eat or it will get cold!
Uh... excuse me for... being late.
Well, Rocky... so you went to see
the outside of the forest today?
Papa isn't angry.
How was it outside of the forest?
Oh, papa, outside the forest
is so wide, so large!
There was fish swiming
and lots of animals and clovers!
I decided to go live in a forest that's...
bigger... larger!
Oh? Where are you going to live?
I'll find a good place in the Green Forest.
Oh, the Green Forest, is it?
Papa and mama, why don't you scold Rocky?
Yeah... well, the time will come
when you, kids, will understand.
I'm definitely going to that forest,
I'm gonna jump around to my heart's content!
Cook, Kiki, Rocky, now, now,
how long are you going to sleep?
The sun is already up, now get up!
- Oh, mama, oh!
- Let me sleep more!
Now, now, what am I going
to do with such children? Oh!
- Cook, Kiki, where is Rocky?
- I don't know!
Me either!
What happened so early this morning?!
Oooh!
Papa!
Oh, papa's gone too!
Sure is funny!
Rocky!
Papa!
Rockyyy!
Papaaa!
Papa...!
Papa, where is Rocky?
Mama, Rocky has gone
and left home.
Whaaat?!
There's no need to worry, Mother.
Rocky is a grown-up and he can live
and survive well in the forest.
Oh! Rocky...!
Little bird, this morning I'm going far away
to the Green Forest to live! Bye bye!
- Well, I guess he's gone!
- Rocky...!
Rocky...!
Huh?
It's mama's voice!
Mama! Papa!
Forgive me, papa... mama.
Goodbye! Goodbye!
Goodbye!
Goodbye...!
Hi there!
Uh... uh...
Good day!
You're a woodchuck, like me.
Aren't you, huh?
Where did you come from?
Where are you going?
Huh? Wow, sure is fast!
Wonder what that is!
Well, well, well!
You, I've met you before!
Yeah, I'm Rocky Chuck!
Is that so? You must be the child
of old man woodchuck. And where are you off to?
I'm going to the Green Forest!
The Green Forest?
By yourself?
Oh, no, stay! But... but I still think
you should return home!
Oh, help me!
Give them back!
Give me back my clovers, please!
Don't bother me, I'm hungry!
Wait!
You?
What are you?
Return those clovers, you!
Huh, pretty brave for a little one!
Well, don't think too badly of me.
Well, I'd better go.
Oh, wait!
Stop it, come on, stop it, Rocky!
Oh!
Oh, I give up anyway...
Darn you, you pest!
Uh-hu, I got to see!
Oh, go, go, go! Yeah!
How's that you've had enough, you shrimp?
Had enough?
Who's giving up?
This could go on forever!
Let's go!
Shall we go too?
Here I come!
No, wait!
I give up...
Pretty tough shrimp, huh?
Say you...
...the day is almost over
and the Green Forest is still far-far away...
You better go home, right?
I'm going, of course!
Well... alright.
I'm going home. Bye!
It's still better for you to return home!
Papa...
Mama...
xxx
OK! Who's giving up?
I'm off for the Green Forest!
Let's see, he says that Rocky the woodchuck
is not yet appeared
and he's getting tired of keeping
a lookout so he's going to go home.
Why, was it too much to ask that woodchuck?
No use all of us waiting here.
Let's go!
What's there?
Hey, isn't this the guy I met yesterday?
Mister, hey mister!
Oooh!
Oh, the shrimp from yesterday!
Have a heart,
I'm finished fighting with you!
Oh, that's not it!
I mean, if you slept here,
the fox or a hawk might get you!
And please excuse me for yesterday!
Hey, I have an idea!
I'm going to the Green Forest!
Hey, mister, why don't you come along with me?
It looks so big, there we could find
enough food for both of us!
Mister, will you come?
What's the matter mister?
Yeah, Rocky, the Green Forest
is a wonderful place!
Everyone wants to live there, that's why
all kinds of people are mingled there,
likeable people and not so likeable people!
Fearful enemies and dangers are found there
but all are striving and living,
living cheerfully, pleasantly,
all bad things are soon forgotten.
That's how wonderful it is to be alive!
Yeah, that's right, it's the truth.
But, shrimp, that is a place
for young people like you to live.
Yesterday I lost to you.
I lost to your youth.
Me, I'll return to the pasture to live.
xxx
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango