Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Huge Tracks in the Forest
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
Hey, Polly, look at these
pretty flowers I found!
They're just perfect for you!
I don't like them.
Right, I just remembered a spot
with even prettier flowers!
Oh, how pretty!
Polly should be happy with these.
Better hurry home now!
What was that noise just now?
What is this?
There's nothing there!
It was just my imagination!
Wow, a bigger footprint
than this tree, you say?
Boy, yeah,
it must be a big one, wow!
Honestly, I really did!
I saw it with my own eyes!
Maybe it was a ghost?
All right, then, come with me!
That monster might be still around.
Nah, I think we'll pass.
Follow me.
It was around here.
There's nothing around here,
is there?
Do… Do such
huge beasts even exist?
Aha! Everyone, come here!
Look at this.
It looks like a giant track!
That's a track, you say?
No animal in existence could
leave such a huge track, dummy!
But I'm saying, I really did see it.
Oh, everyone, come here!
Look up there, at this tree!
Looks like a scratch left by a claw.
What do you think?
Oh, look at that!
Oh, wow!
Who could've done this?!
There are more tracks!
It continues on into the forest…
Uh-oh! Looks like those tracks
go to my storehouse…
Chatterer!
I better wait here!
Darn, darn, darn!
Who destroyed my storehouse? Who!?
It's all gone, gone, gone!
Who ate it?!
All my hard work,
all my berries and everything!
You have no idea how hard
it was to gather it all.
Darn, darn, darn!
Who could have done this?
What's this uproar about?
Oh, Uncle Billy, have you seen
a beast around here, with big feet?
A beast? No, I didn't.
I met lot of folks on the way over here,
but nobody mentioned anything about it.
Look at this. These are the tracks
that the beast made.
Oh… this is it?
That's funny. As far as I know, there aren't
any animals in this area with such big feet.
This must be someone
playing tricks.
Well, so long.
Squeak, squeak!
Oh, my. Excuse me.
Well, so long!
You hear that? There is no animal
in this forest to leave such big tracks.
– Yeah, somebody's playing tricks.
– If Uncle Billy says so, it can't be wrong.
I know, somebody stole my food and made it
look like the work of a big footed devil!
Darn, darn, darn!
Then the culprit is…
The one who claims to have seen
the nonexistent monster.
Are you saying that the one
who made the tracks,
took the tree down
and stole Chatterer's food was me?
You can't be serious…
Chatterer!
Surely you don't have
any doubts about me?
It wasn't me. There really is a big-footed
monster! You've got to believe me!
Believe me… Please.
Don't be silly!
Rocky couldn't do such a thing!
To doubt Rocky is cruel!
You can't fool us with tears!
Get out of this forest, you thief!
Cheer up, Rocky.
But they called me a thief…
Hey, Joe, good morning!
Huh?
Hey, have you seen a best
with feet as big as this?
Grandfather! Grandfather Frog!
Say, have you seen
a big footed monster?
Spotty!
Hey! Danny, Chip! Say…
Let's go home, Polly.
There's no one who will even believe us.
It's too early to give up.
Finally Rocky has to
leave the forest!
I guess I'll just leave.
Rocky, wait! You really saw
the monster, didn't you?
You really didn't steal
anything, did you?
Why don't you try
and find the real thief?
I believe you, Rocky. I'll help you,
even if nobody else in the forest will.
Polly…
Rocky, let's go search for it,
with just the two of us.
Thank you, Polly.
I feel much better now!
All right, I'm not giving up!
And I'll never think about
leaving this forest again.
Oh, goodie.
All right.
Let's go find that monster!
Yep.
So now, Rocky and Polly
set out to search for the monster.
Polly?
Polly! Polly!…
Polly!
Where did she stray off to?
Stop playing around and come!
I'm not playing around.
How did it happen, Polly?
I got dirty in the Laughing Brook.
Oh, it happened when
we crossed the river!
Look at your face!
Sorry.
My clothes are messy
and all you do is laugh!
Not to mention you
didn't notice when I fell.
Uhm… sorry, Polly.
I really didn't mean it.
Well, well, so here you are!
Well, Rocky, what happened
to your monster search?
My, my, Polly,
how dirty your face is!
You keep trying so hard,
but you'll never find it.
Why don't you just give up?
Oh, be quiet!
Now, now!
The likes of you can never
understand Rocky's feelings!
I'll be pretty
in no time, just you watch.
No matter how hard you try, stubborn Polly,
what doesn't exist, doesn't exist!
It's humans! It's humans!
Save yourselves!
– What happened?
– It's a bear!
It couldn't be.
I'm sure it was over there,
by the shadow of that tree.
You must be seeing things. There haven't
been any bears in this forest for a long time.
I wouldn't say so.
Anyway, we'd better
call it a day soon.
We should be out
of the forest by sundown.
Right.
Does the monster really exist?
Hey, Bobby!
Huh?
Bobby?
Hey, Bobby!
Peter, please, don't block my way.
I wanna get home and go to sleep.
You were up playing around
all night again?
Say, Bobby…
You haven't seen Rocky, have you?
– No, I haven't seen him.
– I wonder what he's doing…
…hear this, hear this, hear this!
Hear this!
Something happened, I guess.
Hear this! Hear this!
Peter, I'm going home to sleep.
I'm so tired!
Sleep… Sleep.
Sammy!
Did something happen?
Ah, Peter.
I was just looking for you.
Rocky and Polly are in big trouble.
They're all muddy from falling in the river
and Polly is crying!
And to top it all off,
humans are here!
Humans?!
With guns! Kaboom!
Were they… hit?
Gosh, I don't know. I got so wound up,
I didn't even see what happened after that!
Sammy!
Where did it happen?!
What, are you going there?
That's why I'm asking!
Upstream,
by the Laughing Brook!
That said, why don't you
just let this thief be?
It's all right, Polly.
I'll search by myself.
No! I said I would help,
so I'm going to help!
But…
W-W-What was that, just now?
Boy, am I hungry…
I sure am hungry.
Boy, I sure came a long way here.
I've been traveling a long time.
I sure could use a full meal.
– Rocky!
– Peter!
Did you hear the growling?
What was that?
I sure would like
a hearty meal of anything.
He must be hungry.
Having come from far away, this bear,
unfamiliar with the Green Forest,
could not find enough food to eat
and consequently, was very hungry.
The bear went further and further into the
forest, until he finally reached the other side.
Behind the forest trees,
Mr. Brown's farm stretches out.
The man loading strawberries
is Mr. Brown's son, Tom.
Oww!
I'm Buster, you know.
Buster the Bear, yeah!
Joe the Otter thought
the river fish was all his own,
so when Buster the Bear
settled in the Green Forest
he got very upset at the news that
someone else was eating fish from the river.
Joe chased away the fish.
Buster got very hungry again.
A hungry bear does not bode well.
What will Rocky do?
Next time on "Fables of the Green Forest":
"The Commotion over the Big River".
Be there to watch!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango