Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Mischievous Chatterer
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
I wonder if there are such easy to live in
forests far beyond this horizon as well?
I got news, again!
I got news, big news!
I got news, I got news!
I got big news!
News! I have news!
Big news, Peter!
News! News!
What happened, Sammy?
Let's check this out!
News! News! Big news!
Rocky! Polly!
Listen, listen!
You know why
Chatterer's so depressed?
The reason Chatterer
is depressed is because…
The Mean Weasel is coming home!
The Mean Weasel?!
Dear me, no wonder
Chatterer is so glum!
When I told Chatterer the bad news,
he trembled like a leaf!
Really? Poor thing.
Hi, Chatterer!
Hmph! Just because it's not your problem,
you're all having fun on my expense!
That's not true at all, Chatterer!
Rocky's right, we're all afraid
of the Mean Weasel!
You're lucky, Peter.
You can hide in the Briar Patch!
I've no place to go,
I can't escape from the Mean Weasel!
Now, we've got to do something!
Words, words!
There's nothing you possibly can do!
Chatterer…
Apparently the Mean Weasel
holds a huge grudge against Chatterer.
Ah, fascinating!
Extra! More news,
news, great news!
I understand.
Grandfather Frog…
Please, tell me what to do about this.
The problem is that
you're such a meddling busybody.
Perhaps someone sent the Weasel
out to get you, Chatterer.
Problems, I already have problems.
Give me solutions!
I'm afraid I have no solution. Did you try
discussing it with your friends in the forest?
No. With friends like that,
one doesn't need enemies.
If you can't trust your friends,
it's time for you to leave the Green Forest.
I guess I'd better leave the forest.
How crushing…
Wait! There's no need for me
to leave by myself!
I've got it,
I'll take someone with me!
Oh, my. Chatterer apparently came up
with something, but it doesn't sound very nice.
Looks like he's
up to no good, again!
My name is Reddy Fox.
I'm a very bold guy.
You'd be amazed by my intellect,
and my very sharp eyes.
Oh, there you are, you crafty fox!
Hmm?
I'm not the only one that calls you crafty.
Everyone in the forest calls you that!
What? Everyone?
That's right! What's more, they all shout
“We don't dread silly Reddy”!
Argh! I'll show them!
Run over to Lonesome Pine.
Everyone who calls you silly is gathered there!
This is bad for my ego!
I'll show those animals how nasty I could be.
Darn it, gosh.
He fell for it!
They'll all be terrified, and some of them
will bid to escape from here with me!
Don't just sit there saying nothing.
Let's do something!
Well, well, you sure are
an inspired-looking group!
Why… it sure would astound me
if one of you had the courage
to face the challenge and chase
the Mean Weasel out of the Green Forest!
Oh, if there's one brave one among you,
my troubles would be over!
Alright, then, we'll fight!
Huh? Are you mad? Not a soul among us
can beat the Mean Weasel!
That's why we must all fight!
United we stand, divided we perish.
When you say “we”
are you including me?
Why must we all fight
for a rascal like Chatterer?
He's always haunting us,
insulting us, calling us names.
I know that Chatterer plays pranks
and keeps annoying us, it's true…
But he's one of us.
He's our neighbor, guys!
Rocky…
Well, even though he has teased us,
all he has hurt is our pride, yeah.
It is not that he hurt us, it's just that
he likes practical jokes, that's all.
If Chatterer leaves,
the forest will be a duller place.
You're right!
Chatterer can be quite amusing.
– Yeah!
– That's right!
But how can we contend
with the Mean Weasel?
We can beat him! Remember,
we've all got our secret weapons.
Right. The weak ones will cooperate,
and union their strength!
– Yeah!
– Let's do it!
It's Reddy the Fox!
Alright, everybody, freeze!
Which one of you called me silly?
Was it you, Peter?
N-N-N-No!
Was it you, then?
You, Sammy?
Who, me?! Never!
Then it must be you, Rocky!
No. I'd never offend you, Reddy.
Stop lying!
Chatterer told me everything.
Chatterer?!
Chatterer…
Well… I… uh…
How could you lie to
Reddy the Fox… about us?
Uhm…
Why do you do such things
like that, Chatterer?
You've got it wrong!
I was only… uh…
It really doesn't make any difference
because you're all gonna get it!
Don't run away, guys.
We're only weak when alone.
Didn't we all agree
to stand together and fight?
Y-Y-You're right.
What's this? Acting big?
Don't run away, guys.
Well, I… it just came
to my mind it's Sunday!
I never fight on Sundays,
it's against my principles.
I'm not afraid of you…
it's just that I'm very religious!
Phew! That was close!
Hey, that's a signal from Knocker!
I think that he says…
“Mean Weasel has been sighted
at the Laughing Brook and he's on his way!”
Um…
Chatterer!
I don't care about him anymore.
G-G-Green F-Forest, huh?
It's been a while.
H-H-Hey, K-K-Knocker.
L-L-Long t-time n-no see.
I-I see. “T-The Mean Weasel
appeared, SOS”, huh?
I-I-I see.
H-Hey, K-Knocker.
D-D-Do s-s-say…
Wanna know where
Chatterer is, right?
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Well, I don't know anything about it.
So ask somebody else.
A-A-Alright. Alright.
“Red alert! The Mean Weasel
has entered the Green Forest…”
I'd better hide!
The Mean Weasel's on the lose.
I hate to leave this behind…
Rocky, Rocky.
Are you thinking
about Chatterer?
Not at all! I don't give a hoot
what happens to that little troublemaker.
Polly, why is it that everything Chatterer
says and does upset me so much?
Polly realized that Rocky was kind and
grumbled only because he couldn't do anything.
Can't do anything, huh…
Gosh, I said that out loud!
I'm such a goofball.
I don't really want to leave.
But I guess there is no choice.
No! I just can't leave
the Green Forest!
Really, Rocky?
Digging a hole here.
I'm sorry.
No use crying over dug hole.
What's wrong?
You look so gloomy.
“The Mean Weasel's…
found Chatterer”!?
They've converged
at the Lonesome Little Path!
Gosh, again?
How annoying!
Where are you going, Rocky?
I'm going to see
if I can help out Chatterer!
No, don't!
Stop, you'll get hurt!
That woodchuck,
he's so fullhearty!
He doesn't stand
a ghost of a chance.
Robber! Robber!
Thief! Thief, thief!
Thief!
Robber! Robber!
Hey! Everybody!
Get out!
Chatterer's in trouble!
He needs your help!
Come on, everybody!
Chatterer boasts to be the fastest
in the forest, but this has now changed.
He keeps running desperately,
though he knows he doesn't stand a chance.
The Weasel is so flexible,
he gets to any place he wants with ease.
Rocky!
So you changed your mind, huh?
Yeah! Hey, Knocker reports
that the Mean Weasel has chased Chatterer
to the mouth of the river!
Let's take the shortcut!
Chatterer's in trouble!
It's all over!
It's okay! Just let go!
It's you guys!?
Gotcha!
W-W-Where did they all hide?
Where? Where?!
Hm?
– What? What? What? What? What?!
– Get him!
Will the Weasel be okay?
Chatterer, wake up!
Polly? What happened?
Look! They're all fighting for you,
Chatterer!
They are? For me?
O-O-Ow.
It takes more of you to get me,
I'll tell you! Yeah.
Oh, heaven,
they're no match for him!
What can we do?
It's Whitetail the Hawk!
Chatterer!
Hey, there!
Mean Weasel,
I dare you to come up here!
T-That squirrel!
Come up here!
A-A-Are you insane?
S-Stop it!
N-N-N-No way!
I-I-I-I'm outta here. Outta.
He-He-Help me!
What a heavenly smell!
My favorite trees.
I just can't get enough
of the Green Forest.
Hey there, Chatterer.
You certainly look happy.
Yeah! It's pure bliss!
It appears that you decided
not to leave the Green Forest, huh?
How could I ever leave
this beautiful place?
See ya!
Do you know beavers, children?
Beavers make dams.
They work hard days and nights
with their strong teeth
to build dams that
surprise even humans.
A beaver named Paddy came to the Green Forest
and made a dam on the Laughing Brook.
It caused the river to dry up.
Otter Joe and Marten Harry
aren't happy about this.
What is Rocky going
to do about this?
Next time: “Paddy Beaver
Comes to the Green Forest”.
Be there to watch!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango