Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Rocky and Polly
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
Oh my goodness.
I can't oversleep this morning.
I've got to build a house!
My happy home
in the Green Forest!
Let's see, now,
where should I build my new house?
There should be food
available at all times.
I'd love a place with lots of clover.
Under an apple tree would be ideal.
A tree that will bear a lot of fruit in autumn.
That's the kind of tree to find.
It's also got to have an area
where one can nap in the sun!
It'll be rather tough
to find such a place.
I just love to be able to sunbathe
in a nice sunny spot in front of the house.
Interesting.
I'm going to check throughout
this entire forest and find such a place!
Well, good for you!
Well, this is it!
Lots of clover on this clearing!
I'll give it my best!
Hey!
So you're homeless, huh?
Now, go away. And you'd better
not interrupt my nap again, you hear?
I'd better build a home of my own.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Can't you tell someone else's
house from your own?
Oh, is this your house?
I'm Green the Snake and you have
no business around here, you know?
Oh, my name is…
This is my territory.
Now you get out of here!
I understand, all right.
I'll go find another spot.
Ha, that should teach him.
Hey, you're Polly, aren't you?
The one I met the other day.
Huh?
I'm… I'm sorry.
What are you staring at?
You're no better yourself, you scaredy cat.
Huh?
I saw you apologizing
to that snake Green.
You saw that?
Well, that was a…
I don't think I want to know you.
Bye-bye!
Hi there, Rocky!
Is everything going okay, huh, Rocky?
Tell me, have you finished
building your house yet?
That's no good, Rocky.
Playing around all day long.
Rocky!
Please don't listen
to what Sammy's telling you!
What? What's that voice?
Who do you think you are,
trying to tell Rocky not to listen to me!?
Rocky! Come here!
Sammy is disliked in the forest,
so don't pay any attention to him!
You, you!…
Po… Po… Polly,
I'm going to get ya!
Boy, I'm so mad now!
Don't do anything to her, Sammy!
Ah! Ow!
I'm sorry.
Come on, let's go, Rocky.
Rocky!
Sorry.
Such a beautiful blue sky.
Such a beautiful…
Lush green forest.
What… a beautiful… day.
I sing pretty good, don't I?
It's the woodchuck's children!
Oh, gosh, it's Reddy!
What? Reddy?
Oh, darn it…
Darn it!
Hi, Reddy!
Wow, what's up, Reddy?
Ah, look at Reddy spotting Rocky and Polly,
the woodchucks! Get them, get them!
Over there!
It's a vacant den.
This soil is pretty soft.
No rear exit, either.
Ow, ow, ow. Owie!
Boy, he almost tore my nose off.
You were so brave, Rocky!
But you just called me a scaredy cat
moments ago, didn't you?
Oh? But I didn't really mean it.
I was just mad at you.
Let's forget about it.
Oh, my buddy Rocky!
Oh, my dear Polly!
Reddy is standing watch outside.
Maybe we could
beat him up a little?
You could easily do it, Rocky.
Oh, my dear Polly,
why don't you come outside?
You shouldn't be dwelling in some vacant den
on such a nice day. Why don't you come out?
Do you hear what he's saying?
Gee, Polly, you sure are lucky,
to be friends with a guy like Rocky.
I really never thought
he'd be so tough.
Say, Rocky, why can't we be friends?
I really think it would work.
What do you say?
Does he mean it?
It's a big fat lie, of course.
I really mean it, Rocky.
I respect you from the bottom of my heart.
Rocky, he's saying
that he respects you!
Can't you see he's lying?
Oh, boy, it hurts!
It hurts so much.
I'm dying! I'm dying…
Oh, it hurts, it hurts!
Ah, I'm dying!
– Is it true?
– He's lying, again.
Should I go out and check?
You bit him twice.
Even if he isn't dead,
there's nothing to be afraid of.
No, you just stay there
and be quiet.
But I'm getting hungry!
Oh, ah, it hurts! Hurts!
I'm dying!
It hurts, oh, ah…
I'm in pain… It's over.
Oh, boy, Polly's come out.
Rocky won't trust me, but Polly's a girl.
Oh, it hurts, it hurts…
Aww! It hurts so much!
Come a little closer!
Oh, I'm dying…
It's over. I'm done for.
Gosh, I was worried so I came to check,
but everything's all dug up!
Where is everyone?
Thief! Thief! Thief!
Robber! Robber! Robber!
When Sammy the Jay
cries out in that shrill voice,
you can bet there's danger near.
But Peter has a very bad habit:
he always wants to know where the danger is.
See? He just can't control himself.
Oh, help me, please…
It hurts so much, I'm gonna die.
Polly, Reddy's only pretending.
Don't get too close, don't get too close!
Gee, thanks, Sammy.
Watch out, Polly,
don't get too close!
No, I really can't move at all!
It's a lie, it's a lie!
It is the truth, I'm telling you!
You big mouth! Uh…
Rocky! Save me, Rocky!
Take this!
Rocky!
Ah! That's it!
Who could have done this?
Oh, we're out!
That Reddy must have given up.
What do you think, Rocky?
What's the matter, Rocky?
I can't go wasting time like this.
I've got to build a house.
Really have to watch for trouble
with guys like Reddy being around.
If I were to build a house…
I'd want it to be safe,
and I think I know the right place!
Really? Where is it?
Want to go see it?
Yeah, let's go!
How's that, Rocky?
Isn't this a wonderful place?
It is. It's great!
Hey, I'll build my house
right beneath this tree.
Reddy, as we know, is quite proud.
If he knew that someone had seen him
in this condition, he'd be really flustered!
But apparently nobody had seen him today…
Or so Red has thought.
In days of snow,
rain, even storm…
I'm going to build a house
that I can live happily in.
Peter!
That looks like a good house
you're building.
That's right!
This will be my new home.
Bobby, you remember him, right?
Yeah, he's Rocky
from Papa Woodchuck's place!
This will be my new home soon!
This is my new home
and it's almost completed!
It will be ready real soon.
Real soon!
One day, Rocky found huge tracks
in the woods he had never seen before.
Not even the animals who lived in the forest
for a long time could recognize them.
Everyone says that Rocky is lying.
Rocky has to find out
who left these tracks.
Rocky and Polly decide to follow them
and venture deep into the forest.
What do you think they saw?
Next time:
"Huge Tracks in the Forest".
Be there to watch!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango