Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
The Troublesome Four
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
Delicious! There's nothing better
than eating eggs.
Attention!
Uncle Billy has died!
Farmer Brown's son killed him!
Reddy…
Is it true what you are saying?
Of course it's true!
I saw Tom with my own eyes,
grabbing him by the tail.
I can't believe Uncle Billy died.
Rocky…
No great loss for us.
All he did was stealing eggs.
What a liar!
Reddy, you're lying!
Ow-ow! Owie!
Why are you
throwing acorns at me?
You're lying, Reddy. I'll never believe
that Uncle Billy has died.
It just can't be, you hear me?!
It doesn't matter if you believe it or not,
because Uncle Billy is really dead.
He's not lying!
Reddy's saying the truth.
I saw him dead as well.
See? Maybe he wasn't as clever
as everyone thought.
The news about Uncle Billy's death
quickly spread through the forest.
All his friends mourned
when they heard the sad news.
But Reddy was overjoyed.
He was always scorned
and ridiculed by Uncle Billy,
so the news of Billy's death
made him really happy.
That old black rat Uncle Billy is finally dead.
What a great happiness, I'm telling ya!
What an awful guy he was.
Yeah, he was a huge thief.
He went to steal some eggs
but was caught and killed.
Hey! That's not half bad!
It's the first time that I listen
to your singing, and you're pretty good!
It's Uncle Billy's ghost!
That Reddy, almost fainted
when he saw me.
How I wish that you all
had been there to see it.
But tell us, how did you escape?
I wouldn't believe if I wasn't
seeing you with my own eyes.
It was easy. I simply fooled Tom
by pretending that I was dead.
By pretending
that you were dead?!
Of course, my friends.
That's one of my best tricks.
I freeze my entire body,
control my breath,
my heart almost stops beating,
and everyone thinks I'm dead.
Tom fell for it
and left me in the field.
And here I am, alive and well!
Darn him, he fooled me.
Now everyone will laugh at me.
I won't forget that!
Uncle Billy has many friends,
but right now he felt alone.
What's wrong, Uncle Billy?
Why are you so serious?
He remembers about his wife and children
that were left in the South Country.
Although he doesn't want
to leave the Green Forest,
where he is happy, he wants to return
to his family in the South,
and he decides to tell
everything to his friends.
So I'm thinking about
returning to the South.
I really miss my family.
But if you go, the forest
won't be the same again.
Let's play together,
like we always do.
I'm afraid that playing around
won't fix my feelings.
Goodbye, Rocky.
Goodbye, my friends.
Wait, Uncle Billy!
You don't need to go away.
Why don't you bring your wife
and children here?
If all of you live here together,
you won't have to feel alone.
Of course!
Uncle Billy, Polly is right!
But how can I call my wife?
She's so far away.
Mrs. Swallow can do it,
she flies really fast!
Ah, that's a good idea!
I'll go ask her immediately!
Nice one, Polly.
Thanks, but now
we have much to do.
What do you mean?
Isn't that obvious?
We have to organize a welcome party
for Uncle Billy and his family!
I really like that idea!
Let's go, Polly!
A party, huh?
Great!
I agree with that.
Here goes Sammy, your favorite
newsbringer in the forest!
Attention, attention, listen up!
It's the good jay that brings
the news to everyone.
News that everyone
needs to know!
Listen up, everyone, attention,
attention, listen to Sammy the Jay!
Hello, everyone.
It's a beautiful day, isn't it?
They ran away?
What were they talking about?
I should investigate immediately.
Sammy went to ask
Reddy, Blacky the Crow
and even the Mean Weasel
about Rocky and Polly's plan,
but no one of them
knew what was going on.
Sammy thought
of a different way.
How wonderful, Knocker!
How I'd love to have your ability to do that.
It's not that big of a deal.
But why do you work so hard?
For the party, nosy Jay.
Oh, yes, for that. Of course.
Exactly.
Who knew you'd be
an honored guest!
Oh, but I'm not the guest.
The guests are Uncle Billy's family.
Oh! Oh, of course.
Uncle Billy's family.
It'll be a big party for his wife and children.
They came from the South to live here.
They'll have a big surprise
with this party.
Reddy!
Wait up!
It's about Uncle Billy.
His family is coming
to live here in the Green Forest.
What do you say?!
What you just heard. His friends
are going to give him a big party.
And they didn't even invite us!
They didn't?
Exactly. They didn't.
Darn it! How dare they
treat us like this?
Now I'm angry.
We will destroy that party,
I swear, on my Granny's honor!
…my wife is coming
from the South.
La la la, she's coming here.
My wife is one pretty busybody.
Her grouching
is the best in the world.
I can't wait till she comes back.
Now she's quite old,
but back when she was younger
she was good at cooking,
good at cleaning
and ironed all my clothes
really, really well.
She's the only one
who can boss me around.
Hurry up and come back,
my sweetheart.
S-S-Sammy.
Is that… Is that…
Yes, yes, it's all true.
S-S-So we're r-really…
That's right.
We're the only ones uninvited.
T-T-They'll pay us.
W-W-We…
Yeah, we'll show them.
I don't know. In my book,
we're letting them off too easy.
I-I agree.
Maybe we could get
invited to the party?
Sounds good, but how?
When the time of the party comes, we'll hide
close by to where they normally gather.
We'll remain hidden until
that stupid party starts.
Good idea, don't you think?
What we do after that?
When the party starts,
Blacky and I…
Bowser! Bowser!
Bowser's coming!
We'll give them a big scare.
You scared me.
I thought it was for real.
Gosh, remember that
I have a weak heart.
They'll all run away, afraid of Bowser,
thus leaving all the food for us.
What a great idea!
Y-Y-Y-Yeah.
So it's decided.
Yeah. Yeah.
The truth is that in the Green Forest,
there isn't anyone as bad as these four.
And they are so mean,
that they would steal from anyone,
and only cause trouble
for everyone in the forest.
They think that
they're so cunning, huh?
My, my.
Now they'll understand that it's not easy
to keep secrets from the great Sammy.
Quite intriguing.
I'd better look for Rocky and
share with him what I've just heard.
I almost forgot.
Today is the day that my wife arrives!
I'll go ahead
and surprise her midway.
My wife is coming
from the South.
Her grouching
is the best in the world.
I can't wait till she comes back.
Now she's quite old,
but back when she was younger…
Stop it!
Make it stop!
R-R-Reddy.
T-T-They'll hear ya.
Darling?
Is that you, dear?
Come, children.
Go say hello to your father.
One, two, three, four…
There they are, all together.
That means the party
is going to start any moment, now.
Exactly.
Hey, what are
Rocky and Polly saying?
W-W-What does it matter?
I-I-I wanna out already.
You think I like
being stuck here with you?
Bowser's coming!
Here he comes!
Run everyone, fast!
Bowser is here!
Everybody, run, quick!
Run, run fast!
Bowser is here!
Run away!
Why are they laughing?
D-D-Darn it!
I-I-I've had it.
I-I'm going to beat… beat them! Beat!
Ow! What are you doing?!
Quails are very clever birds.
Their specialty is building nests
that no one can find.
Rocky and Peter naturally are curious
where Bob the Quail made his nest.
But not just them – Reddy and Grandma Fox
also want to learn its whereabouts,
coveting a nice meal of
newly hatched chicks.
Bob and his wife
take necessary precautions,
but then, one the chicks
that hatched out leaves the nest!
Things are getting more
dangerous by the minute.
Next time: "Bob the Quail".
Be there to watch!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango