Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Rocky's Secret Door
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
All the little animals of the Green Forest know
how to protect themselves in case of danger.
This includes Rocky. In case of
an emergency, he has a secret rear exit.
No one would ever notice that a rear door
was located in such a spot, right?
There is delicious clover,
growing abundantly in this area.
There's not a single thing
that I don't know about.
I wonder what prank
I can play today, anyway.
There's Polly.
How can that young lady
eat so much?
She'll get fat by eating so much.
If she gets fat, Rocky will be sad!
Shall I play one of my same
old tricks to make her quit?
Ah! My tummy is so full!
What a treat! Ah-oh.
It's Reddy, it's Reddy, it's Reddy!
Huh?
I wonder if it really could be
what I'm thinking…
Why, that's a strange place
for a door to be.
I found it. Why, that's
Rocky's secret door there!
Hidden away in such a far away grassy field,
no wonder that nobody else found it yet.
Alright, then!
What if somebody learned of it?
If somebody learned of it, it'd be bad, right?
Hey! Reddy, my friend!
Good morning, Sammy.
Got some interesting news?
News? You're the one faster
than anyone on hearing news.
Reddy, there couldn't be
any news from my side.
May be so, my ears are pretty fast,
comparatively speaking!
By the way, Reddy…
you know about Rocky's secret door?
What?
Rocky's secret?!
Uh… sure, I know it!
Why, it was just this morning
that I found it!
You did? This morning?
Well, I found it
yesterday morning.
Rocky's secret door…
it's something!
I see. He must've
found out his backdoor.
Anyway, it opens right into
the middle of a clover field.
At first, I thought it was
the front door,
but located at the rear
of the tree grove, out of sight.
You know, Reddy,
nobody would ever notice that!
Right, I was only searching
the front of the house.
Furthermore, Rocky thinks that nobody,
and this obviously includes you,
knows where
his secret door is placed.
Oh, yeah?
You really think so?
Oh! I just remembered something
I had to do. See you!
See you later!
Go ahead if you feel
so important…
Are you going to Rocky's house
and find that secret door, Reddy?
He's really going there!
I can't stop playing tricks!
It's so much fun to play tricks!
But to have a trick
played on you…
…it's really annoying!
But we can't stop playing tricks!
We can't stop playing tricks!
Because playing tricks
is so much fun!
Rocky would periodically open the door
and smell the outside air.
One cannot be overly careful.
Rocky? Rocky!
Oh! Sister South Wind!
Shh! Rocky, Reddy the Fox
is nosing about!
Reddy?!
Be careful!
Thank you, Sister South Wind!
It's true, it's Reddy! He's roaming
around my secret back door area.
That's really funny.
Oh, wait!
Could it be that Sammy the Jay
was telling me a great big bib?
The woodchuck is an animal
found only in North America,
and is sometimes
called a groundhog.
Related to the chipmunk,
its body movements are very similar.
Woodchucks have a natural talent
for construction projects.
First they dig a vertically straight tunnel,
five to six meters deep.
This section is built so that when it rains,
water running in will not be a problem.
The house that Rocky built is like this,
but let's use our beautiful imagination
and call this long vertical tunnel,
a circular stairway.
In the horizontal section of this tunnel,
let's have another door.
Then let's also place
the tables and chairs.
Polly!
Maybe she went
out the secret door!
Just as I thought!
Sammy fooled me again.
As long as I know that,
there's no use hanging around here.
Oh, what a day!
I just love this backdoor.
What Sammy said was true!
Mhm… good.
Hey, Polly, watch out!
Polly, come back!
You spoiled it!
What's the matter, Rocky?
Oh, it's Reddy!
Darn it, if I've been
just a little bit quicker!
Never mind.
I can return at night.
Rocky, are you going
to close the backdoor?
Yeah, now that Reddy knows about it,
it can't be used as an escape route!
Rocky, if you growled at him,
wouldn't he be scared and then run away?
I love that backdoor so much…
I was thinking of giving up this old house,
and finding somewhere new to live.
What are you saying? We're not going
to give up our home sweet home!
If Reddy knows, next,
Granny will come, all laying for us.
We won't be able to live quietly.
It was a lot of effort
to make it like this.
Okay, I'll make the rear exit
in another place,
one that will absolutely
not be discovered.
From that day on, Rocky immediately
began working on another secret door.
Oh?!
What's this?
I don't hear it now.
Is it Rocky?!
That's funny that he would be way out here
in the middle of the Green Meadows!
I must be dreaming!
Rocky!
That really was Rocky.
That's funny, there's nothing
like an exit anywhere!
Well, it looks like Rocky has dug a long, long
tunnel that reaches to the Green Meadows.
Let's hope that the secret rear exit
is one that cannot be readily discovered.
Sure is boring! All Rocky does
these days is dig in that tunnel!
I wonder if I should go for a walk.
Hello, Polly!
Nice weather, eh?
Oh, Peter! How are you?
Uh… real good!
By the way, where's Rocky?
Everyday,
Rocky is digging a tunnel!
What? A tunnel?!
Yeah! Tell me, tell me, tell me!
Where, where, where?
Uh, say, where is he digging it?
Where?
It's a long tunnel that exits
into the Green Meadows!
That's amazing! He always does
such wonderful things, that Rocky!
Now that you mention it, I just saw Rocky
in the Green Meadows!
I was so astonished, you know?
He kept appearing and disappearing.
But I couldn't tell where
he was coming from at all!
Say, Polly, I'd love to know!
Come on, Polly!
You know I won't tell anybody.
Where is he hiding it?
Come on, you can tell me.
Goodness, I just remembered
something I have to do!
Amazing, amazing, I never realized
how amazing his house was!
Who's there?
Peter!
I… I… I…
Rocky, I…
I thought once in a while
I should pay you a visit.
And then, the stairs were so steep I slipped
and fell all the way to the bottom…
That's the whole story!
Rocky, you were
watching, were you?
It sure did hurt!
Boy, your curiosity
sure is troublesome.
Forgive me.
Have you seen Polly anywhere?
She went that way a while ago.
She went out, then!
It's Redtail the Hawk!
He's been flying around
since yesterday.
I told Polly
not to wander outside.
– Let's go look for her!
– Yeah!
Rocky! Hurry!
Boy, you're so slow.
Oh, pooh, such a face
isn't good at all.
My goodness! I'm scared!
What will I do? Oh!
About the time the evening sun
was setting in the Purple Hills,
the hawk finally gave up
and disappeared into the evening sky.
I'm so scared! So scared!
Rocky, separated from Peter,
is still wandering around in the forest.
She must've gone very far,
because it's getting really late.
Polly!
What on earth
could have happened?
Looks like poor Rocky
became a bit overwhelmed.
Why was he making
that tunnel to begin with?
He just didn't feel
like doing anything anymore.
But the next day, Rocky set out
early in the morning to look for Polly again.
Polly!
Who is she, who is she,
get her out of here!
Who does she thinks she is, barging into
somebody's house without a word?!
Today is the day
my wife has to lay eggs!
So this is really annoying!
I don't want her here!
What is this place?
Hey! Hey-hey-hey-hey!
Get out of here!
Get out of the way!
How nice!
Thank you, thank you everybody!
You're all wonderful, thank you!
Oh! That's right!
Where am I?
I need help, I'm lost!
Rocky!
Hey, Sister South Wind.
What's the matter, Rocky?
Why are you so dejected?
Well, Polly is disappeared!
Oh? Since when?
Well… since yesterday!
Hmm…
Sister South Wind,
I have this terrible feeling that
Polly isn't coming back to me anymore…
Oh, so that's why!
When I think about her being gone,
it makes me all sad inside.
How would you feel
when Polly is by your side?
When Polly is by my side,
then I feel big and strong and brave
like a woodchuck should feel!
I see. How wonderful
to have such a friend!
When Polly is cheerful and happy,
I become cheerful and happy as well.
It appears that you, Rocky, have found
the most precious thing in the world.
Little birds, what is the matter?
Rocky!
What is it, Sister South Wind?
They say that Polly is nearby!
By that tree, over there!
Thanks very much, little birds!
And thank you, Sister South Wind!
Sister South Wind?
What do you mean when you say that I've
found the most precious thing in the world?
Most precious thing in the world…
is for one soul to love another.
Polly!
Rocky!
Polly, if you run that way,
you'll be running further from home again!
Oh! That's right, isn't it?
Oh? Well, well!
Oh, gosh. Looks like
you found Polly, Rocky!
Yeah.
Sorry if we worried you.
Rocky, I wasn't worried!
I knew you'd find her!
Yeah, well, so long, Peter!
Rocky has completely forgotten
the sadness of a few moments earlier
and is again the energetic,
bright Rocky we know.
Never before, not even once,
has the Green Forest
seemed so beautiful,
and so wonderful.
Reddy the Fox is very vain.
He wants to show how smart he is,
but he always gets into trouble.
This time he gets shot at with a gun
and gets seriously injured.
Everybody in the forest is delighted at Reddy's
misfortune and comes to ridicule him.
But when it turns out that Reddy is unable
to hunt anything and gets very hungry,
how do you think Rocky, Polly
and the rest of the forest will react?
Next time: “Reddy's Huge Blunder”.
Be there to watch!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango