Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
The Thing the Forest Animals Dislike
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
Peter! Who is singing?
I don't know.
The voice is coming from over there.
Peter, Polly, you'd be surprised
to know who that is.
Ah, Grandfather Frog.
You seem to know who it is?
Of course I know!
It's an old friend of mine.
He's known as the Singing Toad.
The Singing Toad?
Oh, I can't hear him anymore.
I would like to know
what kind of person Mr. Toad is.
I know him, although we've never spoken
because he is not very sociable.
Honestly, I find it strange that
such an ugly toad can sing so well.
You know that saying:
"Don't judge animals
by their appearances".
That's right, Peter!
Don't judge anybody just for their looks.
Don't scare me like that,
what's the matter?
W-W-What's going on, Polly?
Look, over there…
Don't scare us like that.
How are you, Singing Toad?
So that's the famous singer?
I didn't expect it at all.
So, what do you think now?
It is really wrong to judge people
only by their looks.
Unlike old Grandfather Frog,
the Singing Toad is no good jumper.
But now he's trying his best
to run as fast as he can.
What could be the reason?
Look, what's that behind him?
It's Green the Snake!
It's the toads' worst enemy,
and now he's chasing poor Singing Toad.
Stop right there!
Don't interfere, Rocky!
Get out of here, cruel animal!
Rocky!
Green, what are you trying to do?
What's the meaning of this?
Just a moment, horrible snake,
if you do anything, I'll bite your tail, I swear!
Well, it doesn't matter.
I'm not that hungry today.
Don't you dare come back!
Thank you for helping me.
Be more careful the next time.
From now on,
we'll be good friends.
Thank you, thank you so much.
If it wasn't for you, dear friends,
that evil snake would have eaten me.
Thank you, thank you so much.
That was too close.
I'm so slow to escape,
so easy to be found.
To think that those little animals
had to rescue me…
What an embarrassment!
Now I'm starving…
Oh, yes!
There are some worms over there.
I thought I was the only one who eats ants.
Looks like I found a soulmate!
Singing Toad, what do you think?
Would you like to dine with me?
Why do you react like that?
The Singing Toad thought
the Bear was going to eat him.
When he heard his suggestion,
he thought he was making a cruel joke.
But Mr. Toad figured the best
decision was to pretend to go along.
After all, there is never harm
in replying in a polite manner.
I'll be pleased to dine with you,
my friend Buster.
Huh?
I said that I'll be pleased
to dine with you.
Not too far from here, there's a place
where you can find a really delicious food!
Follow me, and then
we'll have dinner together.
Hey-hop!
We've arrived, my friend.
It's time to dine.
I don't see food anywhere.
I'm not hungry anymore.
I've never seen
so many ants together!
Feel free to eat, my friend.
I've never eaten this much!
I'm so full.
Are you satisfied?
I could never have dreamed up
that deliciousness.
In that case, you can come and dine
with me whenever you want to.
Seriously? Thank you.
I will, I gladly will!
Be careful on your way back,
Singing Toad!
Thank you, Buster.
Hi, Mr. Toad,
do you want to play with us?
Haven't you heard me?
I've just finished dining
with my friend Buster.
I don't want to have
anything to do with you.
What's with this attitude?
He's already forgotten
that we saved him!
So ungrateful!
I don't care much about it,
but that was really rude from him.
What is going on, guys?
We're talking about Singing Toad.
Look, he's walking rather strange.
After dining with Buster the Bear,
he doesn't even want to talk to us!
He was so modest
when we rescued him!
I think he has a reason to act like that.
I'll go and find out!
Singing Toad…
Mr. Toad, I'm Rocky,
do you remember me?
Let me pass, please.
But, I'm Rocky!
We're supposed to be friends.
Oh, you don't say!
Don't make me waste more time.
Buster is my only friend
here in the forest!
Whoa, uugh.
Why are you laughing,
you rodents?
Did he call us rodents?
I can't believe it!
I told you, he must have
a good reason.
A good reason, my foot.
He's never had friends in his life
and he's just showing off.
I'm not really sure of that.
I have the best ears of the whole place,
and yet I'm not showing off for it.
Me neither. And I have the best
defense of the whole forest.
Nobody can climb trees
as fast as I do,
but I don't feel better
than anyone else.
You have a point…
If he keeps walking so clumsily,
he'll get eaten by Green someday.
Wait, I have a good idea!
Come closer and I'll explain it.
What we have to do is…
I think this is a cruel thing!
It's the only way to teach him.
Guys, I can go and tell it
to the Singing Toad.
Jimmy, meanwhile you can explain
to Buster what our plan is.
Okay.
Time to tell it to all the
animals in the forest.
Let's not do it.
Come on, guys, let's stop…
Mr. Toad!
Mr. Singing Toad!
Singing Toad, are you here?
Do you hear me?
I have news from
Buster, the Bear!
What do you say?
From Buster?
There you are! Buster is eager to see you,
and is inviting you for a meal.
Oh, well!
Where is my friend Buster?
I'll tell you now.
He says he's waiting for you by
the walnut tree at the end of the forest.
Can you tell Buster that
I'll gladly accept his invitation?
I'll do that!
Buster asked me to meet him again!
I bet he likes my company…
Singing Toad, you better don't go.
I think they're playing a prank on you.
You're just jealous.
Buster never asked
any of you for dinner.
You try to make fun of me, right?
How dare you try to
make me doubt my friend.
I shouldn't keep him waiting.
Goodbye.
All the animals started laughing
when they saw the Singing Toad passing by.
The only one who didn't join
was Reddy the Fox.
Peter doesn't like him so much
that he decided not to tell him.
All the forest animals were following
Mr. Toad, looking rather peculiar,
but he didn't notice them at all.
Oh, how are you?
You look tired.
I'm really hot.
Thank you for coming from
so far away, my friend.
This is a nice place to chill.
Oh, I feel flattered.
To celebrate this meeting, I've decided
to invite another friend, as well.
Oh, then, I'm not the only one.
He should be here
any moment now…
Ah, here he is!
Somebody help me!
We were too late…
Poor Mr. Toad, he must be unhappy
to see everyone making fun of him.
If we don't do anything about this,
he might end up dead.
There he is!
Oh?
Where did he go now?
Singing Toad!?
Singing Toad, where are you?
Here I am, help me!
Here, in this hole?
Help me…
Mr. Toad!
Here I come!
Try to jump!
Don't lose hope!
That was so funny.
Where were you, Rocky?
You missed all the fun!
It's something terrible!
Singing Toad fell into this hole!
He's a toad,
he'll be good in this water.
Spending some time there
will teach him a lesson.
But if he can't get out, he'll die!
Boastful Singing Toad, puff up
your belly and try to float!
Don't behave like that!
Hold on just a little longer…
Mr. Toad!
Singing Toad, don't lose hope,
we'll save you!
Thank you. But it's no use.
There's no going out of this hole.
I'm really done for.
Forgive us, Singing Toad.
We didn't want you to fall in there,
we just wanted
to teach you a lesson.
Peter, you should have thought
about the consequences.
I insisted we shouldn't have done it
from the beginning.
This is not the time or place
to be arguing!
You're one to talk, Rocky.
Why didn't you make them stop
to begin with?
I'm ashamed of you!
What's going on, fellas?
One second ago you were
happy and laughing.
Buster, could you save the Singing Toad?
He's fallen in there…
Hmm? He's fallen?
Thank you, friends!
Wow, Buster, you're wonderful!
But what's wrong with you?
First you ask me to teach him a lesson,
and now you ask me to save him?
Sorry, I'm the one at fault.
That's not true, if it wasn't because of
my attitude, nothing would have happened.
Buster is the best,
no doubt about that.
I'm nothing much, really.
Mother Nature is the one
that made me big and strong.
But I'm unable to hurt anyone.
I won't be a boastful
toad anymore.
And we will never make fun
of you again, I promise!
Polly and I made that promise
a long time ago.
Why haven't you told me?
Why? Tell me!
Look, look, there goes
Peter with his curiosity again!
Nothing good ever comes of it.
You ought to learn
to let go some time, buddy.
Do you now know what is it that
the forest animals dislike the most?
The Singing Toad sings in the lagoon,
They say he does it
When it's full Moon,
He is the major,
He's is a tenor,
His music always present,
Because he's a good friend,
Because he's a good friend!
One day, Bobby the Raccoon
has a nasty dream.
But when he wakes up,
the same thing happens as in his dream!
He meets Tom under
rather unpleasant circumstances.
Tom's found Bobby while he was hurt,
and has captured him.
He's taken him
to Mr. Brown's farm.
When Rocky and friends learn of it,
they go to the farm and try to help Bobby.
Next time:
"Bobby Wants to Go Back to the Forest".
Be there to watch!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango