Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Poor Mrs. Quack
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
After circling the Green Meadows, Laughing
Brook that flows through the Green Forest
transforms into the Big River.
I heard the sound of guns again.
Where do you think
they come from?
T-That sounds like
its near the Big River!
Scary, isn't it?
Rocky! Polly!
Oh, Peter, you're here, too?
Something terrible seems to be happening
from the early morning on the Big River!
W-W-What is going on?
I'm not sure myself. I just heard this from
Blacky the Crow, I don't know any details!
All I know is that
it's something terrible!
But never before has there been
such continuous gunshots.
It seems to me that the sound
is getting louder.
I wonder if this forest is safe?
We'll be safe.
That's right. This forest is safe.
They won't come here.
Polly, even if they do come, I'll protect you,
so it'll be safe for you and all of us.
What's so funny?
Huh, Sammy?
Well, how to put it…
Peter, what's so funny?
Why, now that you ask about it, I guess
there's really nothing funny about it, at all.
Absolutely.
Huh? Peter, where are you
going so fast?
If I go as far as the Smiling Pool, I might
learn something about those gunshots!
What's this? Are you trying
to get there ahead of me?
Rocky!
Are you going with them?
The gunshots
may start all over again…
I'm not going, Polly.
Dangerous or not,
I've got to know it all.
Mrs. Quack, it's better
not to overwork yourself.
Do your grooming when you've regained
your strength completely.
Yes… but it's just good personal hygiene
to wash one's face in the morning.
How true, but…
Oh, is it you, Spotty?
Fortunately, your wounds are light,
but you are hurt. You mustn't overdo it.
Grandfather Frog is the wisest
animal in this lake, you know.
You're better off
if you listen to his advice.
Furthermore, you just made a long trip
and must be quite tired.
That's right, that's right!
Grandfather Frog is also really considerate.
You should take a little rest.
That's enough flattery.
Usually you're talking behind my back
saying what a talkative old man I am.
Never… what?
That's Spotty!
Huh?
You… You're a cheat, Spotty!
Eh, that's awful.
Who's there? Who?
It's me. Me, Peter.
Oh, so it's you, Peter.
What's up?
I heard the sound of gunshots, so I came
to investigate. Are you guys alright?
Yes, yes.
That Peter, he's the most gentle guy
in the forest, and also the most curious.
The most curious
in the forest, you say?
Now that you mention it,
those long ears look like it, don't they?
Is that right?
Peter and Sammy stared amazed
at this strange bird.
It looked like a duck, but it was
the first time they've seen a bird like this.
Small in size, a brownish color,
it presented a neat, trim, appearance.
Huh? So you're Mrs. Quack,
the migratory duck?
Peter, what in the world are you
so surprised that?
Well, I never expected
to find Mrs. Quack here,
I thought that to meet her,
I'd have to go over there, to the Big River.
Well… Peter, since you put it
like that, I feel at ease.
No one will ever think that
you're here, Mrs. Quack.
So, rest here until
your wounds heal.
Eh? Did something happen,
Mrs. Quack?
Mrs. Quack has just fled
from the Big River!
Just fled the river?
Yes. It's really sad.
Does that wound hurt you?
Yes… a little.
What a terrible wound.
You'd better not move around.
Actually, Mrs. Quack is on her way home
to the North from the South.
She made a stop to the Big River
in order to rest and eat.
Some men were waiting
over there and she was shot.
She got shot?
How barbaric!
Furthermore, she got separated
from her husband and children.
We flew over the Big River,
led by my husband.
My husband carefully
watched the area below us.
He finally found a bush
where we could rest our wings.
There was no trace
of any humans.
That's when…
That's when they…
Fly away!
Get out of here!
Darling!
Fly! Escape from here!
I listened to my husband.
I and my children ran away
with all our might.
Just then, a terrible pain ran
through the base of my wing
and everything turned black.
How terrible!
What a scary experience.
Then, I don't know
how much later,
I had the feeling
someone called me.
On recovering my senses, I found I have
fallen to the underbrush of the Big River.
It was Joe, the friendly otter,
who revived the lady.
Joe, huh?
It was most fortunate that
he was the one who found you.
Yes, Joe told me that going to Smiling Pool
would be the safest place.
And… is your wound alright?
Yes, if I rest a while.
Right, better not move about.
Please, forgive me.
I've caused you great concern.
In this world one saves and gets saved.
Don't be apologetic.
Alright! I'd better tell all our forest friends
about Mrs. Quack's predicament!
Take care!
That's the kind of guy he is,
all buttermilk, Peter.
Take care of yourself,
Mrs. Quack!
Oh, that was our news caster,
Sammy, the poke-a-nose jay.
News! News!
Terrible news!
That will never do!
To the forest animal,
I'll be one step ahead.
News! Big news!
A disaster, a disaster!
Everyone gather
at the Green Meadows!
News!
After being called by Peter and Sammy,
everyone quietly assembled by the Lone Pine.
Here they all had a lengthy discussion.
What do you suppose they decided to do?
As a result of this discussion,
everyone headed towards Mr. Brown's farm.
The most good-looking
in the Green Forest,
that's Mr. Reddy,
the beautiful fox.
A stylish lady-killer,
his intellect razor-sharp,
faster and cooler than anyone.
– Reddy?
– Uh-huh!
Mrs. Quack, quick, hide yourself.
Go hide in those bushes
over there.
Alright.
What's up, Reddy?
Out for a walk out here?
That's strange.
What is?
Something smells
so good out here.
What are you saying? As you can see,
this is the same unchanging pool.
Something does smell very good.
Since when did your nose go bad?
What did you say?
Looks like you won't catch any game with
your lack of smell… Sort of feel sorry for you.
How about it?
I'll let you eat me if you like.
What a nasty old man. No satisfaction
eating the likes of you, you wrinkled old frog.
That's some nice manners
you have. Good grief.
He's gone, he's gone!
He's gone.
He's gone!
About that time, Rocky and his friends had
made plans about how to help Mrs. Quack.
It's alright.
Nobody's here, Peter.
So… that's it.
For the sake of the
very hungry Mrs. Quack,
Rocky and his friends had decided
to sneak into Mr. Brown's barn
and take some of that corn
that Mrs. Quack loves so much.
And the responsibility
of sneaking into the barn…
The coast is clear.
Yeah, let's go.
Peter and Chatterer, who were the fastest,
were going to take care of it every day.
– They've been spotted!
– What do we do?
It's over!
What a relief.
Everyone got taken aback.
Tom had guessed that Peter and
Chatterer had come to look for the corn.
So he scattered the corn in a conspicuous
place and left pretending ignorant.
Tom loved very much
the animals of the forest.
Oh, it's Bowser! Run, run!
Everyone, run! It's Bowser!
It's Bowser!
Chatterer! Hurry up and come!
Chatterer!
Rocky!
Rocky…
Did you get him?
Terrific!
Gosh, too bad it happened
to old Bowser.
I should have confidence in my feet,
but I was so frightened
that I was petrified with fear.
That's how it is
when one is frightened.
Is that so?
But… look at how
Rocky was able to run.
Should I say how impressed I was
with Rocky's courage, or how amazed?
Yeah, and I always felt
he was such a simpleton.
We can laugh about it now,
but I really thought that
Peter and Chatterer were caught.
Yeah. Yeah.
That Bowser is really scary.
You were scared, too,
Chatterer, right?
Right?
Right?!
Uhh…
Just a bit.
It's too embarrassing!
Thank you very much.
All this, just for me…
Mrs. Quack…
Don't cry, Mrs. Quack.
We did what we had to do,
because we want you to regain your health.
It's nothing to make
a fuss over… Huh?
That's right, that's right!
Thank you, everyone.
This is the first time that I have ever
received such a warm kindness.
Thanks to you,
I have mustered my courage.
Mrs. Quack…
I will not be scared
or sorrowful again.
I have feasted on the food
from your heart,
and the hurt from my wound
has lessened thanks to you all.
I will muster my courage
and try my wings.
I'm going to try to fly.
Please, watch!
She's flying!
Hey, look at her fly!
Mrs. Quack's flying!
She's flying!
Mrs. Quack, the duck, warmed by
the friendship of Rocky and the others,
flew gracefully
upward over the lake.
Rocky and all the forest animals had protected
Mrs. Quack with their help and friendship.
Mrs. Quack recovered under the care
of Rocky and the other animals
and was able to fly high in the sky.
Now she's looking for her husband,
Mr. Quack, hoping that he's still alive.
She wants to go back home
to the North with her family.
Rocky and his friends start a great rescue
operation to find Mrs. Quack's husband.
But through Sammy's chatter,
Reddy learned everything.
How will this end?
Next time:
“The Search for Mr. Quack”.
Be there to watch!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango