Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Sammy's Revenge
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
Chatterer the Red Squirrel finds a new home
on Mr. Brown's farm and lives there.
I had better put something in
my storeroom, even a little at a time!
Looking intently at the already
harvested corn field of Mr. Brown,
Chatterer got lost in thoughts.
Over there is Bowser the Dog…
Tom, too…
And that pesky cat, Blacky…
Nothing… Not a thing!
Oh, wow, here's a lot of corn fallen
where the field's not trampled so!
Hi there, Chatterer,
did you move over here now?
I was under the impression
that you lived in the orchard.
I'm busy storing food for the winter,
there's no food left in the orchard.
Ah! If it were me, I wouldn't be doing
what you're doing.
I'd just be using my head a little!
If you want corn, why don't you go
to Mr. Brown's house?
Why, he has all the corn that you'd
ever-ever want, believe me!
I go there often
and just help myself.
I wonder if what Sammy the Jay
is telling me is true.
If it is true, I should be brave
and go check it out!
Where could it be?
The storehouse that Sammy mentioned?
At that moment, Tom,
Mr. Brown's son, came outside.
Wow, look at all that delicious corn
he has in those buckets!
Tom brought buckets
full of corn from the corn house
and was about to feed it
to the cows on the farm.
I wonder how Sammy manages
to get food from there.
That's it! I'll come early tomorrow morning
and keep an eye on Sammy!
For the time being,
Chatterer decided to wait.
It's Sammy!
Can you believe it? Usually so noisy,
Sammy approaches without making a sound.
Quietly just like when he arrived,
Sammy flies off.
Hmm… I see how he does it.
If Sammy can do it, I can do it, too.
Today Blacky the Cat isn't here,
so I have the perfect chance.
What a funny building!
Turns out, the storehouse
leaned on stone pillars.
Furthermore, what are those things mounted
on the pillars Chatterer is trying to climb?
Those are pots,
attached upside down.
Mr. Brown put them to further protect
his grains from chipmunks and field mice.
Oh, if I only had wings
like Sammy has!
Now Chatterer pondered.
He knows that it's useless to wish
that he had wings like Sammy.
How could he do it on his own?
Is there any way for him to get inside?
Chatterer continues to think hard.
Ah! That's it!
Hey, Blacky, come over here!
You won't eat me if you don't come.
Come on, coward!
Too scared to follow me?
Scared, you coward?
What's the matter? Hey, you can't
even find your own food in the farm!
You cowardly cat!
Ha! You don't scare me
in the slightest!
I'm not afraid of you!
What's the matter, Blacky?
Ah! This is bad!
What are you making
such a fuss about?
Did you find a mouse
or something?
But mice can't get
into this storehouse.
It's alright.
You're probably just seeing things.
Come on, I'll give you some milk.
Blacky!
Oh, wow!
Amazing, fantastic!
This is it, the whole world
is made of corn! Wow, wee!
Hey, that guy is putting a lot
of my yellow corn in that bucket!
All the nerve!
Chatterer began to think that all the corn
in the storehouse belonged to him.
So the next morning when
he saw Sammy approaching as usual,
he thought about
getting him to leave.
What are you doing?!
What is this predicament?!
Sammy was really scared.
He was sure that
he had fallen in a trap.
Oh, boy. I've never been
so scared in all my life!
It must've been a trap set by
Mr. Brown's son, Tom.
Mr. Brown's son is an awful guy!
Better be aware of him,
he's out to get us, yeah!
Reddy had just eaten three crickets
this morning and was therefore in high spirits.
Hey. Hey!
Wow! That bug smells so bad,
he doesn't want to be friends!
Mr. Brown's son
is an awful guy!
Tom is an awful guy!
It's animal cruelty!
Tom is one nasty guy!
Listen, listen, listen everybody!
Mr. Brown's son is an awful guy!
Tom is a horrible man!
Listen! Everybody, Mr. Brown's son
is cruel! I'm telling you!
Hey, Chatterer!
You know what Tom did?
He's an awful guy!
I've never seen anybody so cruel before!
A trap! I fell victim
to a great big trap!
Having all that corn and he doesn't
even give me two or three kernels.
Why, what kind of guy is that,
that stinking old minor!
But his trap is really fearsome.
Oh, boy, just remembering
about it makes me so scared!
If I can get revenge,
why… I would!…
Chatterer, watch out
for yourself, too.
You'd better not go
near Tom's storehouse.
I'm gonna spread the word all around
the forest to be aware of Tom's traps,
and to not go near that farm.
See you!
Something's fishy here. Tomorrow morning
I think I'll go visit Mr. Brown's house.
How many times have I told you
not to go near any dangerous places?
That's the secret to long life!
Gosh! It's Chatterer.
So that's it.
Now I've got it.
That thing that scared
Sammy was Chatterer.
Chatterer grabbed Sammy's beak
from the inside and frightened him.
Tee-hee! Stick it!
Bowser!
Bowser.
What's the matter?
Is it Reddy the Fox?
Alright, alright, I understand.
Now, be a good boy.
Look, here's your breakfast.
Boy, Chatterer sure has grown fat.
Looks like he's had quite a feast there.
What a racket.
Get out of here!
Hey, why are you
so sullen, Sammy?
You sure sound like
you're in a foul mood.
Could be!
Actually, this morning I went
to check out something.
Don't you want to hear about it?
I don't want to hear a thing.
Are you sure?
Not even about traps?
What did you say?
Oh, it's really insignificant.
I only thought you wanted to hear about
something I checked out this morning,
if you're not a coward, that is.
I'm not a coward,
who said I'm a coward?
I did.
Didn't you say that you were so scared of
the farm that you'd never go there again?
I'm not a coward, I only said that there
was a trap set up there, that's all!
Then do you have the courage to go with me
to Mr. Brown's corn storehouse tomorrow?
And confirm something
that will happen there?
You don't, do you?
You're a coward!
Of course, I'll go! I'll go and show you
that I'm not a coward!
Good, then it's a deal!
Very early tomorrow,
before sunrise, we'll go together!
Good, of course I promise!
I don't know what's supposed to happen,
but I'll clearly show you that I'm not afraid!
Tomorrow morning, Sammy's face
will be something to see!
Reddy's plan is working well.
And so, the morning next day…
You scared, Sammy?
You're shaking!
Who's shaking?
Let's go already.
Alright, just quietly!
That's where the trap was set.
Now we should be able to find out what it was
that grabbed your beak the other day.
But regardless of what you see,
don't make a sound. Don't make a fuss!
Hey, there he is!
Why, that's… Chatterer!
Why… I'll fix you, Chatterer!
Serves you right, Sammy, you crazy fool!
Now, to get Chatterer here.
– I'll get you! Thief!
– Oh no, it's Sammy!
Shh!
Darn you, you thief!
I'm gonna fix you!
I'm sorry!
Stop it, Sammy! Be quiet?!
Thief!
You squirrel thief!
Sammy, quit it! If you're not quiet,
Tom and the others will hear it! Stop it!
You little chipmunk!
Thief!
That jay is raising a racket!
The fox must be after a chicken!
Stop it, Sammy!
Get away from here. Stop it!
Thief!
You little robber!
Time to run.
What a fix…
What a fix!
Big trouble!
Bowser! Bowser!
Come back, Blacky!
That's enough!
Come back, you two!
Come back, Blacky!
I'll give you some delicious milk!
What are you doing, Polly?
I'm going to make a wonderful pillow
with this soft grass.
It's going to be
this big and fluffy!…
Until now, we've only seen the Rocky's house
at the foot of the Poplar Hill from the outside,
but how does it look inside?
When you enter the front door,
there is a long spiral staircase
and a beautiful, cozy room.
There's even a secret tunnel
that leads to a clover field.
But the secret tunnel
was found by Reddy the Fox,
and now Rocky has to dig
a tunnel to another place.
Rocky digs a long, long tunnel
that surprises Peter.
Next time: "Rocky's Secret Door".
Be there to watch!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango