FABLES OF THE GREEN FOREST
14. Peter Rabbit's thorny escape
Today, the Forest shines with bright colours,
nice smells and beautiful singing.
Peter Rabbit was almost caught by Reddy Fox,
but Peter was able to get away quickly,
and poor Reddy ended up in the lake,
completely wet.
Ribbit.
FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Peter's thorny escape"
Ribbit.
Excuse me for laughing, Weasel!
Don't be angry because it escaped!
Y-yes, it escaped,
and what does that matter to you?
Come on, come on,
don't be angry, my friend,
in fact, I have a wonderful plan!
A-a-and w-w-what kind of plan is it?
A plan to catch Peter Rabbit!
P-P-Peter Rabbit?
Johnny, don't you think
this forest is really great?
Yes, it's wonderful and full of peace.
INSERT
So wonderful! There's nothing better
than the things that Mother Nature gives us!
Look, we should come here for a walk every day!
INSERT
Do you think we can catch Peter Rabbit?
I'm pretty sure, Weasel.
Well, maybe for you it's difficult,
but I'm faster than you!
I'll catch him, that's right!
We'll have a great feast!
INSERT
Wait! What's wrong, Johnny?
We have to go warn Peter. The Mean Weasel
and Reddy Fox want to catch him.
Johnny, what's wrong?
Reddy and the Weasel want to catch Peter!
Don't annoy me now, it's my nap time.
Reddy and the Weasel are coming!
They want to catch you!
Why don't you come to our home?
You can hide there.
I'm all right here, thank you very much.
But...
There's no need to argue.
I can protect myself.
I hope that Peter knows what he's doing.
Hello, Reddy, hello, Weasel.
Where are you going together?
Why we are together is not your concern.
Let us be.
But how could I talk about things
that doesn't matter to me?
Do you think I like to meddle?
I'm going to inform everyone
in the Green Forest, right now.
You'll see.
More news, more news!
They will pay and lose a friend,
my dear Weasel.
Those two look suspicious
circling around the Bramble Bush.
I'm going to follow them
and see what is going on.
Wait here,
I'll bring Peter Rabbit!
Do as you say, my friend Weasel.
INSERT I Will!
I'm worried about Peter.
Do you think he's alright?
- Do you want to go to him?
- But I'm afraid.
The place where Peter is resting
is hidden by natural obstacles
like rocks and brambles.
The Mean Weasel has no problem with it,
but Reddy wouldn't dare to enter.
There he comes.
I have to go!
Did he take the other path?
I think he went this way.
INSERT
Hey!
I know that face.
That Weasel should have catched
that rabbit by now!
INSERT
What happened, friend Weasel?
I think I will be able to catch him now.
Catch him now?
But you should have done that already.
Well... now he won't escape me.
Do you want to catch me, silly Weasel?
This situation is really interesting,
don't you think?
INSERT
I should jump!
You don't like to take a bath,
isn't that right, Weasel?
But I can run around this pool.
In any case I'm going to catch you, rabbit.
Hey!
What's the matter, Weasel,
don't you want to catch me?
You're too slow.
You'll see.
I'm starting to get bored.
Nothing is going to happen.
But what kind of hunter is this?
I've never seen such a bad hunter.
You're useless, useless!
What is Weasel doing?
I'm waiting for hours.
I'm going to see what's up.
No, it's very dangerous and Peter said
that he was able to take care of himself.
You don't need to go.
You won't be able to catch me!
You'll see, rabbit.
Yeah!
I can't catch him!!!
But didn't you want to catch me?
Slowpoke!
Save yourself!
Here he comes.
I'm sure he was able to catch him.
Reddy.
I ended up in the middle of the pool
while I was trying to catch him.
He's a very mean rabbit.
You're also here, Reddy?
How humiliating!
Your friend, Weasel, couldn't catch me!
What news, it's really great news!
Attention everyone in the Green Forest!
Reddy and the Mean Weasel
weren't able to catch Peter Rabbit!
After being humiliated by Peter,
Reddy ran away with his tail between his legs.
Reddy, you're such an idiot!
Afraid of the things Peter was going to say.
You're an idiot!
Darn bird!
Granny!
INSERT
Granny, aren't you happy
to see me back here?
Hello, how are you?
Were you able to catch anything to eat today?
Well...
I was expecting that.
Attention!
I have great news!
It was fun to see how Reddy
and Mean Weasel weren't able to catch Peter.
The Mean Weasel was trying to catch Peter,
while Reddy only waited on the other side.
And you know what happened next?
Reddy returned empty handed,
and his grandmother was furious,
and Reddy was really sad!
I always said they were a bunch of idiots.
And I'll repeat it. Idiots, idiots!
Now, if you excuse me,
I'll continue to tell everyone the news!
So neither you nor the Mean Weasel
were able to catch Peter?
I'm sorry, really sorry, but we couldn't do it.
He's just too fast.
Now I know you are good for nothing.
That bird is right, so you don't need
to get out of the house for today.
You're useless and the laughing stock
of the Green Forest,
so you don't need to go out.
Granny, please, don't get angry.
You're obviously not a good hunter,
so you should stick to cut flowers.
And I bet Peter is very confident
thinking that you won't go
after him again for today.
Don't you think that you should
take advantage of this opportunity?
What a great idea, Granny!
This time I won't fail!
I won't ever run out of luck
because I have four rabbit paws!
Confident and intelligent,
No one will be able to catch me,
I'm the smartest rabbit,
The smartest rabbit in the forest!
That's right!
What a beautiful day!
Now that nothing will bother me,
it's time for my nap.
More news, more news!
Reddy is very embarrassed
and wont come out of his hole
because of Peter, Peter Rabbit!
Reddy is sadder than ever.
His grandmother is angry because
he didn't catch Peter and condemned him,
and we all know that when a grandmother
says something, we have to obey.
That's no good, it's not right.
Just think for a moment if he ever catches Peter.
Our Green Forest would become
full of sadness and loneliness!
You're right, I didn't think of that.
I'm going to see Peter to prevent that.
Goodbye!
Walk in the shadows to avoid being seen.
It's Reddy,
I'm sure he has bad intentions!
Peter is sleeping.
What can I do?
I have a great idea!
- Reddy!
- Hello, Johnny!
- Peter is sleeping.
- Sleeping? W-where?
You really want to know
how to catch Peter Rabbit?
Of course!
Reddy doesn't know what to think.
After all, Peter and Johnny are friends.
But sometimes friends argue.
And since that seems to be the case,
he should take advantage of it.
Please, Johnny, could you be so kind
and tell me how to catch Peter?
Peter is sleeping in the shadow of that tree.
Go to him slowly
and try to be quietly as possible.
Then swiftly enter the clearing and grab him.
Thank you, Johnny. I'll do just that.
Help me! Bees! Help!!!
Help me!!!
Hello, Johnny. What are you doing?
Why are you laughing so much, Johnny?
I'm dying of laughter.
What happened? Tell me! Tell me right now!
Reddy thought you were over there
and jumped against a hive.
Reddy thought that I was a hive?
Peter Rabbit discovered
everything that happened.
Everything that happened
while he was sleeping.
Peter drew a conclusion.
A real friend always helps a friend
without wanting anything in return.
And sometimes putting his friends first.
Translation: Cyber Zero
Subtitle: South Wind Subs