FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Paddy builds a dream house"
Paddy the Beaver works feverishly
from early morning until dark.
He works so hard without seemingly
taking any time to sleep.
And finally he completes a splendid dam.
This is the dam I built!
Wow, oh, great, wonderful!
Oh!
Oh, hi, Johnny Chuck!
Paddy!
Polly and Peter too!
Nice of you to come!
We heard you were building a house,
so we come over to see how it was!
Hey-hey-hey, where are you building it, huh?
I've already started building the house!
- Where, where...?! Where?!
You can't see it!
I started from the foundation!
It's almost completely built now!
Well, Joe and Harry are also here!
Did you, fellows, come to watch Paddy
build his house?
- Yeah...
Hey... what is Paddy doing underwater
I wonder...
That's what we don't know, Joe!
- I'm going to go see!
- Me too!
Oh, a mountain of mud and timber?!
It can't be helped that Johnny
and the others don't understand it.
What Paddy was building
so diligently was the foundation.
From the surface it can't be seen.
His first task was to build a mound
to the level of the water surface.
Hey!
It's finished!
What's it be, huh?!
Well...
- Oh!
- I don't know!
It really is beyond me now!
Does Paddy really know how to build
a house with those sticks?
He must've made a mistake.
He sure did!
What else can one think, huh?
Yeah, what a disgusting fellow!
This won't be much of a house, anyway!
That's right, that's right,
one can't stand such a sight!
The rumor that Paddy had somehow
made a mistake in building his house,
spread quickly throughout the forest.
However, Paddy was still continuing
to work very hard.
Everyday he brought more sticks,
logs and mud to the site.
And everyday the house
grew larger and larger,
as Paddy put in more and more effort.
Paddy... is that a house?
How are you going to sleep?
Hear, can't you even reply?
The truth is you don't even know
how to build a house!
Right?
If asked, we could teach you!
It's okay... I'll show you! I'm going to build
my house the way I want to!
Huh! Here I am, trying to be nice,
and you, look at you!
From the beginning I just couldn't
talk into you, don't be so irritating!
Hey, everyone in the forest! Paddy
doesn't know how, but he's building a house!
He's a big fool!
I just can't like that Paddy!
That's right! Even when he build a dam there,
I was against him all the time!
I can't stand him!
I just can't stand Paddy!
That thing, the case... I think I'll bother him!
Now, how can I bother him?
Hey...
Hi, Jimmy the Skunk!
A beautiful day, isn't it?
You don't seem to be in to good a mood,
what's the matter with you?
Hey, I'm talking to you!
You don't want to answer!
Oh, beetle, you're just a fly in my ointment!
Oh, you're in a bad mood 'coz you
can't find any beetles, huh?
If that's it, I know a place
where there's a bunch of them!
What?! Really?!
You know Paddy's dam, right?
Go there to the White Poplar Grove
and I'm sure you'll be very satisfied!
Indeed it's swarming with plump beetles there!
To be able to eat to my heart's content
my favourite beetles!
Well, then...!
Hello there, Weasel!
Say, have you ever thought
you'd like to catch Paddy the Beaver?
You mean P-P-P-P-Paddy?
Of c-c-c-course, yes!
Say, I've got a swell idea!
Let me tell you something...
The beetles...?!
Singing...?!
Sure funny!
Maybe the beetles don't like me at all!
A suspicious looking shadow...
Whoever you are, Mr. Shadow,
you better not come any closer,
I'm getting very nervous...!
Oh, it's Jimmy's gas!
Hey, that's right!
What's Jimmy doing in this place, huh?!
- Paddy...!
I wonder where Paddy is!
He must've run off and hid somewhere.
Since he can't build his house,
and he's ashamed,
and since the grove is like that
he can't live here either, do you see?
Oh, what a terrible thing!
Paddy won't be able to feed anything like that!
Knowing the white poplar is Paddy's favorite,
who would do such a thing?!
Huh, now Paddy must leave the Green Forest,
Paddy must leave the Green Forest,
the Green Forest, the Green Forest,
the Green Forest...!
Paddy?
Where did he go?!
Paddy's not discouraged by the withering
of the poplar trees nearby.
Instead, he builds a waterway,
because now he has to go
some distance to get trees,
and the waterway will facilitate him
bringing the trees back to the lake,
by floating them in.
Beetle-beetle, the you-don't-like-me beetles!
I never can find enough to satisfy me...
What am I gonna do?
Oh, you all together...
What's the occasion?
You sure do some terrible things!
What do you mean?
- That's right, say you're sorry to Paddy!
- Don't you feel sorry for Paddy?
What's that?
Why did you do such a thing?
Forgive me, Johnny, I didn't mean to...
Yesterday, Sammy came and told me that there
were many plump beetles over there.
- Huh...?!
- Sammy said that?!
I tell you there's no beetles there!
I've never once seen any there!
That's right, but somebody, I don't know who,
started to attack me,
and that's when I let the gas go,
it's the truth!
Sure funny!
Why did Sammy told such a lie?
It's funny, isn't it?
- This is one of Sammy's tricks!
- I think I see the light...
Sammy's accomplice could be that guy, maybe...
P-P-P-Paddy...
he-he's left t-t-the d-d-d-dam?
I saw it with my own eyes!
He's gone and he's digging a big hole!
I-i-if he le-le-leaves the-the d-d-dam,
he's m-m-mine!
He-he-he can't r-r-r-run in the w-w-w-water!
Let's g-g-g-go!
- Paddy's in danger! Quick, let's find him!
- Yeah...
Woe to him who makes a fool
of Sammy, the Beautiful Jay!
Get him! Get him, get him,
you Mean Weasel you!
Get him!
Go get Paddy!
Get Paddy!
Huh...
Hey...
Sammy, nice to see you!
What are you doing around here, buddy?
What are you hanging around for?
There's no one in this forest
a better person than he!
I wonder if is right to let the Mean Weasel
get him, but he made a fool of me!
But he is a kindhearted guy!
However, I'd send the Mean Weasel on him!
And that's when Sammy realized,
that getting his revenge
was not giving him pleasure.
After all, to take revenge solves nothing.
And now finally...
...Sammy realized that for himself.
Then...
...he saw something.
Watch out, Paddy, run!
Run! Paddy!
It's the Weasel!
- Paddy!
- Oh...!
I-i-i-t's about time...
he starts to h-h-hurt!
- Johnny!
- Huh?!
E-e-e-everyone, get-get-get out of here!
J-J-J-Jimmy!
I'm mad! Fooling me and being mean to Paddy!
Not that!
Of all things! W-w-w-wait!
Hey...!
Johnny, where are you?
Why doesn't anybody like such
a pleasant aroma?
Beavers place the logs they collect for food
firmly around the base of their dwelling.
So when hungry they leave by the exit,
enter the water and carry the logs
back inside... so they can feast.
- Hi, Paddy! Is your house finished?
- Hey!
Just a little more, then it will be finished!
Come and see it, Johnny!
Hey, it's finished!
It's finished!
All finished!
Hey...!
Oh boy, it's finished! My house
is finally all finished! All finished!
Congratulations!
How wonderful!
I sure would like to see
what it's like on the inside!
OK, I'll go see!
Hey, take me along!
That's sneaky, Johnny! They go
and leave me behind! That's sneaky!
No furnishings and decorations yet,
but please, please...
Tremendous!
Good thing you just scoop out the inside!
I could enter the dam through there!
It's beautiful!
Paddy's house... really wonderful!
Paddy's house is completed!
And Paddy doesn't know
how to build a house is a lie!
Paddy has built a house!
Polly, Paddy is a genius in house building!
It's really a wonderful house!
That's sneaky, Johnny, to see the house
all by yourself! Show it to me too!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs