Terrible, terrible, awful!
I've got terrible bad news for everyone!
OK, listen up now!
FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"The straw hat monster"
Terrible, terrible!
Johnny, it's cruel!
Could anything be more cruel?
Sammy, what happened?
It's that guy, Reddy!
Who, Reddy?
Chatterer is the one to be pitied,
I'm so mad, so mad
I just can't stay still!
I must tell everyone about it!
Terrible, terrible!
He's such a scatterbrain, he left without
telling us the most important part!
He was saying something about Chatterer!
Let's go see!
It was really terrible, the fruits and nuts
that I gathered... that guy, Reddy!
He took them all...?!
Look at all those nice smelling fruits!
Hmm... If the owner isn't around,
I'll just pick 'em up!
I'm the owner, I gathered them!
I don't want these stupid nuts anyway!
Well, I'm sorry to have intruded!
Hey...!
- I'm amazed!
- That Reddy is really a problem!
That Reddy, oh...!
Alright, Granny, eat, I went out and stole it!
Hmm, now listen, Reddy.
What I want is a soft little rabbit.
Peter Rabbit that is.
Catch him for me!
Oh, my empty stomach!
I'm starved!
I know, I know, Granny,
tomorrow I'll catch Peter for sure,
but the problem is how to catch him!
Oh... I hear Lady Gentle Breeze's song.
Hey, Lady Gentle Breeze,
will you listen to one request?
Of course, Reddy.
- What can we do about this problem, Johnny...?
- Yeah...
...we seem to really have a problem
on our hands...
Johnny, for a while now you've been
grumbling and groaning about what?
Groaning? About Reddy!
Oh, Peter, you are here.
I was looking for you.
What is it, Gentle Breeze?
I have a message from Reddy.
- Oh...?!
- It's from Reddy?!
He said he found some tender budding carrots
on Mr. Brown's farm,
and would like you to go with him
first thing tomorrow morning at sunrise.
Oh, budding carrots you say?
My favourite food!
You're not thinking of going, are you, Peter?
What...?
Be careful, this might be a trick of Reddy's!
I can't refuse
a kind special invitation like that!
I...
Then your answer is... an OK?
Yes...! Tell him I'll be happy
to accompany him... tomorrow!
Oh, Johnny, speak to him, stop Peter!
If he goes with Reddy, he'll be eaten up!
Aren't you afraid?
I'm not afraid!
Bye!
Wow, wonderful!
It's just like Reddy said!
How delicious!
Oh, what a delicious meal!
Good, good, good, good, good!
Thanks for waiting! OK, now let's go
to Mr. Brown's carrot patch!
Peter, yesterday you promised to go with me,
didn't you, huh?
Peter...!
Funny, no answer.
Then I think I'll go by myself
and check the carrot patch.
Hmm?
Hey!
This smells like Peter!
Darn, darn!
That Peter, he fooled me!
I'm so mad at him!
- Oh!
- Good morning, Reddy the Fox!
Good morning!
Peter asked me to see you and tell you this:
he said he is truly sorry that he could not
meet you this morning by the Bramble Bush.
But thinking about those tender budding carrots,
made him so hungry, that he departed
early this morning, before daybreak.
He said he is really grateful to you
for telling him about those carrots.
And those carrots were the most delicious
he had ever eaten.
Lady Gentle Breeze, would you tell Peter this:
I'm glad the carrots were delicious!
Tomorrow morning at daybreak we'll meet again
and I'll take you to the sweet clover field!
OK?
I found it near the old walnut tree, alright?
Yes, that's fine.
I'll relay it immediately for you.
Next morning, Peter set out
almost two hours before daybreak.
Oh, that was delicious!
Now... better hurry home
and get back to sleep!
I just wonder what happened...
Peter always waits for me at the usual edge
of the Bramble Bush.
He never had ideas of fooling me.
Good morning, Peter!
Good morning, Reddy!
Well, Peter...
let's go to that sweet clover field!
I got so hungry... I couldn't wait
for the sun to come up, Reddy!
No...
So I went about two hours ago.
Thank you very much for telling me
about that new clover field!
You aren't mad at me, are you, Reddy?
Of course not!
Nothing is more pleasing than
to make people really cheerful!
I like to make people really happy, you know!
However, I just heard about it, but, uh...
...Mr. Brown the farmer planted some cabbage
in the corner of his yard.
Tommorow morning at daybreak...
...you want to meet here and go there?
Yeah...?
That sounds keen!
Let's definitely go!
OK, then it's a promise this time!
So long!
I'm mad!
This time I'll go there two hours
before the sun rises,
then, Peter, I'm going to teach you
who the smartest is!
Yeah, I will!
The moon, the moon
Please, light up the road,
The night's a good night,
The stars are twinkling,
A happy night,
My friends are calling me...!
Oh, it's Reddy...
That R-R-Reddy is thinking:
"H-how shall I eat him?"
Ah-ah... what do I do... n-n-now...?
Oh-oh...
Oh... Reddy's face looks startled!
I just thought of something...
Oh! I don't believe it!
I'm getting out of here!
- Good morning, Peter!
- Good morning, Reddy!
Hey, well, I'm sorry to make you wait so long,
but I was actually really frightened last night!
Oh, did something happen?
I ran into a hideous monster!
I was so frightened I didn't feel like
coming out until the sun was out!
So that's why I'm a wee bit late!
Hmm... Tell you what, Peter:
let's start out for the new cabbage patch, huh?
Tell me, did the monster catch you?
Uh, Reddy, uh?
No, he didn't catch me.
You know I can run faster than he can.
Then I decide not to go to
the cabbage patch until morning.
I might get caught by that monster, Reddy,
isn't that right?
And besides, I've already had my share
of budding cabbage plants.
The... what-what...?!
I just couldn't wait till morning...
...so I went early last night.
Thanks for telling me about the cabbage.
Yes, Reddy, my heartfelt thanks.
Don't...
Don't mention it, Peter.
It's alright, it's alright!
But...
...tell me, didn't you meet up
with that terrible monster?
I didn't meet it!
What in the world it's so funny with you, Peter?
Tell me, I wanna laugh too!
- The monster who frightened you...
- Mhm...
...you won't believe it, Reddy!...
...was the old straw hat of Mr. Brown's son!
I was hiding under it!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs