Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Sammy Gets Mocked
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
There it is! That's the Green Forest,
where Uncle Billy lives. That must be it!
I finally found it!
One day, a strange bird arrived
at the Green Forest.
It seems he's a friend of Uncle Billy
from the South Country.
Good day!
I would like to ask you something!
Is this the Green Forest, where Uncle Billy lives?
Yes, it is.
And who are you?
No, it doesn't really matter now.
I'll meet you all formally later.
I'll see you!
What was with that bird?
What a weirdo.
He's probably Uncle Billy's friend.
Uncle Billy will be surprised
when he sees me here.
Now that I'm here,
I might as well surprise him.
Thief! Robber!
It's a thief! It's a thief!
Thief! Thief!
Who stole my breakfast?
It's a thief! A thief!
Thief! Thief!
Now that gives me an idea.
Come on, kids. Cut it out!
I'm telling you to behave.
It tickles!
Oh, come on now, cut it out!
Dear! Instead of playing
with the children all day long,
why don't you for once go out
and find us something to eat?
I know, I know,
I was just thinking to do that.
You always say "I know, I know, I'll do it",
but in the end, you never do…
Just like last night, for example.
You don't have to nag me like that.
I know, I know, indeed.
Come on now, kids,
you go back to the house now.
I'm going now!
Really, I just don't know what to do
with that husband of mine.
Hey, Uncle Billy!
Hello, Rocky, Polly.
Uncle Billy, one of your friends seems
to have come a long way just to see you.
He's a weirdo, isn't he?
My friend? Who?
Oh, haven't you met him yet?
It's that bird with the shrill voice!
No, I haven't met him yet.
Hmm…
My friend, with shrill voice, huh?
You know, the one that
wears a brownish-colored suit.
A brownish-colored suit?
Hmm…
What?! That guy?
Here, in the Green Forest?
Yes. Just a while ago,
near the Clover Hill.
He was asking Polly and me
about you, Uncle Billy.
Oh, really?!
Why, that guy, oh my!
When Uncle Billy remembered his friend
and their days in the distant South Virginia
and that he was here now in the Green Forest,
he felt great joy and excitement.
I can't say I have seen him, no.
That's strange, for someone with sharp ears
like you to not know about him.
But don't worry as I'll keep it in mind
and search for him.
So, tell me, what does
this bird look like?
Well, he's a friend of mine from long ago
in that good South Country.
And? And? Tell me more!
But maybe
it's a misunderstanding.
I'm sorry I have bothered you.
Hey, hey, hey, Uncle Billy,
but what does he look like?
Rocky and Polly were
probably mistaken, that's all.
That must be it.
That must be it, indeed!
Huh?
Uncle Billy, you miser, miser, miser!
It wouldn't hurt you to tell me more!
No, I haven't seen him, no.
So not even Knocker knows…
Dear!
Where were you wandering
about until now?
You know we were all waiting for you
with empty stomachs!
I'm sorry, darling!
Please, forgive me, I, uh…
Why, I was just looking for my friend
from the South Country!
Really, what a hopeless chap you are.
You can be so trying!
Uncle Billy was
at a loss for a reply.
He felt absolutely terrible.
Furthermore, he was exhausted
from walking about all day.
You're hungry, aren't you, dear?
Oh, I sure am.
I haven't had a bite
to eat all day long.
If you've eaten,
hurry up and go to bed.
The bed is already made up.
Hurry up and come to sleep!
You'll catch a cold
from the night wind.
I know, I know, darling,
I'll be right up, good night!
My wife's bark is a lot worse
than her bite, you know,
but her soul is really very tender
and I love her a great deal!
I'm off, darling!
Good morning, smiling sun. Today
I'm gonna try find my friend real hard!
Today good old easy-going
Uncle Billy was eager to work hard.
In the meantime…
I've eaten a hearty breakfast,
and the weather is perfect.
What a pleasant morning it is!
Hey, Sammy!
Hm?
Say, Sammy, what were you doing up
so late last night?
I couldn't catch any sleep at all
because of it…
What are you talking
about, Jimmy?
I wasn't up that late last night.
You know, Sammy, you really ought to
tell the truth every once in a while.
You kept me awake all last night
after the sun went down
making all that disturbance
by the Green Forest.
What happened, huh?
I need my sleep!
I'm telling the truth!
I went to bed as usual
and didn't wake up till this morning!
Then you must've been talking
awfully loud in your sleep.
Lies, lies, lies!
Darn lies!
Lies! Lies!
Darn! Lies! Lies!
Lies!
Hey, Sammy!
Wasn't last night enough for you,
do you have to bother us today as well?
Don't be funny, Peter!
That's the second time already this morning.
I slept soundly last night,
and to be told that I was causing
disturbance bothers me a lot!
Hmm… then you must
sleep awfully funny.
Now, just tell me the truth,
why were you flying about the Green Forest,
shouting "thief, thief" all night long?
Peter, you and Jimmy too must've
something wrong with your heads.
You're crazy! Now listen,
I was asleep! Why shouldn't I be?
I wouldn't mistake you voice!
I'd stop it if I were you.
If Hooty the Owl hears you,
you'll be finished!
Now, go bother somewhere else!
I'm about to sleep.
Sammy is furious,
but he doesn't know what to do.
Is everyone trying
to play a trick on him?
Or did he really
shout out in his sleep?
Sammy, the talkative jay,
has never been as angry as this before.
Although he doesn't remember
a thing about it, most of the forest animals
are complaining that they couldn't sleep
well last night because of his shouting.
What's going on?
Sammy starts to wonder
if he's going crazy.
There goes Sammy,
the sleepyhead jay,
shouting all day long,
the noisy jay.
Not having enough during the daytime,
now he also shouts during the night,
It's a lie! It's a lie!
It's a terrible lie!
sleepy jay Sammy,
oh-oh, crazy Sammy!
It's a lie! Slander! Lie!
It's a lie! Lie! Slander!
Slander! Lie!
Lie!
Lie! Lie!
Slander!
It's a lie!
Lie!
It's the truth, really,
please believe me.
So you really don't remember
anything that happened?
Yeah. Yeah!
But you may've been half asleep?
Rocky, are you going
to doubt me, too?
I don't dance and jump around at night.
Why would I do that?
You have a point.
I haven't heard it myself. Maybe
everyone is playing a trick on Sammy?
But it's the truth.
He's causing quite a commotion
throughout the forest!
It's a lie, it's a lie!
I assure you, the one
who's lying is Sammy.
It's just like Jenny said.
Sammy was up all night, alright.
I didn't sleep at all thanks to him.
It's unheard of to disrespect
other animals like that.
It's a lie! It's a lie!
Everyone's lying!
Calm down, Sammy.
A lie! Lie!
That's weird, Sammy says
he was sleeping last night,
and everyone else says
he was raising a ruckus.
Hmm…
Couldn't it be that there
are two Sammys, huh?
That's it! Everyone's mistaken
someone else's voice for mine!
That's the only option!
Who would ever
mistake Sammy's voice?
That "This is terrible, this is terrible"
was without a doubt Sammy's voice!
That's right, I guess
it won't work, Sammy!
That's right!
But, but it wasn't me!
It wasn't me!
Alright, then sleep
quietly tonight, Sammy.
Ah, gosh!
Anyway, it's all settled.
Right, Sammy?
Let's go, everyone.
Well, goodnight everybody.
It's a lie! It's a lie…
It's all not true, not true!
What should I do now, Rocky?
Let's see…
Be sure you aren't
half asleep tonight.
It's a mistake!
I keep on telling you it's a lie!
Everyone's wrong!
It's a lie! A lie!
It's a lie!
Okay, this being the case, I'll see with
my own eyes. I'll keep lookout…
Better get plenty of sleep for now,
otherwise I'll be very tired tonight.
Sammy was worried.
He had never slept so early,
with the sun high in the sky.
Still can't sleep… Maybe I could sleep
in that dark spot over there.
Nope, didn't help at all.
I just have to endure it.
My wife's bark is a lot worse
than her bite, you know,
but her soul is really very tender
and I love her a great deal!
Ah, Uncle Billy!
Oh, Rocky and Polly,
you're going for a walk, too?
Yeah. There's something
bothering me
and I thought of asking you
about it, Uncle Billy.
Oh, there's something
you want to ask me?
Hmm… Sammy,
all night long, huh?
Sammy insists that
it's absolutely not him,
but everyone says that they
couldn't mistake Sammy's voice.
They're right,
his voice can't be copied.
So, that means…
That's it! You said that a bird from the South
came to visit me yesterday, didn't you?
I admit I did say that.
But what about it?
Well, Rocky, that's your answer!
Oh my, oh my!
What a guy! He's really here!
Today, Sammy's antics will end.
Just tell the forest people to sleep peaceful
tonight and leave the rest to me.
Uncle Billy! Billy!
I wonder what's really going on…
Not scared.
I'm not scared at all!
I'm not scared. I'm not.
I will… find out…
the truth, all right…
Aha, I'm sure that Bobby is going to eat
the corn from Mr. Brown's corn field.
How lucky to be
easy-going like Peter.
I've been watching
and I haven't seen anything.
Was I really half asleep
and did what everybody says?
This is terrible!
News! News!
Terrible!
It's terrible, terrible!
I'm not asleep at all!
I'm right here, completely awake!
News! News!
If this is my voice,
Terrible!
then…
Whose voice is that?
Terrible!
It was about here, for sure.
News! News!
News! Terrible news!
Ah!
It's terrible!
That's my voice!
I'm really over there!
News!
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it! Cut it out!
That's my voice for sure…
Stop it! Stop it!
It's no use. I'm going crazy.
Out of my mind!
Crazy! Crazy!
Terrible!
News! News! News!
News! Terrible news!
News, news, news!
News, terrible, terrible news!
News! News…
Sammy!
U-U-Uncle Billy?
I'm absolutely certain
I'm going completely crazy!
News, news!
Oh?
It's terrible!
Well, just follow me.
News, news!
It's terrible!
News!
You can't fool me,
I know his habits well.
It's terrible!
Let me introduce
my friend to you.
That's Mocker, the Mockingbird!
Huh? Mocker the Mockingbird?
Oh, that's enough fooling around for now.
So how about coming out here, Mocker?
Well, how you've been doing,
Uncle Billy?
You've come a long way, Mocker,
and I'm glad to see you
but you haven't changed a bit.
You still love to fool around.
Right, Mocker?
That's right.
After all, I've come a long way to see you again,
and I wanted our meeting to be a fun thing!
So we meet again in the soft moonlight.
It's good to see you, Mocker!
Thanks, Uncle Billy!
Then my voice was his?
Mocker is a real expert
in imitations, you know.
Forgive me, Sammy,
will you ever forgive me?
Are you kidding?!
That sounds just like my voice!
Darn, you made a fool of me!
Why imitate my voice?!
It must've been because Sammy
is the noisiest one in the forest.
I apologize.
I'm sorry, Sammy.
What use is that to me?
Thief! Thief! Thief!
Now, now, if you make such ruckus, everyone
will gonna wake up and chase you out of here.
I'm letting you
off the hook for today,
but someday I'll get my revenge,
make no mistake about it.
You voice thief!
I guess I shouldn't
have done that to him.
It's good for him to be given
a flick on the beak sometimes.
Anyway, I want to introduce
you to my friends.
Please do, Uncle Billy,
I'd like to meet them.
Well, now, you just leave it to me.
You're going to come with me
to my house tonight
and we're going to spend
the whole evening talking over old times!
I'd like that, I really would!
Today we met Mocker the Mockingbird.
An interesting bird, don't you think?
However, Uncle Billy and Sammy are
still the only ones who know about him.
Sammy has an idea to
play an unthinkable prank.
When his plans come true, the Green Forest
becomes a very noisy place.
What kind of mischief is it, that it goes
as far as setting Rocky at variance with Polly?
Next time:
"A Big Commotion in the Forest".
Be there to watch!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango