Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Reddy Fox Keeps Home
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
All right, I'm going, then.
Look after the house
in my absence, Reddy.
Granny, just set your mind
at ease and go.
I wonder if it's really alright.
Recently, I've been feeling a little weak,
so I'd like to eat something tasty.
So I thought I'd revitalize myself
catching the field mice on the farm
that I noticed last year.
A little thing like caretaking
is a piece of cake for me.
I certainly hope so.
Don't worry.
Go and take your time.
Is it really alright?
Now, Reddy,
you listen to me again.
Make sure you do not
get close to any stranger.
Follow this simple rule
and you'll stay out of trouble.
Yes, yes.
I know that.
Do you really know?
Always be careful. There is
no such thing as too much caution.
Alright, I'm going.
Hmm… Granny's
going on a trip, eh?
Are you sure of that?
Yeah. Should be gone for two weeks.
We can spread our wings without any worry!
What's so funny about that?
Unfortunately…
…we don't have any wings to fly.
So? It was just
a figure of speech!
Still, that's some
good news, eh, Polly?
Yes. Say, Rocky,
now that we know,
why don't we assemble
everybody in the forest and play?
Okay!
Let's have a party!
Hey! Let's all go play
hide-and-seek!
Peter, you're "it"!
Oh! That's not fair!
Alright, have it your way, guys.
I'll quickly find
where everyone's hiding.
Hop!
Is this Bobby's idea of hiding?
What the deuce was that?
I've never heard that voice before.
Don't scare me like that, gosh.
Chin up, chin up!
I'm not a weakling!
What should I do?
Everybody's left.
I'm gonna hurry home
and go to bed!
How boring, they're all
a bunch of silly weaklings.
Everybody's gone!
This is no fun.
I might as well go home.
Well, so long!
So long!
– I'm scared!
– Let's hurry!
Good night!
Must've been my imagination.
What a wonderful night!
I am carefree and free,
there's nothing in the world
that I'm afraid of!
And with Granny relying on me to take care
of things, I will handle the situation.
Don't you worry, Granny… Hm?
Granny said not to get close
to anything that's unknown!
This hasn't been
a good day for Reddy.
His stomach was so empty
that it's begun to hurt.
Eventually, he decided to look
for something to eat and left home.
I hope that this scary beast
sleeps during the day.
Reddy was too hungry to stay at home
and went out very early in the morning.
He sniffed the wind-blown air
with all his might.
Reddy's nose is able to distinguish things
that the eye cannot see nor the ear can hear.
I smell some kind of baby bird!
It's chicken meat!
Wait a second.
Right.
Now hear this, Reddy.
When you want something
so much that you can't stand it,
turn around an go home.
If you stay there, you'll be caught,
but if you go home, you won't be hurt.
Righty.
I guess I have no choice.
What a pity!
I wonder if there's a way to verify
if there are any traps around it…
That's it! Yeah, that might work.
Yum!
Hey there, Jimmy!
I'm so glad to see you.
Got something up
your sleeve again, hm?
Reddy! You sure look smart
and magnificent today.
Oh, don't flatter me so much.
No, it's true, it's true,
no one is as brave as you.
We, who tremble every night
hearing that strange voice,
just cannot
be compared with you.
That's true, I'm not afraid
of anyone or anything, that's right!
By the way, Jimmy, I found
a half-eaten piece of meat!
Meat?
Yes. If you don't believe me, come
with me and see with your own eyes.
That's nice and all, but
I don't care about meat that much.
But aside from the meat,
there might be some fallen eggs
that you like so much!
Really?
And, Jimmy, that meat might be left
by the stranger who scared us all…
Um… I mean, me,
I wasn't scared, of course!
But yea, maybe that's
where it came from.
Oh, really?
– Look, beneath that tree.
– You're right!
Who do you think
could've leave it here?
Say, let's go closer and look.
Then we'll be able to see who left it.
That's a good idea!
Yes, let's do it.
Say, Jimmy, to avoid any danger,
wouldn't it be better
if someone
stood guard over here?
You may be right.
Then, let's do it like this.
I'm taller than you and can see
beyond the grass field,
so while you're checking, I'll stand
guard for us. How's that for an idea?
That Reddy, he wanted me
to check for traps.
What a cheap guy!
Hey, Jimmy, is that okay?
Yeah. That's okay.
So, how was it?
The teeth marks and tracks
closely resemble yours,
although he's much larger.
Have you ever seen this guy?
I can tell without seeing,
by its teeth marks on the meat
and its tracks that
remained on the grass.
It's probably this stranger
that we're hearing.
If you think I'm lying,
come and take a look!
I-I'm fine here.
What's going on? You're the one
who wanted to check, wasn't it?
You know…
Ah, I just remembered something
important that I have to do.
If you find out anything more
about it, let me know.
Later!
Hmph. What foolishness!
Thanks to him,
I've wasted a lot of time.
Ah! Wait, wait, wait!
Wow, that was way too close!
I thought for sure it was
that howling stranger!
That's it!
We'd like to know about it, too!
So we decided we'd go to
Digger the Badger and ask him!
A good idea.
But… Jimmy, with that weapon of yours,
you don't have to be afraid of anyone.
So?
So, well… uh…
I was just thinking…
You're not afraid of that beast
even if you don't know its identity, are you?
No, that's no good. I don't have this bag
just for the sake of quarreling with others!
I still think that
you ought to go see Digger.
He's from the West, so he should
know something about this stranger.
And what is it, fellows?
You want to know
about that voice, you say?
Yes. We thought that maybe
you'd know who it was, digger.
Well, well.
You see…
Usually, he doesn't associate with others,
so it's a little hard for him to converse.
In short…
He's come from the Great West
and he's a friend of mine.
A friend?
In short… uh… uh.
A coyote. Old Man Coyote,
who's come from the Great West.
Old Man Coyote?
Huh? Old Man Coyote, he said?
Coyote?
Jimmy and Rocky quickly told everyone
what they had heard from Digger the Badger.
What they should do to avoid
being caught by the coyote
or how to react
if they did meet up with him.
Now that everyone learned this,
they were a bit more at ease.
Well, why is everyone so jumpy
about that nothing Old Man Coyote?!
You're nothing but
a bunch of cowards!
Me, I'm not the least bit scared!
Oh, yeah?!
You're really not scared?
Yeah! If I meet up with him,
I'm thinking of giving him a scare!
Oh yeah? Is that so?
Well, show us some
of your strength!
In due time!
Terrible, terrible!
That coyote is out
in broad daylight!
Terrible! Terrible!
The coyote guy is out there!
Coyotes live on plains
in North America and Canada.
They're slightly smaller than shepherd dogs
and have grayish brown coat.
The coyote, also known
as the prairie wolf,
has much smaller paws than its lupine cousin,
making it easy to identify by its tracks.
The fast and smart coyote
chases its prey alone.
Its speed is very fast
and can reach even 69 km / h.
Sometimes they steal some
of the prey caught by other animals.
They're not very active during the day,
preferring to prey under the cover of night.
It's been a long time,
brother badger.
Hey, if it isn't Old Man Coyote.
I thought it was about time
for you to make an appearance.
I sure did miss your voice!
You're about the only one
who'd say something like that.
So, how long will you stay?
It's such a nice forest.
I think I'll stick around for a while.
Well, in any case I'll have to pay
my respects to my immediate neighbors.
It'd be nice
if they aren't too scared.
You have a mean streak. You know full well
that they are all afraid of you.
Speaking of that…
Reddy, the Fox is saying
that when he meets you,
he's going to get you!
Oh?
Reddy the Fox, huh?
I'd better check for myself to see how much
courage that Reddy the Fox really has.
Judging by the voice,
he's over at the ranch!
Okay, now is a good time
to go look for some field mice.
Good evening,
my vulpine brother.
O-O-Old Man Coyote!
Why are you here?
Why, is it wrong for me to be here?
No! No, no, no!
I didn't mean that at all.
Well, I understand that you want
to live in the Green Forest.
I think we could be good friends.
By the way, is it true that
you're not afraid of anything?
Oh? Ah, yes, I guess!
I'm not afraid of anyone.
Although everyone seems…
to be afraid of me!
So, you're not afraid
of me either, right?
Yes, I'm not…
I'm not afraid of anyone at all.
Got a lot of courage, eh, Reddy?
Yes, yes, yes, that's right,
I'm not afraid of anyone at all!
Then what about this?
Oh, geez! Spare me, please!
Help! Somebody help me!
Ah, don't eat me!
No! Let me go!
Anyone would run
if they met Old Man Coyote.
I did just what anybody else would do,
so I'm not a coward.
My Granny is always saying that
if you wanna live long, you've gotta run!
But if you flee, you're laughed at,
you must run and live in hiding!
And when you run again,
you're laughed at again. It's a vicious cycle!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango