FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Mr. Condor comes to the forest"
One morning, all the creatures of the forest
were frightened by something
they had never seen before.
A large strange looking bird
with a pointed beak
soared overhead cruising the sky over the forest.
They were scared and didn't really know
what to expect.
Why is everyone so frightened?
Why are you hiding under that?
You look funny, funny!
I'm hiding from that big bird flying in the sky!
That's why you're hiding
under that silly umbrella!
Go home, go home, go home,
That big bird loves
Silly pop little woodchucks like you, Polly!
I'm not afraid, I'm not afraid...
of anybody!
I'm not afraid, I'm not...
Of everyone in the forest,
Of the tree climbers, I'm...
Hey, chipmunk!
Oh, come on!
Chatterer, Chatterer... are you alright?
You aren't hurt, are you?
Boy, was I scared!
Such a scary bird!
I've never seen one before in my life!
What kind of a bird is that anyway?
To be able to stand so high...
such a bird...
...gives me the shiver...!!
Everybody be careful!
That's a hungry spooky bird!
If you're caught, you'll be eaten up!
Hey! Hey! Get out of here!
Everybody hide! Get out of here!
Run and hide...!
- Hey, rabbit!
- Huh?
- Huh?!
Hey! Hey, rabbit!
Hey...
...rabbit!
Hi there!
A spook... a spooky bird!
A spook...
A spooky bird!
A spook... a spooky bird!
I really don't understand why they are afraid
of me, I'm a gentleman!
Excuse me, I'd like to ask you
an important question if I may.
Don't be afraid! I won't do anything!
I've come a little distance.
I can't seem to get my bearings in this forest.
Hey! Hey, come on!
Come on, just one moment!
I'm not trying to hurt you!
Hey, I'm not trying to...
Look out now! Look out!
Hey there!
Are you OK, young lady woodchuck?
Hmm... none of your business!
My, oh my! I've certainly come
to a funny, unfriendly place!
Polly!
Johnny, Johnny, Johnny!
Something terrible, terrible, terrible!
What?
Hmm, look at it!
Polly was chased by that spooky bird,
then she fell into the Laughing Brook!
Thanks for the tip, little birds!
Hmm, that spooky bird
must really be a bad guy...
...pushing Polly into the river like that...
Hmm, maybe Polly is still helpless
in the Laughing Brook!
Polly!
Johnny!
I hear you're looking for Polly,
is that right, Johnny?
Why, do you know something?
You know,
Polly was drifting down the Laughing Brook.
Riding on some strange looking thing,
which looked like a hat.
When I asked her, "Where are you off to?",
she replied "I don't know either!"
Thanks, Grandfather!
I hope you'll find her, Johnny,
good luck!
Polly floated happily down the Laughing Brook
in the hat that served as a raft.
Very content, she was not aware
of any danger,
that Reddy the Fox had plans
to catch her as she floated by.
Polly!
Johnny, how did you know I was here?!
Stay calm, Polly, stay calm!
What's happening, Johnny?
It's Reddy!
Don't panic, Polly, keep calm!
Polly, here!
Hey, Polly, paddle with your hand,
paddle this way!
Hey, Polly, grab it!
Grab the stick, Polly!
Don't let go!
Hold on, Polly!
Why, you!
- Take that! And that!
- Oh...
Polly!
Hey...!
Hey, you fox,
what do you think you're doing?
Hey, get out of here!
- Get out of here, what do you think you're doing?
- What-what?
What-what?
I'm after you!
Get out!
Oh, Johnny, you saved me!
Oh, I'm... I'm full, I hate it,
from swallowing all that water!
Thank you, Mr.!
Oh, it was nothing, but, thank goodness,
since coming here to the forest,
this is the first time I've been able
to talk to anyone!
Don't know why, but when I spoke,
everyone ran away!
Really, I was at a loss!
I'm Johnny Chuck, the Woodchuck!
I'm Polly!
I'm Mr. Condor, nice to meet you!
Where are you from, Mr. Condor?
I am from a warm country to the South.
But Gosh...
...this is sure a lonely place!
Why do you choose to live in such a lonely
place, huh, can you tell me that? Huh?
We love the Green Forest,
that's why we live here, it's beautiful!
I'm sure if you live here for a while,
you'll like it as much as we do!
Yeah, well, actually, I'm supposed to meet
the Mrs. here, at this Green Forest.
We'll stay here for a while
and see if what you say is actually true.
- Good!
It's a lie, it's a lie,
that bird was chasing me!
Oh, that's not true.
Mr. Condor just wanted to talk to someone!
That's right. Really, Chatterer!
It's a lie, it's a lie,
that guy tried to eat me up!
That's a lie!
Try hard and talk to him!
You'll realize what a good friend he really is!
Yeah, but I'm a fraidy-cat, you know...
Mr. Condor is just looking for someone
to be friends with!
Y-y-y-y...
Yeah, but I'm still scared...
Does it matter either way?
A-ha! I know!
You all wanna have that big spook bird
chase me and all have a big laugh!
Well, I'm not falling for that... ahem!
But Reddy was saying, "Be careful with that bird"!
- H-h-how do you know he's not scary?
- How do you know that, eh?
Even when Polly and I approached him,
he didn't jumped us!
Sure slept good, all night long! Oh!
Would that possibly be
one of my feathered friends
from my old Southern country days?
It is, it is! There's no mistake!
That guy has come to our forest!
Mother, Mother, I have good news!
Hmm...! My goodness, what can I do?
These forest people here, as soon
as I approach them, they run off!
Such a lonely place, I can't stand it...
Be quiet for a while!
When my wife arrives, we'll talk it over
perhaps go to another forest!
It's no mistake! It's Mr. Condor!
Mother, Mother, come here!
Everyone, come here!
Perhaps...
Well, well, so you finally come, Mr. Condor!
- Well, Uncle Billy!
- Well, I certainly missed you! Missed you!
Wow! Look at Uncle Billy's children
playing in that big bird!
Hey, Uncle Billy, Uncle Billy!
Hi there, Peter!
I-is that big bird a friend of yours?
It's Mr. Condor, my old friend,
who's come from the Southern country!
My pleasure!
I'm Peter.
Welcome to the forest, Mr. Condor!
Out of my way, out of my way!
Pardon me, pardon me, pardon...
Good day, chipmunk!
I-I-I-I'm Chatterer.
Glad to know you, Mr. Condor!
Hey, here comes my wife!
- Well...!
- Ah...!
Oh, there-there she is!
Hey, this way!
- Well... really good to see you!
- Oh, that's nice!
And do-do you think this forest
is a good place for us to live?
It's good, it's good!
I think it will be a wonderful place
to raise our children!
- Ah...!
- Well...!
Well, Madam, so glad you came!
Oh, Uncle Billy!
We should all remember this,
and let it be a lesson:
don't make snap judgements.
We should not judge things
as they seem in the beginning.
The Condor that frightened
the forest animals at first,
turned out to be their friend.
The Condors love the forest,
and the animals that live there.
This was a fast friendship,
that would last forever.
Subtitle: South Wind Subs