Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Ah... I'm awful hungry!
Hey, Jerry!
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Oh, Bobby Raccoon, what's up?
Better be careful, Jerry!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
What's that mean:
"Better be careful"?
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
It seems like some men have
set up traps around here...
Traps?
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Sister South Wind informed us about it.
Fables of the Green Forest
That she saw them last night,
setting the traps.
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
You better be careful!
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
I should think that I can take
care of myself... That's right.
I'm just trying to be helpful.
If you get trapped, don't blame me!
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Jerry the Muskrat, although acting arrogantly...
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
...really didn't know what a trap looked like,
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
nor what to be careful of.
Right now, all that was in his head was...
that he was hungry.
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Traps in the Forest
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
Jerry wondered, is this a dream?
Well, after all, for Jerry,
carrots were his number one favorite food.
Jerry didn't bother
to take the time to doubt or
to wonder why carrots
could possibly be found
in such a place as this?
Mm, mm... yum... yum!
It's so good, so very good...
Oh my, but how happy I am to be able
to eat my favorite food!
Help! Help, help... ow, ah!
That's why I told you all to be careful!
With these things we can't live
with peace of mind.
What do you all think?
You're so nonchalant there, Peter,
but there may be a trap for your leg...
Hey, don't scare me like that!
- I'm scared, I am...
- Better do something.
Where on earth are you going to find a trap?
Huh, if we knew that,
there wouldn't be need to worry.
Then, what should we do?
That's why we were talking
over just what should be done...
Once and for all:
Let's get rid of all those humans!
Huh?
And who's gonna get rid of them?
Uh... Hmm.
Rather than that, it would be better
not to let the men to the forest at all.
We may say that, but they'll enter anyway,
there's no way to stop them.
Rather, we'd better not to eat
the bait on the traps...
It's difficult to distinguish
which is the trap bait.
Better to prevent them from setting up
the traps in any way we possibly can.
And how do you keep them from doing that?
What are you saying?
You yourself don't understand a thing!
Huh, me? Your opinion too is completely useless.
Rather than that, let's talk
over what we should do...
Perhaps I could suggest a good idea?
Well...
Oh...
- Huh?!
Huh?
Now, that's it!
Everybody, listen, I've got a good idea!
Tell us what the good idea is, Rocky!
If we can't get all our opinions coordinated,
why not tell Grandfather Frog about
the traps and ask him his opinion?
Mm-hm, I see, that you mean to ask
the opinion of an elder.
Grandfather Frog is elderly, very smart
and knows very well all about the old days.
That's a good idea!
Grandfather Frog might know all about traps.
Hey, Joe, how about
calling over Grandfather Frog?
It's on!
Harry, come along with me.
Thus, it was decided to ask for
an opinion from Grandfather Frog.
Good day!
Hey, Mr. Frog!
Good day, Harry!
What's up, I see Joe is with you?
Pardon us.
But everyone is waiting at the Big Rock
for you to come to give us advice.
Why, you little tricksters!
What kind of joke are you intending
to play on this person?
Grandfather Frog...
...just as you say: we are tricksters.
But this time were on the level,
it is not a trick.
Actually, there's a meeting being
held at the Big Rock.
What's that? A meeting you say?
Grandfather Frog wore a surprised look,
but actually, Sister South Wind
had already told him everything.
Huh? You say Grandfather Frog won't come?
The other day, I pulled down the water lily
that old Grandfather Frog was sitting on.
How disgusting!
Okay, I'll go call him.
- Oh...
- Oh, Rocky, be careful of the traps!
Okay!
Ah...
Grandfather?
I have a request, Grandfather Frog...
Please, lend us your wisdom! Please...
Yeah, yeah.
At this rate, we-we will not be able
to continue to live in the forest.
Uh-hm.
I beg of you, if something isn't done,
we will all be captured by man...
Have everyone assembled by the trap
that Jerry was almost caught in.
Yes? Then you-you are really
gonna tell us about the traps?
Now everyone, look carefully.
This is the trap made by man!
- Oh...
A truly frightening instrument.
Oh...
Hey, this is a trap, this is a trap!
That's right.
Bobby, push this with all your might.
Nay, not me!
It's alright.
Once a trap has been released
there's not a thing to worry about.
Now, try it!
Yeah...
- Oh...!
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
- Huh?!
- Oh!
Eh!
Don't put your hands out.
Now, this time, don't put out your hands!
Ah. Mm.
Okay, watch closely.
- There!
- Huh... Oh...!
Eh!
That's how it is.
Bobby, push the spring once again.
Why, why me again?
- Pfew!
As you can see, if you place your foot
on this round spot,
the weight separates this metal lock,
which releases this spring.
- Wow, what a fright!
Dirt or grass over this trap
makes it almost unnoticeable.
Peter, there might be one
right there by your feet.
Ah! What'll I do?
Only scaring ya, there's none there.
Don't ever frighten me like that again!
Anyway, you never know where it'll be,
so always be careful.
- Only...
- Only?
Usually around a trap
are placed some delicious bait.
That's right, the one that almost caught me
had my favorite carrots around it.
Oh!
Now we must find, without exception,
all of the traps set by man!
- But how are we suppose to find them?
Just find them.
Just find them?
Use your eyes and your noses.
Your eyes... your noses...
- Eyes and noses?
I told ya earlier that if you see some food
in a spot usually not found
then that is a warning.
And, without exception,
there will be the scent of man there.
- Eh?!
If you find one as I just showed you,
hit it with a piece of stick
and the trap releases.
Hey, let's do it! Everyone look
for traps all around here.
Uh-huh.
Uh-huh. Although I'm very brave,
I feel a chill.
- Okay, let's find them.
- Without exception.
Let's find them!
Let's do it, everyone!
Yes, let's do it!
Yes, that's right, let's do it!
Come on, everyone, let's do it now!
The amount you guys can find,
I can find all by myself. I'll show ya! Yeah!
Hm?
There's something wrong?
I smell men-scent around here...
Did you say "men-scent"?
No... No...
It's much more like fish, I think.
A fish! Harry, come on!
Someone left a fish by the bank!
Come on, let's feast!
Joe, don't touch that fish,
don't touch that fish, Joe! Stop, Joe!
Oh, Harry...
What's the matter with you?
Do you think I'm going to eat it up
before you get here?
Stop it!
Stop!
Ouch... Oh my, it hurts!
Didn't I tell you? Didn't I tell you
that it was very dangerous?
Didn't Grandfather Frog say
that if you found any food stuffed
in any unusual place,
to be careful, huh?
Now...
Oh my, did that hurt...
What's the matter?
- Oh, it's nothing. We found a trap.
- That's no reason to argue!
You should be glad. Terrific!
Joe, I've changed my opinion of you.
Joe and Harry found a trap,
found a trap!
- Oh?
- Huh?
Rocky, I think there's something
very-very strange going on here.
Eh, something strange going on here?
- My, what a delicious looking carrot!
- Don't, Polly, don't do it!
A carrot in this place is rather strange...
Oh...
Oh!
Aah!
Just as I thought!
What?
Hey, Rocky has found a trap,
Rocky has found one, he's found a trap!
Ah...!
Well, well...
Yeah.
Yep.
Just as I thought!
There's a man heading this way!
It must be the one who set the traps!
- Oh!
Oh!!
Ah!
This one's no good too.
But there are animal tracks,
they positively came close.
Okay, let's set it once more.
Okay, all clear, release the traps!
Good, good! Go, go!
Uh-hm, uh-hm.
Look, again it's escaped!
This one too!
This one's been tampered with too.
This one too has been tampered with!
This time, let's put lots of bait on it.
The thing to do is hide the traps,
so it won't be noticed.
We'll come back later.
Hey... This is a rabbit path...
Okay...
- Good morning!
- Hush!
Many thanks for your trouble!
Now, today's bait is really something...
After you release the trap,
pick up the bait and everyone assemble.
Grandfather, what do you intend to do with them?
Never mind, just hurry.
Something for your later pleasure.
Let's go, Polly...
...Peter.
There's some, there's some! A whole bunch
of carrots! A whole bunch of carrots!
Fishes, fishes! A whole bunch of fishes,
fishes, fishes!
Come on, little trap,
come on over here, let me find ya.
Cabbages, cabbages, cabbages, carrots,
corn and are some potatoes too!
A-ha!
Polly, come here!
Help me carry these lushes goodies!
Oh, is it alright?
Oh!
Rocky, help me! My foot, my foot!
What?
What's the matter?
- Oh... ow...
- Ah...!
- Polly!
- Mm... Mmm... Mmm...
The men, the men, the men are coming!
The men are coming!
- Huh?
- Oh?
Hurry and save Polly!
Hurry, Polly, let's flee!
Oh, oh, my leg...
Ow, oh, it hurts!... It hurts!
No good, no good. It's no use pulling,
rather just check the base of the wire.
Huh?
Better hurry, the men are just
over there, hurry!
Oh, ow!
Hurry, hurry, hurry!
They're here, the men are just over there!
No...!
Ah...
Ah! They're here!
- Ah...
- Oh!
Look!
I can't figure it. The trap is released
and all the bait has been swiped.
Now, with the bait from the traps,
time for a big party!
- Yeah!
Oh, boy, this is, yeah...
- Well, Reddy, having a party all by yourself?
- Yeah...
Yummy, yummy.
Good food!
Without a doubt some of the best
carrots I've ever had!
I'm going to have another one...
That is so good,
good, good, yeah!
Some of the best...
Just delicious...
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango