Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
The Secret of Mr. Condor
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
Mr. and Mrs. Condor, who've come
from a country to the South,
have temporarily decided
to live here, in the Green Forest.
Although scary in appearance,
condors don't harm any live animals.
The couple became great friends with Rocky
and all of the other forest animals.
They've flown over here
all the way from the distant South.
How wonderful!
I too would like to fly high
in the sky with the wind.
Me too…
But won't one get dizzy
from flying up so high?
They're not like us, Polly.
I'd sure like to go and see
what the South is like…
That's funny, usually
he's flying with Mrs. Condor.
I wonder if anything has
happened to Mrs. Condor.
Or has she become tired of the Green Forest
and returned to her homeland?
They were always
flying together…
That's it! Let's have Mr. Condor tell us
all about the country to the South.
Okay.
That's it!
Mrs. Condor must be
building a nest!
That must be it!
Why didn't I think of it before?
All of my bird friends are building nests.
Take the case of Bob the Quail,
or Tommy the Tit, or even old man Northly,
all of them are building nests
and brooding their eggs.
The condor couple must
have a nest somewhere!
I'd love to see it.
Boy, would I like to see it!
I've got to see it!
A big bird like the condor couple must have
a large nest, so it should be simple to find!
Alright!
Just find a new nest high in a tall tree,
it should be simple.
Nope, not here.
Blacky! Blacky!
Blacky! Gosh, Blacky!
Blacky!
Caw!
Hey, Peter.
Have you seen a large nest
around here?
Haven't seen any.
Why do you ask?
Oh, no reason.
Just wondering, that's all.
What's the matter
with that guy, Peter?
Caw! Caw!
I never dreamed there were
so many trees in the Green Forest…
What are you doing, Peter?
Uh… Peter?
Hi there, Rocky.
What's the matter, is something
wrong with your neck?
I was looking up at the tops of the trees
so much that now it won't bend.
What on earth
are you doing, Peter?
Oh… Uh…
Just looking for something.
I've gotta run. See ya!
What a weirdo.
Having Rocky find Mr. and Mrs. Condor's nest
would spoil all the fun I'll have when I find it.
Now, where did… Oh?
What's this?
Where is Mr. Condor headed to?
Gosh, why I was so stupid?
Why didn't I notice this before?
I didn't have to bend
my neck searching,
all I had to do is watch
Mr. Condor from a distance.
I'm just so curious…
What is it that
you want to know, Peter?
A nest. I want to know
where the Mr. Condor's nest is.
Mr. Condor's nest?
It's been over a year since Mr. Condor
and his wife have come to our forest.
I see. And no one knows where
their nest is, let alone see it.
And when you don't know something,
Peter, you just can't get it out of your head.
Right?
Yeah… Sounds about right.
Speaking of which, I know everything
that is going on in the forest,
but even I haven't seen it.
Wait, that's it!
I could ask for your help, Sammy.
Sammy! Wouldn't you like to know what
a great big bird like a condor has for a nest?
It must be quite
a large one, I'll bet!
Maybe you could try looking for it?
I know you can do it!
Okay, I'll try to find it.
Peter, you keep searching
for it too, okay?
Okay!
I'm sure Sammy can find it.
Like the clear blue sky that's above,
a wide expanse of water continues far out.
Are ocean really so immense?
It's so immense that one
cannot see any land.
One looks around and
sees nothing but ocean.
Oh, I'd love to see an ocean…
It's not only an ocean, is also has large cities,
cities with lots of humans living there.
I've even lived in one of those cities
inhabited by humans.
The cities where the humans live?
Aren't such places
very dangerous?
We don't attack
any living thing, do we?
So humans don't do
anything against us, either.
No matter how well hidden,
if it's there, I know that I'll find it.
It was right around here…
Mrs.?
Mrs. Condor?
Mrs.!
Peter? Peter!
Rocky and Polly?
Oh, Mr. Condor…
What are you doing? What are you all
talking about with Mr. Condor?
We were listening to stories
about the Southern country.
Would you like to listen
to them with us, Peter?
Which is bigger, the cities of the country
to the South or Mr. Brown's house?
No comparison.
It's many, many-many times bigger.
Like the Lookout Pine?
Yeah, yeah.
None of those things matter.
Mr. Condor, please, tell me
where is your nest, tell me!
Peter!
Lookout Pine?
Nothing like that.
It's much, much taller. There are many
houses piled on top of each other.
Such large houses
are called buildings.
There are many, many
such buildings.
Who cares how many
buildings there are!
Mr. Condor, better tell us,
where's your nest? Come on, tell me!
You have nothing to look for.
Huh? What do you mean?
We just don't have a nest.
It's a lie, it's a lie, it's a lie!
What kind of a bird doesn't have a nest?
All of my friends have built nests,
laid eggs and hatched them!
That's why, Mr. Condor,
you must also have a nest!
So tell me!
Come on and tell me where it is!
We really don't have a nest.
It wouldn't hurt you to just tell me.
No need to come up with these lies.
I'm not going to do anything bad!
I wanna see!
I just wanna see!
Eggs were laid already, right?
How many? Big, I'll bet.
Mr. Condor, is your wife
keeping them warm?
Peter!
We haven't seen your wife
flying around with you for a while, now.
Oh? You noticed even that?
I thought that the Mrs. Condor
must be brooding the eggs.
Now, to brood eggs,
you need a nest!
Please, tell me where your nest is.
I promise not to tell anyone.
I'll be the only one to know!
I'm telling you,
we don't build nests!
Huh?
Then where is your wife?
What happened, huh?
She hasn't returned
to the South, has she?
She's here.
She's here, alright.
Busy with the family chores.
F-Family?!
The wife is warming two eggs.
Today or tomorrow,
the two most good-looking babies
in the Green Forest should be hatched.
But you said you didn't have
any nest, didn't you?
Exactly. Exactly, absolutely true.
Condors don't have nests at all.
Now you're just
making fun of me!
I don't mean to.
Then something
doesn't add up here!
Brooding eggs, no nest…
I'd like you to tell me
what's up with that!
As it is, I can only believe
half of your story, at best!
This is the first time
I have ever been doubted, rabbit.
B-But…
I told the truth because of your
ridiculous persistent questioning.
Now, if you're still not satisfied,
why did you even ask to begin with?
No nest, but his wife
is brooding eggs…
Strange…
I just can't believe it.
To have no nest?
Okay, I'll solve this puzzle,
just you wait and see!
Peter's curiosity really
is a problem now, isn't it?
Wanting to find out things that others
don't want you to is a bad thing.
Peter, you should not try to invade
the privacy and the lives of others.
What a beautiful
weather it is today.
Oh, it's Mr. Condor!
Mr. Condor!
Rocky, there's no way
that he can hear you.
Look how high he is.
It doesn't matter
if he can't hear me.
Hey, Mr. Condor!
Good morning!
Beautiful, isn't it?
Rocky, let's ask Mr. Condor to tell us
more stories about the country to the South.
Yeah.
Ah, he's coming down!
Okay, today for sure I'm going
to find Mr. Condor's nest!
Peter, Peter!
Oh, Sammy! Did you find it the nest?
Was Mrs. Condor there?
Ah, I've met her.
Mrs. Condor, that is.
Really? Wonderful.
That's Sammy for you.
But, you know,
there weren't any eggs.
Huh?! But that's crazy.
What? Are you suggesting that
I'm lying about those eggs, Peter?
You don't have to believe me.
Why did you ask me for help, then?
N-No, but Mr. Condor definitely said
that there were two eggs.
No nest, but two eggs.
Peter, do you know about the hollow log,
near the large spruce tree in the Green Forest?
Oh? Why are you asking me this?
Yes, I know the log.
But what's so special about it?
Go there and take a peak inside it.
You'll find something there
to make you very happy.
Aha…
But go there quietly
and don't make any noise, alright.
Well, see you!
I wonder what's there… Alright!
In the city where the humans live,
there are long things called chimneys.
For some reason,
they are really warm.
And what is there
beyond the city, Mr. Condor?
Fields.
The fields continue way out.
And what's beyond the fields?
A huge lake.
There are plenty of fish
and many birds flock there.
And what's beyond the lake?
Mountains, steep mountains.
It's a home to other woodchucks like you.
And beyond that, what's it like?
A city. Another city
and another city!
I wonder what's in there.
That Sammy, do you suppose
he could be trying to scare me?
It doesn't snow in the country
to the South, does it?
Oh, it does. In the winter,
there are areas where it snows.
Then it's best to sit on the chimney
to keep yourself warm.
Boy, what a boring story.
Surely Reddy couldn't be waiting
inside that log, could he?
You never know with Sammy
and his tricks.
Is it safe, I wonder?
What to do?
I want to see it.
Whatever is in there,
I have to see it!
Sammy knew
that I was scared off
and then he followed me
to see what I would do.
For crying out loud,
what a mean guy he is!
But who was that in the log,
saying "shush"?
A voice like that could
only belong to a snake.
Mrs. Condor, it's alright!
Sa-Sammy?
Surprised, huh, Peter?
You are Mrs. Condor, aren't you?
Yes, that's right.
And when I looked in the log a moment ago,
that was you who made that noise?
Yes, that's right.
I yelled, because you startled me.
But I've got to say,
your feet are real speedy, you know?
But, Mrs. Condor, what were
you doing inside that log?
I mean, why would a condor
be sitting inside of a log?
For a short while,
it is serving as my home.
What did you say?
So, Mrs. Condor,
what were you doing in there?
Now you understand, eh, Peter?
It was true what Mr. Condor said
about not having a nest, you see?
She was brooding two eggs,
now baby condors.
Hey, that tickles!
Now's the time!
Reddy!
Reddy, leave them alone!
This is terrible, terrible!
The baby condors
will be caught by Reddy!
This is terrible, terrible!
Terrible, terrible!
This time it's Peter
who takes beating!
Terrible, terrible!
Peter, it's okay now.
Did you understand, Peter? How it's
possible to have two eggs, but no nest?
And now, they've become babies.
They're our babies!
Are these really baby condors?
But how? Without a nest or…
Peter!
It's alright, it's alright.
My father, grandfather,
great grandfather and even further back,
they all were born this way.
It wasn't because
they didn't liked nests.
Doing it this way is the best for us.
But, but without a nest,
you can't warm your eggs, can you?!
I was in the log,
warming my eggs all the time.
There are various
species of condors,
but the one in this story is known
as the western turkey vulture.
They migrated to North America
from South America
and as you all have just seen,
they really do not build a nest.
I have one more thing
that I wanna ask you!
Mr. Condor!
Rocky and his friends organize
a party in the moonlight.
No party can go without games!
And so, the game of
hide-and-seek starts.
But suddenly an eerie voice
comes from somewhere.
It's a terrifying howling that neither Rocky,
Polly nor Peter have ever heard before.
Everyone gets alarmed.
This also applies to Reddy, who takes care of
the house in the absence of Granny.
Who could this
ominous voice belong to?
Next time:
"Reddy Fox Keeps Home".
Be there to watch!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango