Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Oh, little birds, good morning!
Always in good spirits, I see!
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Well, squirrel, good morning to you too!
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Mr. Brown's son, young Tom,
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
often goes trout fishing in the Laughing Brook
of the Green Forest.
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Today somehow, he has no luck with his fishing.
Funny, someone must've caught
all the fishes already,
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
or they've been scared off...
I wonder which it is?
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Oh!
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Oh! This hasn't been cut with a knife,
it's been bitten off!
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Who's the one that did this?!
Who's the one that's been
bothering my fishing?
Buster the Hero
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
Could it have been a hawk?
Or...
B-b-b-bear tracks...!
Wow!
Joe... Tom was scared!
That young Tom, running scared
just at the sight of your tracks!
Buster, you are something!
After an incident like that,
Joe the Otter just couldn't keep quiet.
So that's why he came here,
to the Smiling Pool,
where everyone always gathers.
Joe, big incident, big news,
what's it all about?
It is just... Well, in any case,
Buster's quite a guy...!
Ah, well, about that I just wonder!
I haven't tangled with him yet
in a fight till the end!
Reddy the braggart, Reddy the braggart!
That's just enough out of you, Peter,
you wanna get hurt?
Reddy, Reddy, Reddy!
Smart he is, but evilly only smart!
A tricky one like you
couldn't catch even one fly!
Just you keep on talking, Peter,
and you're finished!
Peter, let's listen to Joe's story!
Now, Joe, tell us, just what did Buster do?
That's right, Joe. Now you quit beating
around the bush and hurry and tell us.
That's right, that's right.
Now, tell me, what is it that Buster did?
You see, Mr. Brown's son, Tom,
is really terribly afraid of our Buster!
I just can't believe such a story.
Take the group at the Green Forest,
for example,
and the bunch from the Smiling Pool.
Tom is hardly afraid of them.
Although we are all afraid of him,
as everybody knows.
I don't care what you say, because
Tom really did run away from Buster.
Yeah, Tom was scared!
Without a doubt, that Tom did run away!
Buster taught Tom a lesson!
That Tom could've retaliated!
Buster is great! Buster is a hero!
The hero of  the Green Forest!
I want to see with my very own eyes!
- Whether is true or not, before I decide!
- That's right!
With the exception of Reddy the Fox
and Blackie the Crow,
all of the forest animals are very happy,
because, just at the sight of Buster's track,
everybody says that young Tom fled.
So that's why Buster's popularity
is so tremendous in the Green Forest.
Now, Tom won't come in the forest anymore!
We won't have to guard against him!
He won't be trying to trap us either!
All of this is because of Buster!
Now why don't we all go and try
to give our thanks to Buster?
That's a good idea!
Right, let's go!
Huh?!
Oh...
What's the matter, Blackie?
Move out of the way.
Now, wait just a moment!
Let's check first and see if it's true!
Hey, Blackie, are you saying
that what I said was a lie?
No, no, I'm not doubting you.
Is just that you said Tom saw Buster's tracks,
and not Buster himself, right?
Well...
That's the problem...
I-I have a really good plan to see
whether Tom is really afraid of Buster,
or whether Buster is stronger than Tom!
And this plan, please, Blackie,
tell me, what is it?
Alright.
Now, assemble as many of your friends
at the walnut tree by the Laughing Brook,
I'll explain there.
- OK!
- Leave that job to me...!
- We'll go too, alright, Polly?
- Yes...
Blackie is overjoyed,
because almost everyone in the Green Forest,
has come here, to the Laughing Brook,
just to listen to him tell them
about the plan that he has arranged.
Ladies and gentlemen, now I shall speak to you
about the plan that I have in mind.
Joe the Otter has said that
Tom fled upon seeing Buster's tracks,
but whether he was really frightened and fled,
or whether he remembered some other business
and left, we do not know.
You, ladies and gentlemen,
have made Buster the forest hero.
I'd like to think so too.
And if Tom really did see
Buster's tracks and fled,
then we have the right to make him a hero.
I would like to verify that. You too.
So my plan is...
Tomorrow morning, at the edge of the forest,
Sammy, that talkative jay, and I,
will create a big ruckus.
Tom will certainly come
to see what is happening.
Then, Sammy and I, the two of us,
will entice him into the forest.
We will lure him to where Buster is going to be.
And if Tom runs when he sees Buster,
then I and all of you too,
we'll crown Buster king of the forest.
Please, come on!
Let's all hide and watch!
And learn the truth! Once and for all!
OK, that should make everything clear...
Mr. Crow, why are you making so much noise?
I'd like to know why...
but after feeding the cows,
then I have to milk the cows.
Huh...?!
- It looks like they succeeded luring Tom towards Buster.
- Yes, indeed.
Excellent, excellent, lure him
to Buster's house just as skillfully!
It's working, it's working!
Oh...!
Oh...
Buster!
Huh?!
Well, how about it?
It's true, isn't it, what I said about Tom
being afraid of Buster?
I guess it's true, Joe, just like you said,
really sorry to have doubted you.
Look!
He's running!
- Oh!
Ah...
- A-ha...?!
- Huh...?!
- Oh...!
- Buster!
- Buster...!
- Hey...!
- What...?!
- Wow...!
- Ah...!
Boy, if that's a king,
well, even I could be one!
Oh, the king has fallen!
It seems that Buster too was scared.
He's big in size only!
But to me, he's just a cowardly weakling!
Is that so...?!
I just can't believe that to be so!
The forest people have forgotten already
all the nice things
that Buster has done for them.
And they're noisily saying
all kinds of bad things about him.
But Buster...
...already he's forgotten
about his meeting with Tom.
Well... what in the world
was I planning on doing now, hmm?
Ah... hmm...
Ah... That's it, I wanted to lick on some honey!
Ah...
My, my...! My favorite food!
The fat bear has long claws,
sharp teeth and is strong!
He crouches somewhere in the forest!
He's hiding from morning till night, yay-yay!
- Yay-yay, fat Buster, fat Buster, fat Buster!
- Fat Buster, fat Buster, fat Buster!
- Weakling Buster, yay-yay!
- Weakling!
Huh...?!
Ah... shut up...!
One...
...two...
- One, two! One, two! One, two!
- Ah... come on, you guys, that's enough!
- One, two! One, two! One...
...two! One, two! One, two!
The fat bear has long claws,
sharp teeth and is strong!
He crouches like that,
and hides from morning till night!
Yay-yay-yay, the fat bear has long claws,
sharp teeth and is strong, yay-yay!
Even our good-natured Buster
can't stand all the bad things
the forest people are saying
about him any longer.
Blackie the Crow and Sammy,
the talkative jay, flee into the sky.
So Buster can't do a thing,
except stamp with rage.
When even Chatterer, the friendly squirrel,
began to repeat all of those bad things...
poor Buster could stand the strain no longer.
The fat bear has long claws,
sharp teeth and he's strong!
He's fled somewhere in the forest!
And he's hiding from morning till night!
Hey, you, weak coward Buster!
Oh...?!
If I knew I was gonna get into such a fix,
I'd never would've said those bad things!
Now... I'll teach you what happens
when you try to make a fool of me!
You just wait there, and I'll eat you up whole!
Chatterer was too scared...
...to notice that Buster couldn't climb-out
on the slender portion of the limb.
Oh!
Well... I'll let him escape this time,
but I'll get him!
Well... that's what he said...
...but Buster wasn't... really angry...
The fat bear is a coward!
Mr. Brown, there's something I have to tell you.
Buster's out at your field, and he's eating your berries!
Your berries, your be....
Hey! You, Sammy! Shut up...!
Thief...! Thief...!
Thief...!
Buster's stealing Mr. Brown's bucket!
Thief!
Oh, shut up, Sammy!
I don't know why everything
has to be as bad like this!
Today I just did terrible!
Nothing I do seems to be right,
I just can't do it, there's no other way...!
What...?! Buster committed a robbery...?!
I didn't steal anything!
Oh, boy, this is funny!
Oh...!
I'm sure, this will destroy the Green Forest!
Better do something quickly,
or my resting trees are goner...!
He chased me out on a tree limb, and I was so
scared that I had to jump down to the ground!
I think Buster ought to leave the forest!
That's mean! In reality, you all are
a little bit at fault, understand me?
Oh!
- Uh?
- Oh?!
Rocky, where are you going?
Oh, stop it!
Rocky, it's dangerous!
Rocky...!
Hmm... are you still mad?
I'll try to take the bucket off.
Now lower your head.
Now... Buster, lower your head to me, quickly!
Rocky's gonna help him now!
Thank you, Rocky...!
Thank you, Rocky, you really saved me!
Yeah, yeah...!
Here's the bucket!
Buster, wasn't it swell
that you weren't a thief after all?
Hey...! Buster is laughing,
he's really laughing!
Hey-hey-hey-hey,
hey-hey-hey!
How nice!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango