Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hang in There, Chatterer
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
Is there anyone smarter than I?
I'm the smartest one
under the sky!
Is there anyone smarter than I?
Good morning, Chatterer!
You're always in good
mood, aren't you?
That's for sure!
I always have enough food,
so I can do anything I wanna do,
any way I wanna do it.
Every day is just so much fun!
Bragging again, huh?
But it's the truth.
Though I may not be very strong,
my head is very sharp, you see?
What I lack in strength, I can cover
more than enough with my intelligence!
Chatterer, let me ask you: compared to
Sammy, which one of you two is smarter?
That guy? He doesn't even reach
the bottom of my feet!
Our levels may be similar,
but his smartness is the crafty kind.
I'm a beautiful, smart jay.
Pretty feathers, like blue sky.
The most intelligent
creature in the forest…
Sammy, do you mean that?
Hey there, guys!
Why, are you doubting
my beauty?
No, we wanted to know whether you really
are the smartest animal in the forest.
Well, the fact is, I don't know anyone
in the area who'd match me intellectually.
But Chatterer boasts that
he's the smartest one around!
What? Chatterer?
Yes. He said that you
don't even reach his feet.
And that your smartness
is the crafty kind!
Wait, what? Someone is getting
ahead of himself, I see.
Alright, I'll show you that I'm smarter than him,
with one wing right behind my back.
I just saw a weasel.
I talked with him a little.
Oh? Where?
Oh, by your main storeroom.
On the outskirts of the forest. The weasel
said he's not leaving until he catches you.
You didn't tell him that
I was here, did you, Sammy?
I didn't, at least not yet.
But you're so conceited.
Sometimes I think that it's better for
someone like you to be caught by a weasel.
Sammy, don't scare me like that!
I beg you, please,
don't tell the weasel!
Then, will you listen
to my request?
I'll listen to anything!
Well, then…
Well, then?
As for my supper…
Your supper?
From today on,
for one week, every day,
you will go and get some corn
for me from Mr. Brown's farm.
From Mr. Brown's farm?!
How about it? If you can promise
me that, I won't tell the weasel.
Sammy, that's ridiculous!
Why?
Because in the daytime,
Blacky the Cat and Bowser are on guard.
But you're real smart, aren't you?
That's true, but…
Then I'd think it'd be very simple for you to
fool Blacky's eyes, you get what I'm saying?
Alright, Sammy.
Well, I'll be waiting here,
so hurry and go get it!
And please, make it the most
delicious-looking ones!
Ah, gosh!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Blacky, you foolish black cat!
You can't even reach me here!
Blacky, you silly cat!
Stupid, silly cat!
What a predicament!
It went smooth today,
but that doesn't mean
tomorrow will go the same.
How do I get out of this situation?
If I go to the granary again,
I'll be only chased by Blacky again.
That's it! I've got it!
Yeah, Sammy…
Too bad you're not gonna have
the satisfaction of seeing me scared!
Gosh, I've got such a smart head!
I'm overwhelmed,
even if I do say so myself.
Today is another beautiful day!
Good, good!
It sure is great to be alive!
Who's the smartest one
under the sky?
Hey, hey, say, Chatterer, tell us,
what did you think of?
You'll have to wait and see.
Then you will find out
how smart I really am!
Hey, hey, hey!
Hello there, my friends!
Sammy, exactly how long
are you gonna keep me waiting?
If you don't get here on time,
it's very awkward.
Oh, well, somehow I didn't think
that you'd be here so early.
I'm always an early riser!
Well, I'll be running off!
Is there anyone smarter than I?
That's funny.
He should be more hesitating.
That Chatterer was awfully enthusiastic.
Did he say anything to you?
He would just smile and laugh,
and not say a word.
Ah. Hmm.
Who's the smartest one
in the Green Forest?
That Chatterer, he's late.
Well, maybe he got caught
at Mr. Brown's farm?
Why, he left here
full of confidence.
But there's always
the unexpected.
Anyway, Sammy's wrong in making
such unreasonable demands!
Not at all. He surrendered
and agreed to it of his own free will.
Hmm…
Chatterer!
Ha! I'm back!
You sure took your time.
I guess you're right.
We were really worried whether
you had been caught by Blacky.
I'm not so stupid as to be
caught by that guy!
My, how immodest.
But it's the truth.
Here. Here!
Still got any complaints?
This corn today
doesn't taste very good.
Is that so?
Did you really get this corn
from Mr. Brown's granary?
Nope, from my storage
in the fence.
Huh, your fence storage?
Yeah, but it's still corn
from Mr. Brown's farm.
Ah…
How's that? Did you finally
realize how smart I am?
Well, tomorrow I'll give you
a feast again all you want.
Is there anyone smarter than I?
Sammy, Chatterer was
one step ahead of you.
Why not end this game?
Out of the question.
Tomorrow you'll see
who's smarter.
I'm sure Chatterer intends to go to his
secondary storehouse tomorrow again.
If he can't enter…
Have you thought of a way
to defeat him?
You could say so. I'm gonna make him
realize that he's not as smart as he think he is.
Say, tell me!
How are you going to get him?
Okay, get over here, I'll tell ya.
So, that's my plan, more or less.
Well, see you later!
Now, the next day,
Chatterer set out enthusiastically
for his storeroom in the fence.
Help!
Chatterer!
Are you alright?
I'm okay. Had a little
excitement, but it went fine.
Hmph, what a liar.
Look, you're still shaking like a leaf!
I'm not shaking. I ran out of breath
and I haven't got it back, that's all!
Hm. You sure
got a way with words.
Anyway, you didn't bring
the corn, did you?
What? So you did run off scared.
You'd better hurry
and go get it for me.
Oh… That is…
If you don't want to, that's fine.
I'll just tell the weasel where your house is.
Alright, I understand!
As long as I go, it's alright, isn't it?
Gosh!
Once again, Chatterer decided
to go to his storehouse in the fence.
But Whitetail was still guarding it,
so he couldn't get near.
But that's strange.
What's Whitetail doing over there?
What? You failed?
More or less, yeah.
I'm sorry to say that.
So he escaped…
I'm really sorry, after you went
out of your way to tell me.
Now, now, you don't need
to feel so dejected.
Sammy will probably plot something again.
I'll tell you when he does.
Alright. Thank you, brother.
I'll see you later.
So that's it! Sammy used Blacky
to tell Whitetail about it.
I won't let him get away with this.
Chatterer wondered for the rest of the day
how he could get even with Sammy.
Whitetail will probably be waiting
in an ambush tomorrow again.
If he only wasn't there…
That's it!
The next day, Chatterer woke up
earlier than everyone
and he went to Mr. Brown's granary
through his secret entrance right at daybreak.
Once inside, he gathered some corn.
Then he hid it in a safe place in the fence.
His plan was to get the corn to Sammy
without going through any trouble.
This plan went very smoothly.
Sammy, seeing that Chatterer
showed no signs of anxiety,
felt a deep disappointment.
Sammy, just because you can't cause any
trouble, you don't have to make such a face!
I'm the smart one. To try and think
of getting me is a big mistake!
Well, till tomorrow!
How mortifying! How mortifying!
As matters stand, Chatterer will be considered
the smarter one thorough the forest.
Isn't there anything that I can do?
How mortifying! How mortifying…
What to do?
Wait a minute.
That Chatterer, he'll probably go
again to the stone fence for more.
What if Reddy suddenly leaped out
from behind the fence?
Reddy?
Yeah, I'm thinking of telling Reddy about
Chatterer going to the stone fence for corn.
How about that, gang?
Isn't it a good idea?
When he sees Reddy hiding
near the stone fence,
Chatterer won't hide
the corn there anymore.
Then, even if unwilling, he'll have to go
to Brown's house for the corn, you see?
Sammy, you're
going way overboard!
Polly's right. What are you thinking,
letting Reddy catch him?
Huh. You guys really
don't know me at all, do you?
I just want to scare
Chatterer, that's all.
If Chatterer is really in danger,
I'll raise a ruckus and let him know.
So don't you worry, okay?
Sammy will handle this.
How's that?
No more complaints, I presume?
You really are one crazy bird.
Yeah, I think so, too.
If you admit that yourself,
there's no helping you.
This must be the place
that Sammy spoke of, huh?
Alright, guys, I'm going!
Have a safe trip!
Here! Thanks for waiting.
Now, don't be shy.
Go ahead, eat up!
If you want more, I'll get more.
Thanks, but my stomach
is not feeling too good.
I'll accept your treat next time.
Sammy, I bet it's just that
your throat got dry
from thinking what you're
going to say to Reddy now.
Chatterer! How did you know?
I wasn't born yesterday!
If you were going to think
of some way to bother me,
it had to be about causing
some accident to happen.
So I went at daybreak
to make proper arrangements.
Reddy! I already saw you
this morning!
If you have to hide,
try to do a better job about it!
Darn! Shut up.
Sammy, you went through a lot of trouble
to have Reddy waiting in an ambush.
I'm sorry that I didn't fall for it!
Hmph. I don't need your pity!
So how was it, huh?
Now, do you see why I say that there's
no one around smarter than me?
Are you sure of that?
Huh? What do you mean?
I mean, Chatterer, this whole story
about the weasel looking for you,
was made up by Sammy
from the very beginning.
What?!
And you took the bait without thinking twice.
That's not something I'd call smart!
Besides, Chatterer, you think you're smarter
than Sammy and that you outwitted him.
But when you were about
to be caught by Blacky the Cat,
Sammy deliberately raised a ruckus
and distracted him to save you.
That's right. If you think that you
were able to escape on your own,
well, I don't think
that's being clever!
I'm sorry.
I apologize, Reddy.
Reddy…
Forgive me?
Look at Sammy,
after all that big talk.
I'm sorry.
Bragging is one of
the pettiest acts in the world.
Because of his bragging, Chatterer
ran into many frightening events.
Sammy didn't avoid
humiliation, either.
But one's nature
is hard to change, isn't it?
These two will probably
always continue to brag.
What a pair of troublemakers.
Autumn comes to the Green Forest
and to the Green Meadows.
Migratory birds fly to Purple Hills
and further, towards the South.
Rocky watches the birds every day,
as they disappear over the horizon.
He's starting to want to go on some distant
journey and see new places himself.
Rocky leaves the Green Forest
with but a small bundle on his shoulder.
Where is he headed?
The truth that not even Rocky
himself knows the destination.
Next time: “Rocky's Adventure”.
Be there to watch!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango