Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Reddy Fox and the Sheep
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
Peter, run a little slower, will you?
Beetles!
Wowee! This is the first time
I've seen this many.
Rocky, Polly, hurry!
– Amazing!
– Right?
If Jimmy saw this,
he'd sure be happy.
That's true, shall we tell him?
Okay, then I'll go tell him!
With my fast feet, it will be but an instant.
That guy, Jimmy,
should be very happy!
Whatever the case,
beetles are his favorite food!
That guy, Reddy,
napping right in my path…
This is bad…
If I pass by real quietly,
maybe Reddy won't notice.
Wait a minute!
That Reddy is pretty shrewd,
so he may just be pretending sleep,
waiting for me to pass by and then…
Gosh. Because of him,
I've wasted a lot of my time.
Boy, I'm hungry. I'd better go see if I can
find something to eat around here…
Hey, Jimmy!
Jimmy, I just found a place around here
where there's oodles and oodles of beetles.
Huh? Did you say “beetles”?
Yes, and it's not just
one or two beetles,
it's two hundred maybe,
or three hundred!
Where is it, Peter?
Please, tell me, tell me, please!
Follow me.
I'll take you there.
Sure.
Gosh, you sure are slow!
Can't you run any faster?
Don't be so impatient, Peter!
How awkward.
What's the matter, Peter?
There, there, beyond that tree.
Huh, beyond that tree?
Is that where the beetles are?
Huh?
Peter suddenly felt
like playing a trick.
Reddy was always
frightening or chasing him,
and Peter thought of a way
to pay him back a little.
That's right, Jimmy!
Beyond that stump there are tasty-looking
beetles, just swarming all over the clearing!
Really?
No, no! If you go at it recklessly,
they'll run away!
Go quietly up to that tree,
and when I give you a signal,
you leap out from this side of the tree.
Do you think you have all of that?
Yeah, I understand.
Tasty-looking beetles,
tasty-looking beetles.
All of you are my biggest friends.
Tasty-looking beetles,
tasty-looking beetles.
Go!
I did it!
What?! Who?…
W-What… What was that?
That's… That's my line!
J-J-Jimmy?
What are you doing?!
I was sleeping so peacefully,
why did you do such a thing?
Forgive me…
You little skunk.
Pardon me. There was supposed
to be a lot of beetles here.
Peter told me so, but when I leapt,
instead of beetles I found you.
Peter did?!
Oh, so it was you, Peter!
Peter, you darn rabbit!
Peter sure did a mean thing tricking me
that there were beetles.
Next time he won't
get off so easily!
I'm not one to be
caught by you, Reddy!
Once I crawl in the Briar Patch,
Reddy won't be able to enter!
I won't let you escape!
That Reddy, he's awfully
persistent today!
Peter is so late.
“My feet are fast, you know”,
is what he said, too.
He is the fastest one in the forest.
Here he comes!
Really, that Peter, how could he lie to me
like that, that there were so many beetles?
Jimmy!
Hi, Rocky and Polly!
Listen to this,
Peter's a terrible guy.
He lured me out saying
there were a lot of beetles,
then he tried to set up a fight
between Reddy and me.
Really?
But the beetles really are there.
Huh? What?
Then there really are some?
Peter must've decided to play a trick
on a whim, no doubt about it.
I see.
Never mind that guy.
Quickly, tell me where the beetles are,
please, tell me where they are.
Sure.
But now…
I wonder if Peter's alright.
Peter will be alright,
with those fast feet of his.
But please, you got to tell me
where the beetles are, please!
Oh, what do I do
if Bowser's around?!
That's it, I just got a good idea!
Oh? I can't see them…
Peter completely forgot that
he had been chased by Red until now.
He couldn't stop himself
trying to find out
how the chase between
Reddy and Bowser was going.
Good, it's quieting down now.
I'll wait here till night fall, then return home!
Get this, Reddy.
When chased by Bowser, don't do such
a stupid thing as running straight home!
Why?
You need to ask?
Reddy, try to think for yourself.
That's just like telling him
where our house is located!
We won't be able
to live here anymore.
I'll try to leave
Bowser in the lurch!
I'm scared, I'm scared, Granny!
Reddy!
Sammy?!
Reddy, looks like you're
in real trouble!
Say, Sammy, please, please don't perch
out there so conspicuously like that.
I'll be in trouble, you see!
Oh, I see!
But Reddy, you really
don't know anything.
Bowser's nearsighted!
In other words, anything
in the distance he sees as a blur.
So that's why
he relies on his nose.
Scared, eh, Reddy?
No matter where you flee to,
he'll absolutely smell you out!
Bowser's nose is really something.
Oh? Are you nervous?
What, me, afraid?
Who's afraid?
Well, Reddy, hang in there!
Sammy!
Were you watching, too?
Yeah! I was just talking to Reddy.
Looks like this time
he won't be able to run away.
No matter where Reddy hid,
Bowser would quickly smell him out.
From the looks of it,
he was going to be caught inevitably.
Is there no place
in the entire Green Meadows
in which he could hide
without Bowser finding him?
This shouldn't be far off.
Poor Reddy!
Alright!
Try catching me now!
Onward, onward!
Alright!
Onward!
Come on, come on!
Keep going!
By the time Bowser located the sheep,
he had completely lost Reddy.
Peter!
Are you alright?
What happened to Reddy?
Here, here!
Here is where we're different!
That dumb Reddy, he's never gonna
catch me, not in a million years!
By now, Bowser
should've already caught him.
What a delight!
Well, now the Green Forest
will be peaceful.
I mean, everybody
has been hurt by Reddy, and…
Hey, guys, you could
at least say “thanks”!
Are you sure Reddy won't be
coming around here anymore?
Rocky! Don't you
believe what I'm saying?
It's not like I don't believe you,
but who is behind you
there, Peter?
Huh? It's Reddy!
Reddy's not one to be caught
by the likes of Bowser!
Hop!
Come back!
Get back here!
Peter…
It's over!
Geez!
Darn that Peter.
Just you wait!
In our next adventure, Chatterer and Sammy
try to prove which one of the two is smarter.
Both of them think
very highly of themselves.
Neither of them
is willing to admit defeat.
They try to show their intellect
by deceiving the other party.
Rocky, Polly and Peter are watching
this silly contest in suspense.
Oh, dear! Looks like Sammy
sicced a hawk on poor Chatterer!
Look out!
Next time:
“Hang in There, Chatterer”.
Be there to watch!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango