Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Danny's Adventure
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
All the fruit
has started to turn red.
Maybe in three days,
they should be edible.
Danny!
Danny, what are you
so scared of?
It's just me, Danny.
Oh, it's you, Rocky!
I thought like
my heart was gonna burst.
Wow…
Danny, you're sure
some coward, aren't you?
That's right, I'm a coward.
It's hard not to be, when…
What's the matter
with you, Danny?
Hush! Be quiet.
Is that a hawk flying over there?
Yeah.
There's one flying over there.
But… He's gone now.
I'm going home now.
Wait, we're returning to the forest, too.
Let's go together.
My, how shocking!
Now that I've made it here,
I should be safe.
Thanks, both of you.
Thanks to you, I got home
much earlier than usual today.
But why do fraidy-cats like you venture
so far to such a strange place, huh?
I went to see when the currant fruit
growing there would be ready to eat.
But there are plenty of currants
available much closer.
But I love the fruit over there!
I just must have them, Rocky.
I want to eat them.
Hmm… Are they
really that good?
Well, they're so good that
they're like little pieces of heaven.
Do you see something?
Yeah, the hawk is flying again.
Oh?
Oh…
Bye-bye, guys!
Oh, Danny is such
a coward, really.
Come on, let's go.
Then, when Rocky said
“it's the hawk” and turned around,
Danny had already disappeared!
That's the way he is.
That Danny would be scared
of his own shadow!
There's no one
as cowardly as that guy.
But in my case,
I'm not afraid of anything.
That's right. Even I have too many days
passed without being chased by Reddy.
Believe me, I get lonely.
I feel sorry for animals
that have no courage.
If I was that scared,
I'd be better off dead.
Only yesterday, I risked my life
on a hazardous adventure.
And it was so much fun!
What kind of
an adventure was it?
Oh?
What's the matter, Rocky?
Hey, Chatterer, hurry up and tell
the story of your adventure!
I'll get to there,
don't be so impatient.
Rocky was thinking about Danny.
Why is Danny so cowardly?
And how can be he so timid
even when the others laugh at him?
Just how can he stay calm without
feeling embarrassed in the slightest?
Today, it should be
ripe enough to eat.
If I was smarter, I'd control myself
and wouldn't go after those fruit.
It's such a lot of trouble
to get them.
But they're just something else!
Oh, I can't win by speed alone.
I'd better use my head.
Alright!
I can get out of here!
He'll notice me pretty soon.
If he comes chasing me, he'll think
I've fled the other path this time.
Alright, then!
That was scary!
But I should be safe now.
Now, about Danny, the coward.
After such a frightening adventure,
one would think he'd go home.
But Danny proceeded towards
the spot with the fruit.
Ahh!
Oh, how boring.
Isn't anything
amusing happening?
Oh?!
Oh! There goes Danny, the coward!
I'm gonna go and tease him a little.
Danny… It's me!
Why did you do that, Chatterer?
My heart is in my throat.
Well, maybe I overdid it a bit.
But what is a coward like you
doing in a place like this?
I'm going to eat some more fruit.
Oh? You'd better not bother.
It's different for a brave
animal like me, though.
But when your heart gets in your throat at
the smallest thing, you won't live for long.
But I want to eat that fruit
more than anything!
Then, I will take you there.
I, Chatterer, who fears nothing at all!
Follow me!
N-No, it's okay.
I'd rather go by myself.
See you!
So be it.
Well, take care and get home
before it gets too dark!
Oh, darn!
What's this?
What in the world is he doing?
Aha, he tried to grab
something and failed.
It's my chance!
I'll get it in his place.
My life is saved.
But I'd better not leave yet.
It's Reddy!
What a fix! I hope he doesn't
notice that I'm in here.
That's funny. That hawk…
What in the world was he chasing?
There's nothing around…
Aha! So that's it.
It's in this can.
So he did find me, after all.
Well, Danny, what a funny place
for you to be hiding.
You know you can't escape
from me in there.
Now, are you ready, Danny?
How would you like to be eaten?
From the tail first?
Or maybe from the head?
Or shall I take my time
and eat one leg at a time?
The front or rear leg,
which do you think is tastier, Danny?
Ah! Ow-ow-ow!
Alright, I'll drag you out there!
Come out of there!
Ah! Ow-ow-ow!
You come outta there!
Come on out right now! If you don't,
I'll crush you and the can together!
Now!
That's funny…
It sounded strange.
It's empty!
Oh, I was so close!
That was too close.
That's the most frightened
I've been all my life.
But I must eat those fruit!
And so, Danny reached the red currant
bush and ate to his heart's content.
Hey! Rocky!
Hi, Chatterer.
What's happening?
Oh, nothing.
I just teased Danny a little.
Who, Danny?
Right. That fraidy-cat!
He was wandering about the Green Meadows,
saying he was going to get some fruit.
So I snug up at him
and yelled like this!
Oh, Chatterer…
That's going too far!
For a spineless guy like him,
that's the only way to make him brave.
Now, that I wonder about…
Hi, Grandfather Frog!
Chatterer, you mustn't
do such terrible tricks.
It was just a little fun.
What is just a little thing to you,
is a matter of life or death for Danny.
Furthermore, I don't consider
Danny a coward.
What happened to Danny next?
He went after the fruit.
I'm gonna see!
Wait, I'll go with you!
Maybe it was wrong to scare him,
but I can't believe that
Danny has courage.
Look? There's no fruit!
It must be Danny.
Danny's eaten all the fruit!
Furthermore, I don't consider
Danny a coward.
Rocky felt that he now understood
what Grandfather Frog had said.
Oh, dear! I wonder if it's okay
for such a little pup to walk alone?
This is dangerous!
Watch your step!
Now it's the hawk!
And Reddy, too.
Where did this
cute guy come from?
Rocky and Polly have
trouble looking after him.
By the way, even though this pup looks
like a little dog, actually, it's a coyote.
Everyone is surprised!
They don't know what to do at all.
Next time:
“Lost in the Green Forest”.
Be there to watch!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango