Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Grandfather Frog Leaves the Forest
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
Good morning, Grandfather!
Have you finished your breakfast
already, Grandfather?
Well, I have finished already, yes.
But, uh…
Why do you ask, Joe?
No reason.
But if you hadn't, maybe you'd
fancy this small fish I had caught.
But if you've eaten already…
Ha! Ribbit-ribbit.
Joe, if you're willing to divide that,
I'll be happy to accept your gift.
But, with such a friend
like you, Grandfather…
I can't present you with
such a dinky thing.
I'll throw it away.
Oh… What a waste!
Jerry, have you ever seen
such a greedy frog?
Why doesn't he pull it out
of his mouth and try again?
Hey, hey, hey!
What are you laughing at, guys?
Why, just look over there.
Oh, what a greedy Grandfather!
Thank you, Spotty.
A little while longer, and I would
have lost my breath and died.
Really, Grandfather,
you're just too greedy!
Grandfather Frog was respected
as a very wise and old grandfather.
But now that his blunder was been seen by
everyone, his reputation went down to zero.
Well, Grandfather Frog.
I've come again to gossip with you.
What's the matter? You've been
gazing at the sky for quite a while.
Grandfather Frog, it's me!
What is it?
Oh, it's you, Old Mr. Toad.
What do you mean, "What is it?".
I just came to see you.
You're not our Old Grandfather Frog today.
Whatever has happened?
I no longer want
to live here in this pool.
That's right. If you knew more about
this Wide World like I do…
You'd know that Joe the Otter would
never give you a fish for free like that.
Ribbit-ribbit.
Old Mr. Toad, you'd better return
to that Wide World of yours
and learn that it's best not to meddle
in the affairs of others.
Better not pretend to know,
when you haven't even seen any of it!
Ever since you've been able
to hippity-hop around,
ribbit-ribbit,
you've been in this Wide World.
But what good things did happen to you?
I'd like to hear about it.
Sure. Sure. I'll tell ya.
Listen!
Farmer Brown's son is coming!
Be careful! When that boy comes to the Smiling
Pool, he carries a pocket full of pebbles.
Grandfather Frog
was completely astonished.
His cousin, Old Mr. Toad, was
really friendly with the human child.
Grandfather Frog had been
taught a good lesson.
Grandfather Frog spent a sleepless night
thinking about what he had seen.
Eventually, morning had come.
Ribbit-ribbit.
Ribbit-ribbit!
Okay. I'll do that and show them!
What… What are you doing?
I'm taking off.
Where… where to, Grandfather?
I'm thinking of going to see for myself
just what the Wide World is like.
Eh? Don't do it, Grandfather.
It's such a foolish thing to do.
Really, Grandfather!
It's just too much for an old frog like you
to go out into the Wide World!
If cousin Toad can go out into the
Wide World and stand up alone, I can too.
Old Mr. Toad is only half as smart as I am,
you know. I'm going out there, too!
I'm going… there!
I must go!
News, terrible news! News!
Hey, Sammy!
Another one of your "big" events?
No kidding, this time
it's really a big event.
Grandfather Frog has left
in a big journey by himself!
What? Grandfather Frog has?
Let's go!
Okay.
I sure miss water… Oh?
Hey! Hey, wait a minute,
that's not polite!
Ah, it's over!
Rocky!
He's here!
Grandfather is here!
Grandfather…
What's happened? Is he dead?
I'm still alive.
What a frightening experience!
My gosh…
You really scared us!
By the way, why are you here?
My, Grandfather, we rushed here hoping
to stop you from taking such a long journey.
That's right, Grandfather! After all,
traveling alone is too much for you.
Mind your own business.
Please go home.
But… Grandfather…
Until I see the Wide World,
I will absolutely not give up my journey.
Then, don't blame us if you have
another frightening experience.
What's there to be scared of?
There, just a little while ago,
I was careless, that's all… I'm off!
Don't tell us later
we didn't warn you!
Here's a nice shady spot!
Hm. That spot seems a lot cooler.
This was a trap, set up by Tom,
to rid the fields of wild rats.
This is the bullfrog that
I always see at the Smiling Pool…
To be caught in a mouse trap…
Now, Tom was really
just only playing around.
He simply wanted to show everyone
the frog that he'd caught in the place of a rat.
Hey! Wait a minute, come back!
You can't just leave me like this!
Even a frog has rights, you know!
Funny… The mouse trap is gone.
Grandfather…
What on earth happened to him?
It's very unlikely that
with Grandfather's legs,
he could come all the way this far.
Rocky, look over there.
Oh… Grandfather's been caught!
What are we gonna do, Rocky?
Bowser!
So, it was you…
Water? Ribbit-ribbit!
How wonderful, my own private pool!
Ribbit-ribbit!
It's too slippery for me
to climb out.
Say, Rocky, what are we
going to do now?
Rocky, did you find Grandfather?
Well… We did, but he's caught in there
and we're not sure what to do about it.
I'll just go and
look over the situation!
Well, Grandfather, what is it like
to live in the Wide World, huh?
You got business here, Sammy?
It's nothing.
I was just passing by.
But everyone seem worried
and was searching for you.
Listen, Sammy. Don't tell anyone
that I'm caught in a fix like this.
But are you sure you are okay?
Will you be able to climb out?
Don't worry about me!
I can take care of myself, alright.
Oh, dear.
Grandfather can be
so stubborn sometimes.
If the word gets out that he had to be saved,
he'll probably lose face, you see?
Sammy, it still is a secret
among us, isn't it?
Of course it is.
But how are we going to save him?
Bowser, the watch dog, and Blacky the Cat
are both still there, you know?
Hmm… For now, let's wait.
We'll wait until they leave.
I shouldn't have spoken
so strongly to Sammy…
Hey, what is this?
Must be the wind around here…
What a shame!
Just a little bit more to go.
You weren't discovered
by Grandfather, were you?
Of course not.
He thought the wind was playing tricks.
It was quite an idea of Rocky's.
If all goes well, we can save Grandfather
without hurting his pride.
Terrible! Grandfather
will be eaten up!
Well, Blacky, did you find something good?
Come here and show it to me.
Oh? It's the frog that
I had found yesterday.
What happened? Is he dead?
Look at you, you're still alive!
Blacky, I'm going to take this.
Bowser! Come here, boy!
Bring the bucket!
Grandfather Frog by now,
had abandoned all hope.
I'll never see
the Smiling Pool again.
Then, after quite some time…
The whistling stopped.
All was silent.
Grandfather waited,
listening intently,
but not a sound was heard.
Wait… This is…
Isn't this the Smiling Pool?
Ribbit-ribbit!
Oh, Grandfather?
When did you get back?
Why… just this minute.
Everyone was very worried.
You must have suffered a lot.
They shouldn't have.
The Wide World is just fine!
Not as bad, really,
as I thought it might have been.
Something wrong?
N-No, it's nothing.
Well… Any questions?
Reddy and Granny Fox tried several times
to get Old Man Coyote out of the forest,
but Old Man Coyote always
outsmarted Granny thus far.
Granny is getting frustrated.
One day, Reddy
comes home out of breath.
He reports that he has found the place
where Old Man Coyote takes naps.
Granny, listening to this revelation without
a word, comes up with a wonderful plan.
Who do you think will be smarter,
Granny or Coyote?
Next time:
"Granny Fox and the Coyote".
Be there to watch!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango