Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
What's going on?
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Jerry, his small head cocked
to one side, is roaming
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
back and forth along the bank
of the Laughing Brook.
What is he thinking about?
What could be wrong?
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
What?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Funny, sure funny!
Strange, strange...
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Jerry, what's so strange?
Oh, Johnny!
These eyes of mine, please see
if there's something wrong with them!
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Something happened to your eyes?
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Nothing's wrong with them.
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
No-no, what I want to know is whether or not
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
my eyes can distinguish objects clearly or not.
Here, do you see that pace on the bank,
over there?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Johnny, my eyes, my head too
is become funny!
That's not so!
It's just like he said, the river water
is diminishing, is rapidly going down!
That's right!
What is it all about?
Terrible!
This is awful!
Jerry, the Muskrat
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
Huh, sure is sultry!
It's times like this that I envy those
of the Smiling Pool,
for they can quickly cool off in the water.
Well, good morning all of you
of the Smiling Pool!
Hey...
Grandfather Frog, what is this?
If this isn't a dream, the world is turning
topsy-turvy, I don't know what's what!
- Hey...!
- Grandfather...
- ...all gone, the water's gone from the lake!
- What is this?
I can't understand it.
Even during midsummer,
when the forest streams dried up
there's never been a time when the water
of this lake has ever disappeared!
Grandfather... Grandfather...
How was it over there at the Big River?
Nothing wrong there.
So the water is dissappeared only from
the Smiling Pool and the Laughing Brook.
And in these conditions, there's no alternative
but to move to the Big River, right?
Are you moving?
Poor me, my house is visible, my secret
underwater pass can be discovered,
I can't live here anymore!
Wait, wait, you can't simply throw away
your homestead of many comfortable years!
- We can't live in a waterless lake or river!
- No...
Keep calm everyone!
Before rushing off, the thing to do is
to determine why the water disappeared!
Right, that's right!
Thanks to the water disappearing,
we can see the bottom of the pool!
This is amusing!
Jerry, what are you looking for down there?
I thought maybe there might be a hole
at the bottom of the pool!
Can't be a stupid reason such as that!
And Grandfather, you'll figure it out?
Well...
I'm giving it a good think
over here in my head...
Hmm...
Hmm... Johnny, what's the matter,
what's the reason?
Hmm...
What do you mean by that?
That's it!
The reason is the Laughing Brook!
The Laughing Brook?
Get this: the water running from the Laughing
Brook makes up the Smiling Pool, you see?!
That flow of water stopped. That's why
there's no water in the pool!
That's it!
Something like this,
why didn't I notice it sooner?
That's right!
Paddy's dam is located up river...
Maybe...
Johnny, Johnny!
- What's up, Sammy?
- What happened?
Grandfather has started out
with the four others!
- Started out?
- Are they moving to the Big River?
They've gone up the Laughing Brook
to see Paddy.
If they meet with Paddy, they'll find out
the reason, according to Grandfather.
- Johnny?
- That's Grandfather alright!
They should be climbing about
the old log bridge about now.
Spotty should be the tail end,
but this race seems to become interesting!
My-my, here they come!
For these five, to be in the water
would be easy and a pleasure,
but today, they must walk uphill along
the waterless riverbed, so it's quite a job.
In the lead, the slim but nimble Harry.
Next, Joe the Otter with legs so short
that he almost doesn't seem to have any.
Behind him comes Jerry, the muskrat.
At swimming, he's a real expert.
And then leaping along, Grandfather Frog.
And now... oh my, the slowest one
is poor Spotty the Turtle,
walking along with his house on his back.
And he just can't go very fast.
Hey, Harry, don't rush so!
Joe, you're the one who should wait a little!
Jerry, do you intend to leave
this old one behind?
I'm getting out of breath!
Well, they're trying, they're really trying,
believe me!
At times like this,
if only I had wings!
OK, everyone! Buck up, Spotty!
Don't loiter, keep on moving!
I'll be back to cheer you all again!
Grandfather, we heard from Sammy.
So if it's Paddy you're going to see,
we'll go and meet him for you,
if you like.
Sure we'll go for you.
Appreciate your concern, but this matter
concerning the brook and the pond
we decided it should be settled
by the five of us.
Hey, Jerry, walk a little slower!
Oh, water, how nice!
Oh, is that all?!
Grandfather... better not overdo it!
Are they coming?
At that rate it's quite a struggle.
The riverbed is like a heavily pebbled road,
isn't it?
They're all just probably puffing along.
Let's go ahead and look for them!
Alright, let's do that!
You think they're alright?
They're all strong in the water,
but to climb a dry riverbed, you know...
We're about half way to Paddy's dam, aren't we?
Yeah, can't see anyone yet...
Although Grandfather Frog had said that
they would settle their own problems themselves,
still, Johnny and Polly were worried.
Now, our resolute five climbing
along the dry riverbed
still had not come even half way
to Paddy's dam.
Uh-huh? Oh, yeah, somebody's coming!
Yeah, somebody's coming!
It looks like Spotty!
But... but Spotty shoud've been the slowest!
Where are the others?
Anyway, my feet hurt,
and Spotty isn't here, so I...
...I'll just take one quick snooze.
Spotty?
Oh... Go ahead, OK, you go first,
I'll easily catch up to that slowpoke.
These shellfish are so delicious!
Pretty soon now!
- Oh, that's Paddy's dam!
- Paddy's dam?
Oh, this dam, this is a new dam,
where is the old dam?
What's the matter?
- It's over there!
- Oh! That's right!
Well, if it isn't Johnny and Polly together!
I haven't seen you two in a while!
Actually, Paddy, we beg you...
You've got time, haven't you?
How's this one: this dam's gonna be
a really fine one!
I nearly 60 % completed now, and in
one more haul, I'm going to take a break,
so why don't you go and sit over there?
So that's it! The new dam is the reason!
That's why the Laughing Brook's water
has been stopped up, you see!
So now we know the reason.
Paddy the Beaver, when he found
a spot that he liked,
would build and rebuild a dam just like this.
Johnny, we must inform
Grandfather Frog about this!
No one...
What's this?
What's the matter?
- It's Spotty!
- That's right, Spotty!
Spotty, you're the first to arrive!
Well, I'm simply amazed!
So slowpoke Spotty is number one, eh?
Sammy, what are the other guys doing?
Have you seen them?
The energetic guys are still downriver playing,
sleeping and generally wasting their time.
Hmm, nothing we can do.
They sure were energetic in the beginning!
Why, look, over there, Paddy is building
another new dam!
Well, what a nice one this is!
We can't just be admiring it! Because of that,
the water to the Laughing Brook has stopped!
I thought for sure that I'll be here first!
Who cares about such a race?
More important, we found out the reason
for the stopped up Laughing Brook!
That Paddy, he's a mean guy!
He built a new dam and made it so
the water wouldn't flow down our brook!
Oh, Paddy!
Hi, Harry, Joe and Jerry!
Altogether now!
Paddy!
You-you're a meanie!
Because of you doing this,
do you realize how much
the people of the Laughing Brook and
Smiling Lake have suffered all around here, huh?
Such a thing! I didn't know that
I was doing anything wrong!
Don't try to fool us!
Because you built this new dam,
the water has disappeared from the Laughing
Brook and the Smiling Lake, you meanie!
Oh, things aren't that bad...
There's enough water!
It was turned off just for a minute!
Nothing to get so mad about!
Break the dam and let the water out!
That's right, break it right away!
Paddy, it's everyone's request.
Now, please listen to us.
I won't!
You big bum!
No!
Paddy, do you mean to say that you don't care
what happens to the people
of the Laughing Brook?
I'm not saying that!
In three days the dam will be filled!
The water will spill over, and
the Laughing Brook will flow as before!
- We can't wait three days!
- That's right!
Why don't you say something, Paddy?
If the Laughing Brook is a necessity
for you people,
the dam is a necessity for me!
For me, to protect myself
against Reddy and Coyote
a house inside the dam is a must.
Unless the water level outside the dam
is not constant,
the rooms inside will always be soggy.
That's why when building a dam, the water
level is maintained at a constant height.
Such stuff doesn't concern us!
That's right!
This brook doesn't belong to you alone!
Now hurry and break it up!
You break up the dam!
J-J-Jerry!
If you want to build a dam, that's up to you!
But if the water stops running
in the Laughing Brook
because of that the Smiling Lake will disappear!
Paddy... if that happens,
everyone must abandon their beloved lake
and move to the Big River!
Paddy, can you really understand that?
No...
What?!
Jerry, I'm bigger than you are
and I have strength too!
If I say that I'm absolutely
against breaking up the dam,
what can you do about it?
Well, I think...
Huh, what about it?
OK, Jerry.
Even if I say absolutely not,
do you still intend to break up the dam?
Well, you're big and strong,
so you can do what you like,
but we've lived for a long time in this forest,
and we have to abandon our beloved lake
and everything else and move away!
Well, I probably won't be able to do a thing
and lose to you,
but there comes a time when
you got to stand up for what is right,
and what you're doing is unfair, it's unfair
the most unfair thing I ever heard of!
So right now, I want the water
in this dam let loose!
Jerry, you are indeed my dear cousin!
Oh, I lose!
No, I feel fortunate to have
such a dignified cousin.
I understand now.
I'll break up the dam, let the water run free,
and I'll be satisfied with the old dam.
You mean that? Really?
Yeah.
Paddy...
That's it, it's wonderful, for a moment there
I wondered what was going to happen!
Isn't it wonderful, Jerry?
Yeah, Paddy is my cousin.
He'll listen to reason. After all,
for his size, there's no more valiant guy.
This guy...!
Hey, Spotty, there's no need to hide
your head in the corner anymore!
OK! I'm off to let the forest people
know about this joyful news!
News, I've got news!
Water-water, the water is ready!
Water! Water's come back to the Laughing Brook!
Thank you, Paddy!
Hereafter, no matter how much
it may storm or rain,
I'll be here, regulating the waters
of the Laughing Brook!
You don't have to worry from now on!
Thank you!
Spotty, now let's go home!
- Everyone seems so happy!
- Yeah!
Grandfather, this time was easier, hey?
Yeah, but I can't swim nearly as fast
as Harry or Jerry can swim, you know?
Well, now the Laughing Brook
is laughing all over!
Now it's really the Laughing Brook,
it really is the Laughing Brook!
Going up on foot we had sore feet,
but going back with water,
that's not going to happen!
Hey, on the return trip,
let's make a friendly trip together!
No racing! Don't leave the elderly!
Hey, the current is too strong!
Can't... flow... myself...
I'm gonna... hit... that... rock!
Oh... my goodness!
Oh... help... save me!
Oh... someone!
Spotty...!
You... you saved me!
Beavers are never satisfied
with building just one dam,
but must be building dams
continuously throughout their life.
From parent to child, from child
to grandchild continuously adding on,
until there is even one dam
almost 600 meters long.
After seing everyone off,
Paddy the Beaver realized
that the next time he build a dam
he must be careful not to stop
the flow of the water completely.
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango