FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Longlegs the Heron"
What a beautiful summer afternoon,
and all my friends are sleeping!
Ah, they all look like
old people taking naps!
What shall I do?
Ah, hi, Chatterer!
Oh, what a beautiful house you've built,
you seem to be a great architect!
It's my summer house.
Don't bother me, please, Sammy.
Mmm?
Well, despite your mood,
I am still admiring
your wonderful summer house.
You are a wonderful builder.
And you also think ahead.
You have a good provision of nuts
for the winter.
And, besides that,
you also have a summer house.
You deserve all my respect!
Listen, Chatterer,
do you wanna play?
The weather is wonderful.
Come, let's go and play!
- Please, go away, you good-for-nothing!
- Ah, you genius.
You'll get old soon.
I just want to take a nap.
That's all. Go away!
All right. I'm leaving, I'm leaving.
But to be honest,
- ...I don't like that house so much.
- I don't mind what you think!
Go away! Go away!
Oh, how boring!
There's no fun here.
I wish something happened.
- Such a lovely breeze...
- Oh, music to my ears!
Harry!
- Harry!
- Huh?
What is it, what is it?
Oh, yes!
He's sleeping so peacefully
that he hasn't even seen the flies.
No wonder, he's fat!
I'm afraid those two are planning something
and it surely is something evil.
Let's hope it's something amusing at least.
- Mr. Longlegs, where are you?
Mr. Longlegs?
Oh, they're calling
the dangerous Mr. Longlegs the Heron!
He is a relative of mine from high society.
Mr. Longlegs! Mr. Longlegs!
Watch where you are going!
Listen, Jerry, have you seen
Mr. Longlegs the Heron?
Yes, I just saw him down the river.
Was he as hungry as usual?
You know his stomach is always empty.
That's why I hide from him.
Guys, it's not funny.
What's going on? What's going on?
What are you laughing at?
- Stop asking!
Me, asking?
- Hello, Mr. Longlegs!
Hello, Sir.
If you don't reply
you're probably not hungry anymore.
Please, don't go away, Mr. Longlegs.
You have long legs, Sir, yes, Sir.
Silly animal!
We have already proven that
Mr. Longlegs ate so much this morning,
that he is not in the mood of answering, right?
Indeed, I think so.
I'm so hungry I can hardly see.
I beg you please go away, or I won't
catch my lunch, and I will not allow that.
That is what we would like to talk about:
your lunch.
About your lunch, talk.
- He's not answering.
- Not answering, no.
And we thought you were going
to have the lunch of your life!
Yes, that's true.
Because a while ago, we saw
Old Grandfather Frog sleeping peacefully.
Old Grandfather Frog?!
No, forget about it, Harry.
And let's tell Black the Cat.
He will be interested.
- Mmm.
- Hm...?
Well, let's go.
Listen, wait,
don't go!
- What did he say, Harry?
- He said: "Wait, don't go!"
Please, don't go.
We've been friends for a long time.
Long time.
Of course you are our friend.
By the way,
where is Grandfather Frog sleeping?
It's just that I've never seen him asleep.
I think it must be a delici...,
sorry, pleasing, view.
Where is he?
Indeed. Specially today
that he's eaten many flies.
His belly looks like a balloon.
Tasty! So he is well fed.
He must be delicious.
Eh? What did you say?
No, I didn't say anything.
I was just thinking
how lucky some friends are
to taste such delicious dishes.
That's right.
He ate his belly full on flies
- ...and then he ate more.
- Please, stop!
So he is asleep?
And... where can I find him?
In the middle of the pool.
Oh! In the middle of the pool!
- So you are not going?
- Not going, so?
Well, he is asleep, right?
I will go later.
Don't you think it's unpolite
to watch a sleeping...
...friend?
Uh-hm, it must be terrible
for a gentleman like you.
See you, my friend Heron!
- See you later!
- Bye!
See you!
This is getting interesting...
The eat-and-not-be-eaten game.
I don't want to miss the ending,
I won't miss it!
He's still asleep.
It will get interesting soon.
There comes our long-legged friend!
Mmmm, there he is.
Well, there's no need to hurry.
As soon as Old Grandfather Frog
starts snoring, I'll eat him up.
Grandfather will get a surprise!
What will happen if Grandfather
doesn't see the heron on time?
No problem. We'll scream to warn him.
I think that will be enough,
don't you think?
Enough it will be.
No need to worry.
In case of danger, we'll warn him.
Long-legged birds are like snakes,
skillful and patient.
If the tasty dish is worth it,
they wait motionless
until they catch their prey.
So, as soon as Old Grandfather makes a move,
the heron will catch him right away.
Listen...
- ...this is not fun at all.
- Not fun at all.
This is really boring.
I'm going somewhere else.
Tired of waiting,
our friends are leaving without considering
the risk Grandfather Frog runs
of being eaten by the evil heron.
Johnny, Johnny, wake up!
Huh? What?
You, too, Polly Chuck, wake up!
What's going on, Gentle Breeze?
You'd better hurry up and go home.
- Why?
Whitetail the Marshhawk is hungry
and is flying over the forest.
- How terrible! How scary!
Don't worry but be careful.
I'm telling all of your friends.
I must hurry,
see you!
- Thank you very much, Gentle Breeze!
Everyone, please, hide!
Whitetail the Marshhawk is coming!
Be patient.
He will leave soon.
Hide yourselves away for a while.
Gentle Breeze hurried
through the Green Forest,
warning the little animals
of an unpleasant visitor.
The old Marsh Hawk is hungry,
and is flying over the forest
in search of food.
Look, it's Harry and Joe.
Lovely water!
Look, they're having so much fun.
Let's go and see.
No, wait!
It's safe here under the trees.
The Marsh Hawk can't see us.
- Oh!
Where have they gone?
If Longlegs had scared Grandfather Frog,
it would've been more fun, wouldn't it?
- All our effort to lure that ugly bird!
- Indeed!
Harry! Joe!
It's Johnny.
And Polly, too.
What were you saying
about Old Grandfather Frog?
The thing is Grandfather Frog
and Longlegs are in the pool.
The two of them?
- Just the two of them?
- Yes, that's right.
We did a lot to bring them together.
Why would you do that, Joe?
Well...
...we expected Grandfather
to get scared as he saw Longlegs,
- ...right, Harry?
- Longlegs see.
Don't you think it would be much fun?
But what if Longlegs the Heron
eats Grandfather?
Did you think we
wouldn't warn him in advance?
Nothing's going to happen
if we tell him on time.
- Nothing's going to happen, no.
- We just want to have fun.
- Oh...!
- Alright!
But suppose you cannot warn him on time?
What if Grandfather is eaten?
What did you say, Polly?
Polly is right.
Did you think about the danger,
that Grandfather might be eaten?
Harry, we didn't consider that we might fail
and Grandfather would become
the heron's lunch.
The heron's lunch? Oh!
My goodness!
That's terrible!
Indeed, and it would be our fault.
It would be horrifying.
Let's go! Let's go!
He's waiting until I fall asleep.
I'll wait until he's asleep.
Patience, patience. Don't  hurry.
That's the most important thing.
The marsh hawk realised it was pointless
to fly over the Green Forest.
I'm wasting my time. I'll go to the pool
and if there's nothing there,
I'll have to go to the Big River
to search for food.
The hawk's sharp sight
took Longlegs by surprise.
He's searching for something,
but what can it be?
A frog!
I don't like frogs,
but it will calm my hunger.
I'll have to seize it from the heron!
Johnny! Whitetail the Marshhawk
- ...is flying over the Smiling Pool.
- Oh, no!
- Oh!
Grandfather! The hawk!
- What do you want?
- What do you want? Don't bother me!
So you wanted to steal my yummy frog from me?
Why do you think it belongs to you?
Because I've been waiting for it
for a long time, and it's mine!
Forget it. It will be mine!
- Leave it!
- It was mine, I said!
Croak!
It seems I belong to somebody, but...
...don't know to whom or what for?
It's mine, I say!
- It was mine!
- I'll pluck all your feathers!
We'll see!
- I've come from far away!
- The frog is mine,
and I was waiting for it for long,
and it's mine, and it belongs to me!
Croak.
Oh, that was close!
What a scare!
I'm terrified.
Terrified I am.
I can't be eaten easily.
Thanks for warning me!
I never thought the hawk
would be interested in me.
Yes, we hurried to be on time.
You were all concerned about me.
Thank you, thank you!
- You're welcome. It was nothing.
- Nothing, no.
Shame on you! You are silly.
You're completely right, Polly.
What are you talking about, Polly?
Nothing. Besides, Joe and Harry regret it.
Uh-hm.
Good heavens! What happened here?
Come on! Tell me!
What are you waiting for? I'm curious.
My God, there are feathers everywhere!
What a mess!
- What happened here?
- I don't know.  Did anything happen here?
Do you want to keep a secret?
Come on, tell me what happened, I'm curious.
Well, I don't intend to keep a secret, but...
- ...it's nothing special.
- What, what?
Croak.
Oh!
Stop beating around the bush and tell me all.
I can't wait any longer.
Polly, you're talkative. Tell me.
- Nothing happened.
- No, nothing happened.
Seriously, everything was quiet.
Hm, you're not pleased with the answer,
are you, Sammy?
Well, not completely.
To be honest, I don't believe you.
- I'll have to live with a question mark.
- That's right, Sammy.
- Well, see you.
- Bye!
Croak.
I'm so angry!
Well, they say, "If you want to have fun,
be there on time!"
Translation: Mónica
Subtitle: South Wind Subs