FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Danny in the snow"
The snow has finally started
to fall in the Green Forest.
Johnny and Polly are both
snuggled in their home.
And so the forest has become as silent
as in the middle of the night.
But there are animals that love the snow.
Peter Rabbit is one of them.
Peter... today is the day...!
I'm gonna catch him...!
Johnny, Johnny, wake up!
Come on, it's so much fun outside!
I can't... I can't play outside.
I'm preparing for the winter.
It's a lot of fun to play "hide and go seek"
in the snow. Come on, let's go!
Play in the snow?
Has it snowed that much already?
Yes, it has, in the Green Meadow.
Let's go!
Oh, no-no-no!
All the more reason why I can't.
- Hey, isn't that Peter?
- That's right, it's Peter!
Hey, Peter, what's the matter,
why the big rush?
- Oh, run and hide, it's Reddy, he's chasing me!
- It's Reddy?
Pfew!
That Reddy, he's gone.
Oh, you be careful now, Danny.
- Someday, you'll be chased by Reddy, too.
- Me? No problem!
I'm a coward. But a coward who uses
his head all the time!
Yeah... I use my head too.
Well... I guess I go run around
in the snow at the Green Meadow.
I don't know. You'd better be careful.
You never know. Reddy might still be near.
No problem. As long as there's some snow,
I'm not afraid of Reddy!
Hm! For a shrimp, that guy sure does talk big.
He's the kind of guy who oughta get caught
by Reddy. Don't you think so, Johnny?
Danny, don't get too smart now!
- Bye!
- Be careful now!
Now, where shall I dig a tunnel today?
One. Two.
Oh...!
Johnny should've come with me. Yay!
Well. Now it's this way!
Danny really loves playing in the snow.
He loves digging tunnels, everywhere.
This is what Danny loves doing the best.
He's happy under the snow and on top of the snow.
Whatever he's doing, the snow is his life.
He loves digging tunnels.
Hm...!
That Peter, where could he have hidden?
Today of all days I thought I'd catch him.
Sure makes a fast getaway.
Hm. I wonder where he could have... Oh!
Hm...!
I let Peter escape, but Danny is here.
I'm in luck today...!
Darn it! A little more. I'll catch him.
Yoohoo!
Here I am, here I am!
You little rascal!
Reddy, here I am, here I am!
That's it!
As Granny always says, "At a time
like this, one must use one's head."
Let's see. Pretend that I'm fooled by him,
and then, when Danny approaches, grab him.
Curses! He's not here!
He should have hidden here!
Yeah, where'd he go?
Reddy's a big fool!
Ah! Danny, you little shrimp!
Come out of there!
Alright. I'll get a little closer
and tease him.
He's coming. Where is he coming from?
He's still sitting in the same place.
Hey... Reddy, Reddy!
This way. This way, Reddy!
Darn it, darn it, darn it, darn it!
Bet you can't catch me, bet you can't catch me!
Reddy, over here, over here!
Darn it, Danny!
Where did he go?
This way! This way!
Reddy, come get me! What's the matter,
you slowpoke, tired already?
Darn it! Remember, one day I'll catch you
and I'm going to swallow you up whole!
Silly fox!
You been pretty lucky there, Danny.
But someday, I'm gonna get you, yes, I will.
Curses, curses!
Didn't catch me, didn't catch me!
Reddy the Fox,
Is smart and crafty.
But I'm a meadow mouse,
So I'm much smarter.
Reddy the Fox,
Is such a slowpoke.
Oh...!
"Reddy the Fox..."
Hm... Letting Peter escape.
Even letting Danny escape.
What is going on?
Granny... Danny was fleeing about
in the under-the-snow tunnel
and that's not easy to catch.
Outta this hole and outta that hole.
You just could not tell a thing.
He had tunnels in the snow
covering the entire Green Meadow,
where he could hide.
Hm. Well, that's the time to use
your head, for heaven's sake.
But I-I did use it. B-b-but Danny
is so quick and, uh,
and first of all there were
too many tunnels... Impossible!
Ah, well, today's goings on
can't be helped.
But tomorrow's another day.
I'll go with you.
Huh? You will, Granny, you will?
Yes. Danny Meadowmouse is skilled
in hiding out in tunnels.
You by yourself would be made fool of so easily.
Did Danny look apetising for a good meal?
Yes... Round and plump
and really apetising...
Hm...? That so?
Well, tomorrow we should find
ourselves with a feast.
Tomorrow we'll be early.
Now, go to sleep!
Okay, good night now, Granny!
Good night.
Danny, unknowingly,
tired from his runabout with Reddy,
was sleeping quite soundly.
That Reddy. I fooled him so much yesterday.
I'm sure he'll be back today
to play some more.
That Reddy, he's coming!
- Uh-uh-hm.
- Oh...
Uh-oh, he's brought grandma!
Hm...
Looks like it's gonna be fun today!
What in tarnation are you doing, Granny?
Well... smelling about like this
should tell you immediately
which hole or tunnel Danny's in, see?
Maybe you're right. But beneath, there's
a tunnel that he can go wherever he wants to.
That's why I say you're such a dunce.
At such a time, listen to the sound
of his feet, like this.
Is that so?
You're my Granny, alright!
Old Granny is doing some thinking,
isn't she?
Can Danny do as well
as he did yesterday?
Can you tell, just by smelling for a scent?
Shocks, just a little bit more
and I would've caught him!
Ah, so there's how you do it. Hm...
Yikes!
Oh! Oh!... Oh! Oh!
Ah...
Running about is no good.
I'll stay here for a little while.
Ah, that Danny, trying to fool me
by staying still in the snow down there.
But I won't let him.
Reddy, whereabouts did you last hear
Danny's footsteps in the tunnel?
Well, it sounded like he was coming
this way, so he must have...
Alright. Wherever it is,
jump down and scare Danny.
Then Danny will be startled and start running.
Okay.
Oh!
Hm...
Oh!... Oh, oh!
Reddy, he went that way!
Oh!... Oh!
Ah! Oh! Ah!
Ah, ah, ah...
Reddy, he's going that way.
Seems like Danny is getting pretty tired.
Mm... Okay. This time...
If only there was some place I could stop.
Hey, Granny, what's the matter?
Danny is running,
he should have been tired by now.
Danny suddenly remembered an old post,
wrapped with barbed wire.
He had dug a tunnel leading to there
in order to store a little food.
He thought that place he would be very safe.
If only could get there fast enough.
Ah. Ah...
Granny, I'll bet he stopped here.
Uh-huh, he seems to have stopped
just when I jumped.
- Shall I scare him like I did before?
- No, wait...
Well, why?
Somehow, I think it was about here,
where there was an old fallen post
wrapped with lots of barbed wire.
- No problem, I'm gonna try it.
- No, wait!
Yeah!
Yay!
Oh! Oh!
That's why I told you to wait, didn't I?
Now, you cut your foot on the barbed wire.
It hurts! Ow! Ah!
Don't just lie there, crying
like a baby. Lick the cut!
I'll just stay here quietly for a while.
Then maybe, if I'm lucky, Granny
and Reddy will give up and go home.
- Granny, what are you gonna do?
- Catch that Danny, of course!
But... Isn't it too difficult?
Too difficult? If we give up now...
That's it! There's another way...
Hm. This looks like the closest entrance
and exit spot from where Danny is now.
- Reddy, come here!
- What, Granny?
Throw snow on me until I'm hidden.
Cover you?
That's right.
Danny won't be able to resist much longer,
that's what I'm aming for.
Ah... so that's it!
I'll do it.
You can go home, take care
of your cut foot, and wait for me.
Uh-huh.
Hm. Sure is quiet.
Wonder if they've gone...
Wonder if they're really gone?
Besides, I can't stay quiet like this forever.
It's cold! And Granny, she's given up.
Looks like they finally gave up, tired.
I wonder if that mound was there before...
Or maybe that strong North Wind
played a trick and created one.
Hm...
Huh? Oh!
Oh!
So... So that's what it is!
Danny is not to be fooled by such tricks!
Granny! Granny!
No use hiding there and trying to fool me.
I know!
Bye-bye!
W-w-w-wait!
Oh! Oh!
Oh, if it wasn't for that North Wind,
I'd have had Danny!
Oh... Oh, I think I'm getting a chill.
This is irritat...
Come, let's play in the snow,
in the snow, in the snow,
Come and let's play in the snow...
Who's gonna be caught?
Come, let's play in the snow,
in the snow, in the snow,
Come and let's play in the snow...
Who's gonna be caught?
Come, let's play in the snow,
in the snow, in the snow,
Come and let's play in the snow...
Who's gonna be caught?
Ah! Help, help, let me go, let me go!
Help!
Please, help me!
Let me go!
Danny was overjoyed
that he had fooled Reddy and Granny,
but he had forgotten that he must
always be on guard, even at night,
against his number one enemy, the owl.
Did he drop something? I wonder.
Ah...! Oh. Oh.
It's cold!
Who... Who's that?
Danny?
Is that you, Danny?
Oh, what a terrible wound, Danny!
Johnny, Johnny! Something terrible
has happened, open the door, Johnny!
Oh, my gosh, another visitor.
Just wait a minute!
I said something wrong to Danny. And when
I went to his place he still wasn't home.
And in the Green Meadow there are tracks
of Reddy and Granny, so... I... I...
- If it's Danny, he's here!
- Huh?
Yeah... He's pretty bad.
- Danny?
- Uh-huh.
Peter, somehow this is a punishment.
A punishment?
This morning, fooling Reddy and Granny,
I forgot about the owl.
Oh... I'm sorry.
I should have never wished you bad luck, Danny.
I... I'm sorry!
Thank you.
Thank you for worrying about me.
But what can I do now?
I can't even walk.
But there's nothing to worry about...
You can stay here until your wounds are healed.
But...
As for food, I'll bring all you want
from your storeroom.
Thanks to the help of Danny's friends,
he'll be alright.
But Danny has learned a valuable lesson
we all should remember.
When playing tricks on your enemies,
you're bound to get hurt.
Subtitle: South Wind Subs