FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"Peter the imitator"
Chip! Chip!
Let's play, let's play! Hey, hey!
Chip, look at this, look at this, it's fun!
Look at me!
Oh...
Oh... Hey...!
Hey.
Hey, Chip, come on, let's play.
Look at this now. Hey...
How do you like this?
Saw it?
Oh... come on Chip, let's play!
Hey, look at this.
Isn't this neat?
Come on, Chip, let's play! Oh, boy!
Sorry, Peter, I don't have time. Work, work,
work, gotta work, gotta work, gotta work.
Busy, busy, busy. We've got to get ready
for winter. We've got to work, work, work. Busy.
Oh...
Huh...
You boring people...
Oh, oof... Oh, boy.
Oh. Oh. Uh.
Such a...
Hey, Johnny!
Hey, Johnny, let's go
to the Green Meadow and play, huh?
Don't bother me, Peter.
There's not much time left.
- Huh?
- Winter will be here soon, you know!
Johnny, are you gonna say you can't play too?
- I'm too busy now, I'll meet you in the spring.
- Johnny, meet me in the spring?!
Oh, boy, oh...
Nobody wants to...
- Hey, Chatterer! Chatterer!
- What is it, Peter?
Let's go play, Chatterer.
Golly, I've no time to play.
I'm very busy.
- My work's not done yet, Peter.
- Chatterer!
Well, anyhow, I'm busy.
I don't want to be bothered.
I'm busy with my winter preparations.
Look around, Peter. Winter is coming,
winter's coming!
Leave me alone, the cold winter is coming! Oh!
What's the matter with everybody?
Here I am asking them to play, and they...
...they just... they say...
..."There's no time!"...
...that "I'm busy"...
...that "I'm preparing for winter"...
...and, uh...
...yeah, "Let's meet again next spring".
Why... Wait a minute!
Why, that's what Johnny said,
"Let's meet again".
Well, what on earth did he mean?
Winter isn't here yet,
and spring is far, far away.
That Johnny, I wonder, he said
we couldn't meet until winter has passed.
It couldn't be he's going some place far away?
That couldn't be... that couldn't be...
I wonder why we couldn't meet during winter?
We've been meeting all along up till now.
Hmm...
Peter just couldn't understand why everybody
was so occupied with winter preparations.
For Peter, winter preparations required nothing.
He would just naturally grow longer fur.
That's it!
I'll ask Grandfather Frog of the Smiling Pool.
Grandfather is wise and he should know.
Grandfather! Grandfather!
Grandfather Frog!
Hey...
Where in the world could he have gone?
Grandfather!
Grandfather Frog!
- Hi ya, Peter!
Hi, Joe, hi, Harry, where's Grandfather Frog?
- Grandfather Frog isn't here.
Not here?
Where is he, anyway?
- He's in the mud down below.
- Yeah, in the mud down below.
Huh?
- Yeah, he buried himself.
- Hibernating, he said.
Hibernation?
Yeah, he said to give his regards
to everyone in the forest.
He said we'd meet up again in the spring.
Now, what did they mean,
let's meet again in the springtime?
I just don't understand.
Oh... Winter preparations.
Then wait for spring.
Then spring comes
and you wait for autumn.
And then autumn comes
and then it's springtime again. What?
I don't understand.
I just don't understand.
Oh...
Why, what's that?
I like the winter!
I like the snow!
Why does everybody leave me all alone?
I don't understand.
My head is groggy.
Groggy, groggy, groggy!
I like the winter!
I like the snow! I just don't understand!
Why, my head is groggy.
Groggy, groggy, groggy!
I like the winter!
I like the snow!
My head is groggy!
My head is groggy, groggy, groggy!
I like the winter! I like the snow!
I like the winter and the snow!
My head is so groggy, groggy!
What is it this late at night, Peter?
You know what Johnny said? Johnny said
to meet me next spring, Uncle Billy.
What does that mean, anyway?
- Well, in brief it means that...
- Father, shut the door, please.
What are we going to do
if the children catch cold?
Yes, yes, I know, Mother!
- In brief, Peter, that's just what Johnny said.
- Just what he said?
- Right. So you won't meet till next spring.
- Not meet until next spring?!
- Go to bed and sleep.
- But to sleep until next spring?
M-hm.
That's right. That's what we call hibernation.
But they get mighty hungry by then.
So that's it! So that's why Johnny...
Johnny was eating so much,
so he wouldn't going to get hungry this winter.
- Mm-hm. That's right, Peter.
- Oh...
When winter comes, some people
go to live in a warm climate.
And others... Others...
...eat now and fill up their stomachs
and sleep real soundly
not eating and not running around.
Father!
What are you doing out there for so long?
The night wind is cold.
Yes, yes, yes, I know, mother, I'm coming.
Did you understand, Peter?
- Father?!
- Yes, yes, I'm coming right now...
Good night, Peter.
Good night, Uncle Billy.
Wow... They're hibernating, huh?
Oh...
Johnny and all my friends
are getting ready to hibernate?
They're getting ready to hibernate?
Oh...
To sleep until...
...until spring...
How nice!
Not have to worry about looking for food,
and sleep all winter with a full stomach.
When the snow falls,
there's no place to hide
from Reddy and the Mean Weasel and
that finding men with their gun, oh...
I-I-I'm scared!
So... hibernation...
Hm. Hm...! Hm!
Hm...
Why, that's it!
Hey...!
I'll hibernate, I'll hibernate!
Hey, I'll hibernate, yeah!
If Johnny can sleep all through
the winter, why, I should be able to!
Peter! Peter!
Oh, Uncle Billy!
Uncle Billy, can I ask you something, please?
Why, sure, what is it Peter?
About... hibernation.
Just a minute now. I'm going to come down.
I'm... I'm thinking of hibernating.
What?! Hibernating?
In all my years, I never yet heard
of a rabbit hibernating!
But... even Johnny does it... so I...
I figure I can do it too.
If Johnny the Woodchuck can do it,
I should be able to eat enough food
and stay full winter, be the first
rabbit to hibernate, hibernate!
I'm going to be the first rabbit
to hibernate, hibernate, uh-huh!
I'm going to sleep all winter.
I'm going to be the very first
rabbit to hibernate, hibernate!
I'm gonna sleep all winter.
I'm gonna sleep all winter
and not work, uh-huh!
I'm gonna hibernate, hibernate!
I'm gonna sleep all winter
and hibernate, hibernate!
I'm just gonna be full all winter,
I can hibernate too,
isn't that right, Uncle Billy?
Well... I've never heard of it.
But if you think...
...if you think you can do it,
you'd better find a warm place
for you to sleep all winter.
Uh-huh, uh-huh, uh-huh.
Yeah. That'll be easy.
Also, you must put on a lot of weight.
- Uh, get fat?
- Yes, you have to get big and fat.
Why-why is that?
That's because during the winter
you won't be eating.
So that you won't be hungry,
that's why!
Also, if you're fat during the cold winter,
you can survive in warmth
- ...and you won't be cold at all.
- How do I get fat, anyway?
By eating heartily.
Eat heartily and then... eat some more.
Even if your stomach hurts, eat more.
Then, more and more!
If it's just eating,
that won't be any problem.
I just love to eat and eat!
That's easy. Is that all, Uncle Billy?
Yep, that's all Peter.
Oops...
...just one more thing,
this is the most important thing:
when you go to sleep, don't worry
about Reddy or Bowser coming in.
Just worry about going to sleep.
- Forget about everything else.
- Huh...
That's easy. Thank you, Uncle Billy!
My, my, Peter is sure one
to do odd things.
With his fur, there's no need for him
to hibernate all winter!
Say, Peter, what's the big idea,
entering someone else's house?
Uh, s-s-sorry! Actually, I was looking for
a winter hibernating spot.
Hibernating?!
Yeah.
After looking and looking, Peter finds a cave
that Jimmy the Skunk had previously lived in.
Wow, this is good!
Lack of rear entrance
sort of bothers me, but...
...since I'll be sleeping all winter,
there's nothing to worry about, I guess.
The entrance is small, the interior deep,
it's tailor-made just for me.
Next to eating heartily, and getting fat,
hibernating is easy! Yeah!
And more and more.
Oh...
To get fat isn't as easy as I thought.
I couldn't get too fat, but that's alright.
Because I better start hibernating.
I sure admire his efforts.
Oh!
A bit scared to hibernate?
Or wonder why you made the effort?
Everyone in the forest,
let's meet again in the spring!
Oops!
Let's meet again in the spring!
So...
Ah. Yep. Upon re-examining this place
it's ideal for hibernation.
That's it!
I'll just tease Peter a little...
Ah...
Ah... Hibernating is sure fun!
I've told Peter that when he goes to sleep
he must not think of whether
Reddy the Fox or Bowser the Dog
might find his sleeping place.
You understand?
But is Peter in bed now?
Yes. And the more he tries to sleep,
the more he'll think about Reddy and Bowser
and then won't be able to.
That's funny... Why can't I go to sleep?
Ah...!
What's wrong? I can't go to sleep!
I never have trouble going to sleep.
Maybe if I yawn...
I can't go to sleep!
What's wrong anyway?
I can't go to sleep and hibernate!
Hm. Hm... Oh...
Hm... Oh!
Come on, sleep, Peter, go to sleep, Peter.
Sleep, come on, Peter, go to sleep.
How I'm gonna hibernate
if I can't go to sleep?
Hm...
Sleep, Peter, go to sleep.
Oh... Oh...
Oh!
Oh...
It's Reddy...
Reddy's come to find Peter,
oh, what am I gonna do?
Or maybe it's Bowser?
Wow, what'll I do?
Bowser will catch me and eat me!
Oh, what will I do?
Bowser will eat me up, oh...
Now it sounds more like Reddy.
Now, why did I ever wanna hibernate, anyway?
I... I can't sleep, even!
And I'm getting hungry.
Why did I ever wanna hibernate?
I-I-I'll never get out alive.
Huh?
The noise is gone.
How's Peter? Wonder what happened?
I don't hear him.
Could he have gone to sleep, huh?
If Bowser came, Reddy might have fled.
Then it's my chance to escape.
Ah...!
Nope. Wait. It might be a trick.
That's it, Bowser has returned home
for his dinner.
I bet it's safe out there now.
I'll see!
Wow!
Oh!
Peter was so frightened, wasn't he?
You guys! What's so funny anyway, huh?
Uh.. So that...
It was you guys outside playing tricks?
That was cruel, that was cruel!
Sorry, sorry...
We didn't really mean it!
Oh, Peter, you were so funny...!
Peter tried to be angry
with everyone, but couldn't.
The thought of having faced possible
death it came quite funny to Peter.
So, quite relieved, Peter laughed
heartily with everyone.
Oh, aren't you all gonna
hibernate for the winter?
Huh?!
Better hurry before the cold snow starts falling!
Hey, it doesn't bother me at all!
I'll be jumping and playing
in the snow all winter!
And if something amusing happens,
I'll tell you about it later!
Well... See you all next spring!
In the end, Peter realized
that he couldn't imitate
what was natural, like hibernation,
for some of his friends.
Peter was different,
he had to be himself.
Subtitle: South Wind Subs