Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Say, father, before we go, let's stop
and give our farewells to Rocky and Polly!
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Yeah, let's do that. Those two really did
treat us with kindness!
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Good morning, Rocky, Polly!
Fables of the Green Forest
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
- Well, Mr. Condor!
-You're all together! Is something wrong?
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
No, we're moving to the South country,
so we stopped by to extend our farewell.
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Thanks for everything.
Oh, you're really going?!
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
How disappointing! Say, instead
of going to the South country,
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
can't you live here throughout the year?
Don't you be silly!
For us the cold is just not
for our nature, you know!
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Just as you good people pass
the winter in your burrows,
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
we too shall be warm in our special place.
Is that so? Recently the swallows moved out,
yesterday, the cuckoo bird...
With everyone leaving, the Green Forest
becomes a very lonely place.
Tom and Bob the Quail
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
But of course, that doesn't mean that
we'll never meet again, you understand?
Of course, we'll surely be back again,
next spring.
Is that so?
Listen, Polly.
Let's go see the condor family off
to the end of the forest.
- OK?
- OK!
Well, stay healthy!
Listen, both of you, you have gone
far enough, do you understand?
Our best regards to everyone!
We'll be waiting with pleasure
to meet you next spring!
- Goodbye, goodbye!
- Goodbye!
Thank you, thank you!
- Stay healthy!
- Bye!
Hi, Bob!
Surely you're not gonna say you're moving
to the South country, are you?
We aren't that sensitive to cold.
We're just go to Mr Brown's field
to gather some wheat.
Oh, is that it?
My, that's good!
Well, children, let's go!
- Now, eat all you want!
- But don't wander off too far, little children!
Since it's already autumn,
harvesting is over.
The Bob's family has throughout the summer
foraged all over Mr. Brown's field.
Bob and his family have eaten up
all kinds of wheat seeds,
and naturally, their favorites, those green
worms that could've destroyed the crops.
Now they're munching on white butterflies
that lay their eggs on cabbages.
And these eggs, if left alone,
will develop into caterpillars,
which could destroy the cabbages.
In the wheat field, there are other insects
which suck the fluid from the wheat stock,
killing it.
Bob and his family ate these pests too.
Is everyone alright?
Two, three, four...
Dear, Mike is missing!
What did you say?
What shall we do?
Wait, where are you going?
To look for Mike in the wheat field!
Don't be foolish, darling!
- If you go now, you'll just be shot!
- But Mike has disappeared!
Just take it easy!
Oh, what happened?
Ah! Oh, the blood!
Let's run!
Polly, hide in here, quick!
Rocky, hurry!
Is the scent gone? Can't be helped.
Let's give up and go home.
- It looks like they're finally gone.
- Yeah, but they sure do some cruel things.
Better hurry and tell Bob,
they surely must be worried!
That's true. I'll hurry and go tell them.
So you look after Mike, will you?
But hurry!
Oh! What's this crying...?
You're a boy, aren't you... huh?
Such a small thing, you can bare it?
Oh, that's a good boy, Mike!
Sure is late!
You can stay here by yourself, can't you?
Now-now, you needn't worry!
I'm just going to go and find your parents, OK?
Now, don't wander off.
Stay quietly here, understand?
Hey, Mikey!
He hurt his wing and can't fly,
but... he's alright.
Uh, well, hello there, little quail!
You must be lonely there all by yourself!
Well, shall I play with you?
- Ah, Rocky! Oh!
- Polly, did something happen?
Well, you were so late,
that I came to see what happened!
Now hurry!
Mikey is waiting eagerly!
Mike, your mother and father are here!
Where is Mike?
That's strange, I told him to stay here
and not go out anywhere!
Mike! Mikey!
Sammy!
Say, what are you searching for,
for what, tell me?
Sammy!
Have you seen Mike around here?
Mike?
Yeah!
Mike, you say? Hmm...
You know...
In other words, I know, he's one of the five kids
of Bob, isn't that right, Rocky?
That's right, that's Mike.
Then, just a while ago, Tom caught him
and took him to his house.
Tom did, huh?
Yeah...! From all appearances, it looked like
he would be eaten, I'm sure!
Eaten? Oh...
- Rocky, where are you going?
- I'm going to Mr. Brown's house, Polly!
Rocky meant business.
If necessary, he'd bite Tom's hand, whatever
he had to do, he was going to help Mike escape.
Hi, young man, that quail is the one
that I shot not too long ago.
How about returning it?
No, sir... I won't!
You, sir... you may have shot him,
but he's not yours!
I found him at our field, so he's mine!
I wouldn't say that.
If I say no, it's no!
Furthermore, don't shoot guns in our field.
The quails in our field work all summer in our behalf.
Just because harvest time is over,
it's no reason for you to shoot them.
But the law permits the shooting of birds!
In my heart, that's a mistake!
Such laws are wrong!
Oh, you shouldn't get so mad
over a thing like a meaningless bird,
these things were born to be shot by men.
Oh, no, sir!
You're mistaken!
Birds, men, they're all the same!
Just like us, they become happy or sad.
Look, sir, when you come near,
how frightened he is!
Please, leave, and never again
shoot a gun in our field!
You're safe now, little bird!
You just take it easy!
We're gonna go for just a bit.
Come on, let's go, hurry up!
Mrs. Bob has a glutton for punishment!
She doesn't have to see him everyday!
But still I am apprehensive!
Rocky! Oh, terrible, something terrible!
Polly, what are you so excited about?
Just now I met Bob and he said
Mike can't be seen anywhere!
Mike can't?
Yes, and he said he thinks
maybe Tom has killed him!
Hardly, Tom isn't the type to do such a thing!
I told him that too, but then he said,
"If we look for him,"
"then we should be able to find him"!
I wonder if he really has been killed,
like Bob says.
If so, it's my fault...
Polly, it's much to soon to decide
that he's been killed.
Just to be sure, let's go see one more time.
Let's go.
Polly, run away, run away!
- What's so funny?
- About Mike being in such a place!
Mike, you said, where is he?
Look, is he over there?
No wonder we couldn't find him
with all that searching we've been doing!
Up to now, Mike has lived all his life
in the wide forest and meadow.
Now, Tom realized that he'd be
cramped and miserable in such a small box.
So, he moved him to the shed.
Then Mike is...
- Then he's really alright?
- Alright?
Yes, he is living in good health
in Mr. Brown's chicken shed.
So, be at ease!
Mother, don't you think that's swell?
Y-yes... but a chicken shed, what kind a place is that?
A chicken shed?
Oh, a place where they put those, you know,
birds that cockle-doodle-do!
But what is that child doing in such a place?
He's locked in there.
My, he's suffering such a predicament,
how can I not worry?
But Mike has been shot,
so he can not fly.
I think he would not have been able
to continue living
if he had not been here, Mrs. Bob.
That's right. Sooner or later I think
he would be caught by Reddy or a hawk.
But if he stays there, Reddy won't be able
to do a thing, uh-uh!
Mother, it's just like
what Rocky has been saying!
Mike is in a place like a big bag,
and Mike cannot leave,
but neither can Reddy nor a hawk enter.
A more safer place I don't think
can be be found anywhere!
Naturally, that's not all.
Tom is really friendly with Mike.
Now...
From the distance, we saw Mike leap
on Tom's hand and eat some food.
I'm convinced Tom is really our friend.
Mrs. Bob, are you still worried after this?
Mother, let's just trust him.
Tom is a good boy, and I'm sure
that just as soon as the wing heals,
he'll let our boy come home,
I'm sure of that.
From that moment on,
Bob and Mrs. Bob went every day
to see how their little Mike was getting along.
And every day, Mike's wound appeared
to be getting better and beter.
And then, one fine day, as Mr. and Mrs. Bob
came flying over as usual...
- Mikey!
- Mike, you can fly!
- Good boy!
Isn't it wonderful, my wing? Isn't it?
Tom cured it for me!
Oh, it must be that Mike has come home!
Uh-uh, usually he doesn't whistle at this time,
that must be it!
Sounds real happy!
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango