FABLES
of the
GREEN FOREST
Today's episode:
"The incident at moonlight party"
He can't catch me!
Peter Rabbit's tummy is a very funny tummy!
Yummy, yummy, yummy!
Guzzle, guzzle, guzzle. If you don't eat up,
your tummy won't swell up...!
Quit making a fool of me, Sammy,
you're not one to be able to talk about others!
That's right too!
The time is autumn, isn't it,
appetite's become ravenous!
That's right, I found a delicious fruit tree,
near the walnut tree!
I'll see you later!
Huh... Just because he himself is a glutton...
If I'm found by that pest, Sammy,
I won't be able to do a thing!
Not a thing, and I'm hungry too, darn it!
That scent, it's Reddy!
You, Reddy, with this much distance apart,
you'll never catch this rabbit!
Oh, it's Reddy!
Oh, Peter's in danger!
Peter knows that, Polly!
Look carefully!
Hey, that's Peter!
Oh, I'm near... he's noticed!
In a case of necessity, Peter knows just
how much distance he needs
to escape from Reddy the Fox!
Darn! The wind's blow my scent down to him!
I'd better move around,
so I can get down wind of him!
I wonder if he's given up!
Anyway, that Reddy...
Unless he becomes much more persistent,
he'll nourish down on his own four feet!
One more step!
Come closer, Peter!
Oh... I can't see Reddy anymore, Johnny!
Oh... That's bad!
Reddy has moved around down wind!
Johnny! Peter hasn't noticed anything yet!
Peter! Reddy's down wind!
Run away!
Oh...! I've had it!
Peter, you better take it easy
with all that teasing of Reddy!
After all, he's pretty smart, you know!
Oh... I can certainly understand
your concern, Uncle Billy,
but I must assure you that
I have nothing to fear from Reddy.
Why, with my wonderfully sensitive ears!
And these... unbeatable legs!
And with this smart head,
I'm not even a little bit afraid of Reddy!
Come and find out, Reddy!
Now, come on, make your move,
I'm getting bored!
Better yet, bring Granny!
Go ahead, I dare you! Look before you pay!
It's Reddy, it's Reddy,
it's Reddy, it's Reddy!
- It's Reddy!
- Oh... save me!
What's the matter, Reddy?
- Who's that?
- Up here, look up! Up!
Uh? Oh, it's Chatterer!
Oh, I'm ashamed to tell you, really,
it's my leg, I think I twisted my leg!
Oh, do you suppose you could
come down here and look at it?
Your leg...?!
Oh... it hurts! That's the truth!
Oh, Chatterer!
Do you think I could play act like this?
Oh-oh-oh, shouldn't we help each other
in time of our need?
- Uh-huh. Well... uh, that's... that's true!
- Oh... Look at this for a moment!
Oh...! Aw, aw, it hurts!
- That's Reddy's voice!
- Huh?!
Reddy?!
He's talking to someone!
Yeah, I really like you best
of all in the forest!
Uh-huh, I really do!
Yeah, I thought for a long time
that you were my only friend, uh-huh!
But, Chatterer...
you've always been such a good guy...
I know you'll come down and look at my feet,
after all, they hurt something fierce, oh...!
Well, aren't you gonna come down
and look at my feet...?!
Uh-huh, friend!
- Friends, you said?
- Of course, friends!
- Ouch, oh my!
- OK!
- Stop. Chatterer!
- Huh?
Chatterer! Chatterer?
Now, don't you be fooled!
Reddy is just trying
to catch you that way, you see?
Huh?
That's right! Nothing was wrong,
not too long ago!
Oh!
Oh, it hurts, it hurts!
Reddy's tummy is empty,
he just failed to catch Peter
just a few moments earlier, you see?
Oh! Reddy, is that story true?
Yeah! That's the way it is!
Darn! Darn, I gotta...! Oh!
Yeah... ow...!
- Oh, darn it! You come down here, Chatterer!
- No, I won't!
If you guys hadn't barged in...
Darn...! Those guys sure can run fast!
Go chase them, Reddy!
Oh, but of course after your leg
is mended, Reddy!
Darn! I'll remember this!
Everyone! Reddy's leg is now well,
Reddy's leg is completely mended!
And the next time,
you will definitely not fail!
Hey, I'm home, Granny!
Be quiet! If you're going to plant a seed
of worry again in Granny, I don't want it!
Oh, no, Granny!
Tonight, all the forest people
are getting together for a moon viewing!
You're not going to say
that you want to go too...!
Well, Jimmy was saying that they're all
go together tonight at the Lone Pine!
At the Lone Pine...?!
Yeah. Everyone is going to be coming
and bringing his own feast!
Jimmy's going to be bringing
some delicious beetles!
Hmm... is that really true?
Yeah. I saw Chatterer, he was all dolled up,
he was carrying a lot of tree nuts!
Oh, is that so, is that so?
Then Johnny, Peter... everyone
will be gathering at the Lone Pine.
Uh-huh. 'Course, Granny,
everyone was running around like mad,
trying to get their goodies to the Lone Pine.
But, Granny, this time I'm going to catch Peter
and do as you said, get him at last!
Just a minute, just a minute...
don't do that!
Well, why shouldn't I, huh?
Well, it's true, the area
around Lone Pine is meadow land,
so it should be easy to catch him, but...
But, but what...?
If all the forest folk are gathering together,
it will be necessary to trick them all at once!
But for you, that's an impossible task!
Wow! Fool all of the forest?!
That's right, Reddy!
When all of them are gathered together...
you will trick them all at once!
And then, you will catch Peter, right?
Uh-huh-uh-huh-uh-huh!
Oh, Granny, that's right, that's right!
- Now, watch carefully what your granny does!
- Hmm?!
Well, now, here we are,
all gathered together, under the moon!
Well, now, the only moon viewing of the year!
There's not a cloud in the sky!
Why, we should have a very good moon viewing!
Hey-hey, enough of long speeches!
Let's be merry, and all of us
in hurry and call for the moon!
Well-well, it's just like Peter says.
Why don't we sit here
and call for our lovely moon?
Oh my, it's Granny!
Oh, I think I ate something bad, oh...!
Granny!
- Oh my!
- Now, now don't get close!
Peter! Now, don't do it!
What can we do?
Can't we help her, Uncle Billy?
I tell you, I don't believe
that Granny could be sick!
I just don't believe it, not one bit!
That's mean...!
Uncle Billy, oh...!
Oh, Uncle Billy,
this doesn't look like an act to me!
No, Johnny!
I tell you I don't believe it, not one bit!
Granny, you did it, oh...!
This way! Now!
- Oh my!
- Help me!
Peter has been caught!
- Save me...! Save me, save me, oh, please!
- Now I finally caught you, Peter!
- Please, let me go!
- Now that I caught you, I won't let you go, aha!
Let Peter go!
Help... someone!
Help, help, oh... help...!
- Peter's in trouble!
- Help...!
He certainly is, Uncle Billy!
Come on now, we've got to help him!
- We can't just leave him there!
- Uncle Billy!
- After all, he's a friend!
Help... Oh, help me...!
Oh, please, help, someone...!
- Oh...!
- Oh, just when I thought I would feast!
What's the meaning of this?!
Oh my... goodness!
- I'll eat you, ah...!
- Uncle Billy!
Ah, don't bother me!
Help, help, help!
Leave me alone!
Darn you!
Oh, help!
Ah...
Jo-hnny...!
Oh, Johnny... Johnny!
- Johnny, that was splendid!
- Johnny, are you alright?
- Johnny!
Subtitle: South Wind Subs