Old Castle & south wind subs
present
Fables of the Green Forest
Midori ga mori no hidamari wa
The sunny spot of the Green Forest
Oh... it's cold!
Kakurenbo suru no ni yoi tokoro
is perfect for hide-and-seek
Well, if it isn't Jimmy!
Hey...!
Mada da yo  Mada da yo
– Ready? Here I come!
– Not yet! Not yet!
Where have you been so early in the morning?
What? I could tell you, Uncle Billy,
Shippo no hikatta yamanezumi
The Woodchuck with his shiny tail
but it be bad to make you envious.
Ichiban hajime ni mitsukatta
is the first one to be found!
Oh, you saying such a thing makes me want
to know all the more. Stop teasing and tell me.
Midori ga mori tte doko darou na
Where could the Green Forest be?
Fables of the Green Forest
I just went to Mr. Brown's chicken house
to have some fresh eggs for breakfast.
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Eh? Eggs, you say?
Really, a freshly laid egg is so delicious!
Hissori matsu no ha no kage wa
The shadow of the Lonesome Pine's leaves
Tell me, Jimmy, did you finish up
all those eggs?
Ohanashi suru no ni yoi tokoro
is the perfect place to talk
Hardly, there's still lots left!
Ano ne no ne  Ano ne no ne
You see… You see,
Kin'iro medama no fukurou ni
not even the golden-eyed Owl
As soon as Uncle Billy heard
the eggs story from Jimmy,
Tachigikisaretemo shiranai yo
will hear you if he tries!
he couldn't think about anything else.
Hissori matsu tte doko darou na
Where could the Lonesome Pine be?
Dareka ni dareka ni kiitoite
I keep asking everyone…
Whose Footprint Is the Other One?
Based on the books by Thornton W. Burgess
Blimey... eggs...
What are you mumbling to yourself about?
You sure can dirty things up, no matter
how much I clean up, there's no end, really!
Mother, have the children gone to sleep yet?
What foolishness are you talking about?
The children are sleeping soundly
right in front of your eyes!
That's right, Mother,
that's right, that's right!
Oh, Mother, just look
at those cute sleeping faces!
What delicious looking eggs!
Such smooth skin...!
Huh? What?
Why are you talking about eggs?
Huh... That is...
Before we begin our winter hibernation,
I thought we should eat a lot of eggs!
I'm shocked!
I thought you were fidgety, but...
...is this all you were thinking about?
When we're hibernating,
we won't be able to eat them!
Why don't you look at the ground...?
The snow is piled up!
On such a day, if you roam about Mr. Brown's
house, you'll leave tracks!
Besides, you've been caught before, haven't you?
Learn a little from your experience!
Hey, are you listening to what I'm saying?
Oh... I'm listening, Mother!
Dear... where are you going?
You surely aren't thinking of going
to Mr. Brown's chicken house, are you?
Oh! Never happen!
I just couldn't sleep, so I was thinking
of taking a little walk.
If that's the case, it's alright,
but please don't do anything foolish!
No, I won't!
If I precede to walk in Jimmy's footsteps,
they'll think it's Jimmy who sneaked in
to the chicken house!
Dear!
Don't forget the time that you were once caught!
Oh, I'd be safer just to quit right now!
Wait...
Well, after coming out here
it would be irritating to turn back!
Oh, well...
Wait...
Well, if I'm really, really careful,
I shouldn't get caught!
Uncle Billy was carefully walking
exactly on top of Jimmy's footprints,
but in the confusion wether to stop or go on,
he completely forgot about his tail.
And so he proceeded on,
dragging his tail over the snow.
Now I'm going to eat, eat, eat everything up!
Pardon me!
Oh, that's right. Jimmy has already
completely devastated the bottom shelves.
Wow, these upper shelves haven't even been touched!
Hmm, after all I said about not going,
that guy...!
He'll be lucky if nothing happens!
Oh... boy, did I eat, did I eat!
And now, my tummy is full, I'm getting sleepy!
I'll just rest a little bit before taking off.
Oh, my...!
I guess I'd better start for home!
But...
...at the time before daybreak,
as long as I start, by then...
This is terrible, I've overslept!
An egg thief?!
This looks like the work of a skunk!
If that so...
there must be footprints in the snow...
Looking for footprints...
Well, all he'll find are Jimmy's tracks there....
Just as I thought!
Oh, the tone of that shout means
he's found Jimmy's tracks!
Ah'm pretty smart to walk exactly on top
of Jimmy's footprints!
What's this?!
These footprints are strange!
Traces of a tail here!
No matter how you look at it,
this looks like the trail of a large rat!
M-hm, the thief who came here yesterday
was not alone,
there are traces of the skunk
leaving the chicken house,
but of the other's strange, when there are
no traces of him leaving.
That one!
He must still be hiding somewhere inside!
No mistake!
OK, I'll catch him!
I wonder if I failed up somewhere!
That's funny!
How did he escape?!
This time I'll fix it so he can
never get in here again!
Oh, deary me, when is that
husband of mine coming home?
Here I am, worrying myself to death!
Ah...! That's it, I'll ask Sammy,
maybe I'll find out something!
- Morning, Sammy!
- Good morning, Mrs. Billy!
Ah, is Uncle Billy home?
He went out for a walk,
but did you see him anywhere in the forest?
Hm. Course I haven't.
Sammy, you mean that you wouldn't know?
You're always bragging that you know
everything in the forest!
You know, Sammy, you must be at beside yourself,
enjoying how worried I am!
Why, w-w-w-why...?
You needn't tell me. You probably just got up
and don't know anything, anyway.
You mean jay Sammy!
I got up with the sun, Mrs. Billy,
and your husband wasn't anywhere in the forest!
He must be napping somewhere in a burrow, huh!
Thank you, Mr. Jay!
Usually you wouldn't talk too much to me...!
Now, boys, come on, Mother is going out!
Hmm... this is good!
Anyone, without exception, trying to enter here,
will be caught!
Oh, setting traps, is he!
It looks like I'm trapped
inside the chicken house!
Uh? Uncle Billy?!
That's right! Seeing that
he's not home by now, maybe...
...maybe he might have been caught
inside Mr. Brown's chicken house!
Here! Here, be quiet!
Rocky, can you do something?
If only these young ones
didn't need so much attention!
Mm, my-my...!
See what you've done now, oh!
Breachers!
No, children, see what you've done!
Rocky, excuse us, please!
Really, what should I do about all this?
Say, Rocky, couldn't you please just run down
to Mr. Brown's place and see...?
Eh? Me?
Here, here!
Mother won't forgive you!
Or if you could watch these kids for a while,
I would be able to go!
Why can't you obey me?
I won't bring you here anymore!
Ah, Ma'am! Don't you worry yourself
about Uncle Billy!
I'll go to the chicken house and check!
- My, Rocky, you'd do that for me?
- Uh-huh.
My, I'm glad I talked to you about this!
Don't go outside! Wait, kids, wait!
Then, Rocky, I'm relying on you!
Don't go outside!
Can't keep my eyes off these kids!
Oh... M-Mrs. Billy, there's still one left!
Rocky's weakness was cold weather.
When walking on the snow, his hands
and legs would immediately become numb.
So he decided to call Peter.
Rocky, Rocky, hurry, come on, Rocky!
Feeling weak in cold weather, I know,
but I didn't think you'd be that bad!
Rocky, try harder!
You couldn't hate the cold that much! Fight!
- Uncle Billy! Uncle Billy!
- Answer if you're in there, Uncle Billy!
Is it Rocky and Peter?
- Hey! You're alive!
- Hey!
- Uncle Billy!
- Yeah!
Then hurry, let's go home,
your wife is worried!
Well, I want to go home, but I can't!
- Can't?
- Why, are you hurt?
Wait there, I'm coming in!
Don't do that, don't come in,
there are traps set up!
I'm as well as always,
but with traps everywhere, I can't leave!
Well, son, you go home and tell my wife
that I think I'll be able
to find a way to escape,
when spring comes and the snow melts.
Until then I'll just stay here
and try not to get caught.
But, Uncle Billy!
Say, Peter!
You have any good ideas?
Uh... no. Not that I can think of.
What a fix!
It's OK, you two.
No matter how much thought
is given, there's no other way.
Instead, when you go home, tell Jimmy
not to come around
because there are traps set up!
OK, Uncle Billy, keep your hopes up!
Be extra careful if you don't get caught,
OK, Uncle Billy?
Thank you!
Wish me luck!
Rocky, what's the matter, anyway?
Hey, Uncle Billy, you can escape right away
without waiting for the spring!
Rocky, cut out your bad jokes, please!
It's the truth!
If you think it's a lie, just look outside!
- The snow is falling!
- Hey, Rocky, I'll get mad!
That's right, Rocky.
It's bad to tease Uncle Billy,
knowing he doesn't like the snow!
You haven't noticed it yet?
If a lot of snow falls on the trap,
it won't be able to operate!
So that's it!
And Uncle Billy can easily escape!
Isn't that nice, Uncle Billy?
Thanks, Rocky. I'll just have to bear it
until tomorrow morning.
And eat your tummy full of eggs
before you leave then!
Wow, the snow stopped!
Indeed. It's just like Rocky said.
Uncle Billy was afraid that at any moment
there would be the sound
of a click beneath his feet.
But he past over without any problem.
The chicken house was nearly covered with snow.
Uncle Billy, overjoyed at having
so easily escaped from the chicken house,
had forgotten one very important thing.
It wasn't until only he had covered
almost half the distance
to the Green Forest, before he noticed it.
Oh... my tracks! This is just like asking them
to come right after me!
Oh, why am I such a silly fool!
But right now there's not a thing I can do,
but just keep right on running!
Oh my, oh my!
How far do I have to walk?
My feet are getting cold.
Still, if I walk directly home,
my wife and children will get caught too!
What a fix, what a fix!
I can throw them off by crawling in there!
Rocky said he should be home today!
But, my goodness, he's surely late!
Bowser, right here, boy!
You thief!
I won't let you escape this time!
Rocky!
This is terrible, come quickly!
What's the matter, Polly?
I just heard from Sammy that Uncle Billy
is about to be caught!
You mean... Uncle Billy, Polly?
You possum, probably playing dead!
I'll split the tree!
Hmm... That's funny...!
There aren't any tracks leaving here.
That possum couldn't have wings...!
Well, come on, Bowser, let's go home!
What's anybody looking for?
There...
Ah...! Uncle Billy, weren't you in this other tree?
I was at first, but then Tom found me,
and I changed over to this one!
But without leaving one single track...
...how did you change?
Just use my head a little.
After Tom turned back,
I thought, and thought, and thought...
...about how I could get rid of Tom
and that flea bitten dog.
And... that's how it was...
Hey... without wings, Uncle Billy!
You changed trees without leaving tracks!
Right you are, I'm not quite
ready to be thrown away!
It's snowing!
Well, goodbye!
- Say, Mother?
- Yes...?
Is it alright to walk like this,
leaving so many tracks?
Can't you see that it's snowing?
Come on, let's go!
By tomorrow, the snow will have piled up
and erased everything!
Yes, you're right!
Uncle Billy realized that it was easy
to fall into trouble,
but so very difficult to get out of.
So, happily, he and Mrs. Billy returned home.
Nani ga aru no kana  kono mori no oku ni
What's there, inside this forest?
Nani ga aru no kana  ano sora no mukō ni
What's there, high up in the sky?
Tashikametai  kimi to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Porii
Polly!
Tashikametai  anata to futari de
I want to find that out together with you
Rokkii
Rocky!
Dokidoki shitai  harahara shitai
I want my heart to beat fast,
I want to feel the thrill,
wakuwaku shitai  mesomeso
I want excitement… And tears –
Dake wa  gomen dayo
Anything but that!
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  ame no naka de
What happens tomorrow in the rain?
Nani ga aru no kana  asu  niji no mukō de
What happens tomorrow
beyond the rainbow?
Special thanks from Old Castle & South Wind Subs to:
Cyber Zero, Mónica, Lordwen & Gango