A mask which is as fragile as glass,
people wear it to hide their own faces.
December 31 · Yokohama
Thanks.
Thank you very much.
It sounded!
Kitajima Maya, 13 years old.
An average girl who is not the most beautiful nor the smartest in school.
Auntie, hurry, hurry!
The next delivery!
But in that small heart of hers, there is a strong passion for acting, plays, and movies.
A ticket for the play?
You can have it if you want it that much.
But only if you promise to do all the deliveries on the night before the new year.
Delivery from Manpuku Ken. Thanks for waiting.
But you have to do them all by midnight.
That means you have until all the ships finish sounding their sirens.
Tonight, all the ships that are moored in the Port of Yokohama…
…will sound their sirens in preparation for the new year.
Auntie, the next one.
Hurry!
We have 120 deliveries.
It's impossible for you to do it alone.
I promised her because I knew she won't be able to do it.
I bought that ticket to go with Matsumoto.
I'll get that ticket no matter what.
Sugiko!
What are you putting a coat on for?
Where are you going?
Yamashita Park.
I'll be right back.
Two ramens.
Here you go.
Thank you.
I'm running out of time.
I have to hurry.
I have to hurry!
Oh no… just as I thought.
It's just impossible.
What a silly girl.
Maya!
I got them all done before 12,
just as I promised.
Sugiko… Where's Sugiko?
Maya!
As I promised, I finished them all.
Give me the ticket.
F-Fine, if you want it that bad,
you can have it!
Ah…?
What is so important about this anyway?
Here!
Go get it!
Maya!
Maya…
I can go!
I can go to the play with this!
She's crazy!
She sure is!
Finally, I've found her.
THE GLASS MASK
On the stage, with the lights off…
…blue shadows emerge.
Dancing 'round to hear the applause…
…I listen carefully to an unpredictable tomorrow.
Everyone has a dream…
…with stars in their heart.
Stage light: a moment to shine…
…this city becomes a shining star.
The flower in my heart
is as fragile as glass, a shinin' dream.
You can do it if you want to,
so hold on tight to love…
…because there's someone that smiles
on the other side of my tears.
You can do it if you want to,
this feeling in my heart…
Don't cry. Keep on running
and running, for someday…
Princess Camellia
Starring Himekawa Utako
Tōkyō Metropolitan Theater
—Episode 01—
A Spring Storm
Excuse me, but the play is over.
Excuse me…
Everyone has left already.
Huh?
Ondine Theater
Students wanted
Students wanted.
Ondine Theater group…
Here it is.
What a big place.
I feel out of place…
Thank you, Mother.
I'll be getting off early today.
That's Ms. Ayumi.
How beautiful!
She doesn't look 13 years old at all!
Himekawa Ayumi, born to the biggest
movie director and a famous actress.
With beautiful looks
and a talented gift for acting…
…she is steadily going forward
on the road to stardom.
She's the same age as I am?
I can't believe it…
Excuse me… I saw the advertisement
and I would like to play.
You want to be a student?
Fill this out, and take the exam, please.
Exam?
The admission fee and the tuition
should be paid after you pass the test.
Admission fee and tuition?
The admission fee is ¥150.000,
and the tuition will be ¥20.000 per month.
Six months' tuition has to be paid
in advance, so the total will be ¥270.000.
¥270.000… there's no way
I can come up with that much money.
…you are not concentrating!
No, no!
This is pantomime!
Panto…mime?
Ayumi, can you show them how it's done?
How about doing the "Escaped Bird"?
Yes.
Onodera Hajime, a well-known producer
who is the director of the Ondine Theater…
…as well as a member
of the Japanese Drama Association.
Wow!
I can really see the bird!
Perched!
I can really see the bird perched on her finger!
Wonderful!
Someone!
Are you okay?
Yes.
Oh, you're bleeding!
Oh, no…
Get ready to give her first aid.
Yes.
No, I'm fine! I can walk.
Really.
Please, let me go.
Thank you.
Sakurakōji Yū, a student at the Ondine.
Being a high school student,
he is expected to become a prospective star.
Hayami Masumi, the young president
of Metropolitan Entertainment…
…the sponsor company of the Ondine.
With his cool looks he is known
as the "King of Work" in the industry.
Oh, there's blood on you.
Huh?
Oh, it's okay.
Just like a purple flower.
I want to play…
Oh no, I'll get scolded again.
I told them I would get off early today.
Manpuku Ken
I'm home!
Hurry up and go get changed
so you can help the store.
Yes.
I'm sorry.
Look at you!
You can't do one thing right.
You can only go to school
because they let me work here.
Yes, it'll be just a minute.
How am I going to mange by myself
if you are like this?
I'm sorry, Mother.
Maya, it's okay,
can you go deliver now?
Yes!
This person will pay ¥10.000
for a bowl of ramen noodles.
¥10.000?
It's a little far up on the hill,
but could you go do that?
Wow…
Hello!
I'm from Manpuku Ken!
I'm here with your ramen!
Hello…?
Excuse… me…
What should I do?
Wow!
A script for Princess Camellia!
You must like that book?
O-Oh yes, I've seen this play.
Is that right?
Can you tell me the story line?
Yes, but I…
The curtain silently goes up…
…and the first scene
starts with a gorgeous dance party.
A young man, Alfred, finds
a beautiful woman with a camellia.
"How beautiful."
"Who is she?"
"You don't know her?"
– "She's a diva called Princess Camellia."
– Excuse me…
…but Mr. Masumi from Metropolitan
Entertainment is here to see you.
Have them wait.
I'll wait till you are free.
She's difficult as always.
But we have to play her way
till we get the contract.
Until we get the play rights for the masterpiece
of the drama industry, "The Crimson Goddess".
Yes…
It was 32 years ago.
Miss Tsukikage's "Crimson Goddess"
was fantastic.
It was the biggest hit!
Ozaki Ichiren, the screen writer for the play…
…claimed that Tsukikage Chigusa was the only
person that could possibly play the main role…
…and gave her the play rights.
My father is still after the play rights
for "The Crimson Goddess".
I know.
"When can I see you next?"
"When this camellia goes dead."
"I'll be with you
when I'm wearing a white camellia…
…but a red one means no."
No, no good.
The tone of the voice,
eye movement, spacing, nothing is good—
Be quiet!
Leave.
She has only seen "Princess Camellia" once.
Huh?
But she managed to memorize the entire script
that lasted three hours without a mistake.
How rude!
We'll get the play rights for
"The Crimson Goddess" for sure.
If Metropolitan Entertainment wants it,
it can make it possible.
I love it!
I want to play.
I'm not pretty nor smart, and I don't have
any money to go to drama school.
I'm not well proportioned.
But, but… I want to play!
If it costs money, I can work, but I want to play!
Drama is not as easy as you think.
If this is just a half-way passion,
then you should forget it.
Half-way passion?! No way!
I will do anything to be able to play drama.
Are you sure?
I am!
I would like to show you something.
Come with me.
Here we are.
Tsukikage Theater
This is…
I was once an actress…
…before an accident changed my fate.
It's been twenty years.
This is my drama research center.
I've been waiting for this day to come.
Finally, today is the day
to open Tsukikage Theater.
Please let me in!
I want to be part of this group!
You can't be an actress
as a hobby or for recreation.
Why do you want to be part
of Tsukikage Theater?
What are you going to do after you join?
I'll be an actress!
I want to be an actress!
Well said.
I wanted to hear those words.
That girl…
13-year-old Maya had no idea
what plot awaited her.
It is lonely by myself…
…and I almost stumble.
Somewhere calls me here,
just like a whisper in the wind.
Purple light, shining down
on the horizon…
…more surer than words…
…telling us gently…
…that we'll meet
each other someday.
Of course you can
fly from far away…
…for the dream
on my cheek…
…belongs to you.
Maya gets chosen to play Beth,
the main role of "Little Women"…
…the first play at Tsukikage Theater.
She appears on the stage despite a 40 degrees
fever from standing in the rain all night long.
Please look forward to the next episode:
"Mr. Purple Rose".