A mask which is as fragile as glass, people wear it to hide their own faces.
THE GLASS MASK
On the stage, with the lights off…
…blue shadows emerge.
Dancing 'round to hear the applause…
…I listen carefully to an unpredictable tomorrow.
Everyone has a dream…
…with stars in their heart.
Stage light: a moment to shine…
…this city becomes a shining star.
The flower in my heart is as fragile as glass, a shinin' dream.
You can do it if you want to,
so hold on tight to love…
…because there's someone that smiles on the other side of my tears.
You can do it if you want to,
this feeling in my heart…
Don't cry. Keep on running and running for someday…
Don't cry. Keep on running and running, for someday…
No matter how one looks at it, Maya Kitajima is an average girl…
…but, in her heart, there is a burning desire to become an actress.
Maya, whose talent was discovered by
a former actress, Tsukikage Chigusa…
…is determined to follow in her footsteps by becoming an actress in Tsukikage Theater.
—Episode 02—
Mr. Purple Rose
Dear Mom, I am now a live-in student at Theater Tsukikage.
Sorry I left without notifying you…
…but I'm doing fine here.
Manpuku Ken
I'm sorry, Mother.
But I really want to become an actress by any means.
Now I'm going to junior high school from here…
…and I am getting a scholarship for this school…
…so don't worry about me.
Ouch!
What's going on?
Waking us all up?
What time do you think it is?
I have to get up at 6 tomorrow for my duty.
Let me sleep.
I'm sorry!
On that note, let's get back to sleep.
My four roommates are all
drama girls" from all over the country.
Mina.
Taiko.
Sayaka.
And Rei.
She's so handsome.
But she's a girl without a flaw.
And, Mom, don't be surprised.
I was chosen to play Beth in "Little Women".
Tsukikage Theater's first performance, part advertisement as well as opening the theater.
I'll play Beth on that stage!
Shoot, I slept in!
Good morning.
Sorry, but I'm running late!
I'll see you later!
– Ms. Maya.
– Yeah?
You dropped something.
Oh, that's a letter to my mom.
I can mail it for you.
Thank you.
Bye now!
Oh, Madame, good morning.
That is?
Oh, Ms. Maya's letter.
I'll take care of it.
Huh?
She has left her home to be here.
Madame…
What she needs now is to forget her past.
With the performance date coming close,
they progressed with their practice.
Maya!
Look how you are picking it up!
Are you trying to understand how Beth would like to pick it up?
There she goes again.
It's impossible for her to play Beth,
being a total amateur.
Sayaka would fit Beth much better.
I think Maya's just a teacher's pet.
Emotions!
Emotions will make the play.
Emotions…
Let's play it again from the piano scene.
Jo. Meg.
Beth, play the piano.
Y-Yes.
No!
That's not Beth playing!
Yes!
Try again!
No!
Yes!
Here you go!
Thanks for waiting.
I'm no good at all…
What are you not good at?
You… are from Ondine Theater!
Sakurakōji Yū.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Kitajima Maya.
Oh, I'm helping them out.
Oh, you're helping this store.
Hmm, you enrolled in Tsukikage Theater.
Everyone is like that
when you start out.
I still get corrected all the time.
Here it is.
Come in.
B-But…
It's okay, come on in.
You want to play Beth better, right?
Yeah, raise your hands up a little more.
Come on in.
Here is some tea.
Thank you.
It's not time for tea yet.
We have to practice!
Oh no, what a strict teacher!
Miss Tsukikage has sold all her jewels.
She is trying to sell her house in Yokohama, too.
I see.
Thanks.
Your mom is so nice.
Yeah, she is.
Mother…
What?
Oh, nothing.
Oh, this is fine here.
Thank you for the piano lesson.
I think I can try again.
Maya…
Yes.
…I hope we can play together one day.
I'll try hard till that day!
Good bye!
Well, I sure hope that you will produce a star soon.
Until then, let's see how
many money trees grow.
Well the, good luck.
I'll see you again soon.
I'll come by again, real soon.
Okay then, bye.
Tsukikage Theater
Who is it?
It's me.
May I come in?
I saw Mr. Aoyagi's car outside,
so I waited it out.
The owner of this theater is Mr. Aoyagi, huh?
What do you want?
There's only one thing I came here for.
I have no intention to sell the play rights for "The Crimson Goddess."
I will come back again and again
till you change your mind.
Please go home now.
I'm a little tired.
I see.
I won't bother you.
But let me say one thing before I go.
I wouldn't recommend you signing up with Aoyagi Productions.
And sign up with your Metropolitan Entertainment instead?
No, thank you.
I will run my theater just fine.
Don't you see that you are being used by Mr. Aoyagi?
Please go home.
You have no right to comment like this.
I see.
But now that I know that the notorious Aoyagi Productions is behind Tsukikage Theater…
…I won't just let this pass.
Are you threatening me?
No way.
I just want to protect
"The Crimson Goddess".
Please leave now.
Excuse me.
Please don't harass my teacher like that.
I don't like anyone who harasses her!
I don't like…!
Beth, Beth, look at me!
Don't die on me!
I'm fine.
Jo, don't let anyone come near me—
No good, Maya!
This is the scene where Beth is still thinking of her sisters, even though she's struggling herself!
It's been three hours since we first started this same scene…
Think how a sick person
would breathe.
This scene is where Beth is on the edge of her life, and it is this drama's climax.
Get serious!
Sayaka, let's practice.
You play Beth as a substitute.
Yes!
Maya, go rest and practice.
Sayaka, get into the bed.
Then Jo, open the door and enter.
Yes.
Beth, Beth, look at me!
Don't die on me!
I'm fine.
Jo, don't let anyone come near me.
Sayaka, you play Beth as a substitute.
I don't understand…
I try my hardest
to feel like I'm Beth…
I don't understand.
I don't understand…
Maya, are you okay?
I don't understand what I can do.
I don't understand.
You can't help it.
A healthy girl like you
is trying to play sick Beth.
Of course it takes time to practice.
Three days left.
I have to get the role back by any means.
Sayaka, you play Beth as a substitute.
Yes!
Hey, girl, get on your feet.
You'll catch a cold walking
like that in the rain.
Three days left till the performance.
Healthy Maya is playing sick Beth.
It just won't work.
Hey, you'll catch a cold.
Yes… rain.
Rain.
This cold rain can teach me
how to play Beth!
Teacher, she's not back yet.
What happened to her
that she's not back this late?
Should we call her mother
in Yokohama?
There's no need for that.
She's not the kind of girl who goes home
just because she gets scolded.
Teacher…
You all go ahead and go to bed now.
It got pretty late before we knew it.
Yeah.
Hmm?
Sorry, but wait for me for a little bit.
O-Of course.
That's her!
You!
What are you doing here?
You… Mr. Laurence.
Laurence?
What are you talking about?
It's me, Hayami!
Mister, thank you for the music.
What happened to you?
Hey?
Hey, get a grip!
Are you okay?
Hey?
Mister Laurence?
Music?
"Little Women"!
She has a high fever.
I gave her a shot,
so let her rest for a while.
Maya, hang in there.
Maya…
Maya!
I'm fine, Jo.
Don't let anyone come near me now.
Maya, that's Beth's words…
She's becoming Beth herself.
With that high of a fever…
…will she be able to get on the stage?
Welcome to "Little Women",
the first play of Tsukikage Theater.
What's this?
The Himekawa family…
…Hayami Masumi and Onodera…
…and critics in the middle.
Something's fishy.
Please enjoy our play till the end!
You did a great job getting
this many critics and reporters.
Teacher, Maya…
has a fever of 40°C.
What?
There's no way
she can be on the stage.
Teacher, I can play as a substitute.
Maya, what are you going to do?
I can do it.
I can do it!
What if you pass out on stage?
I'll get up.
Please let me play!
I see. Go on.
Try your best!
But Teacher!
It's impossible!
Maya, Maya.
Can you stand up?
Maya, are you still going to play?
I am… Beth.
Before mother comes home,
let's think of a Christmas present for her.
I'm thinking of something for her.
Maya…
…what a determined person you are!
Hey, Sakurakōji.
Oh, Ayumi.
This play of Tsukikage Theater
isn't all that great.
Especially Beth. She's slow in her motion and her speech. She's no good.
She can't help it.
She has a fever.
Fever?
She's on stage with
a fever of 40°C.
40°C?!
Oh yes, I have something good for Mother's present
I'll go get it.
Maya, your speech is slow.
Sorry, I can't focus very well.
No excuse is useful here.
Stand up!
Your turn again!
Yes!
Here, go!
Oh, did anything funny happen
while I was gone?
Sisters, share the story with me.
Oh, here comes Mother.
What did you all do today?
A fever of 40°C and she grows even more beautiful as the play goes on.
May I help give out present for poor kids?
No, I really want to help!
Where in that small body…?
Where is the magical power hidden?
Beth, Beth, look at me!
Don't die on me!
I'm fine.
Jo.
Beth…
Beth is playing the piano
in her dream.
Maya, great!
Great acting!
She doesn't know the real side
of the acting world.
Kitajima Maya, huh…
Maya, good job!
How do you feel?
Thank you.
I feel a little better.
Great job, Maya.
Here's a gift from your fan.
It was left outside the backstage.
Purple roses?
My god, there's a card!
Let's see… "Please become
a healthy Beth soon. —Your fan".
Wow, an anonymous fan letter!
I'm so happy to get a gift for playing drama!
I don't know you,
but thank you, Mr. Purple Rose.
It is lonely by myself…
…and I almost stumble.
Somewhere calls me here,
just like a whisper in the wind.
Purple light, shining down
on the horizon…
…more surer than words…
…telling us gently…
…that we'll meet
each other someday.
Of course you can
fly from far away…
…for the dream
on my cheek…
…belongs to you.
To become an actress, Maya ran away from home and severed bond with her mother.
It's a choice she made, so it cannot be swayed easily.
But along the way, she makes enemies with a genius girl, Himekawa Ayumi.
Please look forward to the next episode:
"The Beautiful Rival".