A mask which is as fragile as glass, people wear it to hide their own faces.
THE GLASS MASK
On the stage, with the lights off…
…blue shadows emerge.
Dancing 'round to hear the applause…
…I listen carefully to an unpredictable tomorrow.
Everyone has a dream…
…with stars in their heart.
Stage light: a moment to shine…
…this city becomes a shining star.
The flower in my heart is as fragile as glass, a shinin' dream.
You can do it if you want to,
so hold on tight to love…
…because there's someone that smiles on the other side of my tears.
You can do it if you want to,
this feeling in my heart…
Don't cry. Keep on running and running for someday…
Don't cry. Keep on running and running, for someday…
Maya, despite Onodera's terrible plot,
stood on the stage all by herself…
…and received strong support from
the audience at the National Acting Contest.
However, they lost the competition due to Onodera's interruption…
…and Tsukikage Theater was forced to break up.
The only members left with Tsukikage Theater are Maya and four others.
—Episode 08—
Masumi's Passion
Tsukikage Theater
Teacher, I'll do my best.
I'll get a part time job and try
not to be a burden to you.
I'll practice even harder from now on.
Teacher, we'll do the same, too.
Tsukikage Theater is not done yet.
It's just that we just have to move.
We'll just have to start right over.
Yes. We can't let Ondine destroy us.
Let's go, everyone.
Maya. Let's go.
Please take care of yourself, Madame.
You do the same, Genzo.
Please don't worry about your expenses.
I'll work hard and take care of you.
So please don't overwork yourself.
Genzo…
Good morning.
Morning.
Hold it!
We haven't had any new big talents lately.
That's right. Well, I don't know about big,
but I saw an interesting girl.
Where at?
At the National Acting Contest.
She attracted the audience's attention all by herself.
Kitajima Maya was her name.
Hmm. What is she like?
Nothing special.
But I heard Toride-san has an eye on her.
Toride as in that well-known scout?
Yeah.
Okay, we should check her out.
My name is Mizuki.
I have worked for the CEO till now…
…but he assigned me to you, Mr. President.
Yes, I've heard about you.
Could you call Mr. Onodera from Ondine?
I would like to speak to him tonight.
I'm on it right now.
Hello. This is Mizuki from Metropolitan Entertainment.
Yes.
May I speak to Mr. Onodera, please?
I'll have her for Metropolitan Entertainment.
Where are we going now?
A small, one bedroom apartment.
Sayaka, Mina and Taiko will stay on the second floor of a nearby bakery.
Rei, you're from Tōkyō, right?
Why don't you go home?
Home?
Yeah, why?
I like acting, and I like you all.
That's why I'll stay here.
Here, this will be our castle from today!
Yeah, forget about tomorrow,
and let's get off to a new start!
That's right.
Yesterday won't come back even if you think about it all the time.
So let's think about tomorrow and how are we going to live tomorrow.
Yes.
And if things are not good tomorrow, there's always the day after.
Maya…
That's right, and I will be an actress someday.
Hey!
Be quiet! You're about to wreck the stairs!
Sorry!
Even though Tsukikage Theater has gone out of business…
…she…
…she won't stop.
When and how will she come in my way again?
I'm afraid.
Rei, hurry!
I'm coming.
Good morning!
Good morning…
Time for voice training!
Look at her.
Okay, we'll be right there, Maya.
Ta·chi·tsu·te·to, na·ni·nu·ne·no…
Na·n·do ni nu·me·tte, na·ni ne·ba·ru…
Sakurakōji-kun.
I thought I would catch you if I waited at your school.
You moved without letting me know.
Sorry.
Masumi-sama.
Everyone is here.
Oh.
Is anything wrong?
No.
You'll play the knight's role at the student play?
How nice!
I'm glad.
You seem happier than I expected.
That's my only talent.
I can't be depressed forever.
So I'll try to think about tomorrow instead.
Tomorrow…
Yes, I want to act as soon as I can.
What about school?
You'll be in high school next year, right?
Yeah. But I want to act,
and I have to work, too.
Besides, my grades are terrible.
Oh, is this your script?
Wow, how interesting!
You'll be a knight.
How cool!
"Yuria."
"I don't have fame,
status, or money."
"Yuria, I don't have fame, status, or money."
"But I have plenty of love you in my heart."
"Don't say anymore, Floria."
"If my father finds out that we're meeting like this… he'll be furious!"
"Don't go, Yuria!"
"My heart is with you from the first time I saw you."
"Please tell me, Yuria, that you love me."
"They way you smile…"
"The way you move…"
"I think of you every night."
"To be by your side."
"To look at you."
"To love you."
"And to help you!"
"That's my only wish!"
Oh, keep on going.
Well…
Let's stop here.
He's all quiet now.
How weird.
Hey, Masumi-kun.
Did you think about what we talked about the other day?
Yeah, but you know that Kitajima Maya hates me.
Even if we were to give her an excellent offer…
…I don't think she'll fall for Metropolitan Entertainment.
Besides, all the scouts will be all over her.
They've forgotten about her already.
They are all busy promoting a British rock band.
You're such a powerful man.
Excuse me.
Oh, Sakurakōji-kun.
I heard you wanted to talk to me about something.
Oh, have a seat.
I want to talk to you about something.
Well, the girl you have been seeing from Tsukikage Theater.
You mean, Kitajima… Maya-san…?
What about her?
There she is.
Thanks for waiting.
Three coffees.
I'd like some pizza toast.
Me, too.
For me, too, please.
Okay, I'll bring it right over.
She's so cool.
We asked for a waitress, not a waiter.
You're still talking about it.
Oh, Maya, you're here.
Rei, this place is hopping!
Of course. I'm the only one who graduated from high school.
Leave it all up to me!
You were going to go to college, right?
My parents were going to make me.
Excuse me? Can you take our order?
Yes, what would you like?
Not you, mister, but her.
Right away.
I have to look for a job, too.
Part-time job?
Oh, no. We have enough people here.
Besides, aren't you still in junior high school?
But, I…
No, just go home.
It's harder than I thought.
I still haven't even paid my tuition yet.
Maya was becoming irritated.
Not being able to practice was the hardest of all.
When they started practicing at their apartment…
…all they got was complaints from their neighbors.
They wandered parks at night in search of a place they could practice in.
She had school in the daytime and kept on looking for jobs after school.
Her life was getting harder and harder.
I haven't practiced for two weeks now.
Your shoulders are crying, Maya-chan.
Sakurakōji-kun.
To Ondine Theater?
Yeah, it's a good deal.
Mr. Onodera would like to have you as a scholarship student.
Mr. Onodera?
I would like to comment on the play by Tsukikage Theater.
Not only that she didn't play it by the book,
but she continued her selfish play!
Tsukikage Theater and Ondine had to be enemies at the National Contest.
But Mr. Onodera says he hates to see your talent get buried without a chance.
Sakurakōji-kun…
Maya-chan, with Ondine you can study acting without any worries.
Tuition is all free, of course, and you can stay in the dorms of Metropolitan Entertainment.
They pay for school, too.
Hey…
Let's study acting together.
Remember we once said we wanted to get on stage together.
Sakurakōji-kun.
So, let's do it.
No, I can't.
Maya-chan…
I can't betray Miss Tsukikage and my friends.
I can't do it!
This is for your future.
You have to put yourself
as your first priority.
No, I can't.
I love my crew at Tsukikage.
More than me?
I'm sorry. I… I…
Sorry.
I was inconsiderate. I didn't even think about your situation.
I'll go home for today.
But I won't give up on you.
See ya.
Sakurakōji-kun.
To be by your side.
To look at you. To love you.
And to help you. That's my only wish!
See ya later!
Bye.
Working hard on Sunday, aren't you?
Sunday is the busiest day.
Why don't you go out yourself today?
Hey! Slow down!
Sorry!
It's been three weeks.
Everyone is busy with work.
I want to act!
King Lear
Wow, a tragedy.
I really would like to see it.
Ayumi-san.
Oh, you're here, too?
You're from Ondine…
You need to hurry up. The play is about to start.
No, I'm…
At least enjoy the pictures!
Welcome.
Hello, Masumi-san.
Long time no see, Mrs. Himekawa.
Hi, Mizuki-san.
I'm surprised to hear that you, the CEO's secretary, are working for Masumi-san.
Masumi-sama will soon take over Metropolitan Entertainment.
I wanted to be of any help so I accepted that proposition.
Then, you will be the voice of the president.
Here, the show is about to start.
Yes.
What is she doing?
She just stands there looking at the pictures from the play.
Excuse me.
Yes.
I'm so silly. I know I can't go in, but I can't leave either.
Hey…
I'm running an errand.
Here, someone told me to give these to you.
Oh, that's him!
Mr. Purple Rose!
Here.
Hey, wait. Where is he?
I don't know. He left already.
Wait! What did he look like?
I don't know.
Thank you.
Thank you, Mr. Purple Rose!
She's gotten the reserved seat!
I'm envious!
Do what you want, Cordelia.
Take your words with you.
From this point on, we are not
father and son anymore.
You're not my blood anymore!
It was beautiful.
I wonder if I can act like that someday.
You were here, too?
Is it okay for a junior high student to stay out so late?
It's nine o'clock already.
Oh, shoot.
I have to go!
Wait.
Can I give you a ride, little one?
By they way, I heard you rejected the offer.
If you join Ondine, you can study acting without worrying about making a living…
…and fully focus on studying acting.
You were the one!
It was your plan!
You want to get me away from Miss Tsukikage
What would you do if that's true?
No, thank you!
She broke your heart beautifully.
She must hate me so much.
Masumi-sama.
You seem to have so much interest in her.
It's my job.
I can't let a golden egg pass by.
Is that really the only reason?
I wonder who in the world he is?
Thank you, Mr. Purple Rose.
Maya's life has been hard without being able to practice…
…but Maya was building even more passion for acting.
All for Mr. Purple Rose,
who's always looking out for her.
It is lonely by myself…
…and I almost stumble.
Somewhere calls me here,
just like a whisper in the wind.
Purple light, shining down
on the horizon…
…more surer than words…
…telling us gently…
…that we'll meet
each other someday.
Of course you can
fly from far away…
…for the dream
on my cheek…
…belongs to you.
Maya plays in a movie for the first time.
It's just a small role, but she still gives it her all.
The main star of the movie, a singer Tabuchi Emi, is shocked by Maya's performance.
Please look forward to the next episode:
"Maya's First Movie Appearance".