A mask which is as fragile as glass, people wear it to hide their own faces.
THE GLASS MASK
On the stage, with the lights off…
…blue shadows emerge.
Dancing 'round to hear the applause…
…I listen carefully to an unpredictable tomorrow.
Everyone has a dream…
…with stars in their heart.
Stage light: a moment to shine…
…this city becomes a shining star.
The flower in my heart is as fragile as glass, a shinin' dream.
You can do it if you want to,
so hold on tight to love…
…because there's someone that smiles on the other side of my tears.
You can do it if you want to,
this feeling in my heart…
Don't cry. Keep on running and running for someday…
Don't cry. Keep on running and running, for someday…
Maya appeared in a movie for the first time.
Although it was a very small role, she tried her best…
…and her powerful acting had surprised the audience.
Maya is filled with a dream: to try many different roles, and to become an actress.
—Episode 10—
The New Challenge
Wow.
So many theaters in one place.
I hope I can act in a place like this one day.
Yeah. Why don't I go ask?
Asking can't hurt.
Excuse me, but the theater opens at one o'clock.
Could you wait outside?
Oh, I came to see the person in charge of this play.
I mean, a manager.
Ahh.
You mean Mr. Tanuma, the producer?
Yes, Mr. Tanuma.
Do you have an appointment with him?
N-No.
Then you have to leave.
He's very busy.
Sorry!
Wow.
They are all real actors.
Oh, Mr. Tanuma.
How was it?
Oh, that was such a mess.
Excuse me, but are you Mr. Tanuma?
Yes, I'm Tanuma, but you are…?
I'm Kitajima Maya.
Could you give me a role in your play?
What are you talking about? Give you a role in my play when I don't even know you?
Just came out of nowhere.
It's either you have some nerves or you don't know the world yet.
I won't give up!
It's not the same as a play in school.
You have to audition first, and if you get accepted…
…then you have to train for about ten years.
Then you can come talk to me.
We are not that desperate to hire someone like you. Go home.
I told you already about the play rights for "The Crimson Goddess".
How long are you going to be like this, Miss Tsukikage?
You must be having a hard time, just living each day like this.
Your few members can't even practice.
I doubt you can nurture an actress that can play "The Crimson Goddess".
Miss Tsukikage.
Could you please us the rights for "The Crimson Goddess"?
Of course we will audition from all over the world.
I guarantee we'll make it the best.
This is also the wish of my father…
Your father?
So he hasn't given up on "The Crimson Goddess" yet?
If you give me the play rights,
then I'll make sure…
…we'll give you more than enough money so you don't have to live like this ever.
No, thank you.
Even if you put up tens of thousands of dollars…
…I will never give up the play rights.
That's my play.
My and Ozaki Ichiren's…
What's wrong, Miss Tsukikage?
Teacher!
It's your fault!
You're the reason she had a stroke!
Go home now!
We don't have time for this nonsense!
Go get a doctor, right now!
Doctor, this way. Hurry!
Hmm? She seems to be sleeping fine.
Let's see.
Why did you—
I'm home.
What happened to her?
Oh, little girl.
My name is not little girl.
My name is Kitajima Maya.
Oh, that's right.
So, have you changed your mind yet?
Huh?
About Ondine Theater.
They will give you a full scholarship.
It's a good deal.
I like Miss Tsukikage.
And I like my friends from Tsukikage Theater.
Then you should join Ondine Theater even more.
Miss Tsukikage will appreciate it
if she needs to feed one person less.
I hurt her again…
She will hate me even more now.
Huh?
Nothing.
Miss Tsukikage will appreciate it
if she needs to fed one person less.
I must be a burden to Miss Tsukikage.
What should I do?
What can I do not to be a burden to her?
Eishin Za
Performance acting is not so easy.
Which theater are you from?
I'm from Tsukikage Theater.
Tsukikage?
Oh, I've heard of it.
The well-known actress, Chigusa Tsukikage…
…founded it to groom an actress for "The Crimson Goddess".
So, what?
Are you the future Crimson Goddess?
No, no way. Miss Tsukikage told me that there's no way I can play her right now.
I bet.
Famous actresses are saying
that's a very tough role.
Here, you should go now.
– Good morning.
– Morning.
Now.
Harada Kikuko.
A well-known actress who heads the Eishin Za.
Who was that girl?
Oh, she just walked in to see if there's any role available for her.
You know Tsukikage Theater, right?
She's a member of that theater.
Chigusa Tsukikage?
Oh, "The Crimson Goddess"!
Yes.
She said that Miss Tsukikage told her…
…that there's no way for her to play "The Crimson Goddess" right now.
Of course!
Uhm, Miss Harada?
She told her that there's no way for her
to play "The Crimson Goddess" right now.
"Not right now".
Yes, that's what she said. Right?
Yeah.
I see.
Then you mean she's the future Crimson Goddess.
Don't be silly.
What makes you think that?
Miss Tsukikage is a very strict person when it comes to acting.
Especially when it comes to "The Crimson Goddess".
She didn't say that just because.
If she said she can't play that now…
…it might be impossible now,
but it might change in time.
In other words, she has the talent for it.
At least that's what Miss Tsukikage believes.
Next time she comes here,
tell her to come see me. Understood?
Huh?
Hospitalized?
Yeah.
The doctor says it's better for her to do it immediately.
Yes. We need to examine her first,
but she might need surgery.
Oh, no.
So, how much would that be?
Hmm.
I can't say the exact amount,
but at least ¥50.000.
– Huh? ¥50.000?!
– ¥50.000?!
¥50.000?
That's impossible.
But we can't just leave her as she is now.
Only if the theater was still in business, damn it!
Please bring your recyclable newspapers,
magazines and old clothes.
We'll exchange them
for toilet paper and tissues.
They used to be in Tsukikage Theater.
What? You were the ones who destroyed all the costumes and equipment?!
Sorry.
We apologize.
We've been meaning to apologize ever since.
We were tricked by Onodera from Ondine Theater.
Onodera said that he'd give us good roles at Ondine Theater.
But we were naive.
Later, he said he didn't remember any of it.
We were so stupid!
You can kick or punch us all you want!
Oh my god.
No!
I see.
It was Ondine who destroyed our theater.
Hayami Masumi from Metropolitan Entertainment is the same way.
Ah!
Yes.
All he wants is the play rights for "The Crimson Goddess".
How dirty they are!
I won't forgive them!
I will never forgive them!
Never, ever!
Hi, little girl.
How's your teacher doing?
What's wrong? You look pale.
Listen to you, trying to be all nice and kind.
We know it was you that interfered with us at the National Acting Contest…
…and destroyed Tsukikage Theater!
We don't need none of this!
Go home!
Go home…!
Miss Tsukikage's condition will worsen if you come to see her!
You, what are you doing?!
Miss Tsukikage needs surgery, and yet…
Go home!
Mr. Masumi.
Maya…
You're from Metropolitan Entertainment.
Here.
Excuse me, but…
Then she needs to be hospitalized…
She needs to have surgery as soon as possible.
But they don't have the money to pay.
That's how it was…
Hey, isn't that her?
Yeah, that's her.
Asae!
That's not how you do it!
Don't underestimate it
just because it's a small role.
Get back a little bit.
But Teacher, I want to be up in front
since it's such a small role.
Such a small role!
What do you think a theater play is?!
Even if it's a small role,
it's an important piece in the play.
But listen to yourself.
If you can't even play small roles, then you will never be able to play the main role!
Sorry, Mr. Suzumoto.
I know directing is your job.
Oh, no.
All you young people want is to be in the spotlight, without even showing any talent!
Miss Harada!
Just watch!
Say what you want at practice…
…but once I'm on the stage, it's me who's in control.
Thank you for waiting.
H-Hello, how do you do?
I'm Kitajima Maya.
How's Miss Tsukikage?
I used to compete with her
back in my day.
Huh?
By the way, I heard that you're going from one theater to another.
Yes.
I love acting and I want to become an actress someday.
Acting is all I got.
I hope I can become an actress sometime soon.
I see.
Display joy, anger, sadness and happiness using this chair.
Huh?
You can use any words.
Here, go ahead.
Using the chair…
What should I do?
I've never done this before.
Joy, anger, sadness and happiness.
What should I do using this chair?
Wow!
You bought me a new chair!
Great!
Thank you, Mom!
I wanted a new chair.
Oh, look!
There's a scratch on the back, how bad!
Why am I so unlucky…?
Well!
I can go exchange it for a better one.
Good, you're okay.
Sit on this chair.
What's going on?
Miss Harada is putting her to the test.
Here, now!
Sit on the tipped chair…
What is she doing?
She said to sit on the chair,
but she's on the floor?
Why did you take that pose?
W-Well, the chair is tipped, so if I was sitting on this chair, then I would be tipped, too.
I see.
The pose goes best with the tipped chair.
I'm getting what you meant now.
Candidate for "The Crimson Goddess".
I see it now.
Theater is a serious deal.
You never know what happens.
This was to test her theater spirit.
And, how did she do?
Tremendous!
Everyone, be quiet!
I have an announcement to make.
We will no longer keep Yuki Asae as the baby sitter.
Huh?!
Instead, we'll go with Kitajima Maya!
This girl here
will play the baby sitter.
Are you serious, Miss Harada?
It's five days before our first play
and you're switching roles like this?
He's right. And she just walked in right now?
Be quiet!
The decision has been made.
Asae!
Miss Harada.
She should learn from this lesson.
That conceited, big headed girl.
So, you are giving me a role?
Yes.
Isn't that what you wanted?
Here's the script.
Try your best.
But what about that girl?
Don't mind her.
All you need to do is try your best.
If you make mistakes,
we'll fire you too, okay?
Yes!
I can act again now!
I can be on stage again!
Miss Tsukikage,
the door is opening up for me.
Teacher!
Teacher.
Maya.
Where's Teacher?
Where is she?
Don't worry about Miss Tsukikage.
Rei, what happened to her?
She was admitted
to the University Medical Center.
So, she's in the hospital?
Yeah.
I just came back from taking her there.
But…
But what about all the money?
Well, they say we don't have to worry about it.
Someone has paid for it all. He even chartered us a car to go to the hospital.
Someone?
He sent a gift, too.
What do you think it is, Maya?
A gift?
Here, close your eyes.
Okay…
You can open them now.
Oh, that's him.
Mr. Purple Rose!
Yes. It's your secret admirer.
Here. He sent a fan letter with it, too.
"I finally found out where you live, and then learned that Miss Tsukikage is very ill."
"I don't want to be meddlesome,
but please accept my good intentions."
"I'm waiting for the day
I can see you on the stage again."
Waiting…
Eishin Za
Please watch me, Mr. Purple Rose.
You'll get your share, girl.
It is lonely by myself…
…and I almost stumble.
Somewhere calls me here,
just like a whisper in the wind.
Purple light, shining down
on the horizon…
…more surer than words…
…telling us gently…
…that we'll meet
each other someday.
Of course you can
fly from far away…
…for the dream
on my cheek…
…belongs to you.
Eishin Za's owner, Harada Kikuko made Maya play the role of the babysitter.
Asae, blind from the lust for vengeance,
aims to take the first opportunity for revenge.
Please look forward to the next episode:
"Stage Storm".