A mask which is as fragile as glass,
people wear it to hide their own faces.
THE GLASS MASK
On the stage, with the lights off,
blue shadows emerge.
Dancing 'round to hear the applause,
I listen carefully to an
unpredictable tomorrow.
Everyone has a dream
with stars in their heart.
Stage light: a moment to shine,
this city becomes a shining star.
The flower in my heart
is as fragile as glass, a shinin' dream.
You can do it if you want it,
so hold on tight to love,
because there's someone that smiles
on the other side of my tears.
You can do it if you want it,
this feeling in my heart…
Don't cry. Keep on running
and running, for someday!
Maya had been going from one theatre
to another trying to get a job as an actress.
One day Miss Tsukikage collapsed,
but she was able to get medical care
thanks to help from Mr. Purple Rose.
In the meantime, Maya's talent was
recognized by Kikuko Harada of Eishin Za,
and she obtained her first
role in the performing arts.
East University Medical Center
—Episode 11—
Stage Storm
Really?
It's called "A Woman's River".
Yeah.
I play the role of Tazu,
a babysitter.
Screenplay
The heroine marries into
a patriotic family in the Meiji era,
pursuing her true desires as a woman.
It's very dramatic.
Wow, that's a real woman's story!
Maya, are you going to be okay?
Anyhow, seeing you go
to so many theatres,
you have a lot of guts
when it comes to acting.
Do your best, Maya.
Teacher.
Your play at Eishin Za
with Kikuko Harada
will mean so much
to you as an actress.
Teacher…
It has been such a long time,
Miss Harada.
Oh, how lovely to see you,
Mrs. Himekawa.
You too, Miss Ayumi.
You have grown into
such a beautiful lady.
I have heard about
your involvement
in "The Prince and the Pauper"
at Fujinaga Hall.
Yes, I would like to try
many different roles.
My daughter is one day hoping
to play the Crimson Goddess.
"The Crimson Goddess".
Yes.
She has become one of my strongest
rivals, is that not wonderful?
There is another young lady
you should be keeping an eye on.
I have encountered
another rival for you.
Another rival?
It can't be…!
I have cast a girl named
Kitajima Maya from Tsukikage Theatre.
Kitajima Maya…
My guess is that
Miss Tsukikage wishes to see
her attempt to become
the Crimson Goddess.
Attempt to become
the Crimson Goddess?
"The Crimson Goddess"?
Mr. Masumi,
is there something wrong?
No, nothing.
Mr. Masumi?
Maya.
She's the candidate
for the Crimson Goddess?
No, I won't lose.
Not to her.
Sleep tight, and smile.
Oh, babysitting is so boring.
Sleep tight, and smile…
I had doubts about her,
but she's doing pretty good.
Yeah.
Why in the world did
Miss Harada choose her over me?
Just watch, you'll see.
See you tomorrow.
Oh, Sakurakōji!
I just thought I'd drop by.
Your first day is coming up.
Yeah.
I can't believe I get
to perform again!
Practicing has felt
so good lately.
Sounds like you're
back to normal.
You don't mind forgetting about theatre
for a little and hanging out with me, right?
No worries.
Get your T-shirts here!
Wow! I've never seen
anything like this before!
Oh, crepes.
I'll get one for you.
What would you like?
Chocolate.
No way!
Ayumi?
Why is Ayumi here
looking like this?
She is an incredible genius.
So why?
To learn about a beggar's life
for "The Prince and the Pauper"?
But still…
Kitajima Maya.
I refuse to let you win.
I have been called
a genius my whole life,
but I must prove
that my talent outstrips yours.
You may be the candidate
for the Crimson Goddess now,
but I will prove to Miss Tsukikage
that I am a more deserving actress.
Sakurakōji.
So, that really was her?
Yeah, I heard she goes everywhere
looking and acting like that.
The theatre members
are all pretty shocked.
I guess she's unsatisfied with just being
talented, now she's getting more experience
so that someday she can play
the Crimson Goddess.
The Crimson Goddess.
Oh.
Maya?
Ayumi hopes to play
the Crimson Goddess?
That genius, Ayumi?
Maya…
Fujinaga Hall
"The Prince and the Pauper"
There are so many kids.
Must be summer vacation.
Many kids love
Ayumi for her beauty.
I'm a little worried about how
everyone will receive her new look.
Oh, I'm so hungry.
That's Himekawa Ayumi!?
No… No way!
Where's the money
you got today?
It's you, old man?
I got nothin'.
Watch how you talk.
No dinner for you today, then.
Mom, I don't like that Ayumi.
Let's go home.
Be quiet.
So it was a mistake, then…
Let's go home.
I've had it. Let's go!
I hear ya, old man.
I'll go make some money.
Excuse me, Mr. and Mrs.
Please have mercy
and spare some change.
Ayumi!
Excuse me, excuse me.
Nice ta meetcha,
the name's Tom Canty.
Look at that candy!
It looks so good.
You really givin' that to me?
Thank ya so much!
What is she doing going around
the audience like that?
But the audience's attitude
has completely changed.
"The Prince and the Pauper"
had an excellent first day.
"The genius Himekawa Ayumi
proved her talent."
"Playing two roles in one play"…
Such good reviews.
Today is my first day.
I'll do it my own way,
and I'll do my best.
Eishin Za
"A Woman's River"
Wow, all adults.
Mostly old men
and women, too.
What's wrong?
Miss Harada.
Audiences can be very different,
depending on the theatre or the play.
You will find they react very differently,
even if your acting remains the same.
What type of audiences
have you had?
Hmm…
Mostly students
and younger people.
I see.
Then it will be
a good experience.
We will see how what the audience
of Eishin Za thinks of your acting.
The atmosphere is really different
from what I'm used to.
What am I, really?
As his wife,
I'm just a tool to him.
A tool to raise a son.
What's the reason
for me to live?
I'm afraid.
Can my acting be accepted?
H-Hey, are you okay?
This is not good.
You're up.
It's my scene.
I'm Tazu.
Miss.
The babysitter is here.
Her name is Tazu.
Hey, Tazu, greet her!
Yes!
I'm Tazu!
Your house is so big!
I heard it's best to babysit
at a rich house, but it's true!
A village chief told me I can get
three cups of white rice, is that true?
Now, Tazu, come inside.
Here, Tazu, this way.
Okay!
Now then, Chief.
The reason I called you was…
The audience is looking at her.
She has stolen all the attention
from us, the lead roles!
W-Why is everyone
laughing so hard?
What did I do wrong?
She stands out so much!
She's just a normal girl, but when
she's on stage, she really stands out.
Her acting isn't
all that great, either.
Kitajima Maya.
Don't think you're on top of the world.
I'll make it so you won't be able
to stand on stage ever again.
Mr. Masumi.
You can only stay for thirty minutes
if you want to make the next meeting.
I know.
What? There's no doll?
I just saw it right there,
but now it's gone.
Can't find it?
She can't get on stage
if there's no doll.
Here! I got it!
It was sitting in the back room.
Oh, good.
How strange,
I was sure I saw it here.
Here, hurry.
Thank you.
Babysitter, you're up.
Yes.
Sleep tight, little baby!
Oh, that's her.
Yeah, that's her.
Sleep tight, little baby…
Oh, baby-sitting is so boring.
They work me so hard,
and I only get one cup of rice.
That village chief
was a big liar.
Here, don't cry. The crows
will laugh at you if you cry.
Sleep tight…
little baby…
Oh!
Theatre is no joke.
Go ahead and cry,
you'll never get on stage again.
Miss Harada!
You sit back there
like I told you.
Oh, it ain't easy
babysitting you.
No way!?
I can't believe it!
Wonderful theatre spirit,
little girl.
The future Crimson Goddess…
She sure is something else!
Okay, that's enough babysitting.
Let's go home.
Sleep tight…
little baby…
I thought I would die…
I can't believe it!
Now people think
even more highly of her.
Fujinaga Hall
"The Prince and the Pauper"
It's as popular as ever.
Tickets are sold out every day.
Ms. Ayumi will monopolize
all the tabloid news for this summer.
Everything You Need to Know
About the Girl Genius, Himekawa Ayumi
But she must be out of her mind
to aim for "The Crimson Goddess".
You're right.
The play rights
are Miss Tsukikage's.
There's no way she will let
Ayumi from Ondine play the role.
No.
Miss Tsukikage
is only looking for talent.
If Miss Tsukikage
recognizes Ayumi's talent,
she will consider her for
"The Crimson Goddess", too.
No way!
I'm Tom!
I'm not Edward.
I keep telling you, I'm Tom.
What are you talking about?
Let me go.
Let me go!
Let me go—
Teacher…
Eishin Za
"A Woman's River"
Wow, I get chills.
I don't know
if I can be your little cupid.
Don't you think she gets more and more
of the audience's attention every minute?
Yes, have you noticed
the audience's eyes?
They've all turned away from Shino,
and they're looking at her.
If she had a bigger role,
she would have easily overtaken us.
Maya was doing great
on the stage.
For some reason though,
Miss Harada's strict gaze did not soften.
What's that girl's name?
Right…
She's not on the program.
Then look her up.
She's pretty interesting.
We might want her
for our theatre.
Miss Harada.
She's pretty good, isn't she?
Would you like her
for our next play?
Miss Harada?
No…
This will be her last role.
Huh?
But why?
You were the one
who wanted to use her.
She could be a huge risk.
It all depends on how you cast her.
Especially here at Eishin Za.
W-What do you mean?
She has an incredible fate.
Yes, a fate called Stage Storm.
Stage Storm?
Please tell me, Ms. Harada,
what do you mean by Stage Storm?
It is lonely by myself,
and I almost stumble.
Something calls me here,
just like a whisper in the wind.
Purple light, shining down
on the horizon,
more sure than words,
telling us gently
that we'll meet
each other someday.
Of course you can
fly from far away,
for the dream
on my cheek
belongs to you.
Tōyō Theatre invites Maya to audition for
the role of Catherine in "Wuthering Heights"
but she struggles, not being able
to grasp Heathcliff's role.
Please look forward to the next episode:
"I'm Catherine".