A mask which is as fragile as glass,
people wear it to hide their own faces.
THE GLASS MASK
On the stage, with the lights off…
…blue shadows emerge.
Dancing 'round to hear the applause…
…I listen carefully to an unpredictable tomorrow.
Everyone has a dream…
…with stars in their heart.
Stage light: a moment to shine…
…this city becomes a shining star.
The flower in my heart
is as fragile as glass, a shinin' dream.
You can do it if you want to,
so hold on tight to love…
…because there's someone that smiles
on the other side of my tears.
You can do it if you want to,
this feeling in my heart…
Don't cry. Keep on running
and running for someday…
and running, for someday…
Maya's rival, Ayumi, has increased
her reputation even further…
…with her acting in "The Prince and the Pauper."
So has Maya, who gained the public's attention
playing a small baby sitter role at Eishin Za.
However, Harada Kikuko
of Eishin Za fears her talent…
…calling it a stage storm, that separates
Maya from the other actors on the stage.
—Episode 12—
I'm Catherine
"The Prince and the Pauper"
One of my friends in college
is putting a small acting group together…
…and is looking for some people
to work backstage with equipment and stuff.
Thank you.
Free People
We have a children's play at a kindergarten
and we would like you to come…
…but I wonder if it will be okay,
since you are still in junior high…
Yes!
I'll do the best I can!
Manpuku Ken
Maya… I wonder what she's up to now.
Having a crazy dream
to become an actress and all.
I hope she's not hurt and crying and stuff.
Blood! Oh my gosh.
About the Metropolitan Town Building,
which will open next October…
…the decisions regarding tenants, including several
boutiques and restaurants, have all been made.
What about the opening play for
the Metropolitan Theater on the 10th floor?
Yes, we have decided on the play
"The Miracle Worker," about Helen Keller.
Hmm. "The Miracle Worker,"
about the blind girl.
We're planning to audition for the role of Helen,
but the best candidate so far is Himekawa Ayumi.
That's right.
She has gotten much better
since "The Prince and the Pauper."
But, she does have one rival.
What?
Mr. Masumi, the next meeting is about to start.
I know.
Mr. Masumi, who is this rival
of Himekawa Ayumi's?
You have a lot of time until next summer…
…so do some research and get
as many good candidates for Helen as you can.
I wonder who Himekawa Ayumi's rival is.
Fukune Kindergarten
Hello.
Oh, no, there has been an accident on the road?
Excuse me…
The members will be a little late due to traffic.
Oh, that's not good.
We can't have these kids waiting any longer.
Hey, everyone, be quiet, quiet!
The people from the acting group
will be a little late, so let's hear some stories first.
A long, long time ago,
there was a fair skinned, beautiful princess.
People called her Snow White.
This is not working…
You're a big boy, don't cry.
But it hurts!
Good boy, but don't cry.
Okay, I'll tell you the rest of the story.
Snow White's mother, the queen,
was really a scary witch.
Everyday she would stand up
in front of a big mirror, and say:
"Mirror, mirror on the wall…"
"Who is the fairest of them all?"
Then the mirror would say:
"The most beautiful woman
in the world is you, my Queen."
But one day, she asked the same question,
and the mirror answered:
"The most beautiful woman
in the world is Snow White."
O-Oh, I…
That's okay.
Why don't you continue playing
till the members get here?
In fact, on stage.
Yeah, please!
Do it!
But I…
Long time no see, Miss Tsukikage.
I know, it's been so long.
That girl is scary.
I know.
The play she played on was stormed.
All the audience was looking at her,
even though she only had a small role.
Anyone who stands on the stage with her
is in her way, and becomes a shadow of her.
So, I decided that I shouldn't use her anymore.
I don't want Eishin Za to be
messed up because of her.
Her talent can be a threat to other actors.
While she's young, I bet she will be envied…
…and get kicked out of many theaters
because of her talent.
But, Miss Harada, she will get
her recognition someday—
Because people want to see her more.
Yes.
There will be a day
when she will be supported by the people.
It will come.
We're so late.
Yeah, I bet the kids must be out of control.
Oh, you'll give me that red apple?
I'm sorry, but I'm not supposed
to eat anything from strangers.
"But, young lady…"
Oh! The members are here.
Oh, I'm sorry!
I didn't notice you here.
Oh no, I apologize for being late.
Okay, everyone, the members are here,
so big sister's story is over.
No, I want to hear her!
Her story!
She has so much talent.
I'm really sorry, but since the kids are like this,
would you mind waiting till Snow White is over?
No.
I'm sorry about this.
Hey…
What can we do?
The kids want to see her play.
Okay, everyone.
Big sister will finish Snow White.
She took our stage.
Then, we're all done.
Thank you very much.
It seems like she was just telling a story,
but it was definitely a one-person play.
It's not sophisticated, but she had something
that grabbed everyone's attention.
That's the real attraction of actors.
Shirayuri College
Here are your earnings for the day.
Thank you very much.
Also, you don't have to come anymore.
Huh?
W-Why?
You've hurt our pride.
They're just envious, Maya.
You were kicked out because of your talent.
Just forget about it, Maya!
Let's think about something that you like.
– Something that I like…
– You like acting, right?
Rei…
No matter what happens, you have acting.
As long as you don't throw that away,
acting won't throw you away.
Right?
Acting. Yes.
No matter what happens,
I have acting.
No matter what!
What a girl.
She was so depressed just a minute ago,
but she cheers up just by thinking about acting.
Huh…
What?
The young Catherine from "Wuthering Heights?"
Yes.
The president of Tōyō Theater
saw you acting for Eishin Za before.
He would like you to come
and audition for Catherine's role.
Wow, Maya!
That's great!
Catherine's role!
It's when she's young,
but that's a main role!
Please wait in the waiting room
till the audition starts.
The other two are already here.
Yes.
Wuthering Heights
Here's the script for the audition.
Read it thoroughly and memorize it.
Yes.
I wonder who he is.
Everyone, please meet Majima Ryo,
who will play the young Heathcliff.
Nice to meet you all.
The young Heathcliff?
Let me introduce everyone.
Mr. Murase, the chief director
for "Wuthering Heights."
Mr. Sawaki, the director.
Mr. Suzumura, the producer.
Ms. Natsu Eriko,
who will play Catherine…
…and Mr. Hideaki Kagawa,
who will play Heathcliff.
Now, we'll begin the audition.
Please state your name
and age, please.
Tanaka Keiko, 14.
Egawa Yuki, 16.
Kitajima Maya, 15.
Ms. Egawa, you're from the same theater as
Majima Ryo, who'll play the young Heathcliff, right?
Yes.
Ms. Egawa, have you ever read
"Wuthering Heights?"
Yes, of course.
What about you, Ms. Tanaka?
Yes, I've read it.
Ms. Kitajima?
No, I haven't.
Hmm. Ms. Tanaka, what do you think
about the heroine, Catherine?
Shoot!
I think she's passionate and a great woman.
I see.
What about you, Ms. Egawa?
I love her passionate love towards Heathcliff…
I should have read it.
Maya had to take the audition without knowing
the story of "Wuthering Heights"…
…nor the role of Catherine.
Okay, please come out as Catherine, Ms. Egawa.
Yes.
Ms. Tanaka.
What should I do?
I don't know how Catherine walks.
Ms. Kitajima.
Ms. Kitajima!
I'm sorry, I haven't read
"Wuthering Heights…"
…so I don't know
how to walk as Catherine.
I'm so sorry.
It was beyond description how the audition went
for Maya not knowing Catherine's role.
Oh, no, I couldn't wear the mask of Catherine.
I really want to get this role.
I want to be on stage with you.
You will be fine.
You were the best.
You are the only one to be my lover.
Even on stage.
Ryo.
So, Egawa Yuki, huh?
Yes, she had the atmosphere
and everything.
Anyhow, what's up
with the girl, Kitajima Maya?
She just could not give 100% of her talent.
Mr. President!
Since she didn't understand
who Catherine really was.
But, it will be easier to train her rather than
the others who already have presumptions.
We'll announce Catherine's role.
It wouldn't be me anyway.
Ms. Kitajima Maya.
Kitajima Maya?
M-Me?
Re-Really?
Yes.
You'll play Catherine.
I can't believe it.
Let's do our best.
Y-Yes.
Why?
Well, learn from everyone…
Excuse me, but can you tell me why,
why she was chosen?
In one word – possibility.
Possibility?
No way.
This girl will play Catherine?
No way!
It's nice to meet you.
Y-You too.
Ryo, I wanted to be
your lover on stage, too.
You must understand, this is a big bet
for us to give you the role, too.
You have to do the best
you can, okay?
Y-Yes!
Catherine. I'm Catherine.
Catherine…
Congratulations, Maya!
She's been like this all night.
She hasn't even noticed that we're here.
What can I do
to become Catherine?
To understand people, you have to understand
the circumstances in which they were brought up.
Then, you will start understanding little by little.
Circumstances.
The circumstances she grew up with.
Heathcliff, why did you come back?
No, I know.
To destroy everything!
Natsu, great work!
It's only a script reading,
but look at her powerful acting!
Heathcliff!
Wow, a Catherine that's
passionate, selfish and wild.
I'm not understanding Catherine yet.
The most painful punishment for Catherine
is not being able to play with Heathcliff.
But what about Heathcliff?
Not to be with Catherine.
The most painful punishment for Catherine
is not being able to be with Heathcliff.
That's Kazuo.
He's looking at us!
Oh, no!
He's so hardheaded.
And he smells, too.
You go play by yourself!
Ouch! Hey, what do you think you're doing?
We'll never play with you again!
Oh, are you okay?
Oh, no!
You're bleeding.
No one's her.
Mom and Dad are both at work.
Wow!
Shiny cars!
My dad bought it for me.
Can I play with this?
Yeah. Let's race each other.
I'll be the police car.
Okay.
Ready, get set, go!
Wow, I wonder how many years it has been
since we've been able to play with toys like this.
Play?
I wonder if Heathcliff and Catherine played?
They didn't have any other friends…
…nor all these toys.
Kazuo!?
Oh, Mom!
Welcome home!
Oh, hi, nice to meet you.
W-Where are you from?
This girl here,
she helped me when I fell.
Here, look!
Oh, thank you very much,
and to play with Kazuo as well.
My pleasure.
Hey, let's play with this again!
Here, this one.
Here, Kazuo…
…big sister has to go home soon.
It's getting late now.
Yes, that's right.
Kazuo…
Kazuo!
No, don't go yet!
Stop crying.
No, don't go, don't go!
Kazuo…
I'm sorry.
In the daytime,
he's usually by himself.
So he must be really happy
that you played with him.
No, don't go, sister.
Sister!
Kazuo, he's so cute.
But poor Kazuo,
he's always all alone.
No!
All alone?
To understand people you have to understand
the circumstances in which they were brought up.
Catherine!
She lives in the middle of nowhere.
There was no one to play with,
and she was all alone.
The only person to play with
was Heathcliff.
They didn't have any toys,
but all they had was each other.
Heathcliff for Catherine,
and Catherine for Heathcliff.
She's honest to her true feelings,
and so she's wild and selfish.
No, no!
I can…
I can become Catherine!
It is lonely by myself…
…and I almost stumble.
Somewhere calls me here,
just like a whisper in the wind.
Purple light, shining down
on the horizon…
…more surer than words…
…telling us gently…
…that we'll meet
each other someday.
Of course you can
fly from far away…
…for the dream
on my cheek…
…belongs to you.
Maya steps up on the stage, trying to grasp
the passion between Catherine and Heathcliff.
There, she feels a dangerous feeling in her heart
that goes beyond the world of acting.
Please look forward to the next episode:
"Love is Like a Mosaic."