A mask which is as fragile as glass,
people wear it to hide their own faces.
THE GLASS MASK
On the stage, with the lights off,
blue shadows emerge.
Dancing 'round to hear the applause,
I listen carefully to an
unpredictable tomorrow.
Everyone has a dream
with stars in their heart.
Stage light: a moment to shine,
this city becomes a shining star.
The flower in my heart
is as fragile as glass, a shinin' dream.
You can do it if you want it,
so hold on tight to love,
because there's someone that smiles
on the other side of my tears.
You can do it if you want it,
this feeling in my heart…
Don't cry. Keep on running
and running, for someday!
Maya unexpectedly received the role of
young Catherine in "Wuthering Heights",
but she struggled to understand
Catherine's strong love for Heathcliff.
One day, she met a lonely
young boy named Kazu,
and finally she found
a way to portray her role.
—Episode 13—
Love is Like a Mosaic
I'm off to practice!
Practice?
It starts at one o'clock.
Tōyō Theatre Entrance
Authorized personnel only
Good morning!
Morn—
What?!
Why's she here at this hour?
Tōyō Theatre
I've got no idea what the president was thinking.
I know, it's his obsession with potential…
That Maya girl doesn't even have
anything that shines about her.
It's impossible to get
anything special out of her.
Well, I guess we just have to try.
Good morning!
All right, I'll see you after practice.
Yeah.
It's good that Egawa Yuki agreed
to be on standby, Mr. Sawaki.
She's just right for Catherine.
I agree. If Kitajima Maya doesn't do well, then…
Exactly. She's bound to make lots of mistakes.
Let's start the scene
with young Catherine and Heathcliff.
Yes!
No, let go!
Now that our father is dead,
I'm the man of the house.
Heathcliff will be treated
as a servant from now on.
Do you understand, Catherine?
I won't allow you to play with a servant.
No, let me go!
I won't stop being close to Heathcliff,
no matter what you say!
I love Heathcliff!
Catherine!
Don't go, Heathcliff!
Don't go!
Don't go home!
Heathcliff!
Hmm, she's pretty good.
These young ones are gonna
keep us adults on our toes.
Hey, are you okay?
Ouch, she bit me for real!
All right, all right, enough of the
love scenes. Give me some attention too.
Oh, what did I—
Look at this bite mark.
Oh, I'm sorry, I…
What a girl.
Her passion, her wildness…
I was taken by her acting.
I hope you'll like this.
I knitted it.
It took me a month.
You can wear this all the time,
even when I'm not around.
Oh, thanks.
I know you, Ryo.
That girl, Kitajima Maya…
She's the one who's on your mind.
I know it.
I know everything about you.
Tell me, Ryo, what's so attractive about her?
She's so plain and rough.
Forget about the play
for a moment and talk to me.
I'm prettier than she is.
I'm a better actress than she is.
She only got the role because because
the president's interested in her.
She's gonna mess up soon.
Then I'll get to be Catherine.
Hey, Ryo!
Why don't you shut up
for a minute!
Oh!
Sakurakōji!
I stopped by your apartment,
they told me you'd be here.
Here, eat this before it gets cold.
Wow!
Thank you.
This is delicious!
Gift
I'm impressed with your guts.
Hmm?
To come and see me.
I'm seriously concerned
about your health, Miss Tsukikage.
As long as "The Crimson Goddess"
remains in my possession, right?
Go ahead and take it.
A cold and cruel person like you
must have many ways, Mr. Masumi.
I want to acquire it legitimately.
One day I'll succeed.
You're playing Catherine?
That's awesome!
Hey, here's an idea.
Could you read Heathcliff's lines for me?
It's hard to get the feel for it all by myself.
I get to play your boyfriend?
All right!
They said we can't play
with each other, but we sneak out…
And here we are, Heathcliff.
I hope my brother doesn't catch us.
D-don't worry. If he comes,
then I'll hit him good.
Don't go anywhere.
Stay by my side forever.
Please stay with me forever.
If you wish.
I am you, and you are me.
We are united as one soul.
Promise me that we will stay
the same when we're older.
Your real father is an emperor of China,
and your real mother is a queen of India.
You'll leave here someday,
get rich, and come back to get me…
You are not looking at me.
The person in your eyes is not me.
The person you're in love with is Heathcliff.
I wonder if…
What's wrong?
I… I'm not Heathcliff.
I don't want to be
a substitute or a shadow!
Sakurakōji, what's wrong?
Why are you upset?
Cafe Bidoro
Here, cheer up.
But, Sakurakōji was…
Things will go back to normal soon.
But how?
How about sending him a ticket
for the premiere of "Wuthering Heights"?
Okay!
You only need to concentrate
on Catherine right now.
Let Sakurakōji see your wonderful Catherine.
Okay.
Tōyō Theatre
As the opening day approached,
the synergy between Maya and Ryo,
and Kagawa and Natsu intensified.
Catherine, we'll stay together forever.
I am you, and you are me.
We are united as one soul!
Yes.
Mr. Majima's words sound so real lately.
I wonder if they're actually in love.
No way!
Heathcliff.
We'll be together forever.
Forever.
– Great work.
– Good bye.  – Later.
Maya, let's walk home together.
C-Chilly…
It is chilly.
Oh yeah, here.
That's my present!
Tōyō Theatre
Today is the premiere of "Wuthering Heights".
This hall is huge.
My heart's beating so fast!
I wonder if Maya's gonna be alright.
She'll be fine. Once she's on stage,
nothing can stop her.
I'm kind of anxious.
Catherine Earnshaw…
Now I'll wear your mask.
We will be as one.
Miss Tsukikage,
Mr. Purple Rose, Sakurakōji…
Please watch me.
He isn't here…
What's wrong?
Looking for something?
That seat's reserved for Sakurakōji.
Oh, Maya's boyfriend…
The play's about to start.
He'll show up.
I hope so.
Maya's rival, Himekawa Ayumi was present.
Yuki, who passionately loved Majima Ryo,
was there too.
Calm down.
I'm Catherine.
I love Heathcliff.
Just like Kazu, if Heathcliff is gone,
then I'll be all alone.
I don't want to be alone!
Maya.
Let's do our best, Maya.
Get ready, please.
What did you say?
You want me to get along
with Heathcliff?
Hell no!
You are so patient.
Hmph, I'll kick him out
of the Heights someday!
Wearing my shoes, wearing my clothes…
Who do you think you are!?
Don't!
Don't, Brother!
Heathcliff has done nothing wrong!
Nothing wrong!
Get out of the way!
How dare you touch Catherine!
With his passionate acting, the actor
for Hindley had cut Majima Ryo's lip.
This accident was about to cause
a problem for the flow of the play.
I have to do something.
I have to help Heathcliff.
W-What would Heathcliff do?
What would Catherine do?
You are so good.
Even when you're bleeding,
you don't even complain.
I love that about you.
Maya…
Let's go, Heathcliff!
Try to catch me. Come on.
Come on, hurry!
Try to catch me.
Catherine, you are the only person
I love in this world.
You love me,
my everything, my soul!
What were you thinking,
ripping your costume like that?!
Catherine!
That kindness.
To be able to do that
in a blink of an eye, you must love Majima.
Here, hurry up.
I love you!
Despite the feelings of Yuki and Sakurakōji, who
refused to believe Maya and Ryo were in love,
the love between Heathcliff and Catherine
was getting more and more passionate.
Heathcliff.
Those two.
I hope they didn't forget their words.
Look at them, even when they're silent
the audience's attention never wavers.
What a girl.
Now, let's go together.
Let's go.
We finally ran away, Heathcliff.
I hope my brother doesn't catch us.
Don't worry. If he comes,
then I'll hit him good.
Don't go anywhere!
Those eyes…
You are me, and I am you.
We are united as one soul.
Promise me that
we won't change when we grow up.
Yes, Heathcliff!
Mr. Hayami.
Let's talk
If you love her, then watch until the end.
I love her. That's why
I can't watch anymore.
Go back to your seat!
You, you'll never understand how I feel!
Excuse me!
As long as you live here,
I'll stay here in the Heights.
I'll put up with anything.
Heathcliff, we'll be together forever.
It's our turn now.
Kind of awkward to go out now.
We are better-known actors and our scenes
are longer, but I don't feel so confident.
Come on, we're the main roles here.
We can't let her steal the show.
Dressing room
I wonder if Sakurakōji was watching.
Natsu Eriko and Kagawa Hideaki
performed very well too,
and "Wuthering Heights" ended up
having a very successful premiere.
Sakurakōji… I told him to wait here in the letter.
Are you looking for Heathcliff, Catherine?
You did really well.
Passionate and wild Catherine…
Yes, that was true, but…
It was sort of like a little child
whose toy was taken away.
Not the kind of passionate love for a lover.
Not a passionate love for a lover?
Seems like you have much more
to learn about acting out love, little girl.
Hurry and grow up, little girl.
My name is not "little girl"!
Huh…?
How was Kitajima Maya?
Was she playing Catherine in love well?
She doesn't know real love yet.
Mr. Majima was so great!
I know!
Hey, Maya. I'll take you home.
Ryo…
I was waiting for you.
You can give me a ride home, right?
Kitajima Maya, Kitajima Maya.
There's a phone call for you.
Oh, that might be Sakurakōji!
Hi, this is Maya.
What?
What are you saying, Rei?!
You're not serious, are you?
Miss Tsukikage is about to pass away?
Don't die! Please, don't die!
You promised me that you wouldn't die
until you direct "The Crimson Goddess".
Don't give in to the illness.
Don't die!
Operating room in use
No… No!
Don't die!
Teacher!
It is lonely by myself,
and I almost stumble.
Something calls me here,
just like a whisper in the wind.
Purple light, shining down
on the horizon,
more surer than words,
telling us gently
that we'll meet
each other someday.
Of course you can
fly from far away,
for the dream
on my cheek
belongs to you.
The plan to bring back
Tsukikage Theatre begins.
Maya plays the role of an immobilized doll.
To make her movement look stiff,
she ties her limbs to bamboo sticks, but…
Please look forward to the next episode:
"My New Role as a Doll".