A mask which is as fragile as glass,
people wear it to hide their own faces.
THE GLASS MASK
On the stage, with the lights off…
…blue shadows emerge.
Dancing 'round to hear the applause…
…I listen carefully to an
unpredictable tomorrow.
Everyone has a dream…
…with stars in their heart.
Stage light: a moment to shine…
…this city becomes a shining star.
The flower in my heart
is as fragile as glass, a shinin' dream.
You can do it if you want to,
so hold on tight to love…
…because there's someone that smiles
on the other side of my tears.
You can do it if you want to,
this feeling in my heart…
Don't cry. Keep on running
and running, for someday…
The first day of "Wuthering Heights" has started.
The passionate love of Catherine was displayed on stage.
Seeing that, Sakurakōji's and Yuki's heart was moved.
Around that time, Maya learned that Miss Tsukikage's condition has worsened.
—Episode 14—
My New Role as a Doll
Tōgō University Hospital
Huh?
No, no. It's impossible
for my teacher to die.
Operating room in use
I still have so many things
that I have to learn from her.
Operating room in use
Please, don't leave me, Teacher!
How is she?
How is the operation going?
It's been two hours already.
Operating room in use
Two hours?
That type of lifestyle…
It was just too much for her body to take.
Her heart was already bad, and then she had to go through the breakup of Tsukikage Theater.
It sure was too much.
That's right. It's all because of that man from Metropolitan Entertainment.
Operating room in use
Doctor!
How was the surgery?
We did the best we could.
It's up to her will to live now.
Teach—
Besides the time she spent
at school and on stage…
…Maya spent all her time by Miss Tsukikage,
waiting for her to wake up.
It has been four day since the surgery.
If you know of any relatives,
please let them know.
If she doesn't regain consciousness tonight,
then she might be through.
She's… about to die?
No!
That can't happen!
Maya!
Teacher!
You told me you would train me.
You told me you would teach me acting!
Maya…
Please, don't take my dream of being "The Crimson Goddess" away from me!
"The Crimson Goddess…"
I can't die… until I finish that project for this world.
Oh, she's conscious.
Teacher!
Maya…
Listen to me.
The Actresses who will play "The Crimson Goddess…"
…are you…
…and another.
Another?
Teacher, who is that person?
You will know soon.
Here, you need to go outside.
Don't excite her too much.
Maya…
Maya, fight for it.
If you lose, the other person will take "The Crimson Goddess."
Yes.
My face is burning,
so is my heart.
I'm a candidate
for "The Crimson Goddess?"
I'm always being corrected by her.
I can't believe it.
My dream is about to come true.
I don't know who this other person is,
but I won't give up.
That day, "Wuthering Heights"
had come to its last day.
I will die while you will become rich, Heathcliff.
Catherine.
Heathcliff.
If you love her, watch her
till the end, no matter what.
Maya, why did you want me
to come and see your play?
I'm hurt to see
your love towards each other.
I'm hurt that you
didn't even notice me hurting.
Backstage
Great job!
You guys did a wonderful job!
Can I please get an autograph?
Please sign this!
Yes, sure.
Ms. Kitajima, any words?
Did I lose to her?
No, that's not possible.
Ms. Kitajima.
Huh?
Here's a gift for you?
Thank you.
Ms. Kitajima Maya
That's him!
The man who always encourages me with purple roses.
"Congratulations on the finale of your play."
"I'm glad to see that you get better with each play."
"—Your number one fan,
who is always looking at you."
Here.
Snow, huh?
Watch out!
You dumb ass!
Sorry!
For Kitajima Maya?
No, no way.
B-But, I'm—
I'm told not to let
any more fans in.
Oh, then, give her this.
Give this to Maya, please.
Hey, wait!
Shoot, what can I do?
Maya, you have gone somewhere
where I can't reach you anymore.
If I only could love someone else.
This would have been easy.
So much easier…
Ms. Kitajima Maya
Mr. Purple Rose,
please watch over me.
I will be a much better actress,
and will play "The Crimson Goddess" someday.
Excuse me, Ms. Kitajima.
Here, a high school boy
left it for you.
Yū
Sakurakōji!
Maya!
Catherine…
I don't want to end our relationship.
I will never be able to find a woman like you, Catherine.
Ryo, you are just going after your imagination.
Catherine is gone with the stage of "Wuthering Heights."
Please realize that soon.
Sakurakōji, why didn't you wait for me?
You didn't stay till the end on the first day either.
Why didn't you congratulate me on the play's success?
Oh, Mr. President,
you are still here.
Kitajima Maya was great!
You have a great eye
for choosing her, Mr. President.
It was a mistake.
Huh?
Didn't you notice that the childhood Catherine wasn't in sync with the others?
Well, the critics have written that there's not a smooth
transition from the childhood Catherine to the adult one.
That's right.
She doesn't exactly know what acting is.
Acting is about team work,
and not a one-man play.
We won't be able to use her for a while.
That type of actress
messes up the stage.
Miss Tsukikage's once life-threatening
condition got better and better.
It seems as thought it lost to her passion for "The Crimson Goddess…"
…and she spent most of her days reading scripts.
The heart of Miss Tsukikage moved
from her condition to her next play.
In the meantime, they have joined Ikkakuju Theater,
who were visiting Tōkyō, and planned for a joint play.
The Smile of Stone
This is our next script.
The Smile of Stone.
Now, I'll announce the casting.
Pio, a male swindler: Rei Aoki.
Huh, a swindler?
Me?
The rich daughter, Marisa,
also Hannah the maid…
…Sayaka Miyazuki.
A double role!
The widow, Frederica: Mina Sawatori.
The roles were assigned one after another.
The Countess Isabella: Taiko Kasuga.
Sir Goerge: Satoru Hosoka.
The attorney, Prefew: Hajime Tabe.
The relative, Gallison: Taichi Hotta.
I wonder what I will be.
I'm sure you'll play the main role.
Now, Maya.
Yes!
I will have you play a doll.
A doll?
Yes. A doll who just sits
in the middle of the stage.
You won't have
any movements nor words.
Why, why is she giving me
such a role?
I am Prefew, the attorney.
I heard you called for me.
Mr. Prefew, I wrote a will.
I know I only have
a little time left…
"The Smile of Stone" is about a 12 year old, Marisa, who is about to die after giving away a large portion of her property to a doll.
It is a tragic comedy involving a young widow, a countess, a swindler, and many more.
Maya's role is the doll, Elizabeth.
Oh, I want to move,
or to say something.
This role is no fund,
just sitting around like this.
Miss Tsukikage started training
the group despite her condition.
Then, you will walk towards the doll
and push onto the doll's shoulder.
Very lightly.
Maya!
What are you doing?
You are a doll, not a human.
If you were a real doll, you would lean forward even thought it was a light touch on the shoulder.
Yes.
Countess, go and push the doll again.
Your elbow bent!
A doll wouldn't try to cover her body, would it?
Do it again!
Your hip!
A doll wouldn't fall on her own.
Why would you open your eyes when falling?
A doll doesn't have an expression.
Your body is too soft.
Do it again!
Straighten your neck.
Your neck again.
Do it over!
Teacher!
This is not good for your body.
We should finish for the day.
No!
Maya, continue!
Yes.
I didn't think that the role of a doll
would be this difficult.
Well, in this situation,
I'll become a doll, no matter what!
Give it back!
It's mine!
Let me hold her!
No, you already held her!
Become a doll.
Big sister,
can we have our doll back?
Mama, there's a crazy lady here!
I'm scared!
Would a doll
change her facial expression?
I got the doll's pose.
But, I can't…
I can't quite get the movement of a doll.
Well, but it's too bad that Miss Tsukikage can't come here and train us.
It's a critical time for her now.
I hope she'll get better by the day of the play.
That's why she needs to rest now.
Teacher.
Teacher, shouldn't you be back at the hospital?
I know, if your condition gets worse…
Right, everyone?
I'm okay.
Here, let's get to training.
Maya, come over here.
Huh?
I thought you would be here.
Please go back.
I wouldn't want you
to die just yet.
Maya.
Let her get up by herself!
Mr. Masumi, don't help her up.
What's going on with her?
Hey, you!
No, don't.
Don't.
Take it off.
What is this all about,
Miss Tsukikage?
She's learning the difference between the body of a human and that of a doll.
Humans have numerous joints,
but dolls only have about five.
By putting bamboo all around her body,
she can't use her human joints anymore.
This doll cast should teach her
the movement of a doll.
A doll cast…
You didn't have to do this much.
Hurry! Take her to the hospital.
Yes.
What the hell are you guys thinking?
You and her!
Mr. Masumi, has your father ever told you
the story about my childhood?
A little.
I know your parents died young…
…and so you had to go
through many hardships.
I might have been dead, if Ozaki Ichiren
didn't give me a reason to live.
A reason to live?
Acting.
Because of acting,
I am able to live, no matter what.
I want to give her
the same reason to live, too.
Thank you very much.
Listen, don't do too much of anything just because your wounds are not too bad.
Yes.
No bathing,
nor moving your hand.
Yes, I know.
Thanks!
Does she really know what I'm saying?
I don't want to hear any more about what I can't do.
Little girl,
let me give you a ride home.
No, thank you.
I'd rather walk
than have you give me a ride.
You should accept it when people offer you things.
You are so pushy!
I'm not trying to hurt you or anything.
I just want to take you home safely, little girl.
I'm not a little girl.
I'm about to graduate
from junior high.
And which high school
are you going to go?
I'm not. I'm going to practice acting
while working at a part-time job.
If you want to act, then you will need
at least a high school education.
You should take school
more seriously.
How do you think I can afford it?
I don't have that luxury.
Get away from Miss Tsukikage.
Metropolitan Entertainment will make you a great actress, while supplying you with a scholarship.
That was what you had planned, huh?
I won't do it
even if I was dead.
Even if you were dead…
Okay, take care of your wound.
Screw Metropolitan Entertainment!
You snob!
That reminded me about high school,
thought I was ready to give up…
Manpuku Ken
Here, ramen and a potsticker.
Yes.
Haru, what's wrong with you?
Can't you do something
about that cough?
You're scaring the customers.
Haru, you…
Principal's office
What?
I'm going to high school?
Some noble man said
he would take care of everything…
…from tuition to board,
for the reputable Hitotsuboshi High.
Hitotsuboshi High?
They have great acting programs…
…but, who in the world
did something like this?
Well, I didn't meet him,
but he left something like this.
That's him!
Mr. Purple Rose!
"Please accept my good intentions."
"I'm sure you will be able to learn acting while enjoying your high school days."
"Looking forward to seeing you grow as an actress."
Mr. Purple Rose,
please keep looking after me.
I'll do it.
I'll make it happen.
It is lonely by myself…
…and I almost stumble.
Somewhere calls me here,
just like a whisper in the wind.
Purple light, shining down
on the horizon…
…more surer than words…
…telling us gently…
…that we'll meet
each other someday.
Of course you can
fly from far away…
…for the dream
on my cheek…
…belongs to you.