A mask which is as fragile as glass,
people wear it to hide their own faces.
THE GLASS MASK
On the stage, with the lights off…
…blue shadows emerge.
Dancing 'round to hear the applause…
…I listen carefully to an
unpredictable tomorrow.
Everyone has a dream…
…with stars in their heart.
Stage light: a moment to shine…
…this city becomes a shining star.
The flower in my heart
is as fragile as glass, a shinin' dream.
You can do it if you want to,
so hold on tight to love…
…because there's someone that smiles
on the other side of my tears.
You can do it if you want to,
this feeling in my heart…
Don't cry. Keep on running
and running, for someday…
Practice for "The Smile of Stone," the play that will decide the future of Tsukikage Theater, has started.
Maya's role is a doll who doesn't move at all.
She tries to conceptualize its movements by putting bamboo sticks around her body.
However, around that time, her mother Haru's condition was getting worse and worse.
—Episode 15—
Welcome to
The Underground Theater!
Look at this huge advertisement.
It's put on by Orion Theater.
Their first day is our first day, too.
It will be pretty tough for us.
And where is our theater?
The basement of that building.
There?
We are going to play in the basement of that building?
Basement?
It used to be a cafe,
but it went out of business.
No wonder it went out of business…
Don't complain.
We got this place for free.
Oh, it's dark!
Do you smell the dampness?
Creepy…
The outside is pretty bad…
It's even worse inside.
I'm not sure if we can make this place pleasant.
Welcome to our underground theater!
Yes!
This is our, our theater here.
That's right.
Let's make it look nice.
Let's clean it up.
We can make this a nice place.
This is our home sweet home, right?
Remodeling is up to us now.
Yes!
Hey, let's get to work now!
Yeah!
Look at them.
I wonder why the hell they opened up a theater there.
I know.
What happened to the fame of our theater, the Orion?
Well, we'll get all of the audience here.
They'll go out of business soon.
I wonder if that's true.
Ms. Himekawa.
I just dropped by to see the practice.
You all, you shouldn't underestimate them.
But, neither Ikkakuju Theater
nor Tsukikage Theater is very popular.
They are not even on our level.
Besides, they are not equipped well either.
Do you know about Kitajima Maya?
No.
She's the girl on the truck.
Harada Kikuko called her a "stage storm."
"Stage storm?"
By Harada Kikuko?
We can finally practice, Rei.
She is the stage storm?
You should be careful not to have her storm Orion Theater.
Whew, we're finally done.
Good work.
We have some coffee inside.
Do we have everything we need?
Yup.
Everything is sold as is though.
Oh?
It's raining.
We're lucky we're done carrying everything inside.
Maya, come on in.
You'll get wet.
Rain.
The umbrella!
Excuse me.
Yes.
Excuse me, is Sakurakōji in?
Sakurakōji?
Hey, that's him.
Oh, the one from the donut shop…
…who's with different girls all the time.
Sakurakōji?
You be careful, too.
He's become much of a playboy lately.
Playboy?
I'm so glad Sakurakōji
is asking us out.
Everyone,
eat whatever you want.
It's all on me today.
– Really? Thank you.
– Yes, thank you!
What would you like?
You'll brew it for me?
Sure.
No, your girlfriend will get upset.
You have one, right?
Of course you do, right?
Yeah, used to.
What?
Then, not anymore?
Wow, can I put my name on the list?
No!
Let me…
Well, sure, okay!
Why not!
Yeah. It's a thing of the past.
I should put it behind me.
Maya!
Maya, wait!
Why did I even run after her?
I had just decided to put all this behind me.
I had so many things
I wanted to talk about.
But now it's all gone…
He's doing fine without me.
I might have just been one of those many girls of his after all.
I'm here to give you your umbrella back. Thank you.
You didn't have to worry about it.
Let me walk you to the train station.
There are so many things
I wanted to talk about.
No words can come out.
Bye, Sakurakōji.
Uhh, Maya…
Yes.
You did great in
"Wuthering Heights."
Sakurakōji!
But, I'm not Heathcliff,
unfortunately.
Sakurakōji…
He is as nice as he used to be,
but something is different…
Manpuku Ken
Haru, how are you feeling?
I'm sorry for causing so much trouble.
Well, we wanted to talk to you about something.
How about going…
to a rest home?
We hate to do this,
but we are in the food business.
We cannot keep a sick person
in here like this.
I understand.
You are not going to get better
just laying here.
Then you might as well
concentrate on resting.
Maya will be very worried
once she hears about this.
She is concentrating so much on acting.
The best thing for you is to get better soon, and then come back and work for us again before Maya gets back.
Thank you so much for all of your help for such a long time.
Then, it's okay?
Maya, Maya… Where are you and what are you doing?
In the basement of what used to be a cafe, the practice of "The Smile of Stone" heated up every day.
It's ridiculous to brush her hair everyday.
I'm getting the movement of a doll down little by little.
This is a hard role for Maya.
Yeah, she's on the stage constantly, but allowed no movement at all.
No, what I mean is the time she has to sit still.
Just look at her face.
Sakurakōji, what changed you so much?
I didn't know that it hurts so bad
to have someone you love leave.
Mother! Besides, I haven't
even called her once.
Mother!
No, I didn't
even think about her…
Not once.
I miss you, Mother.
Miss Tsukikage would have done the same.
Rei!
Are you out of your mind?
Thinking about something?
A doll doesn't have any emotions.
Doesn't have any emotions?
That's right.
Nothing in its head, nor in its heart.
That's what a doll is.
You want to learn
the emotion of a doll?
Yes, I think
I'm learning the movement.
But I can't stop thinking
when I'm just sitting around.
You should go visit here.
Sansōji Shrine?
In Saitama Prefecture?
Yes, go there and learn
how to kill your own emotions.
Kill my emotions?
He can teach you
the emotion of a doll there.
Sansōji
This is it.
Look how old it is.
I wonder what she wants me to do here.
You are about to know.
Are you the ones
that Miss Tsukikage sent to me?
Yes.
Then hurry up and come on in.
He seems pretty scary.
I wonder what relationship
he has with Miss Tsukikage.
Miss Tsukikage stayed here
for a while in the past.
He heard us?
Miss Tsukikage…
It has been a while.
Okay, please get into the pose of zazen.
Zazen?
Yes. This is a temple of Zen.
Zen means no mind.
Look what we got ourselves into.
Maya, did you forget about me?
But I haven't forgotten you.
I will live until the day
I see you again.
Here, straighten up your back.
It's hard to achieve emptiness.
There are many minds around,
but look at the stone there.
There are no minds in stones.
Forget that you are a human being,
and become a stone.
Then you will be free from your mind and you will achieve the expression of emptiness on your face.
Think I am a stone
and become… a stone.
A stone doesn't think about
Sakurakōji, nor about mother.
Become a stone…
Become a stone.
Maya, it's been two years
since you left home.
I bet you grew a little, too.
I have cried many times that I don't need you anymore, but I failed.
After all, you are the only daughter I have.
Excuse me, but your magazine…
This is… Maya!
"Natsu Eriko's acting in this play was great, but Kitajima Maya, who played the childhood Catherine, did a fantastic job, doing almost as well as Natsu's role as Catherine."
Maya, this is Maya.
My daughter!
Take a look at this.
My daughter was in a play
with Natsu Eriko!
I can't be sitting
like this anymore.
Ladies and gentlemen,
"The Smile of Stone" will open today at 6:30 PM.
It starts at 6:30 PM.
Don't miss out!
The Smile of Stone
Tsukikage and Ikkakuju Theaters
They'll open today too, I guess.
Look at them. They look like they are trying to draw customers into a cabaret or something.
What can they do?
We have "Hamlet" and they have "The Smile of Stone," which is totally unknown.
Well, we'll see how many people they can get.
It starts at 6:30 PM.
Don't miss out!
Is it selling well?
Not at all.
Only four of them so far.
Four?
Oh, no.
Can I get one, please?
Yes, yes, thank you!
Oh…
Himekawa Ayumi…
I am looking forward
to seeing this.
Yes, yes.
Look how dirty it is here.
Told you we should have gone
to see "Hamlet."
What could have I done?
It was all sold out.
Everyone else here is doing the same:
killing time because they couldn't get a ticket.
Hey, isn't that…
…Himekawa Ayumi!
What is Himekawa Ayumi
doing in here?
Hey, isn't that the guy who played
Heathcliff in "Wuthering Heights?"
Majima Ryo, I think his name was.
Majima Ryo had appeared to see
the remembrance of Catherine…
…not being able to forget Maya's Catherine in "Wuthering Heights."
Wow, we have two starts here!
Huh, what happened?
It's starting.
No, I can't see Ms. Himekawa anymore!
The plane is shaking due to turbulence.
Please wear your seat belt.
I am Prefew, an attorney. I heard you called for me. What can I do for you?
"The Smile of Stone"
has opened its curtain.
After that, the scene continued with Marisa Parsoromeo, a girl…
…who has lost her parents in a plane crash, giving her will to her attorney.
Thank you for gathering here today.
My name is Prefew, an attorney…
Where is Kitajima Maya?
That's Maya!
Maya is playing a doll. Why?
What's her goal?
That's Catherine?
No!
Ayumi?
Ayumi is here.
Mr. Majima, too.
…there are two wills from Marisa here.
May I open them now?
Hello, everyone!
How do you do.
Whoa, who is that?
How good looking!
Then I will open the will.
Marisa Parsoromeo.
Leave all my belongings to my loving doll, Elizabeth.
That's a huge doll.
No, silly!
That's a human.
Oh, you think so?
Prohibited from any facial expression, movement, or words, she's not supposed to act.
That's a hard role.
Catherine, where have you gone?
This is so unfair!
My weekly salary is only 2.50 pounds, and this doll is worth 65 million pounds?
I have to clean her up everyday like this.
How crazy is this?
Here, stay put.
I have to go clean up now.
The doll is the key to the play.
If there's any movement that lets people know that it's a human,
the play is all over.
Miss Tsukikage sure did bet on her,
and she is doing fine with it.
Kitajima Maya… What a girl.
This is Kitajima Maya,
who wears a mask of a doll.
There's no trace of the Catherine who gave me passion and kindness.
How silly was I?
I was an actor myself, and I fell in love with Maya who wore a mask of Catherine.
Good bye, my Catherine.
The play, which started with an audience of twelve, ended in a big success.
My prince Rei… I'm in love.
I shouldn't have let her see…
Please, miss.
Poor people.
The game is over.
Poor people?
Yes, the people of Orion Theater.
Look at that, all sold out.
That's how a theater should be.
Hey, did you think the audience enjoyed it a lot?
Yeah, there weren't too many,
but it was a success.
Those girls went crazy over Rei.
Yeah, they were like, "Mr. Rei…"
No one noticed that you are a woman, though.
Hey, watch your mouth!
Oh, help me!
Why, you!
Wait!
I'm done with the backstage.
When I get you…
I've got you!
Lord have mercy.
What are you doing,
all smiling like that?
We are all here as one.
I like that.
That's right.
That's why the play went so well.
When everyone's heart beats
the same pace, there's born a great play.
Also, it's important for an actor to pace
the heartbeat with the others.
Pace the heartbeat
with the others?
I have never thought of it that way.
I only thought of acting for myself.
That's right, I have never thought of anyone else.
I always focused on just myself.
I just played at my own pace on all the other plays I've done.
Maya, learn how to kill your emotions.
Maya…
That's why Miss Tsukikage
gave me the role of a doll.
To empty myself.
I wonder what happened to her?
Seems like she's learning
another step about acting.
Act to kill her own emotions…
The Smile of Stone
The word about "The Smile of Stone" spread, and the number in the audience grew as the days passed by.
And, ten days later…
Hey, look!
Look at that!
T-This can't be…
It is lonely by myself…
…and I almost stumble.
Somewhere calls me here,
just like a whisper in the wind.
Purple light, shining down
on the horizon…
…more surer than words…
…telling us gently…
…that we'll meet
each other someday.
Of course you can
fly from far away…
…for the dream
on my cheek…
…belongs to you.