A mask which is as fragile as glass,
people wear it to hide their own faces.
THE GLASS MASK
On the stage, with the lights off…
…blue shadows emerge.
Dancing 'round to hear the applause…
…I listen carefully to an
unpredictable tomorrow.
Everyone has a dream…
…with stars in their heart.
Stage light: a moment to shine…
…this city becomes a shining star.
The flower in my heart
is as fragile as glass, a shinin' dream.
You can do it if you want to,
so hold on tight to love…
…because there's someone that smiles
on the other side of my tears.
You can do it if you want to,
this feeling in my heart…
Don't cry. Keep on running
and running, for someday…
"The Smile of Stone" has opened its curtains at an underground theater converted from an old cafe.
There were only twelve in the audience when it started, but it turned out that people had to stand in line to get in the theater as it went on.
However, the only thing that stayed on Maya's mind after she got off stage was her mother.
—Episode 16—
Trace of Mother
Dear mother.
How are you?
Today is the last day
of "The Smile of Stone."
What are you doing, Maya?
We only have an hour
until the play starts.
You know you will be fined
if you are late, right?
Oh, you can take all your time
tomorrow to write that letter.
It's not like your mom
will go away. Come on.
Maya, hurry.
Wait for me!
I'm sorry, Mother.
It's been two years, but I haven't even written a single letter to you.
You don't even know that Tsukikage Theater went out of business, nor that I moved into an apartment.
You don't even know that I am on stage either.
Today's the last day of our play.
I wish you had a chance to see it.
Mother…?
No, that's not…
Mother!
Mom…
That's my mom!
Maya!
Please let me off here!
Please let me off!
What's going on with you, Maya?
My mother.
That was my mother!
She was right here.
Maya, are you sure
you weren't dreaming?
Mother!
Mother, wait for me!
No!
You'll be late for the play, Maya.
Our play…
The Smile of Stone
Hey, did you see our audience today?
Orion Theater's actors are here.
That's right. Their last day
on "Hamlet" was yesterday.
Miss Tsukikage is here, too.
Okay, guys.
Let's do our best.
Hmm, where's Maya?
Manpuku Ken
Where's Haru?
That's what I want to ask you, Maya.
I thought she went to visit you.
She disappeared on her way to a rest home, and we haven't heard from her since then.
Rest home?
Then, her lungs were bad?
Yes. For a long time,
she was just lying in bed.
We wanted to let you know,
but we didn't know where you were.
So, we had to make a—
Maya, it's time.
Hello? Maya?
Thanks.
I'll have to call you back.
So, you have to at least
tell us your address—
Hey, Maya?
Oh, she's gone.
Maya has been doing
a great job all this time.
Of course. She has to.
The success of this play
is up to her acting as a doll.
I'll be watching
your acting today, Maya.
Y-Yes.
"The Smile of Stone's"
last day has come.
The join play by Tsukikage and Ikkakuju Theater went on in an old cafe converted into an underground theater with full audience.
That's Kitajima Maya.
Now, I would like to announce a qualified contributor who will take care of the doll Elizabeth.
A contributor?
Yes, the person must honestly love and care about Elizabeth.
She's been missing…
Then that must have been my mother.
Tuberculosis.
That's why she was so thin.
I'm sorry, so sorry, Mother.
For not being able to take care of you.
So, Ms. Isabella, what is this?
I'm the only one
she has… the only one.
Hey…
Look at that…
Maya!
The mask is gone,
the mask of a doll.
Shoot, the important doll
is all soaking wet.
Hanna, please help me
change Elizabeth's outfit.
Frederica, when did you start
playing with your dolls as a hobby?
Oh, Mr. Gallison,
what's with you and your duster?
The water covering
Maya hid her tears.
The play went on as if nothing happened,
and it was saved by Rei's wit.
What was it?
What was that mysterious attraction?
Yeah, I was sucked into some kind of… passion, too.
They were all skilled actors.
Especially the doll.
Maybe she's a good find.
What are you doing,
taking your mask off on the stage?
Because of your unprofessional behavior, this important last day of the play was almost jeopardized.
Miss Tsukikage, Maya saw someone that seemed like her mother on the way to the theater today.
It doesn't matter what it is, it still doesn't give you a reason to take your mask off on stage.
Maya… you failed as an actress.
Failed?
You won't be in the next play.
You're on probation for a while.
Probation?
I knew I had to kill myself
before I went onto that stage…
You couldn't help it, Maya.
What we wear is a glass mask.
Glass mask?
Yes.
A fragile glass mask.
That's why it's so easy to break it
and reveal the real face.
You can tell an actor's
ability to keep the mask on.
A glass mask…
I took the mask off on stage.
If you fail, "The Crimsson Goddess"
will go to someone else.
No, it's over for me.
Miss Tsukikage must have given up on me.
I won't be able to play "The Crimson Goddess" anymore.
Then, for what reason did I throw my mother out of my life?
Mother… Mother.
Maya, can you stop the alarm?
Hey, Maya!
Oh, where did she go?
Mother… I want to see you.
I want to put my face in your chest
and be your daughter again.
These are the candidates
for Helen Keller.
There are about 15 candidates.
Thanks for all your help.
This one is an exception.
Hmm, an exception?
Yes. I haven't seen her
movement or speech.
She played as a doll.
But I saw great talent in that role
without any movements.
Okay, we'll have her
as a candidate.
Haseagawa…
Yes?
How did you become
such a great scout?
Uhh…
Never mind.
I wonder where the hell Maya is.
Oh, that's Maya.
It has been three days since Maya started walking, looking all over for her mother.
She might not be in Tōkyō anymore.
But where did she go?
Where?
"The Cherry Tree
of Dream Festivals."
That's the play where Himekawa Ayumi
plays a daughter of a wealthy family.
Ayumi is looking fabulous on stage,
and look at me: I'm on probation and looking terrible.
I wonder if the day that I can become an actress will ever come.
Thank you so much for your visit.
The actors were really excited to see you visit them, Mr. President.
I heard Himekawa Ayumi is doing great.
She was born to play the main role.
I'm looking forward to her future.
Mr. Ota! Kawamura Yoshiko
fell off the stairs and broke her leg.
What?
Then make her walk!
There's no one else for her part.
But it's all swollen
and she can't even move it.
Damn. Then we'll have
to change the play.
Call Mr. Isomura, the playwright.
No, there's no need for that.
Mr. Masumi?
Is this your shelter
from the rain, little girl?
You…
Leave me alone!
I can't let you go.
You are our important substitute.
A substitute?
Mr. Ota, could you tell her
what the play is about?
But, we only have another hour before our play starts.
It's impossible for her
to get the words memorized.
It's okay.
Here, hurry.
Wait a minute.
I haven't said that I'll do it.
You will do it.
Or are you going to give up the chance of getting on such big stage so easily?
Besides, this is a play that's been talked about a lot. Your only fan might be here.
Mr. Purple Rose!
Here, get ready.
I will never like this guy!
Go on ahead and memorize the words.
We don't have much time.
Yes.
Ayumi!
Kitajima Maya!
Why is she here?
Everyone, let me introduce Kitajima Maya.
She'll play as a substitute for Chie.
Ayumi, she will play
as your cousin.
Yes, of course.
Cousin?
I'll be her cousin?
Yes. Under a very different circumstance.
This is our first play together.
Let's do our best.
Sorry we couldn't find you a better place,
but we're counting on you.
Your appearances are in the third and fourth scenes of the first act, and the fifth in the second act.
It starts at 6 PM.
Good luck.
I only have 45 more minutes.
So that's the girl
Miss Harada called "stage storm."
I heard she tied with Himekawa Ayumi
in the amateur contest.
But, so what?
It's impossible in such a short time.
It's not like she only has
to remember her part.
What's wrong with her?
Can't she hear the phone?
Look at her concentration.
It's bad luck for us.
She'll be on stage when we are.
"Stage storm…"
She might overwhelm us.
We finally got our part.
I hope she forgets her words
and falls silent or something.
I know…
What?
I have a good idea, Bungo.
T-That's a little too much.
Hmph. It's eat or be eaten
in this world.
Hey!
Why don't you change and do your makeup now?
But I have only gotten
to the third scene.
You can read even after
the play has started.
Well, you're right.
Here, hurry.
I can help you.
This way.
The script Bungo switched was the original one before Isomura, the playwright, did the editing.
Isomura drastically changed the fourth scene, not only the words, but also the storyline.
The time is during the Meiji Era,
when Rokumeikan was flourishing.
This is a drama about
Kaizōji, a baron, and his family.
Uncle, Aunt.
Look at me.
Ms. Barnette, my tutor, taught me
how to greet in the Western way.
Ayumi's role is as a baron's
proud granddaughter, Tsukiyo.
Maya's role is a daughter born to his fifth son, Yukihiro.
As a geisha, she grew up with discrimination.
I finally got through
with the words.
The rest is how to play
Chie my way.
What a girl.
She has memorized
all of the words already.
Well, too bad; your words
will be useless on stage.
Mr. Purple Rose.
Please watch me tonight
if you are here.
You can see my Chie.
You weren't back at the promised time,
so I came to pick you up.
I put her in as a substitute,
so I'll be held responsible.
I knew you would say that, so I went ahead
and canceled your appointments.
Hmm?
How did it go between
Tsukiyo and Mr. Funakura?
It went fine.
The third scene of the first act went smoothly,
but the fourth was about to start.
It's my go at it soon.
Yukihiro, my father,
will come back soon, and—
Bad news about Mr. Yukihiro.
What about Yukihiro?
He went off to be an entertainer.
Different! This is different
from what I've read!
What's wrong?
This is wrong.
The father was supposed to come back.
Huh?
Oh, this is the old script.
Uncle Yukihiro
became an entertainer.
How embarrassing.
I wonder if Chie knows?
Chie.
How did this happen?
I don't know.
Chie!
They're calling me.
I have to go.
Little girl, no, you can't.
Don't!
No!
The play is on now.
She came out.
What nerve.
Chie, your father is an
embarrassment to our family.
And Chie, you are, too.
Why don't you say something?
Say something, but what?
Chie is supposed to have a long speech about her sad and miserable life.
I wonder what she will do?
Say something!
What a girl.
Not only doesn't she have to say anything now…
…but by biting on the lily,
she expresses her sorrow and bitterness.
What should I do?
How should I react to this Chie?
I can't get the play going…
How stupid are they?
Falling into the very trap
they have created.
Ayumi, it's not your turn yet!
Mr. Utahiko, Ms. Kyoko,
your mother is calling.
Y-Yes.
Right away.
She made those two get off the stage…
Where is this play going?
Ayumi.
Kitajima Maya…
I never thought our battle would be like this.
Maya, who came out on the stage not even knowing the storyline.
Ayumi, who came out on the stage when it wasn't even her turn.
The two stared at one another with their spirits challenging each other on the tense stage.
It is lonely by myself…
…and I almost stumble.
Somewhere calls me here,
just like a whisper in the wind.
Purple light, shining down
on the horizon…
…more surer than words…
…telling us gently…
…that we'll meet
each other someday.
Of course you can
fly from far away…
…for the dream
on my cheek…
…belongs to you.