A mask which is as fragile as glass,
people wear it to hide their own faces.
THE GLASS MASK
On the stage, with the lights off…
…blue shadows emerge.
Dancing 'round to hear the applause…
…I listen carefully to an
unpredictable tomorrow.
Everyone has a dream…
…with stars in their heart.
Stage light: a moment to shine…
…this city becomes a shining star.
The flower in my heart
is as fragile as glass, a shinin' dream.
You can do it if you want to,
so hold on tight to love…
…because there's someone that smiles
on the other side of my tears.
You can do it if you want to,
this feeling in my heart…
Don't cry. Keep on running
and running, for someday…
With Masumi's help, Maya gets a substitute
role in "The Cherry Tree of Dream Festivals."
However, the co-stars who thought
of Maya as a "stage storm…"
…try to trap her by replacing
the new revised script with the old one.
Maya gets on the stage without knowing
her words or the storyline.
—Episode 17—
Where is Mr. Purple Rose?
Just watch.
I will make this play flow.
This scene is where Chie is overwhelmed
by her mortifying feelings…
…and shouts that she would rather run away.
But Maya doesn't know that,
or even her words.
Himekawa Ayumi doesn't know
her words, either.
She ran out onto the stage
when it wasn't even her turn.
Let's see what they can do.
With that lily in your mouth, are you going
to entertain me just like your father?
I just heard that your father
has become a traveling entertainer.
What a shame
to the Kaidōji family.
What should I do?
I can't keep quiet forever.
Why don't you say something?
I want to hear your opinion
as Kaidōji Chie.
As Kaidōji Chie…
Just answer my words.
I will answer
to your words as well.
Ayumi is telling me to proceed
with this scene with all ad-lib.
Do you understand, Chie?
Yes, I understand.
She accepted the challenge.
What a girl.
I'll just follow Ayumi.
I wonder, do you remember
when you first came to this house?
Ayumi told Maya Chie's situation
in her own words.
Chie was born to Yukihiro, the fifth son
of Kaidōji, and a geisha from Fukagawa.
Yukihiro has returned with Chie once,
but he left her to be with another geisha.
Everyone used to mistake you as a maid,
because you were always alone.
Ayumi, do you want
to make me sad or mad?
What do you think about this flier?
What a great father, to have his
picture on something like this.
I see, she's trying
to make me upset.
What a great father he is.
Yes…
He is.
That's it.
Now we're playing.
What nonsense!
Are you out of your mind?
He dishonored the Kaidōji family.
What about the Kaidōji family?
All they did was to try and make
my loving father and mother separate.
Shut up!
What an ungrateful thing to say
after all they have done for you.
No! The Kaidōji family, who influences things
with its power and money, I hate them!
Such brave actresses!
They match each other's emotions and words.
Besides, they are almost
following the script.
All they have to do now is to get Chie
to run off the stage saying she would run away.
Is that right?
Then, why don't you run away, too?
You and your father are a stain on our family.
Everyone has to live unpleasantly
because of that stain.
Why don't you go
to that geisha mother of yours?
Or go after your father?
He's a poor actor.
Why don't you go with the poor actor?
I hate this house!
I want to say that I want to leave this house.
But what if that's not in the script?
I'll make a terrible mistake!
This… This house…
I'll… I'll go away!
She did it!
I never want to see your face again, either.
Go, now!
Get off the stage from the left.
Excellent job.
You did great.
Uh, my last words,
was that okay?
Okay? Without these words,
the play couldn't have gone on.
What?
Chie's running away triggers
the breakdown of the Kaidōji family.
It was that important…
I might not have said those words
if Ayumi didn't hit me then.
What, Chie is leaving the house?
Ayumi, what a talented person she is.
Ayumi!
Thank you so much.
We wouldn't have known
what to do if you didn't come out.
Then you should learn from this and never
do a stupid thing like switching a script again.
She knew?
Ayumi, thank you so—
Excuse me.
Backstage
Ayumi, she completely brought me into
her pace and made me say the needed words.
I can't win.
I can't beat her.
Kitajima Maya. She used her full body to sense
where I as going, and followed me completely.
She was as good as I was.
No, I knew the storyline of the fourth act,
so I had the advantage.
She still did as good as I did.
I lost…
Ayumi, a person
with such a great talent.
Mr. Himekawa!
Director!
Ayumi did great on stage today.
Her father is a movie director
and her mother a well-known actress.
She has a shining beauty
and a genius of a talent.
Compared to her,
how boring am I?
What's wrong, little girl?
You seem down despite
your great success tonight.
Ayumi saved me.
It wasn't my work,
but Ayumi's talent.
Let me take you home.
It's pouring outside.
No, thank you!
Leave me alone!
You still hate me.
Yes, I hate you so much!
Aren't you glad that things
are going your way?
You should be satisfied when you have
the play rights for "The Crimson Goddess."
That's right.
I get what I want
using any means necessary.
I don't give a damn
what happens to you guys.
Are you happy to hear me
say that now?
How terrible!
Such a terrible person.
As cold-blooded as they say!
I won't forgive him.
I will never forgive him!
I wonder if Maya is looking
for her mom in the rain.
Maya?
You're soaking wet.
I can't become "The Crimson Goddess."
Maya…
Even if I run as hard as I can,
I can never catch up to her.
Mr. Masumi, what have you been
thinking about all this time?
Could I guess?
Hmm?
The girl who ran from you,
Kitajima Maya.
I must be right.
She was wonderful today,
despite what all happened.
You almost lost yourself then,
unlike your usual self.
I was just worried that
she would ruin the play.
Is that right?
What else could it be?
I'll take your word for it.
Yes, that was all.
That was all…
I feel drained.
I can't find my mother.
I can't even practice acting.
Sakurakōji didn't come
to "The Smile of Stone" at all.
How lonely.
Everyone's gone all of the sudden.
Maya, Maya!
It's him!
Look at the presents.
Mr. Purple Rose!
It's like a sugar daddy
with all this stuff!
"I saw your act
in The Cherry Tree of Dream Festivals."
"I was impressed with your act as Chie,
even as a substitute."
"I'm looking forward to seeing you
on stage again soon."
You were there again for me,
Mr. Purple Rose.
I still have someone on my side.
Maya enrolled in Hitotsubashi High School.
It's known as the "talent school," and there are
many actors and actresses in this school.
Then there's an elite acting club, members of which
are known to have passed challenging acting tests.
I wonder what they are like, winning
the "All-Japan Acting Contest" every year.
The demon!
She's here!
Hide the babies,
hide the children!
Look, that's Kanaya Emi.
The best actress of them all.
Kanaya Emi?
The demon!
It's here, the baby eater is here!
Where are the children!?
Where are the kids!?
If not them,
I'll eat you all!
Go away, demon!
"The scene, played as an ad-lib
by Kitajima Maya and Himekawa Ayumi…"
The Cherry Tree
of Dream Festivals
"…was an unexpected plus
for the night's play."
"Much is expected from their
competitive yet equal talent."
"Their competitive yet equal talent…"
What talent…
Are you Ms. Kitajima Maya?
Uhm, yes, I am.
This was left at the reception desk
with your name and class on it.
Mr. Purple Rose!
Oh, here!
Sorry, I'll get it later!
Please wait for me.
Don't go anywhere.
Where is he?
What a nice car!
A purple rose!
Whose car is this?
Hayami Masumi.
From Metropolitan Entertainment.
Hayami Masumi…
He just went into
the Principal's office.
He's a great businessman.
I hear he donates lots of money every year.
Yeah, thinking that students
will bring him money in the future.
A purple rose in the car
of Metropolitan Entertainment?
Perhaps Mr. Purple Rose
was in this car?
And he might be in the
Principal's office with Masumi.
He must be!
H-Hey, you can't!
Sorry, but I need to see the Principal.
He has a guest right now.
What can I do for you?
Yes. I'm Kitajima Maya
from Class B.
Well, I—
Hell, little girl.
Did you come to see me?
No! I'm looking for
Mr. Purple Rose.
Hmph.
Mr. Purple Rose?
I saw a purple rose in your car.
What?
You know him.
You know Mr. Purple Rose!
Please tell me who he is.
All I want to do is tell him how much
I appreciate him… for all he does for me.
How much he encourages me.
What's so funny?
Oh, I just remembered who had the purple rose.
I picked up an actress on the way here,
and she had some flowers.
An actress?
She had some flowers with purple roses in it,
so she must be the one.
Sorry it's not who
you were looking for.
I thought I could finally thank him…
He knows how you feel.
Please shut the door
when you are done.
Please, excuse me.
"May your school life be filled
with joy and achievement."
I want to see you,
Mr. Purple Rose.
I wonder what he's like.
I want to see him, and thank him.
Hey, welcome home.
How was school?
Look at this!
It's Mr. Purple Rose again!
He came to your school?
Whew, what a love!
Stop it, Rei.
I wonder when I can go
on stage again.
I want Mr. Purple Rose
to see me on stage again.
Teacher didn't order you off the stage out of hate,
and she'll get you back on there again soon.
Yeah.
Why don't you come and see our practice?
Are you Ms. Kitajima Maya?
Yes.
This is who I am.
Hasegawa,
Metropolitan Entertainment?
What can I do for you?
The role of Helen Keller?
Yes. Well, we have a total
of five candidates.
We'll have an audition in August
to make our final decision.
Audition.
Helen Keller has a triple disability
and acts like a wild animal.
It will be a tough role.
Who are the other candidates?
Shiratori Reina,
Hayakawa Akiko.
She's an upcoming actress.
Kanaya Emi.
Kanaya Emi?
From Hitotsubashi High School?
Yes.
She's full of talent.
So, who is the fourth one?
Himekawa Ayumi.
Ayumi…
Let me also mention that
the director will be Onedera Hajime…
…and the main role, Annie Sullivan,
will be played by Himekawa Utako.
Ha!
That's a fair competition.
It's like Maya going
into enemy territory.
Please don't misunderstand.
Our audition is very fair.
The fact that Himekawa Ayumi is the daughter
of the main role won't affect it at all.
Then I guess that's okay.
Huh, Maya?
Thank you for the offer,
but I would like to decline.
Maya!
I would like to decline.
Maya, think about it.
This role sure is hard,
but it's a rewarding challenge, too.
You will grow as an actress.
I know you're not thrilled about Metropolitan
Entertainment, but think of the bigger picture.
You have to grab your chance.
Well, please take your time
to think it through.
I won't take the audition.
Please change her mind.
What's wrong?
It's not like you, Maya.
I can't win.
I can't win against Ayumi.
Maya…
You really are going away?
Yes.
I see.
I will be at the mansion in Nakano.
Practice hard.
I'll talk to your grandmother every three days.
The next time I see you,
it will be at the audition, Mother.
Yes. Until then, we won't be
mother and daughter anymore, right?
Yes. I want to get the role with my talent.
I will choose Helen fairly
from an actress' point of view.
Good bye now, Mother.
Good bye, Ayumi.
I heard you declined
the audition for Helen's role.
Yes.
You are afraid of Ayumi,
is that right?
Teacher.
You got scared after being lead by Ayumi
in "The Cherry Tree of Dream Festivals."
Maya, you are hereby expelled!
Expelled?
You knew you weren't allowed
to get on stage, yet you took that role.
That's reason enough.
Expelled…
But, if you win the role of Helen,
then I'll reconsider.
Helen's role?
If not, you can not only forget about practicing
at my school, but "The Crimson Goddess" as well.
Metropolitan Entertainment
You're still working?
It's my way of taking a break
to read the proposals.
Sounds like you.
About "The Miracle Worker,"
we'll have the interview next month.
The audition is for August 8th.
Is that right?
I see that you haven't heard if
Kitajima Maya will be at the audition or not.
Hmm?
Don't worry. She replied
and she will be at the audition.
Maybe you should send
some purple roses to encourage her.
Maya, you are hereby expelled!
But, if you win the role of Helen,
then I'll reconsider.
I will play the disabled Helen.
Acting is all I've got.
Go for it, Maya.
If you can play Helen, then you will be
one step closer to "The Crimson Goddess."
To continue with acting as her future, she has
to win the role of Helen Keller, Maya told herself.
It is lonely by myself…
…and I almost stumble.
Somewhere calls me here,
just like a whisper in the wind.
Purple light, shining down
on the horizon…
…more surer than words…
…telling us gently…
…that we'll meet
each other someday.
Of course you can
fly from far away…
…for the dream
on my cheek…
…belongs to you.
Mr. Purple Rose lends Maya a summer house
in Karuizawa for her to practice the role of Helen.
Then one day, they meet in person.
Please look forward to the next episode:
"The Challenge of Helen."