A mask which is as fragile as glass,
people wear it to hide their own faces.
THE GLASS MASK
On the stage, with the lights off…
…blue shadows emerge.
Dancing 'round to hear the applause…
…I listen carefully to an
unpredictable tomorrow.
Everyone has a dream…
…with stars in their heart.
Stage light: a moment to shine…
…this city becomes a shining star.
The flower in my heart
is as fragile as glass, a shinin' dream.
You can do it if you want to,
so hold on tight to love…
…because there's someone that smiles
on the other side of my tears.
You can do it if you want to,
this feeling in my heart…
Don't cry. Keep on running
and running, for someday…
Metropolitan Entertainment approached Maya, who has just entered high school, about an audition for "The Miracle Worker."
Maya declines out of fear of losing to her rival, Ayumi.
Tsukikage threatens to expel Maya from Tsukikage Theater unless she gets the role of Helen Keller.
—Episode 18—
The Challenge of Helen
Metropolitan Entertainment has chosen you five as the candidates for the role of Helen Keller.
Shiratori Reina,
from Kaze Theater.
Hayakawa Akiko,
from Tenma Theater.
We recognize both of your achievements on TV series.
Kanaya Emi, who is a member of the acting group of Hitotsubashi High School…
…and whose talent is highly recognized by the critics.
Next, we do not need an introduction
fro Himekawa Ayumi.
Last, but not least, Kitajima Maya
from Tsukikage Theater.
The audition is set for August 8th.
Ayumi, is it true that you moved
out of your mother's house?
Yes.
Why? You can get advice from
your mother, should you live with her.
That's right. And you can practice for "The Miracle Worker" together.
That's the reason
I moved out of the house.
I don't need my mother's reputation to get this role.
I will win this role solely with my talent.
Ayumi,
what a strict person you are.
"The Miracle Worker" is an inspiring and touching drama about a girl Helen Keller, who can't hear, see, nor speak but comes to understand words through Ms. Sullivan's passionate and persistent education.
When school got out for summer break, Maya started practicing everyday at the church with Rei.
Sit still and eat this.
Fold the napkin!
Helen!
Wait, Helen!
Helen.
Don't run away from me.
You are not done eating yet.
Helen, come back…
Miss Tsukikage.
Why did you look at me, Maya?
Helen can not hear anything.
Here, Maya, become Helen now!
Yes.
Walk as Helen.
Get mad as Helen.
Eat as Helen.
Not like that!
Now, Maya, play as Helen.
What?
Now, now…
Play as Helen?
Play as Helen, who is blind, deaf,
and not able to speak.
If you can't do that, you will never
know the real Helen. Understand?
Teacher, that's enough.
I can practice with her now.
Yeah, here it is.
What?
You're tearing the church down?
Yeah, haven't you heard?
A mansion is going to be built here.
No way.
This is our practice hall.
Teacher!
What a patient she is.
If she continues like this,
she'll never get better.
Teacher is ill,
and the practice hall is gone…
What should I do now?
I have a report about the five
candidates for Helen Keller.
Yes.
Shiratori Reina is getting
strict training at her theater.
Hayakawa Akiko is actually playing
Helen Keller with her acting group.
Kanaya Emi is in libraries
doing research about Helen Keller.
And Himekawa Ayumi is volunteering at an agency for disabled children like Helen Keller.
As for Kitajima Maya…
…the church she was practicing at was demolished and now she doesn't have anywhere to go.
Maya, Maya!
Look, it's Mr. Purple Rose again!
Wow!
Ms. Kitajima Maya
"I believe it's hot in Tōkyō now."
"If it's not too much, I would like to invite you to my summer house in Nagano."
Summer house?
Wow, there's a train ticket, too.
I'm going.
Maya.
I'll go and practice
Helen's role there.
"I will not be able to be there,
but my friends will look after you."
Mr. Purple Rose always helps
me out whenever I'm in need.
He's like my guardian angel.
Bidoro
Hey, Sakurakōji.
You should have came a day earlier.
Why?
You know, Mr. Purple Rose.
She got an invitation from him.
Maya, I can't do anything
for you, can I?
How nice!
Hi there, welcome.
I'm Yamashita, the house sitter.
I'm Kitajima Maya.
It's very nice to meet you.
Here, come on in.
We've been waiting for you.
Wow, it's beautiful!
It's bright and has
a beautiful view.
Yes, it has.
We live right down the street, so please don't hesitate to come to us if you need anything.
Of course, we'll come by to clean and prepare meals, and so on.
Oh, I…
Yes?
What is the owner of this house like?
Oh, by the way, he told us to give you the flowers there.
Ms. Kitajima Maya
"I hope you will have
a wonderful time."
"I do have one wish:
please don't ask around about me."
"—Mr. Purple Rose."
I understand.
I won't ask about you anymore.
I will win Helen's role here.
Did you sleep well last night?
Yes.
That's good.
It's a nice day today.
You should go outside and play.
But…
A young girl should not stay home all day. Go on.
Yes.
A yacht and a sailboat,
horse back riding and cycling…
I'm sure Helen
didn't play this way.
Teacher, I suggest we take turns
getting off work to go see Maya.
I'm sure it's hard
to practice without a partner.
No, being Helen
doesn't require a partner.
She's better off by herself.
By herself?
Yes.
All by herself.
Helen… I still don't understand you.
What was your everyday life like?
How did you spend a day?
Helen…
Helen's life.
I got it.
I'll live as Helen.
Some cotton…
…and some dressing.
Helen's life.
I'll live as Helen,
in the darkness and silence.
Maya, Maya.
Maya!
It's strange, dear.
All the windows are closed.
Here, let me have the key.
Oh, yes.
It's dark in here.
Maya, Maya.
Oh!
What the…?
Huh?
Upstairs.
Ma-Maya…
Maya!
Who?
A touch, but whose hand?
Oh, the caretakers.
What's wrong, Maya?
What in the world is going on?
Do · not · wo·rry.
This · is · prac·tice · for · my · act·ing?
Say, dear, she says not to worry,
but do you think she's really okay?
Maybe…
They came,
that means morning is here.
I'm hungry.
Here it is!
The fridge.
I wonder what time it is now.
Night, or day?
Or morning?
Many thoughts come
to me as I sit like this.
Sakurakōji.
How is he?
Teacher and Rei.
It feels so long
since I last saw them.
Mother.
You have been missing,
but where are you, Mother?
Business is well this summer,
huh, Masumi?
Thank you.
This party of yours, with many
celebrities from Metropolitan Entertainment…
…has become a popular tradition in Karuizawa.
It's good advertisement for me, too.
Many big names from the economic and political worlds are here.
So, as artists, your reputation shall surely flourish.
You make anyone a tool of your business, though.
Do you have anyone without business ties?
Him?
Of course not!
You'll choose a woman with the most advantages for your business for your future wife, I bet.
What, are you drunk?
No.
I will be very careful in choosing,
even using a computer if I have to…
…for a person who is suitable
for Metropolitan Entertainment.
What?
Mr. Masumi.
Yes.
The house sitter of your summer house
wants to see you immediately.
I've never seen him lose his cool.
I knew to be careful
when coming down the stairs.
Ouch!
I can't stand up.
I must have sprained my ankle.
I wonder how long
I've been doing this?
Yet I still can't learn her ways.
Helen's life, Helen's play…
I've had enough!
I want to take the earplugs
and blindfold off!
I want to hear, see and talk.
I've had enough.
I'm taking this off.
No, I can't.
I will never understand
how Helen feels.
Whatever happens, I will stay
like this until I learn her ways.
Who?
Whose hand is this?
Not the caretaker?
Who is he?
Oh, a rose?
It's a rose.
Mr. Purple Rose?
Are · you · Mr. · Pur·ple · Rose?
Finally!
I finally get to meet you!
The person who has been encouraging me ever since my first stage appearance.
The person who is always on my side.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Little girl…
What was that?
He just held me and…
W-Wait!
Who are you?
Please tell me, just your name.
I appreciate you with all my heart.
Every time I'm about to give up,
I always think about you.
Please, please tell me your name.
I · am · look·ing · for·ward
to · see·ing · your · Hel·en.
Wait!
He's gone.
Something's wrong with you,
Hayami Masumi.
She's a girl more than ten years
younger than I am.
Being the person that I am,
being the person that I am…
I am looking forward
to seeing your Helen.
to seeing your Helen!
I'll do it.
I won't give up.
I'll become Helen here.
Maya has finally met
Mr. Purple Rose.
It was a mysterious meeting, but it became an inspiration for Maya, who struggles to understand Helen.
It is lonely by myself…
…and I almost stumble.
Somewhere calls me here,
just like a whisper in the wind.
Purple light, shining down
on the horizon…
…more surer than words…
…telling us gently…
…that we'll meet
each other someday.
Of course you can
fly from far away…
…for the dream
on my cheek…
…belongs to you.