A mask which is as fragile as glass,
people wear it to hide their own faces.
THE GLASS MASK
On the stage, with the lights off…
…blue shadows emerge.
Dancing 'round to hear the applause…
…I listen carefully to an
unpredictable tomorrow.
Everyone has a dream…
…with stars in their heart.
Stage light: a moment to shine…
…this city becomes a shining star.
The flower in my heart
is as fragile as glass, a shinin' dream.
You can do it if you want to,
so hold on tight to love…
…because there's someone that smiles
on the other side of my tears.
You can do it if you want to,
this feeling in my heart…
Don't cry. Keep on running
and running, for someday…
Maya started living as Helen, with dressing around her eyes and cotton in her ears, at a summer house that Mr. Purple Rose let her use.
She was visited by Mr. Purple Rose, but his true identity still remains a mystery.
—Episode 19—
A Heated Audition
What?
Maya's not back yet?
No, not yet.
The audition is tomorrow,
but I still haven't heard from her.
Oh, can I help you?
Tōtō University Medical Center
We haven't heard from her at all.
Is that right?
Haven't heard from her…
Teacher?
Go pick her up immediately.
Otherwise, she might not return.
Here she is.
Maya.
Wh-What is she doing?
She's playing.
Babies often play like that,
smiling like her.
She's totally become Helen.
She even forgot the day
of her important audition.
Here, Maya.
Maya.
Rei, Sayaka.
Maya, your audition is tomorrow.
Oh, it has been that long…
Good bye!
Thank you so much.
Mr., Mrs., I'll see you again.
She seems just like an ordinary girl like this.
Yeah.
Good bye!
Miracle Worker Audition
We will now start the audition
for the role of Helen Keller.
Here, we have the five candidates.
What's wrong with that Kitajima Maya girl?
She has scratches all over her.
Yeah, she looks like she just got out
of volleyball practice or something.
The six judges are here.
Mrs. Himekawa Utako, who has not arrived yet due to her delayed flight, will be joining us soon.
Mrs. Himekawa is the mother of Ms. Himekawa Ayumi…
…one of our candidates, but the selection process will be fair.
It's easy to say "fair,"
but, you know…
Yeah, of course you'd have special feelings for your own daughter, wouldn't you?
Now, let's begin the first audition.
Candidates, please change into your costume.
This way, please.
Hey, look.
It's been a month since they have parted.
An emotional moment for mother and daughter to rejoin.
Oh, they just passed each other by without even looking at one another.
They'll remain as strangers as long as the audition continues.
What a family.
I know she has a strict eye for Ayumi's act, but I will do my best on my terms, on behalf of Mr. Purple Rose, too.
The audition has started downstairs.
Candidate number one,
Ms. Shiratori Reina, please come in.
Yes.
Shiratori Reina.
Please come in.
Excuse me.
This is…
The first audition is to play as Helen.
Please start.
As Helen.
I know, she liked dolls.
Candidate number two,
Ms. Hayakawa Akiko.
Yes.
Okay, I'll use the blocks.
Kanaya Emi's play is
different from the first two.
She's about to use all the toys here.
It's rare to see an act like hers
that doesn't bore the judges.
Very dynamic, and it will be great on stage.
Maya, I'm sure she feels insecure
going up against Ayumi.
Candidate number four,
Himekawa Ayumi.
Play as Helen.
W-What is she doing?
She seems to be
playing with her nails.
I wonder how long
she'll be like this.
Hasegawa.
Yes.
That ball, okay?
But…
It's okay.
Just do it.
Oh, no!
She had her eyes wide open without even moving her eyes off the ball.
I'm sure that's what Helen would do.
I'm looking forward to seeing what kind of play the last candidate can show us.
Play as Helen.
Again!
What's going on with her
and Himekawa Ayumi?
Oh?
She's fell asleep?
That's unacceptable!
What do you think this audition is!
Hey, you!
Hey—
We told you to play as Helen.
Don't you understand?
Hey, you!
What…?
Hey, just…!
Wait a minute!
Just look at her.
Her hands, her face.
She's playing, as Helen.
She's enjoying tearing the pages.
An ordinary person would come
in here and play with the toys.
That is common sense, after all.
But, if the real Helen were here,
what would she do?
Huh!
She wouldn't notice that the toys were here at all.
This girl and Himekawa Ayumi definitely possess extraordinary talent.
The meeting is about to start
in the third conference room.
They reported the results
from the second audition.
It's the simulated acting
on the actual stage.
Shiratori Reina and Hayakawa Akiko have equal chances of passing or failing.
Kitajima Maya acted wildly, but the judges didn't like it much.
At this point, Kanaya Emi,
with her dynamic acting…
…and Himekawa Ayumi, who showed
impressive emotion, are leading.
I see.
The audition came to the last test.
The judges will be here shortly.
Please wait here as Helen.
This is the last test.
I wonder if anyone
can pass this test.
If anyone does,
then she's the real Helen.
If not, let's vote for one of these two.
Himekawa Ayumi or Kanaya Emi.
If I don't get this role,
then Miss Tsukikage will expel me.
No, right now, let's focus only on being Helen.
It might be my last chance to be Helen.
I am Helen.
Maya.
I know she will meet
my expectations.
Bidoro
Maya…
Alarm
This can't be happening.
Unbelievable.
No way.
It stopped.
I wonder what it was.
Oh, no!
The last test is over.
What!
Over?
What do you mean?
The alarm was the test.
You were told at the beginning
to wait as Helen.
Given that, though, it is human nature to react to something like the loud alarm.
The ones who didn't react are either the real Helen, or the ones who can play the real Helen.
A long time ago, at the audition for "The Miracle Worker" in America, there was one girl who didn't react to a loud noise.
The girl later became known as Patty Duke (Atson),
who won an Academy Award at the age of 16.
Now, we have two Pattys here.
I see. I didn't even notice
that it was the test.
Didn't notice?
Yes. I was thinking this might be the last time I can play Helen, then I started to forget that I was Kitajima Maya, and then I knew the alarm was going off, but I didn't feel anything.
This girl…
What about you, Ayumi?
I just played the role.
You told me to wait as Helen.
Then what if it was a real emergency alarm?
I wouldn't have stopped until I was told to do so.
Great work, Ms. Himekawa.
No wonder the critics call you a genius.
Judges, may I please be excused now?
Ms. Kanaya?
There's no need for me
to be here anymore now.
Thank you for everything.
Kanaya Emi, I would like to cast her someday.
No, I would like to lobby for
Himekawa Ayumi!
Just think about
the acting audition.
Kitajima Maya's simple acting
is no comparison to hers!
Yes, I would agree with him, too.
…Sullivan, it will bring merit to the theater just for these factors alone.
Wait a minute.
I don't mean to interrupt, but we shouldn't have had an audition if you use those criteria.
That's right.
The purpose of the audition is to judge solely by acting…
Argue all you want.
The executive director and the manager are on my side.
Besides, we have Himekawa Utako and myself; and we'll chose Himekawa Ayumi for Helen by 4 to 3.
I was very intrigued by Kitajima Maya's acting for some reason.
So was I.
I have high expectations that she will play Helen as she has never been played before.
We can't run a business on just expectations.
But…!
Enough said.
I say we put it to a vote.
Let's be democratic about it.
I'm scared. They haven't
made up their minds yet?
Help me, Mother, Rei,
everyone… Sakurakōji…
Miss Tsukikage.
Why is it taking so long?
What's going on inside?
I, Himekawa Ayumi, have so much insecurity and anxiety.
This girl.
That's right.
It's because Maya's my opponent.
She's making me nervous.
I see, they will vote to decide.
Meeting in session
It must be tough for Himekawa Utako.
She's torn between the love of a mother
and her pride as an actress.
I will read the votes now.
Himekawa Ayumi.
Kitajima Maya.
Three to three.
The last vote will decide.
Them, I will read the last one.
Hmm…
T-This is…
What?
Whose name is it?
Both names…
Who did this?
It was me.
Utako.
I chose as the actress
who will play Annie Sullivan.
I'm sure Himekawa Ayumi will play the perfect the perfect Helen, but Kitajima Maya has an interesting possibility of playing Helen as she has never been portrayed before.
I couldn't discard either from my choice.
I hereby announce the decision.
Helen Keller will be played by…
…Himekawa Ayumi.
And, also, by Kitajima Maya.
We decided to double cast them.
Double cast?
With Ayumi?
With this girl?
They will take turns each day to play Helen Keller with Annie Sullivan, played by Himekawa Utako.
By the way, this play, "The Miracle Worker," might be nominated for acting awards by the Academy.
Now, please greet each other in the spirit of cooperation.
Ayumi…
I won't lose.
I will play Helen with Ayumi.
Under Director Onodera…
…and with her mother as Annie Sullivan.
I wonder if I can go on, as Helen.
So, the decision has been made.
It is lonely by myself…
…and I almost stumble.
Somewhere calls me here,
just like a whisper in the wind.
Purple light, shining down
on the horizon…
…more surer than words…
…telling us gently…
…that we'll meet
each other someday.
Of course you can
fly from far away…
…for the dream
on my cheek…
…belongs to you.