A mask which is as fragile as glass,
people wear it to hide their own faces.
THE GLASS MASK
On the stage, with the lights off…
…blue shadows emerge.
Dancing 'round to hear the applause…
…I listen carefully to an
unpredictable tomorrow.
Everyone has a dream…
…with stars in their heart.
Stage light: a moment to shine…
…this city becomes a shining star.
The flower in my heart
is as fragile as glass, a shinin' dream.
You can do it if you want to,
so hold on tight to love…
…because there's someone that smiles
on the other side of my tears.
You can do it if you want to,
this feeling in my heart…
Don't cry. Keep on running
and running, for someday…
The audition for the role of Helen Keller has passed.
The five chosen candidates have each gone through very strict tests.
Maya has earned the role of Helen Keller in the form of a double casting with Ayumi.
—Episode 20—
The Two Helens
A few days later, the cast of "The Miracle Worker" were introduced to each other.
Now, let me introduce the cast members.
Annie Sullivan will be played by
Himekawa Utako.
For Mr. Keller, the father's role,
Jinno Tatsuhiko.
For Keiko, the mother,
Matsumaya Michie.
Now, let me introduce the two Helens.
Himekawa Ayumi.
Yes.
Kitajima Maya.
I can never win against Ayumi.
Kitajima Maya, I won't be defeated by you.
Hey, little girl.
Congratulations on your new role.
Thank you.
This is an important play for Metropolitan Entertainment's new building.
Do your best.
Of course I will do my best so that the young president, Mr. Masumi, can't make fun of me.
Look at me, little girl.
Hayami Masumi of Metropolitan Entertainment is talking to you.
In the entertainment business, greetings and politeness are much more important than acting itself.
If you don't like me,
then that's fine.
Just don't show your personal emotions.
If people don't like you, then you're
done for regardless of your talent.
Now, remember that.
I didn't know you were so kind,
Mr. Masumi.
I have never seen you
giving advice to an actress.
Our reputation will be affected if one of our actress doesn't have manners.
Practice started the next day.
A 7 year-old Helen Keller has lost three of her senses due to high fevers, and was raised selfishly.
Her young teacher, Annie Sullivan, teaches her how to speak.
Ms. Sullivan tries to use violence to teach her some manners and how to write, but Helen doesn't understand why Ms. Sullivan does such things.
However, with time, Ms. Sullivan's passions would be rewarded.
One day, when Helen touched some running water from the well, she learned that it was a thing called "water."
Since then, she understood that things have names, and Ms. Sullivan was trying to teach her that.
Please keep my advice in mind when acting.
Does anyone have any questions?
Yes, what about Helen?
Oh, you.
I doubt that you need my advice.
You have Miss Tsukikage,
a great teacher.
If I give advice to you, then I might
spoil your free-willed acting style.
Hey, Mr. Onodera is not going to give any advice to that girl.
It must be revenge against Tsukikage, who doesn't give up the play rights for "The Crimson Goddess."
Hey, Ayumi, about Helen's act.
About how Helen should act?
Yes.
Then please…
Huh?
Please give me the same advice you gave to the other Helen, Mr. Onodera.
Ayumi?
Excuse me.
T-Then do what you want.
Ayumi… What a person.
She's always so confident.
No, Helen!
Hey, did you hear that sound?
It didn't seem like she was acting.
I'm no equal to Ayumi…
Double casted every other day.
I'll be compared with Ayumi.
Ayumi, who I can't even come close to no matter how hard I try.
Hey.
Sakurakōji.
I was on my way to your apartment…
…but I saw you here.
Sakurakōji, you seem taller than before.
You think so?
I haven't seen you for so long.
How have you been?
Fine.
How about you, Sakurakōji?
You thought about me?
Of course.
Why?
I will be acting in
"The Miracle Worker."
Yeah, I heard.
It's a double cast
with Ayumi.
I heard that, too.
W-What are you doing?
We finally get to see each other
and this is how you act, Sakurakōji?
M-Maya.
Hey!
I still like you, Maya.
I like you just the way you are.
Come on!
I like you when you're smiling
like an ordinary girl.
Hey, wait!
Sakurakōji…
All right.
Wait!
I've got you.
Maya.
I have to go. It's late.
That's right.
I'll walk you home.
No, that's okay.
It's close.
Have to go!
M-Maya!
See you later, Sakurakōji.
Maya!
See you later, see you…
When can I see you, Maya?
You're always busy with acting…
…and it's always me
who has to ask.
Oh, why is my heart
beating so fast?
He just grabbed my hand.
Why?
Why won't you teach her
how to act like Helen?
She's right.
Maya will be compared…
…with Ayumi everyday.
I heard that Ayumi is not getting any help either.
But, she has Mr. Onodera, a well-known director.
That's okay. About the only thing he can do is to ignore Maya.
And Maya will act even better
if she's ignored.
This play will be a battle
between Ayumi and Maya's talent.
And I'm so looking forward to the outcome.
The battle between
Maya and Ayumi had already began.
Backstage
Are you sure you don't want to see Ayumi practice?
Yes, I'm sure.
If I see how Ayumi acts, then I will remember the Helen played by Ayumi.
I'm afraid of that.
My Helen and her Helen are different.
However Ayumi will play her Helen,
it's not my business.
Good work.
Your Helen was really great.
You were wonderful, Ayumi.
Thank you.
Ah, Ms. Kitajima.
You're up now.
Hurry.
Yes.
Sorry for being late.
Your Helen is different from hers,
so everyone is looking forward to it.
Ah, t-thank you.
Ready?
Yes.
Backstage
Excuse me, can I have some hot tea and rice cake?
You too, Ayumi?
I'll have nothing
to do with her acting.
I can't understand you two.
Maya's acting was contrary to Ayumi's perfect acting, something atypical.
Others couldn't take their eyes off her acting, packed full of emotions.
Oh, did it hurt?
I'm sorry.
No, I'm fine.
She's a hard one to act with.
I wonder why, but even I'm drawn
into her acting, her pace.
Good night.
We'll start the miracle scene
next week. Good luck.
Thank you.
Good night.
The miracle scene: that's the climax of the play where Helen touches the running well water and remembers the word "water," which she heard when she was six month old, learning that things have names.
After showering in well water,
Helen remembers it and learns that it's "water."
The miracle Annie Sullivan brought to Helen…
How can I express it?
How?
Water…
Water.
What are you doing, Maya!?
Shoot, you'll flood the apartment.
Water.
Ayumi, it's your grandmother.
I'm coming in.
What's this sound?
Young lady…
Water, water.
It's okay, grandma, don't worry.
Water…!
The opening day is finally coming.
Yes.
I've heard that quite a few judges from the Academy will be there, too.
Good. It would be great to win some awards.
It would give an even greater reputation to the name of Metropolitan Entertainment.
Yes.
The success of the play depends on how the two Helens will play the climactic miracle scene.
Wa… ter…
I don't understand.
The emotion Helen feels
at that miracle moment.
The word "water," which she suddenly remembers when she touched the water from the well.
How can I express it?
Huh?
The cord.
What's going on?
Young lady?!
This is it.
This is it!
Helen's miracle moment:
she's electrified by the water.
I can do it.
My Helen, the miracle moment.
Water, water, water…
Ryu, come here.
Okay, Mom.
I'm… I'm sorry, are you okay?
Ryu, apologize to her.
I'm sorry, Miss.
Water! Helen was just a like water balloon before it exploded.
Filled so much with the word "water" that she was ready to explode with just a little trigger.
Uhh…
I can do it.
My Helen.
The moment that the water balloon hit me,
that was the miracle moment!
The new building of Metropolitan Entertainment and "The Miracle Worker" have both opened for their first day.
Wow, famous critics,
directors and actors.
What a crowd.
Judges from the Academy
are here, too.
Hey, where's Maya?
I wonder where she is?
The staff is supposed to be here.
Please, take your seat now.
No, I'm just fine here.
B-But…
I have a ticket.
I can directly see the stage
straight from here.
I will stand here.
Himekawa Utako's Annie Sullivan, Ayumi's Helen: the first day of the play was proceeding perfectly.
May I serve you some tea?
Hayami Masumi.
…greeting and politeness
are much more important.
H-Hello.
You seem to be doing fine,
as always.
W-What's so funny?
I'm greeting you politely.
Oh, excuse me.
Thank you for your polite greeting, Miss.
By the way,
may I sit next to you?
Y-Yes, please.
That taiyaki looks delicious.
May I have one?
What?
Oh, I know.
I'll be thirsty,
so let me get us a drink.
Why don't you see her play?
I don't want to see her play.
I have yet to see her Helen
even at practice.
I don't want to be stuck
with Ayumi's Helen.
I have my own Helen.
I see. But you can't leave the lobby because you can't stop thinking about it.
I wanted to ask you,
why are you so into acting?
Don't you want to live your life freely,
rather than acting out someone else's life?
You don't want to live a happy life
as an ordinary girl?
I don't know.
I don't know…
what's happiness and what's not.
All I know is that when I act, I feel something hot in my chest, and feel courage growing in me.
"I can do this," a feeling like that come to me, and I feel happy being alive.
My dream is to become an actress who can play "The Crimson Goddess."
I feel like that nearly impossible dream can come true someday.
I envy you.
Eh?
Mr. Masumi.
Here you are.
There's an urgent call for you.
Oh, I'll be right there.
Thank you for the taiyaki.
I used to eat it all the time as a child.
Did I hear him wrong?
I thought he said he envies me.
Ayumi played the perfect Helen that night.
Her Helen was in sync with Ms. Sullivan, played by her mother, Utako, giving the audience overwhelming emotions.
Helen folded her napkins on her own.
Helen folded her own napkins!
Helen folded the napkins!
Helen!
It's still the middle of the play.
The judges from the Academy
are clapping, too.
I want to win an Academy Award
no matter what.
With Himekawa Utako and Ayumi… Kitajima Maya is no comparison to Ayumi's acting.
I will show Tsukikage who is really appropriate for "The Crimson Goddess."
Ayumi…
It is lonely by myself…
…and I almost stumble.
Somewhere calls me here,
just like a whisper in the wind.
Purple light, shining down
on the horizon…
…more surer than words…
…telling us gently…
…that we'll meet
each other someday.
Of course you can
fly from far away…
…for the dream
on my cheek…
…belongs to you.