A mask which is as fragile as glass,
people wear it to hide their own faces.
THE GLASS MASK
On the stage, with the lights off…
…blue shadows emerge.
Dancing 'round to hear the applause…
…I listen carefully to an
unpredictable tomorrow.
Everyone has a dream…
…with stars in their heart.
Stage light: a moment to shine…
…this city becomes a shining star.
The flower in my heart
is as fragile as glass, a shinin' dream.
You can do it if you want to,
so hold on tight to love…
…because there's someone that smiles
on the other side of my tears.
You can do it if you want to,
this feeling in my heart…
Don't cry. Keep on running
and running, for someday…
"The Miracle Worker" opened its curtain
with a double cast of Maya and Ayumi.
The first day was successful
with Ayumi's perfect acting.
And now the second night, after Ayumi's
overwhelming act, Maya appears on stage.
—Episode 21—
Nominated for
Best Supporting Actress
Today is finally here.
Yeah.
Look at how much less of an audience is here today.
It's because this actress
playing Helen is less known.
Look at this. Even most of the flowers
are addressed to Himekawa Utako and Ayumi.
Quality rather than quantity,
it's how much of our heart we put in this.
Excuse me, here's a delivery.
What's wrong, Maya?
I'm nervous.
I'm afraid to be compared with Ayumi.
Maya!
Come look!
Hurry, Maya!
Huh?
Ms. Kitajima Maya
Wow, look at the size of this!
Maya, here.
"I'm looking forward
to seeing your Helen."
He's here!
Mr. Purple Rose!
He's looking, somewhere in this big hall…
…for my… my Helen.
Yes.
Your Helen.
Teacher.
Maya, it seems like you're calmer now.
Yes.
I'm looking forward to your Helen as well.
Teacher…
A miracle is not something that just happens.
You make it happen,
with your own hands.
A miracle is something I make
happen with my own hands.
"The Miracle Worker," played by
Maya and Utako, has started.
Young lady,
it's your day off today.
Please, hurry.
Thank you for coming,
Ms. Sullivan.
This is my husband.
This is Annie.
Nice to meet you.
Mr. Purple Rose.
I'll do it.
I'm not scared anymore.
Since when did this country became so big?
Where should I put the suitcase, sir?
Let's put it somewhere convenient for Ms. Sullivan.
Yes, that will be fine.
Where's Helen?
I'll take the suitcase.
No, I can carry it.
Oh no, I'll do it.
This girl seems so different from practice.
She seems like a totally different person.
That's Helen.
Oh no, it was my turn.
This is it: this breath, this rhythm,
the tension and the calm.
The actor who can capture that,
can grab the audience.
This girl doesn't know that yet,
but her instinct does.
She's leading.
This is dangerous.
Here, Helen.
Let's start with the doll.
D·O·L·L.
A doll.
What happened?
I moved from her hand.
She's supposed to slap me
in this scene.
What happened to Utako?
She's taken by Maya's pace.
Strange. I can see the darkness around her.
The darkness?
The darkness… the kind of darkness that Helen,
who was blind and deaf, was feeling.
The darkness that Helen was feeling?
There's plenty of light,
but by looking at her movement…
…it makes me feel blinded
to the things around her.
But, her movement is not like Helen,
or at least not what's known to be Helen's.
Just because Helen is being played
by a different actress makes it a whole new play.
Maya, you're great.
Wonderful.
They say a play is alive,
but you truly are alive now.
Helen and the lady teacher, Sullivan,
nothing was changed from the script…
…but Utako was feeling that the play
was going in an entirely different direction.
The first act was finally over.
Are you okay, Utako?
You're sweating.
Mr. Onodera, I have a favor to ask.
What is it?
I want you to let me take control of this play.
Huh?
I want to fight her Helen.
No ordinary Sullivan
can fight against her.
With her, I can not just act.
I've noticed that I'm not acting, but being real.
This is the first time this has happened.
I'm an actress.
To make this play a success, please.
Mr. Onodera.
I see.
I'll trust you on this.
It's an actor's world on stage.
Thank you.
The second act has started.
Sitting in the lobby, Ayumi's heart was filled
with a nervous feeling about Maya.
Please hurry up.
Okay, I'll get a bunch of film,
and we've got to take lots of pictures.
Great, why don't we have enough film
at a time like this?
But, this Helen and Sullivan
are really something else.
I've never seen anything like this.
What!?
What did he mean?
What's going on
behind those doors?
Rei?
Different.
This is different from practice.
Mrs. Himekawa Utako.
Why?
Here, Helen. I want you to understand
that things have names.
Helen.
Yes, I am Helen.
Whatever happens or changes,
I am Helen on stage.
The two were no longer acting,
but became real.
Maya became Helen, and, like her,
Utako became Annie Sullivan.
Between them was a shared rhythm,
and they were even feeling a sense of connection.
Finally, the climactic miracle scene came.
Here, pump.
No, your mom isn't here.
No, pump.
This is water.
W·A·T·E·R.
Water.
This is its name.
Helen!
Wa… ter!
The battle between Sullivan and Helen,
Utako and Maya, was over.
It's not over yet, it's a curtain call.
Open it up!
Look at that.
She didn't even kiss
her own daughter.
Maya. You inspire me
to keep up with you.
Mr. Purple Rose, did you see me?
My Helen.
I might have given up
without your encouragement.
Who?
Who's there?
Is it… Mr. Purple Rose?
Mr. Purple Rose,
I know you are there.
Hello there, little girl.
You.
Are you looking
for someone in a hurry?
I… I…
He must be important.
I know it's not you.
You really hate me now.
When can you stop
making that face?
The moment you see me…
…you act as if you've seen
a cockroach, centipede, or something.
Kitajima Maya.
Maya and Utako's acting has received more
and more attention as the play continued.
Ayumi's acting was
also acclaimed by the critics…
…but with Maya, there was an unknown and
unpredictable element that attracted the crowds.
When Maya and Utako were on stage,
their in sync acts had no scripts or rehearsal…
…and it was different every time they played.
Mr. Purple Rose, Mother…
please watch me.
Can you hear that applause?
Fukui Hospital
I hear it, I heart it!
I hear the applause.
How are you feeling, Haru?
Oh, Doctor.
You seem well.
All thanks to you, Doctor.
To take care of me with no money or family.
Oh, no problem.
Haru was taken to a hospital in Nagano
after she was found passed out on the street.
She had lost her eyesight
from malnutrition.
Hmm?
What's this scrap of paper?
It's my daughter.
Your daughter.
She's my only daughter.
She's 16 now.
She loves to act.
She ran away to be an actress, and I found
her picture in a magazine for a play she did.
I know it was a tiny role, but look!
Isn't she pretty?
Oh, what a pretty girl.
I'll be looking out for her in magazines.
Was that okay, Doctor?
You couldn't even see her face on that paper.
Besides, you don't even know if she even exists.
Shh. I know, but it's
the best medicine for her.
Maya…
I hear the applause.
Your mother hears it.
Mother…
"The Miracle Worker," which received
great press coverage…
…finally came to the last night
with a heated audience.
Please, this is for you.
Thank you.
A purple rose!
He's here, somewhere in here!
Mr. Purple Rose.
He's somewhere in here.
I have to hurry.
Where is he?
Excuse me!
Did anyone see who threw
this purple rose?
That's the girl who played Helen!
Please, I want to find the man
with the purple rose.
There's Helen!
I loved your Helen!
I came to see you five times.
Please let me through!
Excuse me!
I need to get through!
Please sign my book!
Please…
Watch out!
M-Mr. Hayami.
Move!
Are you okay, Mr. Masumi?
I'm fine.
It just hit my shoulder.
Why did he… for me?
I thought he hated me.
Are you okay?
Yes.
I… I misunderstood.
You might be a nice person, but I…
Thank you for saving me.
For you?
I can't let our product be injured.
The play has ended,
but we still have two extra nights.
That's the way it is, little girl.
D-Don't worry.
Until this play is over,
I won't be sick or injured!
He's always like that, a cold man.
Always.
He only cares about this theater.
Are you Kitajima Maya?
Yes, I am. But why?
Just for twenty minutes,
in a coffee shop down the street.
We were impressed
with your talent.
What? The main role?
For me?
Of course.
If you come to our studio,
we have TV shows, too.
Yeah, as a start, how about
a main role in this play.
Me for the main role?
It's not a bad story.
You can do it.
I'll take the job.
Really?
Then let's hurry up.
Oh shit, that's Hayami Masumi
from Metropolitan Entertainment.
E-Excuse us.
I don't have anything to do with
Metropolitan Entertainment.
You are so terrible.
I was about to get the main role.
What right do you have?
Always getting in my way!
Listen to me.
Don't just jump
onto any good stories.
They were scouts
from a B-class production.
If you get involved with them,
you'll look like a second class actress, too.
Remember that,
if you want to become a star.
It's my decision.
Please leave me alone.
Was it your dream to become
a second class actress?
Was it?
I thought you'd become an actress
who'd make your mother proud.
Mother…
Uhh, I…
Watch your act, little girl.
You've been nominated for Best Supporting Actress
by the Academy Awards Stage Drama Division.
Best Supporting Actress?
You are the favorite one, at that.
See you at the Academy Awards.
Hello.
I've been nominated
for Best Supporting Actress?
Yes.
Thank you for calling.
Oh, young lady, you've been
nominated for an Academy Award?
Young lady,
you don't look so good.
Young lady?
I'm not the only nominee.
There are five.
The favored nominee is that girl,
Kitajima Maya.
Don't misunderstand,
I don't care about the award.
But the public has chosen her as the best actress.
It must be a mistake, young lady.
It's only natural that you will get the award.
Mama… never kissed me.
I did all I can,
and I don't have any regrets.
I played Helen
as perfect as I could.
You're right.
All the critics said
how perfect your acting was.
But Mama has seen more potential
in her as an actress.
Not me.
That's why she kissed her.
Young lady…
I want to know.
What made her the better actress?
What's the difference between her and I?
I can't believe it.
I'm the favored candidate?
I can't believe it…
Mother.
Mother…!
It is lonely by myself…
…and I almost stumble.
Somewhere calls me here,
just like a whisper in the wind.
Purple light, shining down
on the horizon…
…more surer than words…
…telling us gently…
…that we'll meet
each other someday.
Of course you can
fly from far away…
…for the dream
on my cheek…
…belongs to you.
Miss Tsukikage makes her appearance
on the Academy Awards party…
…to see how far Ayumi and Maya have progressed.
There she announces which one of them
is going to play "The Crimson Goddess."
Please look forward to the next episode:
"New Doors".