A mask which is as fragile as glass,
people wear it to hide their own faces.
THE GLASS MASK
On the stage, with the lights off…
…blue shadows emerge.
Dancing 'round to hear the applause…
…I listen carefully to an
unpredictable tomorrow.
Everyone has a dream…
…with stars in their heart.
Stage light: a moment to shine…
…this city becomes a shining star.
The flower in my heart
is as fragile as glass, a shinin' dream.
You can do it if you want to,
so hold on tight to love…
…because there's someone that smiles
on the other side of my tears.
You can do it if you want to,
this feeling in my heart…
Don't cry. Keep on running
and running, for someday…
Maya's Helen Keller impressed the audience with a different style from Ayumi's.
In the meantime, her missing mother was spending her days in a hospital in Nagano and Maya was being nominated for Best Supporting Actress at the Academy Awards.
—Episode 22—
New Doors
See you later.
Where are you going, Maya?
Oh, Rei, I'm going back to Yokohama to see if the owner of Manpuku Ken ever found out where my mother is.
Maya, what are you talking about?
Today is the awards day.
She's supposed to call you when she finds out where your mother is.
Now, get ready,
or you'll be made ready.
Hurry, hurry.
It's almost time to go.
All right.
What should I do about the purple roses?
Should I arrange
to send some to her?
Tonight's party will be the first big award for Ms. Kitajima Maya.
You must be misunderstanding something.
Is that so?
Why should I have to send her some purple roses?
Because you lover her.
What?
Or is it because of guilt?
You think I love her?
No way. Don't be silly.
Mr. Masumi, you are denying your own emotions.
You understand her talent better than anyone, and you truly love her true self.
But, whenever you interact with her, you act very cold because of your social status.
To escape feeling guilty, you send her purple roses and keep on encouraging her.
You are Mr. Purple Rose.
But that's just cowardly.
Why don't you throw away
your mask as Mr. Purple Rose…
…and show affection as who you
really are, Mr. Hayami Masumi?
Mr. Masumi?
You are acting strange today.
Please arrange the ride.
Yes sir.
…and show affection as who
you really are, Mr. Hayami Masumi?
Here's your seat.
Thank you.
This way, please.
Metropolitan Entertainment is doing great this year.
Look at how beautiful she is.
As soon as she steps in,
the whole place becomes brighter.
She was born to be a star.
I know.
She's so confident.
It must be some kind of mistake that I have more of a chance at winning the award than she does.
Yes, it's just a dream.
I always wake myself just before the best part.
Ladies and gentlemen, let us start the Academy Awards.
The nominations for the awards and their presentations were carried out by divisions such as Music Division, Traditional Dance Division, and Western Music Division.
Now, the Stage Drama Division.
After many awards, the
Best Supporting Actor was announced.
Then it was time for the
Best Supporting Actress award.
The award for
Best Supporting Actress…
…goes to Helen Keller in
"The Miracle Worker…"
…Kitajima Maya.
Ms. Kitajima Maya, please.
Please come to the stage.
M-Me?
This must be a dream.
A dream.
The Academy Award for
Best Supporting Actress: Kitajima Maya.
Your performance in "The Miracle Worker"
has a freshness…
…that has never been seen before
and lends tremendous emotion to the play.
I got it!
That's why.
I see, I know now.
Oh, I feel like I'm still dreaming,
but ouch…
…it's not a dream.
Then the Best Actor and Best Actress
were announced.
Himekawa Utako won the Best Actress
award for her role as Annie Sullivan.
What an irony that her mother
and her rival both got awarded.
But it will make the best headline.
"The Defeat of a Genius Actress, Himekawa Ayumi."
Ayumi.
Congratulations, Mama.
Thank you, Ayumi.
Mama.
Mother…
Congratulations, Maya.
Thank you, Ayumi.
But I still don't think
you defeated me.
I finally understood
when I heard the award.
I still think I played
the perfect Helen.
If you'd have played a perfect Helen better
than I did, then I'd have really lost this award.
But…
Your performance in "The Miracle Worker"
has brought a freshness that has never been seen before…
Your Helen was a new Helen.
This means that your Helen and mine
were totally different people.
I have regained my confidence that mine was truly a perfect Helen.
Ayumi.
After the awards were given,
the reception was held.
There is no contention in that Metropolitan Entertainment monopolized all twelve divisions.
It is no wonder why your father can leave the business up to you with no worries, Mr. Masumi.
I bet he would be even more at ease if you got married now.
Are you seeing anyone right now?
No, unfortunately, not yet.
Well, we hear
you are a workaholic.
Would you like to dance with me?
Congratulations for your award.
T-Thank you.
An award-winning star
should not be a wallflower.
I don't know how to dance.
That's okay.
Just follow my lead.
Good, you're doing fine.
Why did you ask me to dance?
You were the vanguard in promoting
Metropolitan Entertainment.
Everyone's watching.
Just let them.
It will be good advertisement.
Advertisement?
You will be a star.
Huh?
You can't be a star if you are shy.
You have to learn how to sell yourself.
You can't be successful with just your talent.
Why… why are you
telling me all this?
Why don't you, as Hayami Masumi,
show your affection to her?
Why?
I don't want to break
a golden egg before it hatches.
I won't be a golden egg
for Metropolitan Entertainment!
Never!
This feeling.
That summer…
…he's Mr. Purple Rose?
Is he?
You are too young
for the love scene, little girl.
What happened? Has the heat
from the hall affected you?
No way.
That cold bastard can't be.
It's just a coincidence.
Did she notice?
No, she couldn't.
Hello, Miss Tsukikage.
Did you come to see your good student's award presentation?
A good student?
Yes, some future good students.
Future good students?
Everyone, we have
a surprise guest here.
A phenomenal actress, a lily of the stage drama world…
…and the actress from "The Crimson Goddess", Miss Tsukikage Chigusa.
The teacher of Himekawa Utako,
who won Best Actress award…
…and also of Kitajima Maya,
the Best Supporting Actress.
How are you, Miss Tsukikage?
Any words of celebration?
Yes. Both Helens have some extraordinary talents.
I must say they are suited to be candidates for "The Crimson Goddess."
Ms. Kitajima Maya, Ms. Himekawa Ayumi.
Please come forward.
Ayumi, would you like to practice for "The Crimson Goddess" with Maya here?
Miss Tsukikage…
Damn!
I would love to.
I would love to, Miss Tsukikage.
Everyone, I would like to take advantage of this opportunity…
…to introduce the two candidates for "The Crimson Goddess":
Kitajima Maya and Himekawa Ayumi.
The battle has just begun.
I will see how they grow
as actresses, and eventually…
…choose one of the two
for "The Crimson Goddess."
Ayumi.
Maya.
You had the first move.
I was going to purchase
"The Crimson Goddess…"
…and give actresses nationwide
the opportunity to compete.
To promote the name
of Metropolitan Entertainment?
Can I at least still hope for
the play rights, Miss Tsukikage?
I wouldn't give up the play rights
even if I were dead.
No more little tricks of yours, since we have many witnesses now. Excuse me.
There's a phone call for you.
Hello.
This is Maya speaking.
Oh, Sakurakōji!
Congratulations.
I'm impressed.
You're the first 16 year-old
to win an Academy Award.
Thank you.
Yes, I'm happy.
…America?
I'm leaving tomorrow at twelve o'clock.
I'm going to go
to acting school there.
I want to start learning
from scratch.
I'll come back
with ability and confidence.
I'll be there,
at the airport tomorrow.
I'll be there, Sakurakōji.
See you later.
Maya, your mother called.
What!?
The lady from Manpuku Ken just called the landlord.
She heard from your mother.
Hey, you keep looking at your watch.
Are you expecting someone important?
No, no one.
Manpuku Ken
About eight o'clock
in the morning.
She said she was fine
and not to worry.
I asked her where she was,
but then she hung up.
Is that so…
Fukui Hospital
Maya, I've lost my sight,
but I can still see you.
I'm always watching you.
Next time she calls, I'll be sure
to find out where she is.
So don't feel bad, Maya.
Yes.
Sakurakōji.
Maya, I'll do it!
A TV series?
He brought the offer
from the TV station for you.
He also has a television series for Ayumi.
Masumi must be caring for you guys.
To be fair to the candidates
of "The Crimson Goddess."
Masumi finally feels like letting the two candidates, Maya and Ayumi, grow for "The Crimson Goddess."
A TV series for me?
Maya, I don't know how well your act will carry to television, or how well you'll do in the TV world.
Teacher.
You might become a star,
you might not.
You might become worthless as an actress.
Teacher.
Any route you take,
the road will be rough and bumpy.
I… I…
What can I do?
Should I decline?
Teacher?
It is up to you
to make that decision.
Teacher…
You might even become worthless as an actress.
What should I do?
Mother.
Okay, let her in.
Excuse me.
Hello, little girl.
Welcome.
H-Hello.
Don't be so nervous.
I see. This is the first time
you've been here.
You can have a seat there.
No, thank you. I'm just here
to answer your proposal.
I… I accept your offer
for the TV series.
Good. I thought you'd reject it,
since you don't like me.
What made you decide?
Do you want to be know on
television and become a star?
This is for my mother.
Your mother?
If I'm on TV, my mother
might see me someday.
Then I might be able to find her.
I see.
Also, I'd like to thank you for this one, but I don't intend to owe Metropolitan Entertainment a favor.
Excuse me.
She had the upper hand, Mr. Masumi?
Hmm.
Even if it's difficult, she has to keep on walking without looking back once she starts.
She finally started walking, all by herself.
Oh, that Mr. Purple Rose guy you mentioned before. She doesn't need him anymore.
Yes.
Maya has moved forward to a new world,
from the stage to television.
Ayumi, who has refused all television offers in the past…
…has accepted the new challenge
and jumped into the new world as well.
Maya, do it.
Try and see how much your acting ability on stage will work for television.
Go on ahead, Maya.
Be destroyed as an actress, or overcome it and jump even further ahead.
What's important for you
is how you will grow as a person.
Ayumi, I'll do it.
You'll not only notice my freshness and originality, but also my ability…
…and someday…!
The battle has just began.
I will see how they grow as actresses…
…and eventually choose the one of the two for "The Crimson Goddess."
The roads you take might be different, but your destination is the same.
Now, both of you, start walking towards your goal.
Now, new doors have been opened.
That was also the start of a new maze of challenges.
Rolling, action!
It is lonely by myself…
…and I almost stumble.
Somewhere calls me here,
just like a whisper in the wind.
Purple light, shining down
on the horizon…
…more surer than words…
…telling us gently…
…that we'll meet
each other someday.
Of course you can
fly from far away…
…for the dream
on my cheek…
…belongs to you.