Weekly Shoujo Comic
Official Video Animation
Why don't you play with us, Rumi?
I'm Ruka!
If you're looking for
Kobayakawa Rumi, that'd be me.
You're like two peas in a pod.
Why don't you help people tell you apart?
Help how?
Like, wear some name tags,
or put a big mark on your foreheads.
Don't be ridiculous.
Just learn it already.
It reminds me, there is someone
who can always tell you apart.
It is none other than the lovely
Touma Katsuyuki.
See you later!
Sorry, sorry.
I'm glad that we took today's hike
separately from the men's club.
Rumi?
I know about Touma-senpai.
I could hear you back then.
Ruka, would you like
to go out with me?
S… Senpai?
Rumi…
I felt so embarrassed
to have you as my sister.
You ran away without
so much as a word.
Rumi, I…
You wanted to keep it
from me, didn't you?
I understand everything.
You knew I was in love with him
and wanted to spare me the pain.
Come here, girls!
We'll look for a shelter!
Rumi, about what you said earlier…
Oh, you're still thinking about it?
It's frustrating,
but I'll let you have him.
You'll have to give him
a proper answer later.
That you'll date him.
Rumi…
No way! These are human bones!
Oh my God!
I'm so scared!
We learned about these in history class.
It's one of these ancient mass burial sites…
Stop it!
Don't scream! Don't scream.
It's okay now.
We'll leave here
as soon as the rain passes.
Senpai? Senpai!
She's… She's dead…
I knew there was something strange
about this musty air.
Rumi!
I can't… move.
Rumi…
That's right.
It's like you told me.
I'm going to die anyway.
I should've told
Touma-senpai that I loved him.
The Darkness of the Sea,
the Shadow of the Moon
Volume 1:
A Revival of the Curse
Ruka!
Thank goodness.
She's awake!
Call the doctors!
Ah, you were in a coma for 3 days!
Mom?
No, you should stay in bed.
Where's Rumi?
I'm here.
Rumi woke up yesterday.
We were worried sick.
You two are the only ones
who were saved.
Just the two of us…
That graveyard!
I'm so sorry for these girls.
To die of a shock…
But we never stopped having hope.
Of a shock?
Well, they didn't sustain any trauma.
The doctors can't think of anything else.
But that's all wrong!
We hid in some old tomb, and the air there
was so fetid… we felt bad soon after…
Ah, that.
After the rescue action, the police
went further in to investigate,
but they found nothing at all.
That's not possible!
Tell them, Rumi!
Come on, tell them
about that terrible stench.
What are you talking about?
The newspaper only reported
that the girls died of a shock.
The discovery of the burial site got covered
without being linked to this incident
in a small note on a third page.
Anyway, we're resuming
the club activity from today.
Kobayakawa twins and Asako
are now the only girls on the team.
You'll train with the boys
for time being.
I see that not everyone
made it today.
– Ishikura!
– Sir.
Tell the news to the rest.
All right, let's begin!
Ruka!
Touma-senpai?
I'm so glad you're alive.
Let me take care of this.
S… Senpai… talked to me.
All right, kids!
That's it for today.
Let's clean this place up.
Oh, I didn't see you.
I'm so sorry.
It's better that you don't get used
to being close with the boys team.
A lot of stuff may happen.
You're such a child.
What was that?!
I'm just openly saying what I think.
Let me hear it again, Ruka!
You don't even know
how to recognize your rival in love?
I'm Rumi, not Ruka.
You're all the same!
I won't let anybody
speak to me like that.
What's your problem?
Let go of me!
Asako-senpai…
Rumi?
What are you standing there for?
Rumi, Asako-senpai… she just…
Did you know about it?
Of course I did.
It's all over school.
What are you doing?
I'm washing my hands.
What else?
But it serves her right.
She was nothing but making eyes
all day long with the boys from our club.
Rumi…
Let me say this, Ruka.
If you don't want to end up like her,
you better stay off
Touma-senpai as well.
What happened?
There's no way you could do it.
What made you
change so much, Rumi?
After that,
nothing happened for a while.
Rumi has not changed
ever since, either.
Could these terrible events
fade with time?
I couldn't believe it.
I couldn't accept like everyone that
my friends' deaths were caused by a shock.
What are you afraid of?
That's just me.
Senpai…
I came to ask for your reply.
I'm Rumi.
I could never mistake you two!
I'm sorry.
I know what you've been thinking.
But it wasn't easy for me, either.
I'm okay if you hate my guts.
Just tell it to my face.
I love you.
I'm so in love with you! But…
I see. All right.
Hm?
This is…
Were you looking
into this case alone?
I couldn't help it. I mean—
This story is essentially
identical to the Tutankhamun's curse.
Tutankhamun?
He was an ancient
Egyptian pharaoh.
It's a well-known story.
Most of the people involved in the excavation
of his tomb have died in mysterious ways.
This phenomenon caused quite a commotion
and media named it a "curse of the pharaohs".
Senpai!
Did these people really die
because of a curse?
They made it up, right?
There's no way it could happen.
Such questions are best answered
from an objective point of view.
Senpai?
I will investigate this thoroughly.
Don't worry about it
until I have more information.
Okay.
Don't be late
for the morning training.
Rumi?
I told you to stay away.
What happened to you?
What on earth is going on?
I don't know that myself.
But I've got to say…
It's so much fun.
You disregarded my warning.
Now you'll share Asako's fate.
Stop it!
Stop it, Rumi!
You fell off the emergency stairs?
How the hell has that happened?
Senpai!
Why didn't you go the normal way?
What were you doing there?
It's the Tutankhamun's curse.
It's the same…
Don't be stupid!
Sorry.
There's way too much
going on lately.
And you're in the center of it again.
Touma-san!
I didn't expect you here.
Well, I heard everything
from one of the club members.
Thank you for visiting our daughter.
But I'd like her to stay in a hospital
for a while, until her abrasions heal.
Huh?
That's weird.
I thought she fell from the fifth floor?
It's nothing short of a miracle.
I'm just glad she's safe.
I'll be on my way now.
It's okay. You can stay here.
No, I have something to do.
All right. See you!
Take care.
I'll walk him home.
Rumi!
Mom…
Let her.
Mom.
I can't go back to our home.
What are you talking about?
If I come home, I'll get killed.
By Rumi.
No, that's not Rumi.
That's not the kind Rumi we knew.
Ruka's acting weird recently!
So I noticed!
She seems to be
obsessed with something.
We're twins, but we're worlds apart.
Which one do you like more, Senpai?
You like me, don't you?
I guess.
You have much in common.
It's only confusing to have
two things that are the same.
Rumi?
I think I sprained my ankle.
Are you okay? Let me see.
Ow!
Please, help me get home.
There's nobody inside.
All the way to my bed.
That's out of the question.
You'd do that for Ruka.
What's your problem?
What is it that Ruka has and I don't?
What is it… Let's see.
Ruka would never pretend
that she sprained her ankle.
Yes.
Senpai?
I'm calling you so late, I hope
you don't get yelled at by any nurse.
I stayed all night up.
Did I wake you up?
No. I couldn't sleep.
Actually, I have something to share.
My dad is a novelist.
His name's Touma Yuichiro.
Well, it's okay if you don't know him.
Anyway, he lent
some historical records.
Some of them write in great detail
about the Tutankhamun's curse.
They also investigate the causes of death
of the people involved with the tomb excavation.
As expected, it was no curse.
Well, nothing got ever officially confirmed.
But if we trust this book's author—
Hello? Hello?!
Senpai, don't spend
too much time in these books.
Rumi?! Where'd you come from?
What does it matter?
The better question is,
how can I do such things.
Katsuyuki-san, I'm in love with you.
Where does she have
this strength from?
The line's busy?
Get off me, Rumi.
I don't like being pushed down.
I'm Ruka, though.
If you don't stop it this instant,
I'll get really pissed.
I love you, Katsuyuki-san.
Get ahold of yourself, Rumi!
You may look the same,
but your hearts are nothing alike.
You're entirely different people!
Ruka must be worried sick.
This is perfect.
You should listen to this, too.
Hey, dude!
What is going on there?
Takashi!?
Don't open the door! Wait!
What? It's just you?
How boring.
I heard a girl's voice.
I thought you brought someone in.
Don't be stupid.
It was just the radio.
I'm on the phone
with someone. Go away!
Ah, so that's where you hid your girl.
All right, all right.
This is all getting
just way too spooky.
But still…
Hello? This is Touma.
Senpai!
Ruka? Rumi was here moments ago.
What?
Yes… she can fly in the sky
and blends into things.
Yes. I'd be happy
if you were with me right now.
Is that right?
I'm sorry.
See you.
Fire?!
Why don't we see how Touma-senpai
is going to feel if there's only one of us left?
Let me go!
No can do.
Let's hug a little longer.
I guess that's enough.
I wish you
a warm welcome in heaven.
So hot!
Ruka!
Senpai!
You have to jump!
From here?! No way!
If you don't want to die,
you'll have to do it!
I'll catch you!
I promise!
Jump! Hurry!
Ruka… I got you.
It's all right now.
Did you see that?
See what?
I bet it was the same
with that emergency staircase.
Ruka has the same powers.
You may have the same disease.
That should do it.
Katsuyuki-kun.
If your theory is correct,
we should immediately see the results.
I am sorry I woke you up
in the middle of the night, sir.
Never mind that.
But I gotta say, like father, like son.
This man is my father's doctor.
What was that about a disease?
Well, that only matters
if you believe the book I've read.
I was trying to tell you
about it earlier.
It wasn't a curse that the people who dug
the Tutankhamun's grave died to.
It suggests that the cause
might have been a bacteria.
A bacteria?
In my opinion it's pretty plausible that
the tomb you hid in had a similar bacteria.
It killed everybody when you inhaled it,
but in your case, it gave you special powers.
It is a bacteria that do not exist
in the present day.
Thus, you were infected.
Infected?
But how come
that we alone survived?
My theory is that the two of you
were born with antibodies.
Antibodies?
How convenient.
So the people who further investigated
the site also had these antibodies?
It might be the case that this bacteria
doesn't survive long in contact with fresh air.
That's probably the reason
why the rescue party was unaffected.
Cool. I've heard enough.
I'm only in love with you, Touma-san.
Why can't you see past Ruka?
Rumi…
I… love you so much.
Rumi, please go back
to who you were before.
What happens if I do?
How did it go?
Incredible.
Their blood was confirmed
to contain unknown bacteria.
I was unable to see it under the microscope,
but there was a chemical reaction.
It might be a virus.
Can you find a way to treat it?
I don't know anything yet.
But I will concentrate on finding whatever
I can that'll keep their symptoms down.
In any case,
we've already got something.
Thank you, sir.
Sun's up.
We can go back
to being close sisters again.
The hope that it was possible brought light
to our hearts, which were shrouded in darkness.
Next volume
Ruka, who learned of Rumi's intense love
for Katsuyuki, decides to turn him down.
Furthermore,
she notices a relationship
between Rumi's unusual behavior
and current moon's phase.
She asks Rumi to go to the hospital
to run another test.
But something is going to happen
to Ruka in that hospital.
"The Darkness of the Sea,
the Shadow of the Moon", Volume 2:
"A Nightmarish Premonition".
Please look forward to it!