Weekly Shoujo Comic
Official Video Animation
Rumi…
Senpai? Were you here
the entire night?
So it appears.
We've slept together.
I'm sorry.
I'll go back to my room.
Your family may misunderstand
if they see us together like this.
I don't care about what
anyone thinks, really.
What I care about is you, Ruka.
S… Senpai?
Wait! I'm sick, remember?
Just like Rumi.
So what if you are?
Even if I do get infected, just because you gain
control over me, I won't become your enemy.
But Senpai, that doesn't mean—
You can call me Katsuyuki.
Waiting forever is not my style.
What's the matter?
Do you feel sick?
It… It hurts!
Oh, no! Did I kiss too deep?
Just kidding!
You're awful, Katsuyuki!
Geez!
I'm leaving Ruka with you, Mom.
Yes, yes. I'll look after her.
Take it easy, Ruka.
Dude, we'll be late!
Okay!
I thought you'd be here.
Ruka…
I will show you no mercy.
Darkness of the Sea,
Shadow of the Moon
Volume 3:
The Final Confrontation
Please forgive me,
but I know nothing about etiquette…
You don't have to worry about
etiquette in this house, Ruka-san.
Thank you, ma'am.
Katsuyuki's mother
didn't hear about anything.
I was very grateful for that.
I didn't know yet what to say about yesterday,
and she never asked me any questions.
Ruka-san?
Your tea will get cold.
Thank you, ma'am.
Girls are good…
If I had such a lovely daughter,
I could teach her the art of tea ceremony.
Who can it be at this time?
We are Kobayakawa Ruka's parents.
We would like to take our daughter home.
Oh, did she do anything?
We were cautious about our daughter's relationship
with your son, but now she ran away from home.
What are they doing here?
If she is there,
we would like to take her home.
What to do? If I run away,
I will only cause more trouble for Katsuyuki.
But if I go back,
I'll play right into Rumi's hand.
My son did leave Ruka-san
under my care.
Ma'am.
Ruka-san?
I will go with my parents.
Thank you very much for your hospitality.
It hurts! Let go of me.
Where's Rumi?
I thought she'd be
waiting for me outside.
If she's not here, it means
she must be with Katsuyuki.
She's at school.
Ruka!
You were supposed
to stay at my house!
My parents came to pick me up!
What?
But Rumi was nowhere to be seen.
She completely disappeared.
No one at school has seen her.
Then where is she?
No idea. Let's talk
to the rest of the club members.
Katsuyuki, are you sure
you're feeling fine?
Hell yeah I am.
You're not infecting anybody.
Let's go search for Rumi.
Mariko!
Oh? Senpai! Uhm…
It's me, Ruka.
Have you seen Rumi?
I think she went to the storeroom.
She went there
with the high jump boys.
Hey! Anybody there?
What's going on?
Don't tell me she's…
Probably. This is not good.
We've got to let the others know.
We'll gather everyone.
Listen.
Don't let them leave
the school grounds.
I want Katsuyuki-san alive.
But you can kill Ruka.
They're missing, as expected.
The only people missing are the three
from the Kawamura's high jump group, right?
No, we can't find
two more freshmen.
Touma, what is this about?
I'd like to ask you
to let everyone go home for today.
Rumi is very sick. We're worried
that she might infect other people.
Say what?
He's saying the truth, sir.
We think that Kawamura-senpai's group
might have been already infected.
Is her infection an airborne one?
No. It should be okay
as long as we don't touch her.
In that case,
we should be looking for her!
– Yeah!
– Let's go look for her.
But, sir…
We'll split into groups. Let's go!
Sir!
When we find her, we'll just get
everyone tested at the hospital. Don't worry.
They don't grasp the situation
nor the consequences.
What should we do?
Rumi!
What is she trying to do?
What is she thinking?
Found her?
Nope.
The boys are looking in the east wing,
so the west wing is—
Ah!
Sorry I scared you.
Did you find Rumi?
It's you, Ruka-senpai!
No, not yet.
Let's split. Mariko, go with me.
You two look on the first floor.
Okay.
What does Rumi-senpai
suffer from exactly?
We're not sure yet.
But I have to say,
you two really look alike.
I hadn't looked at what clothes you were wearing,
so I thought you were Rumi-senpai just now.
I see.
I can image.
Did you find her?
Ruka-senpai?
When did you get here?
Where's Mariko?
She was with you.
What are you talking about?
Ruka was here with me all the time.
But you were in the uniform,
didn't you?
Uniform?
It was Rumi, all right!
That's why she
poured water on you.
So, where are they now?
They're in the west wing.
Mariko?!
I kissed… with Rumi-senpai.
Huh?
Mariko!
Rumi must be still
somewhere nearby.
Wait! Something's
wrong with Mariko.
Her skin is freezing
and she's trembling all over.
Must be the sickness.
Maybe we still have time.
Shit. That bitch wants
to keep us trapped in here.
Ruka, let's search for a safe place!
What's going on?
No one she has infected has died so far.
Ruka, look!
Her skin went blue…
Marine blue, like deep sea.
Katsuyuki!
Her body is changing
from the infection.
It's getting back to normal.
The pulse stabilized, too.
No way…
And so, our cute Mariko
joins my little army.
Rumi!
Damn! When did
she infect all of them?!
What do you want, Rumi?
Ruka, you are going to die
from an accident.
Something will fall on you
during a casual training.
Stop it, Rumi!
Katsuyuki!
"Katsuyuki"?
Hmm? "Katsuyuki", huh.
When did you two become so close?
I can call Senpai…
I can call Katsuyuki what I want.
If that's how it is, I'll show you
something cool before I kill you.
I'll let you see which one of us
Katsuyuki-san really prefers.
Right, Katsuyuki-san?
Don't do it, Rumi!
Rumi…
Katsuyuki…
All that's left is to wait for
Katsuyuki-san to come to his senses.
Oh my God!
What did I ever do to her?
Katsuyuki!
Looks like it's starting to work.
Put him down.
His body temperature will drop soon.
Come with me, Ruka!
Spread out.
Block all exits from the school.
You have nowhere to run.
The reaction takes time.
It's only a matter of time
before Katsuyuki-san converts.
Hang in there, Katsuyuki.
Mr. Tajima! Mr. Ougi!
What are you doing here
at this hour?
Thank goodness. They're unharmed.
Sir, run away!
Huh?
What… What's with you guys?!
Sir!
Hey, now…
Anybody who tries
to defy me… will die.
Biology Room
His hand…
Katsuyuki's hand is so cold.
Katsuyuki!
I'm all right… for time being.
No, Katsuyuki…
You shouldn't go anywhere now.
Come with me, Ruka.
What are you looking for?
Katsuyuki?
Ruka, if my pulse stops,
use this to finish me off.
I'm telling you to kill me
before I start to convert.
This is the main artery.
You can feel the pulse here, can't you?
No! I could never
do this, Katsuyuki!
Ruka, listen to me.
If you don't do it,
it's likely that I'll try to kill you.
Watch my pulse.
If it stops, do not hesitate, got that?
Please, keep beating.
If you are going to die,
I want to die with you.
Katsuyuki?
Katsuyuki!
Get a hold of yourself, Katsuyuki!
It appears to me that
Katsuyuki-san's conversion is done.
Katsuyuki won't convert
or whatever!
He will never listen to you!
Nobody has resisted me yet.
Katsuyuki-san,
stand up and come to me.
Come on, Katsuyuki-san.
Katsu—
Yes. Walk towards me,
Katsuyuki-san.
Stop it! Don't go to her!
I'm so happy, Katsuyuki-san.
I love you.
Now, I have a small favor to ask.
Could you kill Ruka for me?
This is not real.
Ruka, run as fast
as you can on my sign.
Come, Ruka!
I don't believe it.
Why is it not working on him alone?
Are you okay, Ruka?
Never mind about me,
what about you?
Not sure, to be honest.
One moment, it stopped and I got calm.
So she didn't infect you?
Looks that way.
But why? How is this possible?
It's thanks to you, Ruka!
Huh? Me?
Exactly. Remember,
I kissed with you before Rumi.
Nothing else comes to my mind.
Your blood probably carries
some kind of antibodies.
Antibodies? In my blood?
You both have the same physique and everything,
but on the day you got infected, Rumi went crazy
and you managed to suppress the virus.
This was the big difference between you twins.
Thus, you developed
antibodies, so to speak.
I don't even want to think about it.
I can imagine.
Another day full of action again.
Let's go back and take some rest.
I'll talk to my folks.
Okay.
So frustrating.
This is not at all what I wanted.
I only have control
over those I don't care about.
I don't give a damn
what happens next.
Ruka! Just you wait.
Soon it will be full moon.
Oh? We don't have sweet sake.
I will go and buy it.
But…
I'll go with you.
Fair enough.
It's full moon tonight.
I have a bad feeling about this.
It'll be fine.
Rumi will be stronger, but so will you.
So will I?…
Honey, could you please
make me some tea?
Of course.
Oh? That is strange…
I am sure I closed it.
Whose turn is next?
Honey?
Dad… Dad!
Something happened to Mom!
It's Takashi-kun!
Takashi!
M-Mom!?
Ma'am!
Takashi!
Dad?!
What the fuck is going on, Takashi?!
T-That's…
Rumi-san.
Rumi-san did this to them.
Rumi was here?!
Talk to me!
Don't come any closer,
you murderer!
Takashi-kun?
You monster! You killed them—
Calm down, Takashi!
Ruka, can you go
to the next room for a bit?
This is just not happening.
This is too much!
Are you there, Rumi?
Come to the pier tonight at midnight.
We have to talk.
Ruka…
Are you willing to fight?
I won't forgive her.
I'll go with you.
Tell me the place and the time.
I'll come to you as soon as
the police questioning is over.
B-But…
I won't let something
like that happen ever again.
We're going to capture her, investigate
your sickness and return her back to normal.
It will be my last gift to my late folks.
Katsuyuki…
You did nothing wrong.
What did you want to discuss?
I've never hated you as much as I did today.
I won't forgive you anymore.
Even if I'm tied up or locked up somewhere,
I won't let you do as you please anymore.
Do you seriously think
you can stop me?
We are identical twins.
We got infected with the same virus.
I'm the only one who can stop you!
Don't get cocky, bitch!
We have no choice but to fight
until either of us will die.
You just started to use your powers,
and you dare to challenge me?
Interesting.
Give me your best shot!
I don't stand a chance.
She's way too powerful.
Ruka!
Katsuyuki!
Ruka…
Ruka!
Are you okay?
Where's Rumi?
You are already dead!
Snap out of it, Rumi!
Let me go!
Rumi! Listen to me!
My blood is the key
to treat your condition.
You know what I'm talking about, Rumi!
My blood is the reason Katsuyuki stayed normal!
She's speaking the truth.
So, please, let's end all this and
get you examined at the hospital once more.
And then what?
We'll just pretend nothing happened and go back
to the days when we both longed for Katsuyuki-san?
Rumi…
You and I were exactly the same,
in every single aspect.
The appearance. The constitution.
How we were raised.
Yes. Everything had been the same until that day.
The day when Katsuyuki-san confessed to you.
The following day,
we were infected with the virus.
If there was any difference
between us on that day,
it had to do with Katsuyuki-san.
For me, it was the happiest day in my life.
For you, it was the worst.
Exactly.
Since then our paths have diverged.
Or do you think I'm wrong?
No. That's probably the case.
I do not regret
that we parted our ways.
At first, I was going
to congratulate you both.
But I realized that it would be
pure hypocrisy on my part.
I don't really want to give
Katsuyuki-san to anyone.
What I do or whom I kill
ceased to matter for me.
I want Katsuyuki-san for myself!
Rumi! Rumi, open your eyes!
I hate you!
I can't even look at you!
You have the same face, the same voice!
You're the only one I cannot ever forgive!
If you want me that badly, so be it.
But my heart will never be yours.
My feelings won't change.
I'm only giving you my body.
Kill me if you wish.
Then do with me as you please.
But in return,
this ends here and now.
You will not kill anyone else,
and you will stop harassing Ruka.
Katsuyuki-san…
can be mine?
– Rumi, don't!
– Stay out of this, Ruka.
Rumi, what do you think
will happen if you kill Katsuyuki?
You love him!
You can't kill him!
Don't you get it?!
It's you who doesn't get it.
Katsuyuki-san said
his feelings wouldn't change.
So if I don't want anyone to have
Katsuyuki-san, the only option is to kill him.
Katsuyuki-san will become mine.
Don't do it, Rumi!
Rumi?
Katsuyuki!
Rumi!
I can't kill him!
I can't kill Katsuyuki-san!
That's right.
You would never kill him.
You turned back to normal
in the last moment.
It's better to think that way, Rumi!
Rumi, even when you get charged
with all these murders,
I will watch over you
till the bitter end.
Because you are
my other self, after all.