Moero!
Top Striker
Kick! My dream
Mayotetta kinou ni wa
Yesterday I'd been lost
Sayounara shite
Goodbye to that!
Kick! Your dream
Shinjiteta GOORU made
I believe in my goal
Kakedasou
and I'll reach it
Kanashimi no kaze wo kitte
Time to cut all the sadness
Nijiiro no obi wo hiite
and kick start the happiness
Tondeyuku atsui yume kimi to
I want to be where you are
Oikaketai
and chase my dreams
Hikaru!
We're here, Hikaru!
All right, let's go.
That's the counter attack!
A kickoff to the world!
Try to come at me from both sides!
Gotcha, Hikaru!
Remember, no pushing.
We're almost at the goal!
Hikaru, I'll assist you,
and you shoot from the center!
There!
He missed.
You shot it too high…
An overhead kick!
Nice one!
As expected from Hikaru.
Oops.
Hey! It's you pipsqueaks again?!
Sorry, ma'am!
Here's the scary goalkeeper…
Game over, Hikaru.
See you at school tomorrow!
Good luck with the practice. Ciao!
Ciao! Till tomorrow.
Next time I won't be so nice!
I apologize.
How's your form today, Hikaru?
It's the best!
If you keep at it, you'll become
a professional player in no time, Hikaru!
You can do it.
Cheering from the bench
in the next game again?
Don't let it get to you, Hikaru.
Thanks!
I'll be on my way, sir!
Hey, Toto.
That dog doesn't have
an ounce of decency.
Whenever it gets hungry
it comes fawning.
I'm home, Ms. Maria!
Good morning.
Dinner will soon be ready.
Don't take too long!
All right.
It's yours, Hikaru!
All right!
Move! You're in the way!
It was awesome, Julien.
Listen well, Hikaru.
The best San Podesta Junior
striker is me.
Your role is to pass me the ball,
and I do the rest.
You're Japanese.
It's just a fun game to you anyway.
Just keep low profile
and it'll be all good.
Julien…
Don't let it get to you, Hikaru.
Thanks, Mario.
All right, let's go.
Hey, I figured I'd find you here.
What are you impressions?
Do you see any future talents?
San Podesta's club team is famous
not only in Italy, but also in Europe.
I would say that it is quite likely
that some of this club's juniors
will join the ranks of world-class players.
They're the elite, after all.
Can't blame you if you can't
decide on any individual.
If I had to name some of them,
my attention is drawn to Mario,
and Julien who transferred from France.
They're something different.
I'm sure you'll notice.
Or maybe you were thinking
of someone else?
You can't possibly be thinking
of that Japanese?
He's been on the bench
for a whole year.
Geez, Mr. Robson.
You're here again?
The patients at the clinic
are all waiting for you.
Sorry, sorry.
I'll be there in a moment.
Sir!
I agree that the Italian boys
are eons ahead in terms of technique.
However, I have never seen anyone
play soccer so freely, have so much fun at it.
He's so young, and he's already one
with the ball both in mind and the body.
If he gets hooked on it,
I'm sure that in the future…
Sir.
Ah, I was just thinking out loud.
Yes.
You're thinking too much, again.
I'd understand if he took karate or ninjutsu,
but a Japanese, playing soccer? Fat chance.
Maybe you're right, Anna.
That's enough.
Sir, you're coming with me.
Don't hold me responsible
if the patients wither away or something.
Okay, okay.
That Japanese boy…
He's named Hikaru, if I recall correct.
Hikaru!
Teach… Teach us soccer!
I want to join
San Podesta Junior next year!
Then we can play with you!
Anything's wrong, Hikaru?
Next week, my aunt is coming
back from Japan to take me home.
What? You're going back to Japan?
But you came here to Genua
to study soccer, didn't you?
My dad used to work in Italy.
He loved this country.
So when I told him I wanted to study
soccer abroad, he agreed immediately.
But… about half a year ago,
when my parents were en route
from Japan to see me here in Italy,
both Dad… and Mom…
Now Auntie wants
to take me back to Japan.
She's a good aunt.
She's really worried about me.
But I…
Don't go, Hikaru!
Yeah, don't!
Stay and teach us soccer!
I want to study European
soccer more, much more.
Not just European.
Brazilian and Argentinean soccer, too.
And one day, to have soccer friends
from all around the world.
That is my dream.
If he gets hooked on it,
I'm sure that in the future…
I don't want to go back, either.
I like all of my friends here in Genua.
I want to stay here
and study soccer more.
That's the spirit, Hikaru!
You'll stay here in Italy,
and continue to play soccer.
Who… Who are you, mister?
I'm a dreamer, just like you.
Don't worry about anything.
Leave everything to old Bertini.
I appreciate his enthusiasm, but…
Can that old man do anything?
What do you say, sir?
I have to convince
Hikaru's aunt somehow.
Could you take him
under your wings
and make him into
a world-class player?
I know you can do it!
Aren't you forgetting
something, mister?
Mr. Robson is a doctor.
He doesn't teach soccer anymore.
When it comes to soccer, I know
much more than him. Right, Doctor?
Stay out of this, missy.
I am not talking to
Dr. Robson right now.
I am talking to England's legendary
ace striker, Albert Robson!
All patched up.
There you go.
Don't make your mom worry anymore
and stay out of trouble.
Okay.
Mister Robson.
I'll have you know that I have no intention
of going home until I hear your reply.
This is a hospital!
Keep your voice low.
But why?
You said yourself that Hikaru is
very promising when you saw him play.
So why?
I promised to never get
involved with soccer again.
Oh, that's right!
You were absolute favorites for that
World Cup, yet just before it started
you, the unbeatable ace of the team,
disappeared from the world of soccer
without so much as a word of explanation.
I don't know what
are your circumstances,
the fact remains that Hikaru
needs your power to stay in Italy.
Or are you saying that
you've truly given up on soccer?
Doctor has never
given up on soccer.
I know it the best that
he was an exceptional player.
Anna…
But he's right.
Your eyes look completely different
whenever you see Hikaru play.
Even if you retired,
I can see it perfectly well that
this boy has reminded you of the past.
Doctor…
Thanks for the food.
Oh? You've finished already?
Tomorrow's the day
your auntie will pick you up.
I appreciate Auntie's
concern about me, but…
I just…
Me neither, trust me.
It is very difficult for me
to let you go, Hikaru.
But stay positive!
I'm praying that you could stay
here with us forever.
Auntie!
Hikaru! How have you been?
Well, well!
Are you his aunt, ma'am?
Mr. Bertini!
Hikaru, who is this mister?
Well, Mr. Bertini is, um…
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
I forgot to introduce myself.
I was caught off
by a Japanese beauty.
Come in, come in.
It's a bit dirty, but make yourself at home.
Hikaru, Señorita and I have
some adult stuff to discuss.
What does he mean,
"a bit dirty"? Hmph.
Because of my line of work,
I've seen kids from many different teams.
But it's the first time I've seen a child
with such a great potential.
I'm sure that under my guidance
Hikaru would make it to the Europe's,
no, the world's best.
That's the kind of potential he has.
Do you understand, Señorita?
It's no wonder Hikaru doesn't want to go back
to Japan. You're the one who's deceived him.
Deceive him?
I was able to tell at a glance
whether you were a trustworthy person.
Do you seriously think I could leave Hikaru
in hands of a man such as yourself?
Hikaru is going back with me.
– Can we discuss—
– No, we cannot.
What an unreliable man.
Besides, who leaves a 11-years-old
alone in a foreign country
just so that he can play soccer?
It's unheard of!
Don't you think?
But Auntie, I'm not alone at all.
But… But, Hikaru…
As long as I have this ball, I can
become friends with anyone, anywhere.
I don't even need words.
This ball is all it takes.
You can make plenty of friends back home,
even without a soccer ball.
Ma'am.
One year ago, Hikaru's parents
came here to say hello.
They told me that ever since he was little,
as long as he had a ball, he was happy.
Even when his father had
to work abroad more than ever,
contrary to his parents' fears,
Hikaru would make tons of friends,
all thanks to this soccer ball.
I can't imagine what he'd be going through
if he was forced to say goodbye to it.
Soccer is a wonderful gift
that God gave to us.
That's what his parents told me.
Dad… Mom.
That's right.
Hikaru was born with a ball.
I knew his parents
would understand him.
You're forgetting the fact
that I am his family right now.
This conversation is over.
I am talking Hikaru
to the hotel right now.
W-Wait a moment!
I won't listen to anybody telling me
how to raise my nephew.
I will send someone
to get your luggage.
Auntie, wait!
P-Please reconsider, Señorita.
Ah, thank god we made it.
Robson!
We would be here much earlier,
but we had a surprise patient.
Thank goodness you're here.
Your presence is worth a thousand words.
Let me introduce you.
This man is said to have the longest career
in the history of world soccer.
He is former England's ace striker,
Albert Robson.
I read about you
in soccer books, sir!
You're the legendary ace striker!
Hikaru, was it?
Doctor is willing to coach you.
For real, Mr. Robson!?
No matter who you are,
nothing will change my mind.
We're going, Hikaru.
Wait, Auntie!
Hikaru!
Guys…
Hikaru.
Are you really going?
Don't go anywhere.
Please stay with us…
– Hikaru, don't go…
– Do you really have to?
Please talk some sense to her.
Dr. Robson!
Anna…
This is not happening.
My dreams…
Watch out!
Somebody…
Somebody stop it!
Watch out!
Somebody save that boy!
Hikaru!
What?!
Did you see that?
Amazing! Hikaru!
What a feat!
I… I can't believe it.
Hikaru…
Hikaru can do such
amazing things with that ball?
That's right.
That ball is a source
of tremendous power.
This little ball holds the hope and dreams
of many people thorough the entire world.
And Hikaru just proved to us
what miracles he can do with that ball.
Will you leave Hikaru under my care?
– That was so close.
– Are you okay?
– Thank goodness.
– You were so cool.
So can I really stay in Italy
and continue playing soccer?
Yes. It's just like your dad said.
It's no use trying to pull the ball
out of your hands.
Your dad dreamed of forming
a bridge between Japan and the world,
and became a diplomat
for this reason.
Who knows? Maybe you'll be able
to realize that dream.
Through your beloved soccer.
He's got what it takes.
And he's got me,
old Bertini at his side.
I'll be cheering for you from Japan.
Good luck.
Got it.
Thank you, Auntie.
Don't worry about Hikaru.
Please take good care of him.
Stay safe, Hikaru.
You be careful too, Auntie.
Goodbye, Auntie!
Goodbye!
We did it, Hikaru!
Hikaru.
I'm a cheap guy who finds kids and introduces
them to the club team to earn money.
But when I met you,
something clicked
and now I want to chase dreams
not thinking about money.
Mr. Bertini…
It's just like you said, Hikaru.
You'll make tons of friends
thorough the world some day.
It won't matter who they're from,
what country they belong to.
And together, you'll make a team
that the world hasn't seen yet.
And you'll not only become
a legendary ace striker,
you'll become
the best striker in the world!
The best striker…
But know this, Hikaru. The path
to accomplish your dreams is not easy.
Are you ready for my training?
Of course, Mr. Robson.
I mean, Coach.
Let me help you along the way.
See, I love soccer as well.
My name's Anna.
Nice to meet you, Hikaru.
Thanks. Pleasure's all mine.
All right. Let's do this!
My training has started.
But Mr. Robson doesn't
let me touch the ball.
Instead, he makes me do
all sorts of weird things.
But I want to get good at soccer!
Next time on Moero Top Striker:
"Aim to be the world's best!"
A kickoff to our dreams!
Mishiranu machi de deatta egao wa
The smile I saw in an unfamiliar place
Totemo suzushii hitomi wo shiteta
gave off such a distant vibe
Furimuita toki dare yori chikaku de
When I turned around,
I could see it closer than ever
Itsumo yasashiku mitsumeteta
those kind eyes fixed at me
Ashita ni kujikete nemurenu yoru
I'm crushed by tomorrow,
it's another sleepless night
Namae wo yonde miru
I'm calling the name
Ichiban saisho ni sotto
that comes to my mind,
Mune no naka ni omoi ukaberu hito
of the person I can't stop thinking about