Moero!
Top Striker
Kick! My dream
Mayotetta kinou ni wa
Yesterday I'd been lost
Sayounara shite
Goodbye to that!
Kick! Your dream
Shinjiteta GOORU made
I believe in my goal
Kakedasou
and I'll reach it
Kanashimi no kaze wo kitte
Time to cut all the sadness
Nijiiro no obi wo hiite
and kick start the happiness
Tondeyuku atsui yume kimi to
I want to be where you are
Oikaketai
and chase my dreams
Aim to be the world's best!
Mishiranu machi de deatta egao wa
The smile I saw in an unfamiliar place
Totemo suzushii hitomi wo shiteta
gave off such a distant vibe
Furimuita toki dare yori chikaku de
When I turned around,
I could see it closer than ever
Itsumo yasashiku mitsumeteta
those kind eyes fixed at me
Ashita ni kujikete nemurenu yoru
I'm crushed by tomorrow,
it's another sleepless night
Namae wo yonde miru
I'm calling the name
Ichiban saisho ni sotto
that comes to my mind,
Mune no naka ni omoi ukaberu hito
of the person I can't stop thinking about