kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 08:
Operation "Lightning"
I'm going to school.
Good day.
Hello, my dear.
I heard you won the match.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Here, it's a small gift for you.
They're beautiful.
They smell wonderful.
Thank you.
– Good luck.
– Thanks.
Hey, Yukari.
Hey, Mimi.
They newspapers wrote that Shirobara was going
to be the black horse in this tournament.
Now that we've beaten them,
they'll probably write the same about us.
Kimiko. Sumi'e. Tomiko.
If it weren't for you,
we'd never have succeeded.
Teamwork is the most
important in volleyball.
In the team, every one
of us is needed equally.
You're right. I used to think only about myself,
but now I can endure every workout!
Same goes for me.
Me too.
Thank you, girls.
With that kind of attitude, who knows,
maybe even the main prize is within our reach?
Then let's go and
win this tournament!
What's so funny?
I hope you're not being serious.
Your victory with Shirobara was just a fluke.
Excuse me?
We were simply better.
Exactly. Also, Shirobara isn't just any team.
They wrote in the newspapers that…
Then why aren't they writing anything
about the oh-so-great Tachibana?
Because… it was just a friendly match.
They wouldn't write about that.
I'm afraid you're wrong.
The tournament is around the corner,
which means that every match, official or not,
is going to attract media attention.
Since they don't write anything about you,
they probably think of your victory as pure luck.
This was no coincidence.
We won with our skills!
So long as we don't stop with the training,
we'll easily pass the qualifying rounds and…
Hijiri-san. I advise you to get down to earth,
otherwise she'll never stop making fun of you.
Ichijō-san…
What are you talking about? Mimi unites
our team and gives it a goal and hope
and trample all over it with your
virulent remarks. Have you no shame?
What if reality turns out to be
less beautiful than you paint it to be?
We'll become even
more morose, that's what.
I'm not going to defend
Shiraki-san's mockery,
but your naivety is shocking.
You don't know how strong Hadori Kyōko is.
Oh, and you know her so well?
Although I was sitting on the bench
at the time, when I was still in Shōyō,
we once played a match
with her and her team.
Wait, you went to Shōyō?
That's the school near Mt. Fuji,
famous from its volleyball club?
So that's where Professor Hara
was a trainer before…
Hadori Kyōko.
I still remember her spike,
going straight after our heads.
Our team was known
mostly for defense, not offensive.
Somehow it didn't stop her from
knocking us down like dominos.
Those of us who tried to defend
ended up with broken wrists.
The coach could no longer look
and called the game off at halftime.
He called doctors onto the court.
Soon after, Professor Hara became our coach
and we started slowly licking our wounds.
But, to cut to the chase…
We've got nothing to be happy about.
There plenty of schools with
attackers of Hadori Kyōko class.
Even if we somehow
win the qualifiers,
I expect we'd get eliminated
in the very first round.
Your captain is quite good.
She can assess the situation well.
See, Hijiri-san, there's no point
in setting the bar too high.
The higher you sit,
the more it hurts to fall.
Well said.
Speaking of which, I'm planning to ask
the school to give us exclusive access to the hall.
You're kidding me!
Our club is the only one who has
a shot at winning their tournament.
Giving the hall to us
is in the school's best interest.
Listen, Shiraki-san.
Ichijō-san, you too.
I will not give up
just because you tell me to.
We will not only get to the tournament, but also
to the finals and I'll tell you more, we will win it!
From today the goal of the training is
to develop your own unique attack pattern.
However, before we start, we need
to decide who is going to execute it.
Professor.
I think there is no better
attacker than me.
Yes. That's true,
you're not half-bad.
Hijiri. Although you have inconspicuous physique,
as far as I remember, you also have a good jump.
Hijiri-san has already proven herself on defense.
In my opinion, it's better to leave her there.
All right.
Hijiri, Ichijō. Let's see
which of you jumps higher.
She did it!
Nobody can beat Mimi.
Please, let me redo.
No, that's enough for me.
We are not the athletics club. There is no need.
Ichijō looks like a attacker
because of her height.
We're going to use this
to our advantage.
First, the defense
will play high to Ichijō,
which suggests that she'll spike and
lead the opponent to go into a block.
At this point, Hijiri and Ichijō
are jumping simultaneously.
Ichijō, who was supposed to spike,
passes the ball over to Hijiri instead.
Hijiri finishes with a light strike.
It's a variant of the two-stage attack.
Ichijō's passing to Hijiri has to be smooth.
Because it's supposed to resemble a spike,
it's going to be very strong.
In general, this should be enough
to mislead the opponent.
One more thing. Whoever receives the ball,
must send it to Ichijō as soon as possible.
The sooner, the better.
Looking from above, the ball will draw a lightning,
and that's how we are going to call this attack.
The "Lightning"…
Where have your eyes gone?
I'm here.
If you can't pass the ball to me,
we have nothing to talk about.
You don't have to remind us.
Just take it easy, girls.
Yes. We'll figure it out soon.
Mimi!
Ichijō-san, I understand that and all,
but you put too much strength into these passes.
To mislead an opponent,
they must look like a spike.
If they're too strong for her,
she has no business on the offensive.
She's right.
Ichijō-san, let's repeat.
Okay.
Training is harder than ever,
yet nobody complains.
There's nothing to worry about.
Step by step, we'll go further. And then,
who knows? Maybe national championships?
We're to play with
the Yokohama team?
Sir, please don't say
you already agreed to it?
Coach Kuroda just called
and invited us to a friendly match.
I couldn't refuse him.
We're playing next Saturday.
Is it true that we're going to play a match
with the Yokohama Port East team?
Yes, that's what we talked
with the coach about.
So it's true.
There's no point in discussing it all day.
It won't get us anywhere.
Our club will fall apart
even sooner than I thought.
On the other hand, it was
inevitable anyway, so why stall it.
Ichijō-san!
Fall apart?
Aren't you exaggerating a bit?
Think for yourselves.
Hijiri-san and I might still somehow receive
Hadori Kyōko's spike, but what about the rest?
It'll only break your wrists.
And then what? I see no other scenario
than closing the club.
Professor agreed to this meeting,
because he probably has had enough of us
and just wants to shut down this club already.
He'd never think that.
He could easily turn them down,
but for some reason he didn't.
He didn't even ask us
for our opinion.
Professor Hara has agreed to this match
because he believes in us and our skills.
Mimi's right.
What kind of coach would like to see
his own team disbanded? That's just stupid.
I'm going to train.
I'm gonna train until
my wrists are made of steel.
Hadori Kyōko is a girl just like us,
not some fairy-tale monster.
Exactly. And if she's like us,
why should we be any worse?
That's the spirit. Keep it up.
Ichijō-san, as our captain,
you'll train with us, right?
Of course.
I'd do that even if you didn't ask.
I'll ask Arashi if he could lend us
the equipment from his club.
One… Two!… One… Two!…
Hijiri-chan, what's gotten into you? You want
to start a bodybuilding club or something?
I asked for equipment, not comments.
Go practice some jūdō.
I'm just worried about you. You know,
if you're gonna hurt yourself and such.
Kimiko! Sumi'e!
Tomiko!
Yukari, what's up?
Get a grip, girls!
Get up. Get up!
Yukari?
Kimiko!
Where is everybody?
I told you, Hijiri-san.
They all resigned.
It's hardly surprising,
seeing how you broke their wrists.
Goodbye.
I had high hopes for you.
It was a mistake.
This is the end of your club.
Please don't say that.
Sir, please wait!
I just managed to reactivate the club.
Please don't do this to us.
Professor!
What a dream.
Professor agreed to this meeting, because
he just wants to shut down this club already.
It's not like that at all.
True, he didn't agree when we
asked him to become our coach.
At least not right away.
However, eventually he agreed and did so,
because he saw a potential in us.
And we didn't disappoint him,
we won with Shirobara.
Our team fought very well.
It's true.
You play to win.
Maybe he intentionally set up
this game with Yokohama?
He wants us to prove to ourselves
and to him what we can do.
That must be it.
We won't let you down, sir.
I promise that me and my team
won't betray your expectations.
I was wondering what the noise was,
and it was just you, Mimi.
I'm sorry if I woke you up.
It's okay. However, you should be in bed
a long time ago, young lady.
Look. The sun rises.
Mimi!
Yukari, what are you doing here?
I talked to the girls and we decided to do
an extra training session early in the mornings.
In the mornings?
Yes. We didn't want to do anything behind
your back, so we came to ask you what you think.
We want to practice.
Hijiri-san, will you help us?
With pleasure.
But you are sure that…
If we apply ourselves, neither Hadori Kyōko
nor her machines will scare us!
Wait, what machines?
What are you talking about?
You didn't know?
I heard the basketball club girls
in my class talking about it.
Apparently Shiraki-san saw her
train with a machine.
What else did they say?
Well, that this machine stands in her garden
and that she trains with it every day.
What's the number?
3-21-24.
I saw it in the newspaper,
so there's no mistake.
Which house is it?
Hadori's.
Hadori-san? You could've just said so
right from the start.
Oh? You know them, sir?
It's hard not to know them. They're the owners
of the largest corporation in Yokohama.
I didn't know they were so wealthy.
What a huge residence…
She's probably practicing now.
I thought she was going to practice receptions,
and she's practicing spikes at that speed?…
I see that you're busy as usual,
even though it's Sunday.
Rumi? When did you get here?
Literally just now.
I wanted to invite you for shopping.
Until I fully master this technique,
I don't have much time for such things.
Are you developing a new technique?
What does it look like?
It's almost complete.
Soon, you'll find out for yourself.
Can you finish it before
your match with Tachibana?
I think so.
Ignore that they're weak.
Show them who's in charge.
Naturally. I make it a rule
never to go easy on anybody.
The hall is practically ours.
When the volleyball club closes, the school
authorities will hand it to us on a plate.
When I asked you to arrange this match, I was
afraid you'd refuse saying they were too weak.
Well, well.
Coach Kuroda said so,
but I managed to convince him.
Thank you.
I know I can count on you.
I did it mostly for myself. Their captain,
Hijiri Mimi, caught my interest.
What? Hijiri Mimi?
Anyway, until we get the cup in our hands,
I won't go shopping with you.
That's a lot of time.
The tournament hasn't even started yet.
You also said that volleyball
is just a game for you.
Yes. Volleyball is
just a game for me.
However, this game is a good way of life
and I want to put everything I have in it.
A special technique?
What does it look like?
All I know is that she wants
to master it before our match.
And Shiraki-san told her
to show us who's in charge.
So Shiraki-san organized this match,
wanting to set a trap for us.
That's awful.
Who does go to such lengths?
I'd be more worried about Hadori Kyōko
and her spike. It's just amazing.
She strikes balls sent directly
from the machine at full speed.
"Volleyball is a game for me."
"However, this game is a good way of life".
What is this line, like from some cheap movie?
A good way of life?
Volleyball is a game…
and the game is a way of life.
But what is volleyball to me?
What's up, Mimi?
Ah, nothing important.
It's no use dwelling on that.
We'd better get down to training!
Yeah!
Hijiri Mimi.
I think that you have
an amazing potential.
However, you are currently
too focused on winning.
What's more, Ichijō Asuka
didn't come to train with the team.
Only when she shows commitment
can we talk about the team.
But for this to happen,
the girls need a big trial.
I put a lot of hope
in the upcoming match.
Hijiri-san, this is also your fault.
You wanted to win too much,
and look how it ended.
Will I be able
to give up on volleyball?
What exactly is it to me?
Hadori Kyōko's terrible attack
is tearing our team apart.
However, I still love the volleyball.
I'll play it even if I'm all alone.
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"Dangerous Game! Mimi vs. Kyōko".
See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offense
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death