kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 03:
Our First Admirer
Just a bit longer! You can do it!
See you at the bottom, crybabies.
Who does she think she is?
I'm sick of her captainship.
This girl does nothing
but sows discord in our team.
Let's take different route today, too.
How about the hills outside the city?
Good idea. Let's go!
These hills?
How far do they go?
It's said that the teams
who can conquer these hills
have a bright future
awaiting them wherever they go.
So it's not just us who poured buckets
of sweat on this hellish road?
Exactly.
Somehow that doesn't comfort me.
What a nice change.
I'm starting to see
the good sides of these hills.
We just keep running and running.
I'd like to play already.
I'd like to practice
my storytelling, too.
What are you talking about?
Stamina is essential, without it there's no point.
We run to train our legs and
later be able to jump well.
Changing the subject,
do you smell some food, too?
You're right.
Hey, it's the boys
from the jūdō club.
Oh, you're here.
Thanks, as always.
Alright, guys.
This food is from our sponsors.
I expect these plates
to be licked clean, understood?
Sure thing, boss.
Boy, this is delicious.
They have their own sponsors?
Must be nice…
Yes, but their club has special circumstances.
Arashi-kun's father is very respected.
How about our club
looked for some sponsors, too?
Great idea.
I agree.
Our club has only six people,
and you already think about the sponsors?
Hijiri-kun!
Come here for a moment.
Soon we'll be allocating
the budget for this semester.
Among other things, we'll decide
how much each club will get.
Could you fill out the application?
No problem.
We'll deliver it by tomorrow.
Thanks. See you.
Can I ask you, our captain,
to fill out this application?
Don't make me laugh. You know best
that I'm a captain just for show.
Why don't you fill
that paperwork by yourself?
Yukari, come on, help me.
Sure thing.
We'll be back soon.
Keep practicing.
Hey, I have experience as a manager.
Maybe I could do it?
Don't get me wrong, but here you are
one of the players, not a manager.
Go back to exercise.
Okay.
I don't think we can expect
too much money.
The committee will be definitely looking
at the achievements from recent years.
Our club has no recent achievements
and it's been closed for the last six months.
Despite that,
we've got to try, at least.
– Hey, Kyōsuke, hurry up.
– Okay.
Hey, we finally have the chance to practice some
receptions instead of running around as usual.
I'm all for it!
I don't think they're going to like it.
This is also an important part of training.
It'll be okay. Come on, let's practice.
– I'll serve.
– Me too.
All right, I'll be on defensive.
Ready?
Yes, bring it on!
I'm sorry, could you pass it to us?
Throw it to us!
Yes, I was just about to.
Looks like you'll have
to buy a new net.
I hope you have
enough budget for that.
What are we going to do now?
I told you…
Captain…
Leave it to me.
I'll go talk to them.
Ichijō-san said that?
Yes. I'm afraid
it won't end well.
Ouch!
Awesome. What precision.
Just like I thought,
Ichijō-san must've played before.
Which one of you
hit me in the head?
Where are you going?
Ichijō, was it you?
Come here!
Perfect. Finally we can settle this.
It was me!
Wha… What?
So it was you, Hijiri-chan?
Ah, everything's cool.
It doesn't even hurt that much.
I'm sorry.
There's nothing to talk about.
It's just that the window was opened so slightly,
that I thought you did it on purpose.
But it was only you, Hijiri-chan!
I don't think you can reach there from where
Hijiri-san stands without breaking the windows.
What… What are you saying?
Then who threw this ball?!
It was me, really!
Is that so?
Why don't you try again, then?
If it really was you,
prove it and do it again.
Okay.
Throw me the ball!
Sure.
I'll be happy to see it again,
this time from the front!
Close the window as it was then.
A bit more!
What? More?
Mimi, don't fool around.
If we break the windows, it'll be a disaster.
Show me what you can do.
She did it!
Well, well!
We have a little champion!
I'm throwing it back to you!
Close the window even more.
What?
Watch close.
Ichijō-kun, give me that ball.
Professor…
Hey, boys!
Close that window altogether.
And there you have it, show's over.
It was just about to get good.
I hope you don't think that volleyball
is about showing off such cheap tricks?
Anyway, take a look.
Where are you pointing, sir?
No, it's not possible!
Ouch! God damn it!
Professor, if you're so good,
why have you been hiding it so far?
I wasn't really hiding anything.
Professor was a very good player. In college,
he played for the Japanese national team.
How do you know all this?
Because he was a volleyball coach
at the school I used to go to.
Professor, we have a request.
Please become our coach!
We're begging you!
I'd love to do it, but you see,
you can't call yourself a team yet.
When you unite,
I'll come to you myself.
For now, you still have
to work on yourselves.
Hijiri-kun, tomorrow
is the next budget meeting.
Tell your captain that
she must be present.
No problem.
Thanks.
Mimi, you're not really going
to ask her, are you?
I have no choice.
She's our captain.
Ichijō-san, you heard him, right?
Would you go to this meeting for us?
I don't want to go to any meetings.
So you won't mind Mimi
going there on your behalf?
Be my guest.
We'd better count
everything again.
I'm afraid that it won't be so easy.
Everyone at school
knows perfectly well
that most of the budget will go
to our basketball club.
See you soon.
What did you say?
Yukari!
Good evening.
Here's a little something for you.
We should have at least two uniforms per person,
one for training and one for games.
Yes, we also need to think
about running tracksuits.
Now we use the same ones
we use for physical education classes.
Yes. I'd also like to order
a new net and balls.
Oh, gosh. My head hurts
from all this.
Now you understand,
child, why I'm always saying
that expenditure planning
makes me lose weight.
Yeah, I get it, I get it.
But it's probably nothing serious, ma'am,
because you're not exactly skinny.
You'd better watch your tongue, young lady,
or else you won't get these cookies.
Ah, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
It was just a slip of the tongue.
Student Council budget meeting
Good morning, Hijiri-san.
Do you need anything?
This is where the
budget meeting is held, right?
Yes.
Alright, thanks.
The only people authorized
to participate in the budget meeting
are the members of the Student Council,
and club chairmen or captains.
But I represent…
You don't understand.
Is the chairman there?
Could he come here for a moment?
Yes? How can I help you?
Only club chairmen can attend
the budget meeting, right?
Yes, that's right.
But wait, if the chairman can't
join for some important reasons…
Of course, but like you said, it must be
an important reason, such as illness.
And I've seen your captain
today at school, safe and sound.
Hijiri-kun, rules are rules.
I'm afraid Ichijō-san
must come here in person.
That's why we're forced
to ask you to go there.
It's enough if I just
show up there, right?
Of course not.
You'll need to negotiate with them.
This is the copy of our requests.
They'll try to downplay them, because
we didn't have any achievements last year.
So we're asking initially for 165,000 yen,
but if you manage to get 100,000, it'll be okay.
I've got this.
I'm not sure
if she really does, though.
Ichijō-san has already shown
that she can get what she wants.
I don't know. Somehow,
I have a bad feeling about this.
Then we have the Women's Volleyball Club.
As probably everyone knows…
I think we can just skip over them.
You're terrible. Let's at least
give them enough for the laces.
I'm asking the club captain to speak up. You've
entered in the form the sum of 165,000 yen.
Can you please explain
what you plan to spend it on?
I don't really know the details.
And she's supposed
to be their captain?
60,000 yen should be
enough for their club.
If you want more money,
go find yourself a sponsor.
Who would want
to finance a ghost team?
In my opinion, 60,000
is more than they deserve.
Mimi! I've got some intel
from the meeting.
Have they approved
the budget yet?
The look on your face
says it didn't go well.
That's an understatement. Our budget
for the whole year is 60,000 yen.
60,000?
Ichijō-san!
Yes?
For this sum we won't be able
to afford even uniforms.
What of it?
You're the captain
of this club, right?
How could you let this happen?
Yukari!
They told that if it's not enough,
we should find ourselves a sponsor.
A sponsor?
I'm sorry, girls.
I live on the hills and often see you
girls running near our house.
Ah, you're the one who lives in that house
with beautiful flowers, ma'am?
Yes. However, I haven't seen you for a few days
and I was wondering if everything was all right.
We had a budget meeting and then other things,
so we haven't really had any time to train.
I understand. By the way, I have a sick daughter
who has been bedridden since childhood.
She is a great fan of volleyball
and always looks forward to your visits.
However, she hasn't seen you lately
and she's been missing you so much.
I'm here with
a huge request in mind.
If this is not a problem for you, maybe you
could go jogging in our area again?
No problem.
Your visit made us very happy.
They're here!
Good morning!
Good morning, Kanako-chan!
I hope you'll get better soon!
If you're bored,
you can listen to my stories!
Stop it, unless you
want her to get worse.
How could you say that?
See you soon!
I have a question…
Yes?
Why is each of you wearing
a different uniform?
You see, that's because…
We have our uniforms from the last year,
but the freshmen didn't have any.
I can't wait to see you
in new uniforms.
Me too.
One, two! One, two!
How does the basketball club afford
new outfits for the whole team?
They just have good sponsors.
Maybe we will also find someone
who would be ready to finance us?
If we want to have decent clothes,
we will have to sew them ourselves.
In fact, many clubs do that.
If you want it, you can make it.
To be honest, I don't feel like playing,
at least not until we have proper uniforms.
Okay. Raise your hand if you agree
we could sew the costumes by ourselves.
Here.
Maybe it'd be better
to disband the club, after all.
– Good morning.
– Good morning, ma'am!
I'm glad to see you.
You can go outside?
She wouldn't listen to me.
She said she just had to see you.
To think that once I had
to force her to take walks.
This girl is supporting us so much and
here we're talking about closing the club…
Here, this is for you.
With this, you'll be able
to afford new uniforms.
There is probably no more
than 1,000 yen inside.
However, my daughter kept insisting
that she wanted to help you out.
We hope that you'll be able to quickly
raise the funds for the new uniforms.
My daughter would love
to see you in them.
Here. Take this.
Thank you.
You see?
We have our sponsor.
She is just a little girl,
but she supports us with all her heart.
I'm sorry, Kanako-chan.
We can't accept
your beautiful gift yet.
Rather of focusing on what really matters,
we were concerned with uniforms and budget.
Even the world's largest budget is useless
if there's no team to begin with.
I promise you that one day you will see
all of us in beautiful new uniforms.
Yes. But first,
we must work for this day.
I'm all in.
Me too.
Me too!
Let's give it our best, girls.
Yes!
Are you with us, Ichijō-san?
Alright, fine.
Ichijō-san!
Hey there.
Professor!
Young lady, I'd like
to express my gratitude
as the coach of the Tachibana
High School Volleyball Club.
As the coach?
As the coach…
Your support for their team turned out
to be more valuable than any funding.
Thank you.
Thanks to the warm support
of a single little girl
the team united and Daisuke
agreed to become their coach.
However, this event was only
the beginning of a long, long way.
A match?
You've got to be kidding.
So what if we lose? We should have fun
first and foremost, don't you think?
No. If we play, we must win.
That's the essence of sport.
A match lets us assess our skills
and tells us how much we need to improve.
Our first opponent will be
a team of adult fishermen.
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"A Serve at the Seaside".
See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offense
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death