kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 04:
A Service at the Seaside
What's up, girls?
Can we take some rest
for a moment?
Are you serious?
We rested five minutes ago.
Stamina is essential in volleyball.
We must build it, even if it is not easy.
Taking breaks all the time
won't get us anywhere.
Professor!
Please tell us how to practice!
Please, pretty please!
To be honest, girls,
I don't know much about you yet.
I'm unable to give you
sensible advice yet.
For now I'll be only watching.
Which one of you is the captain?
It is me, although in name only.
Actually, it was Mimi who was
supposed to be our captain.
All right.
Anyway, I need to get
to know you better.
Show me how you have
been training so far.
Catch.
Here.
Ichijō-san,
please come train with us.
The volleyball team consists of 6 people.
You know that we need you.
You're right. Until now,
we've been only running.
It's about time
to start playing seriously.
Looks like she's finally
ready to join the team.
Grandma, look what a big boat.
Yes, very big. The gentlemen from
this boat brought us a lot of fresh fish.
Ah, boss!
I'll be damned,
it's Grandma Hijiri-san.
Please stop calling me that.
I am the president of the
Fishermen Union, not some "boss".
Right, boy?
Don't pretend to be such a big shot.
I remind you that I've known you from diapers.
No one can mess
with you, eh, ma'am?
It's good that they came
back in one piece.
Yes, I am very happy, too.
Dad!
What's up, Sankichi?
Morning, ma'am.
Well, Sankichi?
What did you want?
Next week, our club has a friendly
match with another school.
We'd like to rent a minibus.
Can you give me some money?
We'll talk about it later.
But Dad, you told me
you'd always help us.
They just moored. I have my hands full here.
I don't have time for that now!
It wouldn't hurt if it were you
who helped me sometimes.
Hello, boys!
Hey, boss!
Look who's here!
Get down to earth, you old wolf!
If you insist!
But it's always the best on a boat.
He called him the old wolf.
Men always make up
some nicknames.
Don't hold your arms so loosely.
Put your hands forward!
Let's try again.
Bend your legs a little more.
Okay, I'm throwing!
Senpai, next time at least warn us
and tell who you throw the ball to!
What are you talking about? You think
your opponent will be calling you, too?
She's right.
I can't warn you.
But when you stand on a platform
and throw the ball wherever you want,
it's hard for us to react in time.
Fair enough.
Mimi and I will play a real spike.
Come on, Mimi.
Ready?
Yeah, bring it!
Again. Get ready!
Yeah!
Let me try attacking, too.
Hijiri-san, play it to me.
Okay.
Get ready.
You okay?
Are you all right?
Remember, we don't do it because
we want to bully you or anything.
A real opponent will take advantage
of every weak point they find.
And you can see what it is for us.
That's enough for today.
Professor, can we finish for today?
Yes. I'll trust your assessment.
Grandma, why don't we
eat fish today?
Put it down, child.
Ah, boss, what do you
recommend today the most?
Hmm, I'd have to think.
Let's see.
How about this?
It's just delicious. I'll make a special discount
for you and the first one will be for free.
Thank you very much.
Feed your granddaughter with it and
her volleyball club will become unbeatable.
Thank you.
I heard from my son that the volleyball club
is the poorest in school.
Shove it where
the sunlight doesn't reach!
You're sure you don't want it?
I won't accept squid from anyone
who is mocking the volleyball club.
What, maybe your son's
jūdō club is any better, huh?
A bunch of gluttonous
dunces and parasites.
Did you just call my son a dunce?
What about you granddaughter?!
Spoiled and face like a pumpkin!
Pumpkin?
I think I misheard you?
You heard that right! I'll say more,
real pumpkins are ten times prettier!
Well, now you've said it.
Ouch!
What are you doing?
Let's go, Tsuyuki.
Okay, Grandma.
Wait, you old hag!
I see you're in good shape today.
Me! Me! Ah!
Hey, ma'am. Are you sure you want
to come back empty-handed?
Without any doubt.
Boss! Can you pass us the ball?
What are you doing there, boys?
Ha. We're playing volleyball.
Maybe you know some team
in the area we could play with?
Well, perfect timing.
This old woman's granddaughter has a team.
Apparently the weakest in Japan.
Well, that's great.
You see, when you are at sea
for a long time, you can get bored.
That's why we started
to play volleyball with the boys.
This grim bunch
is only suitable for fishing,
but this one ball has completely changed them.
Just look at their goofy smiles.
Now that we're on land, we thought that maybe
we could play a normal match with someone.
I'm certain that her granddaughter
will be happy to play with you.
You really don't have
any respect, sonny.
These men are just playing keep-away on board
and have never even been to a serious match.
Mimi may be not a world champion, but you
can see that such a match would be pointless.
Is that right? I see that you're
very sure of yourself.
But in sports, you never
know who's gonna win.
Don't be ridiculous.
There's no way Mimi
could lose to them.
So why doesn't she prove it
and play with them?
Come on, don't get too excited,
or your blood pressure will get too high.
No, no! You need to straighten
your elbows more!
Okay.
Let's try again.
Hijiri-chan!
Do you have a moment?
What's up?
I'm to tell you that there's a team that
would like to play a match with your club.
What? A match?
That's great!
I hope you're kidding me.
What team is this?
They're just a bunch of fishermen
who have never played seriously.
Well, that's just perfect!
No way. You're still too weak
to play with other teams.
So what if we lose? We should have fun
first and foremost, don't you think?
No. If we play, we must win.
That's the essence of sport.
I don't know, I play volleyball
because it's just fun to me.
So you don't care if we lose?
This match would let us assess our skills
and tell us how much we need to improve.
I also believe that losing should be an extra
motivation boost, to develop further.
So we have to win.
Well then, how's it gonna be?
Are you gonna play with them or not?
Professor?
That's something
for you to decide.
Why don't you vote?
Who wants to play the match,
raise their hand.
Mimi…
Alright. Boy,
they'll be happy. See ya!
If we lose, we'll make
fools of ourselves.
Not to mention that
we still don't have uniforms.
What are we going to do?
Faster, faster!
It's gonna start any second!
Oh, that's gonna be interesting.
It's just about to begin.
I hope Hijiri-chan will be fine…
Give your best.
We are total greenhorns.
This will be our first match.
I hope you'll go easy on us.
Actually, for us it'll be the first match
we play, too. Good luck.
Really? In that case, we're in
for an interesting game.
Mimi! Don't you dare lose!
Okay, Grandma!
Did I hear that right?
We've already won.
Is this how you talk to elderly?
I am three times older than you.
Hey, boys!
This old lady always
treats me like a kid.
Win this match and
show her who's the boss.
You can count on us. We ourselves bet
something valuable that we would win.
What did you bet?
Well, it's not exactly a bet, but if we win,
we'll buy uniforms for the whole bunch.
Boys got very passionate about it.
We've got the money saved up, and we've
even already agreed on the shirt numbers.
Everyone is looking forward
to these new uniforms.
I can't wait to see you
in a professional outfit, Dad!
You can count on us.
Go, go, sea wolves!
I'm starting to feel
the pressure a bit.
We'll win and teach
them the taste of failure.
Onward, sea wolves!
Hijiri-chan! You can do it!
Don't let some
old fishermen mock you!
Hanabi, better hold
onto something.
What?
The first shot
is the most important.
Oh, I get it!
Show them what you can do, man!
Konaya! Don't meddle
with your own defense.
Konaya, you blind man.
I've already had it.
Great, Hijiri-chan!
Keep going!
Now, nice and slow.
Stand back, Konaya! Phew!
Goal! Haha!
What are you doing?
Get a grip!
Fishermen · Tachibana
Second line!
They're doing well, for now.
Timeout, timeout!
What's this, gentlemen? Have you
forgotten about the uniforms already?
What is this nonsense?
Keep playing!
Alright!
Go, sea wolves!
May the wind be with you!
You ain't that old yet!
Tiny!
Over to you, Beanpole!
Fishermen · Tachibana
We won the first set!
Good luck, sis!
Fishermen · Tachibana
Good job!
Hooray, it worked!
Fishermen · Tachibana
I'm angry now!
Go, wolves!
Time to get serious, gentlemen.
Fishermen · Tachibana
Go, fishermen!
Hurray!
Well done, sea wolves!
You have done well, girls.
For our first match, it went well.
Grandma…
What are you gonna
say now, ma'am?
Just a fluke and that's it.
I guess the better team won.
Who in their right mind cares?
Thanks to your help, ma'am,
we could play a great game.
Thank you very much,
on my and my friends' behalf.
What's wrong?
Tachibana High School's Volleyball Club
is doing perfectly well!
What's with these grim faces?
Smile! What would Kanako-chan say?
Come on, heads up.
That's why I didn't want
to play the match.
We've just learned
the level we're at.
If we don't like it,
let's do something about it!
Mimi, do you realize what others
will think of us now?
Excuse me.
Thank you for the game yesterday.
Please, come in.
We've had a real blast.
Thanks to you, we'll now have the motivation
to continue our adventure with volleyball.
Once again, thank you very much.
You see, when I and my boys leave, we don't
come back for half a year or sometimes more.
Until now, we've been killing time
by playing cards and drinking alcohol.
However, since we started playing
volleyball, it's as if we were born anew.
We hadn't been as happy as we were
yesterday for quite a long time.
Thank you.
You're welcome…
You're welcome.
In this envelope you'll find
a small token of our gratitude.
Many thanks
At the beginning we wanted to spend
this money on sportswear for us.
However, we thought that it'd
be more useful to you than us.
I am very touched.
I'll gladly accept your gift.
Thank you very much. But are you sure?
You really looked forward to these new uniforms.
Workwear is enough for us.
Our game is just a simple play
in strong sea wind.
Our court is the deck of the ship,
and our uniforms are our working clothes.
It's plenty enough for us
to have our fun.
Me! Me!
I'll receive it!
Wearing uniforms at sea doesn't make much
sense, but for you, girls, it is very important.
Buy whatever you need
with this money.
Being able to help you is a real pleasure
for me and all my crew.
Don't worry about us.
Thank you!
Have a safe trip!
Thanks!
We'll be supporting you from afar!
Go, go, sea wolves!
Go, go, Tachibana High School!
And so the girls gained funds for the new uniforms
thanks to the generosity of the fishermen.
Slowly they began to realize that everything
is possible. And in the future… who knows?
Mimi, why did you take
the fall for Ichijō-san?
I realized that my head
was full of bad thoughts.
Bad thoughts?
Yes. I was happy to see
someone's misfortune.
For real! I'm telling you!
My mischievous brother Tsuyuki
put a rubber snake in my bag.
You won't believe the trouble
I got into because of it!
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"Thoughts Twisted Like a Snake".
See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offensive
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death