kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 05:
Thoughts Twisted Like a Snake
Although our heroines
have lost their first match,
thanks to the generosity of their opponents,
they managed to buy new sportswear.
At least those new uniforms
look good for you.
What's that, Professor?
I think we deserve a medal.
– Exactly.
– We deserve some praise.
Okay, okay. But it doesn't change the fact
that you have to train much more.
Yes, sir!
Let's go, then.
What, to do storytelling?
Of course not, I meant training.
Now that we have such nice uniforms,
it'd be a sin not to try them at once. Right?
Yes. Well said.
Get ready!
Okay.
– Again!
– You can do it!
They're like little girls
who just got a new doll.
Something tells me
that they'll make great players.
I suggest that we finish for today.
Come on, let's practice
a little longer.
At least five minutes.
I haven't learned the jump timing well yet.
I'd like to practice it a bit more.
I'm going to leave.
Why am I not surprised?
Ichijō-san is much better than us, so she
doesn't have to train as much as we do.
If we have to train more,
can we stay a little longer?
Okay.
Hurray!
– Ready?
– Yeah, bring it on!
The girls from the volleyball club
sure are full of enthusiasm lately.
New uniforms have given them wings,
but it's not going to last for long.
I'm so exhausted
that I can barely walk.
What's with you, girls?
Where's all your energy from before?
Remember that we still
have yet to do our homework.
Ah, that's Ichijō-san. I can see
why she wanted to leave earlier.
I'm so curious about her family life.
You didn't do your
homework again?
I'm sorry.
Are you ever going to improve?
What is that sound?
Ah… ah…
Today I shall tell you the story
of an ant that climbed the North Pole…
These girls have no respect
for school whatsoever.
Mr. Hara, as their club's advisor,
you should instill some discipline in them.
Mrs. Hirukawa, please refrain
from raising your voice like that.
I admit, however,
that I share your outrage.
Yes. Who sleeps in a class?
That's just preposterous.
Girls! Mimi!
You've got to hear it!
What's up?
The teachers had a meeting and discussed
Nishi-san, Ōta-san and Sekiya-san's behavior!
They talked about us?
Yes. They said that the first graders from our club
confuse the school with the training hall.
That you sleep during classes
and don't do your homework.
You really do that?
But why? That's not too clever.
Exactly.
Professor!
Don't get me wrong,
it's great that you want to train.
I also know that you're happy with the new
uniforms, but I think you're forgetting something.
You are high school students
first and foremost.
The club comes second.
Don't neglect learning.
That's all.
Let's begin the training.
Ichijō-san!
What happened here, Ichijō-san?
A certain someone is interfering
with hanging the net.
If anyone is interfering
with anything here, it's you.
What do you mean, Shiraki-san?
This hall doesn't belong
to your club only.
I understand that
you're full of enthusiasm.
But remember that
there are others here besides you.
Because of your egoism,
our club has to always practice outside.
I'm sorry, but we didn't know
you wanted to train here.
Do you want to let have their way?
Yes.
By the way, I think that boasting your
new uniforms is a bit uncalled for
considering that you just lost
to a group of amateurs.
Say that again, if you dare!
Wait!
You're like a rabid dog.
You should be put to sleep.
Shiraki-san, I can understand everything,
but you're going way too far!
You don't know
anything about Ichijō-san.
Why don't you tell me, then?
Enlighten us, Hijiri-san.
What is she like?
What is your captain like?
I'm listening.
They don't even know what their
captain is like. What a team.
You're worrying me, child. Every day,
you practice volleyball until late,
and then you sit around till late night with
your nose in the books. When will you rest?
I can't neglect my studies
just because I'm tired after training.
The first graders from our club were doing so
and we've got already scolded.
If us seniors also let it happen to them,
the future of our club will be questionable.
It was just a toy?!
Tsuyuki, stop fooling around!
He's messing with you because
he wants to make you laugh.
You should try to understand him.
You're right.
Good morning!
Hey, I have something to ask.
Hmm? Shoot it.
I'd like Ichijō-san to hear it, as well.
Hey, Ichijō-san. I thought a lot
about what the professor told us.
What would you say if we'd stay after school
an hour a day and studied together?
Then training after that?
Yes, sounds good.
I'm against it.
That way I'll be home later.
I don't like this.
Hey, everybody!
Oh, Hijiri-chan!
I have a request.
Let me guess, you want to look
into my English homework.
It's painted on your face.
What are you talking about?
Seriously?
No problem. I have my notebook
in my bag, you can borrow it.
Thanks, thanks!
You are wonderful, as always.
It's a snake!
I hate snakes!
Somebody help! It's a snake!
Somebody get it out of here!
Can't you see that it's just a toy?
Are you stupid or something?
A toy?
Yes. See for yourself.
Here, take it.
You're kidding me.
Who brought it here?
Excuse me. It was me.
My brother played a prank on me.
Like I'd believe you. I didn't think your club
would resort to such cheap tricks.
What?
It's obvious that you're trying to get revenge
for that argument in the sports hall.
It's not like that!
It was my brother who planted it to me.
Never mind,
just take it away from me!
I'll go and throw it away.
I'd sure like to practice…
It's not like we can play outside
in this downpour.
It's been raining
for the last three days…
It's a pity that it's not
our turn to use the hall.
Sometimes it's good
to take a little break.
Come on, let's do our homework.
I'll check the results for you.
Since we're not gonna train,
anyway, I'm splitting.
So maybe let's have
some free time?
I don't think that's a good idea.
It's been raining for three days.
If we don't practice for too long,
we'll lose shape.
Maybe let's go to the girls from the basketball
club and ask them to exchange with us?
Now that's a good idea.
That kind of things should
be dealt with by the captain.
I keep hearing nothing but
"captain this", "captain that"!
I'm your captain in name only.
I made it clear right from the beginning.
Oh, my.
But it is up to the captain
to represent the team.
Oh, really? So as your captain,
I give you my order.
Hijiri-san, go and ask them
on my behalf.
You don't have any sense
of responsibility!
Yukari!
Shiraki-san!
I'm sorry to bother you.
What do you want? If you came to ask
for access to the hall, I refuse upfront.
Please, we haven't been exercising at all
for the past few days. It's a big problem for us.
You ought to understand.
I think you have just
fallen off the turnip truck.
You couldn't even win against a bunch of old men.
The hall would only be wasted on your team.
What are you doing?
Hey, I'm speaking to you!
Ichijō-san!
If talking doesn't work on them,
maybe actions will.
I think you underestimate us.
Hands off me!
Stop it!
Stop it, Ichijō-san.
Now you're screwed.
Stop it! Calm down!
Headmaster's office
Where did it all actually begin?
Hijiri-san started it all.
She came to us demanding that we give way
to her, and then her club attacked us.
Hijiri-kun, what do you have to say?
That's correct.
Regardless of the circumstances, the destruction
of school equipment is unacceptable.
You're both suspended
for one week.
Please wait, sir!
Please reconsider your decision.
Our club has an official match in three days.
Our girls don't stand
a chance without me!
I will accept any other punishment, just let me
practice with them, even if until the match.
Rules are rules.
I won't change my decision.
Please, sir…
I accept my punishment and promise
not to train with the club for a week.
Good. Shoot. Yes! Now!
Good.
Ah, no, not like that at all.
Shoot! What are you doing?
Now. Now!
Good. Now.
Keep it up. Almost there. Now!
Shiraki-san?
What is it this time?
I came to ask you to withdraw
the suspension for Shiraki-san, sir.
That quarrel was our club's fault.
The basketball club is innocent.
You may extend my suspension to two weeks,
but please forgive Shiraki-san.
It's the captain!
I thought they suspended you?
They withdrew it.
So cool!
Good to see you again.
The victory is already ours.
We only have two days left.
Let's get to work.
The girls are rocking today.
It's a pleasure to look at them.
It sure is hot today.
I'm gonna borrow this
for a moment!
It's… It's a snake!
Help me!
Which of you came up
with this ludicrous idea?
Sooner or later, we'll figure it ourselves,
so you'd better confess right now.
Well, suit yourselves.
Since you're all so united,
I'm disbanding your entire club. Happy?
It's me!
What? You?
– No, it's…
– Really, it was me.
It was me who brought
this toy to school.
It's all my fault.
Fusejima-kun, tell me what
the student council's decision is.
At an extraordinary meeting of the council
it was decided that the responsible parties
shall be suspended for one month.
First a week, now a whole month?
Does this mean that Hijiri-san will not be able
to take part in our training for the whole month?
Sir, that wasn't the whole truth.
Ichijō-san,
don't say anything more!
I'd like you to take care of the girls
during my absence, instead.
Mimi!
Mimi? What are you doing here?
I'm practicing my jumps.
I want to jump higher.
Jump higher?
Yes. I practice here on the beach, because
it's much harder to jump off the sand.
I'd say it's a very good workout
for the leg muscles.
But… Hijiri-san, the principal
forbade you to train, right?
I just can't practice at school.
After class, I can do what I want.
I understand.
Then let me join you.
Me too.
Ichijō-san, wait a minute!
Today, the new supermarket in
Minamimachi has terrific discounts!
You can get 500 grams
of sukiyaki beef for 280 yen!
Mimi, why did you take
the fall for Ichijō-san?
It had nothing to do with her.
I realized that my head
was full of bad thoughts.
Bad thoughts?
Yes. When I heard
that Shiraki-san can't play,
I thought with unpleasant satisfaction
that it serves her right.
But when I saw her standing in the rain,
cheering for her team with nobody to see her,
it occurred to me that I'd feel exactly
the same if I was in her shoes.
I got ashamed that
I had enjoyed her misery before.
I felt very bad with myself.
To ward off bad thoughts, I decided
to take full responsibility for everything.
Let's get started.
Okay.
Mimi and her friends started
exercising on the sandy beach.
What other adventures await the girls
of the Tachibana Volleyball Club?
Whatever it is, let's hope that there are
no more victims such as this one here.
Looks like we're not gonna play
in the Spring Tournament.
What? Why?
They said we don't have a full team,
so we can't play with anyone now.
I see. I'm still suspended,
so we don't have a chance to play.
The news that we can't take part in the tournament
drives our team to the brink of despair.
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"A Difficult Beginning".
See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offensive
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death