kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 09:
Dangerous Game! Mimi vs. Kyōko
Victory against Shirobara gave Mimi and
her friends a boost of confidence
and awakened the desire to win
the upcoming Spring Prefectural Tournament.
This wasn't meant to last long, however,
because Hadori Kyōko, a great attacker
from Yokohama East Port High School
challenged them to an ominous match.
Hadori Kyōko. A mysterious figure
for whom volleyball is fun and a way of life.
Mimi began to wonder
about her own purpose.
The opening of the match against Yokohama
was marked by fear and doubt.
If we attack first,
we'll not only surprise them,
but it'll also quickly
allow us to get going.
It's the sign for the "lightning".
The "lightning"…
– Kimiko!
– On it!
Are you okay, Tomiko?
Everything's alright.
But boy, Hadori Kyōko
is even stronger than we feared.
Receive it with your hands,
not your belly!
Is this what you've trained
your wrists with a barbell for?
What?
The "lightning" again?
You know where to aim.
Kimiko!
How can you laugh?!
They're our players!
Hadori Kyōko clearly
plays at Kimiko and Tomiko.
Very clever.
We need to recover
the serve quickly.
Keep it up, keep it up, Hijiri!
We did it!
Now, keep it up, got it?
Yeah!
Yokohama East Port · Tachibana
What should we do, coach?
If this goes on,
we'll also lose the second set.
Please tell us what to do.
What do we do?!
Take it.
First of all, wipe away your sweat.
Then, take a deep breath
and think for yourself.
Sir?!
That's all?…
If we could figure out what to do by ourselves,
we wouldn't have to ask for advice.
Tomiko, how's your hand?
A bit swollen, but thanks to the training
it's far from breaking.
You're so easygoing. Hadori Kyōko
hasn't even shown her technique yet.
If the game is causing you problems now,
what will happen with her spike?
Ichijō-san, we're going back there in a moment.
Your remarks are only breaking our morale.
You're our captain.
You should inspire us, not break down.
Believe me, I'd like to destroy them as much as
you do, but nobody's sending me any good balls.
I have no way
to play the "lightning".
Wait a minute, that's right!
We haven't played it well even once yet.
That's why we are doing so poorly.
From now on, let's focus on it making it succeed.
I don't know if I can.
A little faith in yourself, Kimiko.
You really have nothing to worry about.
If you think that you must succeed by all means,
you'll only apply unnecessary pressure.
So what if it doesn't work out once or twice?
Take it easy and stay relaxed.
You did great at training.
It'll be alright, okay?
You're right.
We did it!
Operation "lightning" worked!
I saw it! I saw it!
It's their special technique, the "lightning"!
The "lightning"?
You're one tough girl, Hijiri Mimi.
Good. This is how a match should look like.
Yokohama East Port · Tachibana
What is she doing?!
Now we're talking!
Kimiko. Tomiko.
See? They're not so indestructible!
If this keeps up, we may even win.
But…
But they still haven't played
their secret technique, right?
No matter how strong she is, I'm sure
we'll be able to take it on once or twice.
It'll be enough.
We must believe in ourselves.
Yes.
The victory is within our reach.
We can win against No. 1 of this
tournament, long before it even starts.
We've come so far.
I want this victory.
For myself, and for our club.
We deserve to participate in this tournament.
Enough of this cat and mouse.
Time to get serious, right, girls?
Yeah!
Get serious?
I won't be fooled.
We will win this match and show
that no one can push our school around.
Good!
Tomiko!
She lost consciousness.
Stay with us. Say something!
Where am I?
Oh, my. We should call for help.
She'll be fine.
It's just a slight concussion.
Is everything okay, Tomiko?
I think so, but I blacked out for a moment.
I got hit straight in the head.
Hijiri-san.
What do you think of my technique?
I'll understand if you decide to forfeit this match.
Forfeit?
I make it a rule not to give anybody any favors,
not even the weakest opponents.
Even though I knew you
were a relatively new team,
I never imagined you wouldn't
have anybody in reserve.
If this goes on, my "mortar"
will damage one of you
and your club will get closed,
just like it happened a year ago.
I'd prefer not to be
associated with such stuff.
Who do you think you can damage?
Hijiri-san, I'm fine!
Exactly.
It worked once, big deal.
Don't listen to her, Mimi.
I wasn't going to.
Hijiri-san, I understand
that you're ready for anything.
In that case, I'll play with you seriously
and watch out, because I won't be gentle.
I wonder what will turn out better.
My attack, or your defense.
Yes. May the best one
win, Hadori-san.
Yokohama East Port · Tachibana
It's not good.
We have to do something about it.
It's going straight at me!
I have to receive it!
Ouch!
Kimiko!
Everything's fine,
everything's fine.
You can see that it's all swollen.
Ouch!
Kimiko!
Don't worry about me.
It's alright. Look, it's the whistle.
Yokohama East Port · Tachibana
So, what do you think
about my technique, Hijiri-san?
Have you changed your mind?
No. We will keep playing.
We will break your attack.
Mimi!
You keep surprising me, Hijiri-san.
You really did receive my ball.
No, I failed.
So what if I bounced it back,
if we didn't even make a counterattack.
I succeeded at nothing.
Hijiri… Girls.
It's not easy for me
to watch you suffer.
However, before you start looking ahead,
your team must face a great trial.
I keep my fingers crossed for you.
Yokohama East Port · Tachibana
We didn't get a single point
in the last set.
We've failed completely.
Both me and the team.
Kimiko and the others
trained so hard for this match.
Though we didn't suffer any injuries…
we blew it big time.
Hijiri-san?
Regarding who will use the hall.
After your club's defeat yesterday,
the school is inclined to give the basketball club
an exclusive access to the hall.
You know, just in case.
By the way,
no matter how hard you try,
without enough members,
the school will eventually be forced to act.
Without enough members?
What are you talking about?
I heard that two of you
had badly bruised wrists.
Your club will be disbanded,
sooner or later.
Kimiko?
No, I didn't see her today.
Thank you.
Yukari.
Kimiko didn't come to school today.
Neither did Tomiko.
Tomiko as well?
Yes. I got a bit worried,
so I decided to give them a call.
And?
They both went to see a doctor
and they weren't at home.
Maybe they got hit worse
than we thought.
I can accept Ichijō-san's
absence, but Sumi'e?
She was always coming.
I don't blame her, to be honest.
She also got injured.
No matter how you look at it,
we're the only ones left again.
I was ready for this
ever since we lost.
Actually, even earlier,
before the match.
That's why I wanted
to win so much!
Mimi…
In the end, Ichijō-san was right.
So at last you admit it.
I warned you
from the very beginning.
I said that we won't beat Hadori Kyōko.
That the more motivated we'll go to this match,
the greater will be
our despair after it.
And you said that all we have to do
is just to win the match.
Hijiri-san. I came here
to say goodbye to you.
Say goodbye?
Yes. I'll just grab my things.
Wait a moment. What kind of captain leaves
their team without caring what happens to it?
Believe me, I want to play, too. But how do you
want to do it with just the three of us?
Hijiri-san, this is also your fault.
You wanted to win too much,
and look how it ended.
Everyone wants to win,
it's only natural!
Think about it. In the second set we were so sure
that we'd lose, yet we won it somehow.
You wanted to win too much,
and look how it ended.
Ichijō-san saw right through me.
She's right,
I was too focused on winning.
It was obvious that a new team like ours stood
no chance against the best team in the prefecture.
We should've been taking
things slow, in small steps.
But it's too late for that.
Will I be able
to give up on volleyball?
What exactly is it to me?
Ichijō-san is not the shrew
everyone takes her for.
She was always serious at training.
She had this thing in her.
Then again, for Hadori Kyōko volleyball is fun,
and she makes that fun her way of life.
She knows what
she wants, unlike me.
Is something wrong, Hijiri-kun?
Nothing you wouldn't
know already.
Where's the rest?
No idea.
You have no idea? How do you
want to practice alone?
I was thinking last night
what volleyball really means to me.
I didn't come to any conclusion,
but I understood one thing.
I love volleyball.
And since I love it,
I'll play it even if I'm all alone.
I can't describe it well, but that's how I want
to remember my last year in high school.
I'm the same.
Yukari!
Mimi, why didn't you tell me?
I understand that you want to continue even
if you're alone, but you have me, remember?
I'm sorry.
I didn't want to bother you.
By the way, I heard that
Kimiko and Tomiko are back at school.
I'm not going to trouble
them anymore.
Who am I to ask them to play with me,
after what they've gone through?
Let's get started.
Okay.
To think that they haven't closed
their pathetic club yet.
What are they going to do with
just two people? I don't get them.
I would like to remind you
what you said to me earlier.
You promised to take full responsibility regarding
the application for participation in the tournament.
Yes.
And now everything seems to indicate
that your club will be disbanded.
In addition, the basketball club
will probably get the hall…
Sorry to interrupt you, sir,
but my club hasn't been closed yet.
Excuse me?
Give your best!
Freaks.
Let's go.
Yeah.
Wait, girls!
Kimiko?
Sumi'e! Tomiko!
We're not going anywhere!
Who told you we wanted to leave?!
Just because we went to a doctor
doesn't mean anything!
So good to see you!
How are your wrists?
Only slightly bruised.
Nothing serious.
I was so worried, Kimiko!
Thank goodness.
Let's start from the start,
this time taking small steps!
Okay!
Hey, girls. What are you doing over there?
I'll see you in the hall in a minute.
But it belongs to
the basketball club now…
So long as I am your trainer,
no one will push you around.
Professor…
Let's go!
Looks like they've passed
their first trial with flying colors.
I love volleyball
and that's all I need.
That's how I'll remember
my last year in high school.
So what if you or I work hard?
We have no chances, anyway.
That's the reason we train,
to improve the skills of the whole team.
It's no use! You know that we won't win anything.
Our participation is just a waste of time.
Preparations for the tournament
are in full swing.
Between one hellish training and another,
we receive a letter from Hanabusa-san.
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"Opening of the Spring Prefectural
Tournament". See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offensive
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death