kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 07:
The Deadly Spike
The permission to take part in the tournament
put the Tachibana High School girls on their feet.
However, in the hearts of the first-year students
unable to keep up with the rigorous training
soon appeared doubts
as to why they were trying so hard.
At the same time…
Yukiko, you must've been lonely.
The official games will start soon, so I have
to train a lot and have no way to visit you.
I'm sorry.
At first, I wanted to hide it from you,
but there is one thing I have to tell you.
Tachibana High School
Volleyball Club has been reopened.
They'll take part in the games. But I'll never
forgive them. Yukiko, I'm going to avenge you.
I'll grind Tachibana's
bones into the dust.
I'd like to come back to the time
when we both played together.
My poor Yukiko…
You've got to be kidding me.
They just withdrew Mimi's suspension
and you want to leave?
If you leave, our club
will completely fall apart.
We are aware of this.
Despite this…
Please, think it over.
Well, we've thought it all out,
that's why we came to you with it.
If there's something you're
not happy about, just tell me.
I'm not going to bite you.
It's no use.
It's no use trying to persuade them.
Let them have their way.
Ichijō-san!
– Since the cat's out of the bag…
– We'll be on our way.
See you soon.
What now?
I feel bad for Hijiri-san.
What, are we coming back?
I don't know, playing isn't fun
to me at all, more like frustrating.
Yes. It doesn't make sense.
That's not how it should look like.
Are you sure?
They say school times are the best.
Just fun, everything is rainbow and unicorns.
That's absolute hogwash.
These are lies for stupid people
who'll never achieve anything.
True growing up is about suffering and doubt.
Searching for a goal in your life.
Who the heck are you?
It doesn't matter.
What matters is who you are.
A bunch of cowards
who escaped from their club.
Pathetic.
But you… you don't know
anything about us!
Are you so sure?
I know enough.
You're mere nobodies.
Nobodies?!
Who are you to call us that?
I won't let anybody
to talk to me like that!
Finally some reaction.
Show some womanly passion already.
Womanly passion?
Our room once more will become
the Forbidden Room…
We'll become the subjects
of ghost stories again.
Don't say that!
I don't want to hear it.
You're still here?
You know that we can't play
with just the three of us.
Even the coach left us and
returned to play with plankton.
Seriously?
When even the trainer
abandons you, it's really bad.
We've been through so much together… I was
finally able to instill some motivation in the girls…
We've just learned that
they let us participate…
I'll never give up,
even if I end up all alone!
News, news!
You've got to hear it!
What's that racket?
We have a match!
We got challenged!
By whom?
Captain of Shirobara Academy
from Yokosuka.
Her name is Hanabusa Mitsuru.
Hanabusa Mitsuru?
Yes. She had a scary face.
I wish you had seen her.
She told us to make up our minds fast.
She's waiting for our response at the beach.
I love this kind of stuff.
Count me in.
Before we decide anything,
I'd like to meet her in person first.
So, where is she?
Strange…
Maybe you got the place wrong?
No, we were supposed
to meet here…
Look out!
It's you?
Yukiko…
Yukiko… Yukiko?
Yukiko!
Bring Yukiko back!
Apparently you know me.
Last summer, girls from your club
killed a girl named Wakamatsu Yukiko.
That girl was my best friend.
Killed? You got it wrong.
It's you who killed her!
Not true. We were still in
the second grade then. We have…
…nothing to do with it, right?
But you watched the third graders
as they tormented her.
You didn't do anything about it.
You are just as guilty.
Yukiko has been my friend
since childhood.
We played volleyball together throughout
the primary and junior high school.
We promised to each other that one day
we would play at a world-class level.
However, at the beginning
of high school, my family moved
to Yokosuka and
our paths diverged.
Yukiko has always been
so passionate about volleyball.
Why?
Why did it end up like this?
We were like sisters to each other.
Hanabusa-san.
You are absolutely right.
We understand you and know that
nothing we can do will return her to you.
There is one thing you need to know.
We love volleyball as much as she did.
This accident led
to the closure of our club.
We had to go to
great lengths to restore it.
I deeply believe that Wakamatsu-san
would understand how we feel.
I remember now.
You are Hijiri Mimi.
Am I right?
That's right.
In that case I'll repeat
what I told your friends.
I will never forgive you
for Yukiko's death.
I'm challenging us to a volleyball match
and I promise you to tear you apart.
Oh, no…
Good. We accept.
I'll tell you the time and place later.
Incredible. Her spike
could break bones.
What now? We accepted on the spot
without even discussing it with the coach.
Good. Thanks to this, maybe we can
persuade the freshmen to stay.
Our club is on the verge of disbanding, anyway.
There's no way he wouldn't agree.
You were here, sir?
Boy, that was a good nap.
So you haven't heard anything
we just talked about, have you?
I heard everything,
from the beginning to the end.
Ichijō. I am very understanding,
but do not try to replace me.
Ichijō-san said nothing wrong.
We really want to go back to the club.
I won't allow anyone to be call
me a coward and a nobody.
Exactly.
She pissed me off so much that now
I want to show her my womanly passion!
She provoked you well.
For me it's very simple. The captain of
Shirobara Academy, Hanabusa Mitsuru,
set herself a goal to break
your club with her own hands.
Of course, to be able to beat you,
she has to have someone to fight with.
That's why she had to somehow
convince you to come back.
Anyway, our club
is united as one again.
Please allow us to play
against Shirobara Academy!
What's the opinion of the rest?
I want to play, too.
Me too!
Even if it involves
some personal matters?
Only Hanabusa-san
thinks it's personal.
I'm sure Wakamatsu-san would be
happy to see our club reactivated.
Besides, I really want to play this match.
This will help us harden as a team.
Okay, you got a green light. But don't forget
that the suggestion comes from you.
Show me what you can do
and don't bring us shame.
Yes, sir!
That's the way it ought to be.
Faster, faster!
What are you doing?
It was a no-brainer.
Sumi'e, repeat the last service.
Hey, Arashi-kun.
I apologize for this turmoil.
There's nothing to talk about.
What did you want to ask me for?
I'd like you to play the ball at me
as hard as you can.
Wait, what? At you?
No way. Not a chance.
I can't do what you're asking for.
You can't, or you don't want to?
Hijiri-chan, if you'd ask me to go through
water or fire, I'd do it for you with a smile…
But that?
I think you know it's just a bit…
Oh, yeah? I understand.
Then our friendship is over.
What? What do you mean, over?
Let's not do anything hasty.
Okay, I'll do what you're asking for.
Just please,
don't break up with me.
Thank you.
I'm counting on you.
Should I hit my beloved
Hijiri-chan with all my strength?
They say girls have a hard time,
but guys sometimes don't get any better.
What are you waiting for?
Come on!
Okay, okay.
What was that supposed to be?
Haven't you eaten breakfast?
Show me what
you're capable of, Arashi-kun.
I said, stronger. Is that all
a jūdō club member got?
You don't deserve this black belt!
What… What did you say?!
You asked for it!
That's not it yet.
Again, harder!
Alright… A bit better!
Arashi-kun, even harder!
Give me a break!
No! We'll play until I fall!
That's enough.
Hijiri, I see that you already have a rough idea
of how strong Hanabusa's spike is.
Probably even stronger
than Arashi's throws.
You may receive it once or twice, but a slightest
mistake may result in a broken wrist.
Remember that even a durable oak
easily breaks under a strong wind.
The willow, in turn, seemingly so soft,
will not break even under the most gusty wind.
Strong shots should be taken like a willow, by
killing their power without going against them.
How exactly do you do it?
Unfortunately, I can't help you with that.
It all boils down to your skills.
That means you have to work out
your own technique.
By the way, I just talked with
Shirobara's coach on the phone.
We will play the match
next Sunday in this hall.
That's all.
Go back to training.
A willow?
To receive the ball like a willow?
What does that even mean?
What did he mean?
Willow will not break
even under the most gusty wind.
Strong arrows shots should be
taken like a willow.
I think I've got it!
Arashi-kun, please, help me again!
The willow doesn't break.
The willow doesn't break…
Taken like a willow.
Take it like a willow…
This is it!
A reception like a willow!
Go, go, Tachibana High School!
– Second line!
– I've got it!
Good job! Great, girls!
We're holding out!
That was amazing!
Hanabusa-san targeted me.
She'll keep on spiking in my direction
until she breaks me.
You won't get away
this time, Hijiri Mimi.
I will not let the first-graders
face that spike.
Let them handle the offensive,
while I'll focus on defense.
Tachibana · Shirobara
It was supposed to be impossible.
Last point in this set.
Just keep going.
Yes, sir!
Now that's a surprise,
our miserable team is leading.
I hope it doesn't snow today.
Awesome!
What's with you? That's totally not your style.
All your attacks are way too similar.
Hanabusa-san insists
on attacking Hijiri-san.
She's the strongest player on their team.
Without her, the victory is already ours.
In my opinion, it'd be a thousand times
better to play at their weakest points.
It'll be fine.
Hijiri Mimi has taken so many attacks
that her arms won't last much longer.
Hijiri, are your shoulders hurting?
Everything's fine.
I'm like a willow in the wind.
I feel almost like
we're doing too well.
I think they'll change the attack soon.
What do you think?
Yes, we should do it, too.
Maybe Mimi could start spiking?
No. I'm pretty sure that Hanabusa-san
will continue to play at me.
She must be thinking that as soon as she
defeats me, it'll be the end of our club.
In my opinion,
our offensive is good as it is, too.
I suggest we don't
change anything.
Yes. The key to winning lies in the ability
to accept her deadly spike.
Let Hijiri focus on defense.
Ichijō, I'm leaving you on the offensive.
Let's keep things
as they were for now.
You can do it, you can do it,
Tachibana High School!
Hijiri Mimi. I'll make with my deadly spike
so that you can never play volleyball again.
Just like I thought,
she only wants me.
Mine!
Get a grip! What's with those
sluggish movements?!
Tachibana · Shirobara
You can do it, you can do it,
Tachibana High School!
Focused on the revenge
Hanabusa Mitsuru and her deadly spike
suffered a crushing defeat against
the girls of Tachibana High School
and their great teamwork.
Wakamatsu-san…
Our volleyball club is still alive.
We have done our best and intend
to keep this up in the future.
I hope you can rest in peace.
Goodbye!
Hijiri-san, let me introduce
my cousin to you.
I'm Hadori Kyōko.
She's the captain of Yokohama Port East
High School's volleyball club.
My name's Hijiri Mimi.
I had the opportunity
to see your unusual reception.
I can't wait to face you
on the court.
Nice to meet you.
The pleasure is all mine.
Immediately after they won their first game,
the girls from Tachibana High School
met the captain of the team who will be
their next rival after Hanabusa Mitsuru.
What kind of enemy
will be Hadori Kyōko,
whose beautiful smile
hints a sinister challenge?
Anyone who has tried to deal with
Hadori Kyōko's spike
ended up with a broken wrist.
We should be realistic
and know when to give up.
No. I can't refuse such a challenge.
For Hadori Kyōko, volleyball is just fun.
I won't let someone like that win!
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"Operation: Lightning".
See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offense
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death