kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 19:
Black Clouds Over the Court
The girls continued their training
for the Interhigh Championships,
but then it was disturbed by
a suspicious man filming them in hiding.
The qualifying round began
in an atmosphere of uncertainty.
The suspicious cameraman
followed them like a shadow.
So that's the "lightning".
Great! You're doing well!
You'll be done soon!
Double spike.
Tachibana · Sei'iku
Is that him again?
Who the hell are you?
Why do I have the impression
that I know you from somewhere?
Tachibana · Sei'iku
New double spike.
Right on! One more point
and it's over!
Go, go, Tachibana!
Tachibana is going to
represent our prefecture!
You'd better make sure
they look pretty on the TV!
Hm? The TV, huh?
Kimiko, match ball.
You know what to do.
Yes.
Excuse me, sir.
It is said that Tachibana High School will win
this championship. I am one of their fans.
Maybe you would like
to interview me?
I'm sorry, but I'm out of tape.
Yeah, right.
Tachibana · Sei'iku
"Tachibana High School
tears Sei'iku Academy apart."
"Yokohama East Port in top form!
Hadori Kyōko's 'mortar' dominates the game."
"Tachibana slides into the third round,
easily beating Hachiku."
And that is the famous
somersault reception.
Tachibana · Tamagaoka
Kimiko!
On it!
I've got it!
A fantastic service.
"Will Yokohama East Port face
the same humiliation as in spring?"
They want to get back at us for their loss
in the Spring Tournament qualifiers.
It'll be fine.
We'll just beat them again.
Yeah, okay, but there's something
that's bugging me.
Like what?
That guy in sunglasses.
He watched us train.
What's more, he filmed us on tape.
Maybe he's a spy sent by
Yokohama East Port?
I don't know.
And I think there may be
something to it.
Hey, Mimi!
What's up, Yukari?
Listen, we're talking about
that guy with the camera.
The idea was that he might be
spying for Yokohama East Port.
What? You mean,
that guy with black glasses?
Filming all our plays, including
the "lightning" and double spike.
Plus we don't really know how much
Hadori Kyōko managed to improve her "mortar".
I'm very worried about it all.
So that's why he chased me away!
Next time I meet him,
I'll have a word with him!
Wait, Arashi-kun.
Rather than losing our minds
over such stuff,
we'd better develop
a new technique or something.
In other words, don't waste time
on nonsense and focus on training.
Yokohama East Port · Tachibana
Hijiri-san, don't think that I forgot
about our defeat in the Spring Tournament.
Today the tables are going to turn.
Hadori-san, for you volleyball is a game,
but for me it is everything I have.
Where could he be?
Did you see that?
She's improved a lot since spring.
Where did that coward hide?
Oh well, I'll go check
the other side.
How does Tachibana intend to respond
to Hadori Kyōko's new "mortar"?
Maybe I'll be able to see
Hijiri Mimi's new technique.
Timeout!
Yokohama East Port · Tachibana
What to do, sir?
If this keeps up, we'll lose this set.
Her new "mortar" is simply amazing.
There's no way I could receive it.
If we try to receive it by force,
it'll only break our wrists.
Mine's already swollen.
Yeah. It's a completely new technique compared
to what she showed at the Spring Tournament.
What do you think, Hijiri?
I agree with the girls.
But I think we could try
blocking it directly.
Directly?
I don't know
if it's such a good idea.
You're kidding me, Mimi!
We'll only get hurt!
Leave it to me.
Hijiri-san, do you want
to use the new technique?
I do not like this.
Remember, we're being
filmed all the time.
That's the one thing
we don't have to worry about.
Now that the match has started,
there's no point for them to spy on us.
No… He's here again today.
So he wasn't a spy for Yokohama.
Who is he working for, then?
Give it a break!
Focus on the game, on here and now,
not this nonsense.
Just remember that if we lose today,
it'll be the end of the road.
Now, go back there.
Yes, sir!
I feel in my bones that
they'll try something new.
This is it!
What… what are you doing?
I got you, spy!
What are you talking about?
What is this slander?
Shut your mouth! I know that you recorded
matches and training of Tachibana girls with that.
What to call it, if not spying?
Wait, where are you going?!
I'm not done talking to you!
Hold it, you pervert!
I got you, you bastard.
Give me the tape.
Your hand…
What's wrong with it?
Let go of me.
I can't move this hand.
I have poor circulation,
so it's cold as ice even in summer.
See you.
Jesus, what a repulsive dude.
We will win, no matter what.
Yokohama East Port · Tachibana
Thanks to Mimi and her somersault block,
Tachibana High School finally beat
Yokohama East Port and won
the prefecture preliminaries.
After a short break, the girls began
special training for the Interhigh.
Hijiri, I can see that
you're getting it.
Yes.
But the angle is still not enough.
You must be able to pull off
at least 45 degrees from both sides,
otherwise our chances of beating Shijōdōri's
"light" and "shadow" are quite miserable.
45 degrees!
It is impossible.
Sir, it's too hard!
You can't demand that of her.
Nishi! Sekiya.
Let me ask you something.
You can keep up with
Shijōdōri's techniques, right?
Keep up? Uh…
Not completely…
No, absolutely not.
Nishi. Sekiya!
And also Ichijō. Sugihara. Ōta!
If any of you can't do what I'm asking for,
we'll have to give up on the "V attack".
We'll play at the Interhigh and drop out like
we did last time, then disband the club.
How can you say that?
You should be ashamed, sir!
Geez, like two different people.
You don't understand anything!
We just won the qualifiers. The coach says such
things so that we don't rest on the laurels
and to give us an extra bit
of motivation to train.
Yes. Captain's right.
Our coach also does everything
he can so that we can win Interhigh.
Okay, fine.
I stand corrected!
If he wanted to make us angry, I'm angry.
I'll unload through training!
– Let's go.
– Okay.
All right, I'm playing!
I followed him right away and soon enough
I caught up with him, twisting his arm.
Then, they camera guy
started to grovel, like
"I'm sorry! It won't happen again!".
But his right hand was so creepy,
I'm telling you guys. All cold, like ice.
Hey, Arashi!
Huh? Yes, sir?
You didn't make up
this story, did you?
Of course not, sir! I really ran
after the guy and caught him.
The right hand…
No, it can't be him.
Opening of the Interhigh
Championships!
Finally that day has come.
The day when the Tachibana High School
girls returned to the magnificent National Hall.
Sanyo Women's High School from Chūgoku
Tachibana High School from Kanagawa
Their first match was against the Women's
High School Sanyo, a representative of Chūgoku.
It's not him. I think…
Did something happen, sir?
What? Oh, nothing.
Go, I'll catch up with you soon.
Yes, sir!
Don't you think the coach was acting
a bit strange in the hallway?
Yes, he looked very stressed.
Maybe he felt ill?
No, that's not it. He's probably worried because
we still haven't mastered the "V attack".
I'll tell you that I'm slowly
starting to share these concerns.
Me too. Usually, he's so nice, and here he turns
into a display of anxiety and despotism.
I can't rely on somebody like that.
Don't be so hard on him.
Come on, girls.
What is it? You look pale.
Is something the matter?
Fuwa, do you remember this guy, Todoroki Jun?
He played with us in college, in the club.
Todoroki?
Oh, he's the guy whose
right hand you damaged.
Yes. I damaged him on the court
and since then he couldn't play anymore.
It wasn't your fault.
You just had bad luck.
But why are you asking about him?
I'd like to know more about him.
Do you by any chance know
where is he, what is he doing?
Unfortunately not.
I see.
But don't sweat it,
I can always find that out.
All right, I have to go.
The match will start soon.
We'll talk later.
Focus first and foremost
on winning the championship.
You're right. Thanks.
Mine! Mine!
Sanyo · Tachibana
A beautiful spike!
Keep it up!
Just what are they so happy about?
They lost the first set and now they scored
some points in the second, big deal.
Time to catch
that damn spy for real.
Now's our chance!
Sanyo · Tachibana
What's going on?
Why won't we ask for a break?
Professor is worried about
the man with the camera.
But why?
Not good. The coach's anxiety
spreads to the rest of the team.
I know.
When the coach fails,
the captain must take over.
I need to cheer up
the girls somehow.
Are you okay?
Get a grip! We played with much stronger
teams in the Spring Tournament!
Just relax and play
like we practiced.
Yeah!
– Let's go!
– Okay!
Sanyo · Tachibana
Good job, Tachibana!
Keep it up! You're the best!
Sanyo · Tachibana
We won! We did it!
You did very well.
I'm sorry, girls.
Hijiri, I'm sorry I put you
in this position.
Forgive me.
Boy, I'm exhausted.
Time for a shower.
Hey, Hara! Congratulations.
Thanks.
I checked out Todoroki.
Yeah?! And what did you find out?
He's now the coach of the volleyball club at the
Women's Technical School Rinsen from Akita.
What? A volleyball coach?
There's more. His club
participates in this tournament.
As representatives of Akita?
It starts to make sense.
I knew that sooner or later
I'd have to look him in the face.
What are you not telling me, Hara?
Why are you so afraid of Todoroki?
Todoroki!
– Hi. – Haven't seen you
for a long time, man.
How many years have passed?
Four? No, wait, more like five.
Unfortunately, this late reunion
is to your disadvantage, Hara.
Disadvantage?
Yes. If everything goes well
on both sides,
Tachibana will meet my team
in the quarter-finals.
If that happens…
Hara, it will be your funeral.
I will do everything
to destroy your team.
Todoroki…
My only goal is to reach
the semi-finals.
Being a trainer is pointless
when you have a disabled hand.
Hey. Hey, wait, Todoroki!
Daisuke, Mimi and the rest of the
Tachibana High School's Volleyball Club
for the first time faced an opponent
who hated them with all his heart.
What will Todoroki do with the secret
recordings of every Tachibana's technique?
What kind of challenge
will our heroines face?
Nothing's working on them!
The computer only understands
data from the past.
It's the man who invents new things,
not the machine.
New things?
The "V attack"…
Finally, we have the opportunity to play with the
team that spied on us, Rinsen Technical School.
Will we be able
to beat the machine?
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"The Shocking Precision of Machines".
See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offensive
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death