kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 15:
The Charging Dragon
Is this where we'll be playing?
I can't wait.
Hijiri, I have to go to the hall to do
some things. Take the girls to the hotel.
Do you know where it is?
Yes, I marked it on the map.
Gee, will the coach ever stop
treating us like little children?
Well, technically
we're not adults yet.
The Isuzu Hotel is nowhere to be seen.
Are you sure we're looking in a good spot?
According to the map,
we're practically here.
I'll ask that girl over there.
Look out!
I'm sorry!
Thank you so much.
Thank goodness that you were here.
Thank you.
Thank you so much!
You're welcome.
Thank you again.
What an amazing girl.
She jumped almost like a ninja!
We'd better go back to looking for the hotel,
or else we're never gonna find it.
What? Ah, yeah.
It's there.
Hotel Isuzu.
It was literally around the corner.
And we've been looking
for it so much.
Thank you. Do you live somewhere nearby?
Can you get home by yourself?
My house is over there.
Oh?
Goodbye.
Wait a minute!
Do you need something more?
Thank you for showing
us the way. We're…
I know. You came here
to play volleyball, right?
It's a high school tournament, right?
I'm going to watch with my parents.
I'll cheer on you tomorrow.
We'll be looking out for you!
We're from Tachibana High School.
Tachibana High School, right?
Okie. Goodbye.
I'm home!
"We warmly welcome the players of the
Tachibana High School Volleyball Club."
So cool! To think I'm one of
those famous players!
We're finally here.
I thought we'd never get here again.
Gee, I'm so hungry
that I could eat a horse.
And there's you, doing nothing
but talking about food all the time.
I can't help it.
Where have you been for so long?
The sun is already setting.
I told you to go to the hotel straight away.
Today you showed me that I can't rely on you.
I apologize, sir.
We didn't come here for fun
and sightseeing. Stay focused!
Yes, sir.
Why are you looking at me like that?
It wasn't me. It wasn't me, really!
I'm sorry… I was trying to hold it back and
tensed my stomach, but it got out anyway.
Good, good. At least
the atmosphere loosened up a bit.
Coach, what about
tomorrow's match?
We'll play our first game with Ryūsei High School,
the representatives of Nagasaki Prefecture.
Ryūsei High School?
(Ryū – dragon)
Sounds dangerous.
Sugihara, don't judge
a book by its cover.
Don't think that they're special.
Each team in this tournament has proven
themselves in their prefecture qualifiers.
Each of them defeated many opponents.
We have to reckon with everyone the same way.
What's that?
Is that really the famous volleyball team
from Tachibana High School?
Have some confidence
in yourselves.
They say that confidence
is the key to success.
Boy, I gotta admit, I didn't expect
to see so many pretty girls.
Finally I can take a sit.
Really, a team of beauties.
I don't like that guy.
Me neither.
You're being very rude.
Coach, could you introduce us?
This is my friend from college and a sports
reporter for Tōzai Daily, Fuwa Tetsutarō.
Hey there.
I asked him to try to gather
some information about Ryūsei for us.
Know the enemy, know yourself
and you'll win a hundred battles.
Let's get to the point.
Take a look at this.
– What should we be paying attention to?
– Looks like a festival.
You're not mistaken.
It's a folk dance festival in Nagasaki.
It's called the Dance of the Dragon,
or sometimes, of the Snake.
What's so special about it?
I called our branch in Nagasaki
to tell me more about Ryūsei
and I learned that their main trick
is something they call a "dragon attack".
A "dragon attack"?
What could it be?
Well, they didn't tell me
much on the phone,
but they described it to me so that their
entire team, including Captain Ebihara Saori,
jumps at the same time and attacks
supposedly like a charging dragon.
Dragons are known for their ability
to summon clouds and wind.
Whatever their attack is, it definitely worked
in the Nagasaki qualifying round.
Sir, what are we going to do?
Let's see.
If they're the dragon,
we'll be the tiger.
A tiger?
Like dragons, tigers fight furiously
until they or their enemy is killed in battle.
In less poetic terms,
we must show the same will to fight.
Thanks, dude.
I owe you one.
You're welcome.
I just hope I didn't
scare them too much.
They're a spoiled bunch,
used to being treated too lightly.
Imagine that they got lost
as soon as we arrived in Tōkyō.
If you scare them, all the better. Maybe it'll
open their eyes a bit about this tournament.
Ichijō-san, you saw this festival, right?
Can you tell us something about it?
My dad was still working in Nagasaki at the time,
and I went to elementary school.
One day we went to see
the Dragon Dance
and I must say that it is wonderful,
very exotic, and very, very dynamic.
It sounds really amazing.
So they probably do something alike,
but with the ball?
I think so. I'm sure that the name of
the "dragon attack" refers to this dance.
Dinner's ready, girls.
Come eat something.
This isn't a good time.
We have to come up with something for the
"dragon attack". I don't feel like eating now.
Any suggestions?
The "dragon attack"…
What could this technique be?
Ah… Ichijō-san?
I was thinking about the little girl
who got almost killed today.
I remembered something.
The girl who saved her
spoke in Nagasaki dialect.
Are you suggesting
that she was from Ryūsei?
I think so.
She jumped very high.
You're still awake?
Still worried about the "dragon attack"?
Yes. I can't imagine
what it might look like.
I'll comfort you that Ryūsei are
probably racking their heads
over our double spike and
the "lightning" right now.
There's nothing to worry about.
You'll see how it goes when you play.
Don't let your fears get the best of you
and just do your job.
Do what you do best
and like the most.
Yes. You're right, sir.
I think so, too.
We can do it!
VIII National High School
Volleyball Tournament
Locker room the Tachibana
High School team
We'd better hurry up.
You saved that girl.
I am Ebihara Saori from
Ryūsei High School. Nice to meet you.
I am Hijiri Mimi from Tachibana.
Nice to meet you, too.
You were right.
I told you.
So it's them who play
the "dragon attack"…
The "dragon attack".
We broadcast straight from the National Hall
in Tōkyō, where the best high school teams
will meet in the National Women's
Volleyball Tournament.
Each of these teams proved their worth
in the prefectural phase.
Today, Ryūsei from Nagasaki, whose costumes
proudly shine with reptile scales,
will play against and a relatively
new team of just six players,
which has already shown that it's better not to
underestimate them – Tachibana from Kanagawa.
Ryūsei with their
fearful "dragon attack",
and Tachibana with their
double spike and the "lightning".
The match looks very promising.
This is it!
It's the "dragon attack"!
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have the "dragon attack"!
Ryūsei didn't make us wait and started
with the "dragon attack" right off the bat!
Don't let them intimidate us.
Let's show them their place!
There goes the "lightning".
Tachibana plays
the first "lightning"!
This time it's the double spike!
We have a point!
Ryūsei · Tachibana
Timeout.
A well balanced
beginning of the game.
The "dragon attack" against
the double spike and the "lightning".
Both teams go head to head, fighting hard
to get an advantage in points.
It's like we assumed initially.
Yes. It's impossible
to tell which one will attack.
The ball is flying from the least expected
direction. I don't know how to react.
Same for me.
Me too.
Hijiri, Ichijō. What do you think?
We can't see that either.
I see. It can't be helped.
There's nothing else for us
but to try to see which one spikes.
If we can do that,
that's our golden ticket.
Yes. We just need to be careful
not to make any mistakes.
Exactly, otherwise
we'll lose points too quickly.
– Alright. Go get them!
– Yes, sir!
Good luck!
Ryūsei · Tachibana
We have a breakthrough! Ryūsei broke the
stagnation, scoring a second point in the game.
They managed to beautifully defend against
the double spike and launch an offensive.
Ryūsei blocks and scores a point!
Tachibana's "lightning" has been grounded!
Captain Ebihara's perfect block
scores another point.
Ryūsei · Tachibana
Timeout!
You can do it!
I believe in you!
What happened?
Can't you defend against their spikes?
We don't know
which one of them hits the ball.
But why?
It's very simple.
Only one person can hit the ball.
Only one person…
Yes, sure, but—
Wait, Hijiri.
I think I know what
the little girl meant.
I have an idea how to neutralize
the "dragon attack".
Listen up.
Don't try to defend all at once.
Let each of you closely watch
one player from their team of your choice.
Don't focus on anyone else
but the person you choose.
Only one person?
Yes.
Hijiri, watch their captain, No. 1.
Ichijō, No. 2.
Sugihara, No. 3.
Nishi, No. 4.
Sekiya, No. 5.
Ōta, don't take your eyes off No. 8.
Once can see which one of them spikes,
the rest should go smoothly.
Suppose we manage to receive it.
What about the attack?
I wouldn't worry about that anymore.
The "dragon attack" is a one-time technique.
After its execution they're
quite defenseless for a long time.
Hijiri, Ichijō, Ōta.
Your spikes should beat them easily.
Good! Good!
Number five!
Ladies and gentlemen, another breakthrough!
Tachibana receives the "dragon attack"!
Number eight!
Sumi'e!
Ryūsei · Tachibana
You can do it!
What a surprise! Tachibana rebounded
completely and won the first set!
Ryūsei's "dragon" has been
stripped of its fangs!
The "lightning" and Hijiri and Ichijō's double spike
of Tachibana have dominated the first set.
The game goes on, and Tachibana
keeps putting pressure!
Number two!
Match ball for Tachibana!
Ryūsei · Tachibana
Tachibana ends the match!
The first match of the National Tournament
ends with Ryūsei's spectacular defeat.
She's that girl…
Congratulations!
Thank you.
It was thanks to you that we won.
Were it not for your hint, we wouldn't
be able to defeat the "dragon attack".
I can't believe it.
How dare you?
Nice way to thank our captain
after she saved your life.
Just because you're a child
is not an excuse.
You should be ashamed, too.
To resort to such methods…
You really wanted to win so much
that you were looking for help from a child
that our captain had saved?
It's not like that.
It was Hijiri-san who saved this girl.
It was her who noticed the falling girder
and shouted a warning.
We lost because
we were the weaker team.
Congratulations, Hijiri-san.
We lost, but I don't regret anything.
It was a very good game.
Good luck in your future games.
Thank you very much.
Watch out, Hijiri-san. When we meet at the
Interhigh Championships, it won't look the same.
You'd better prepare
yourselves well for that.
See you soon.
Ebihara-san…
Ebihara Saori felt very refreshed,
seeing her team's defeat.
In turn, Hijiri Mimi's team
advances to the second round.
What opponent
can they expect this time?
If it goes on, it's over.
Sir, what should we do?
So what if it worked once or twice.
Watch the ball closely.
Mimi and her friends will face Daisetsuzan
Academy, the favorite for this tournament.
An ambidextrous striker in the opponent's team
and a special attack known as the "snowstorm"
prove to be
a real problem for them.
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"The Northern Star!
Daisetsuzan Academy". See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offensive
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death