kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 16:
The Northern Star! Daisetsuzan Academy
The girls' dream to participate in
the National Tournament came true,
but their very first opponent turned out
to be a very strong team, Ryūsei from Nagasaki.
Ryūsei · Tachibana
Still, they managed to win.
We'll play against Tachibana tomorrow.
I feel that it won't be easy.
Daisetsuzan
– Sir!
– Please wait!
Sir!
What took you so long, girls?
Come on, get on.
But, sir, the game between Daisetsuzan
and Tōshō is about to start.
Yes. What about it?
"What about it"? Tomorrow we'll play
against one or the other.
We should watch this game.
I take it that you
really want to see it?
Yes, sir!
What a pain…
but I can't say no to those faces.
Okay, you can stay.
But I'll go to the hotel.
Daisetsuzan Academy from Hokkaidō has a
reputation for being favorite in this tournament.
Their opponent,
Tōshō High School from Tōkyō,
can also boast
an amazing winning streak.
As our dear TV viewers can see,
Tōshō's players are very tall and slim.
Although the girls from
Daisetsuzan are a bit more corpulent,
their team makes up for it with strength,
high jump and great bravery.
They look very united.
Apparently, this is due to the
educational policy of their school.
Today we'll see
if the rumors are true.
Led by Captain Fukuhara Yōko,
their team allegedly trained
in the snow to strengthen their legs.
In the snow?!
Mimi, do you know more
about Fukuhara Yōko?
No. But for some reason I get the impression
that I'd have known her for a long time.
The game begins.
As I told you, Captain Fukuhara Yōko
from the Daisetsuzan Academy
demonstrates excellent leg work
and smoothly proceeds to spike.
In the last match of the prefectural phase,
Captain Fukuhara Yōko from Daisetsuzan
for the first time presented a two-handed attack
and a unique technique called the "snowstorm".
A two-handed attack?
A "snowstorm"?
What is that technique?
For now, they haven't used these
techniques even once
and it doesn't look like it's about
to change anytime soon.
Daisetsuzan · Tōshō
Fukuhara-san… Why aren't you
playing the "snowstorm"?
Isuzu Hotel
We warmly welcome the players of the
Tachibana High School's Volleyball Club
Oh?
Here you are. It was already late,
so I started eating without you.
Sir, is that a beer?
Yes. There's nothing like
a good beer after a game.
But this beer is with alcohol?
And what else would it be?
So, are you going to join me or not?
I was just kidding. But is it really
so weird that I drink beer?
No, but it's just that we see
you drinking for the first time.
I drink one every day
after dinner at home.
Alright, but here?
Come on, just sit down
and eat something.
After we're finished,
I'll take you someplace cool.
Yes, sir!
Sir, we're finished!
Huh? Oh?
But why did you change?
So you didn't rent a hall nearby
so we could train here?
Train?
Yeah. Tomorrow we have a match with
Daisetsuzan. We should properly prepare.
I don't understand, sir,
what's so funny?
Doesn't matter.
Change back to your regular clothes.
You want us…
to exercise in skirts?
Who said we were
going to exercise?
But…
Go change back.
You won't need your uniforms today.
Where do you think he's taking us?
I have no idea.
Wow, look at that! This is a theater
where they stage real storytelling plays!
Sir… I'm afraid I don't follow?
Here, this is your ticket.
If we have too much free time, I'd rather
spend it developing tactics for tomorrow.
Sir, Daisetsuzan's captain hasn't played
any two-handed attacks today.
Here, this is yours.
Yes, not to mention
the "snowstorm".
What do you think about it, sir?
I don't know. You were
watching the match, not me.
All the more reason
for us to develop a plan!
Okay, but how do you want to do it
without knowing what techniques they use?
I know you want to train, but we have a tight
schedule and it'd cause more harm than good.
So you want us just to wing it?
Yes.
But…
Lately, you look very stressed.
When you're that way,
anybody can defeat you.
Let's not think about
the game anymore today.
We're going to comedy now.
Let's laugh and then go to bed.
I don't know about you,
but I'm going to take a seat!
Boys like him have it easy in life.
"Hatsu-san!
Hatsu-san, can you hear me?"
God, doesn't he have
anything better to do?
How is this funny?
Tell me about it.
Isuzu Hotel
All the people who come to visit our town
are called either Kuma-san or Hatsu-san…
That's right, we've come so far that fear
and doubt began to get the best of us.
And all this whole thing is about
is to give your best, no less and no more.
Why didn't I think
of it that way before?
Thanks to the professor,
we can sleep without anxiety today.
The match between Tachibana High School
and Daisetsuzan Academy will start soon.
It is speculated that Daisetsuzan Academy has
the best chance of winning the championship.
Their rivals, Tachibana,
are newcomers to the tournament,
but they've already defeated the prestigious
Ryūsei High School from Nagasaki.
Both teams represent
a very high level.
By the way, it was hard not to notice
in the yesterday's match
that Captain Fukuhara Yōko never used
any two-handed technique or the "snowstorm".
They apparently didn't need such
strong techniques against Tōshō.
The first set was fairly balanced,
but the second was quite one-sided.
The question is, will we have the opportunity
to see their secret weapons today?
For now, play calmly and
don't take your eyes off the opponent.
Yes, sir!
Remember that regardless of their techniques,
we have our "lightning" and the double spike.
For now, let's just try
to feel them out. Understood?
Yes, sir!
Good. Go get them!
Both teams assumed positions.
We can expect a very dynamic match.
Nice to meet you, Hijiri-san.
The pleasure is all mine.
We won't be holding back today. I'll play my
two-handed attack as well as the "snowstorm".
The captains of both teams
shake hands before the match.
Surprisingly, Captain Fukuhara Yōko announces
that she'll be using her secret weapons today.
This suggests that Daisetsuzan has recognized
Tachibana as a worthy opponent.
I am honored, Fukuhara-san.
We won't be holding back, either.
I'm happy to hear that.
It'll be a good match.
Tachibana's captain, Hijiri Mimi,
enthusiastically accepts the challenge!
Mimi is so brave.
Of course she is!
Good luck, Sis!
The match will open with
Daisetsuzan's serve, played by Takahashi!
Will it be the "lightning"?
There it is! Tachibana successfully reclaims
their right to serve with the "lightning".
Get ready!
Ladies and gentlemen,
there's the two-handed attack!
The moment before the spike,
Fukuhara crosses her arms.
In this way, it's impossible to know
which hand she actually plays with.
Captain Fukuhara Yōko of Daisetsuzan Academy
keeps playing the two-handed attack mercilessly!
Daisetsuzan · Tachibana
If it goes on like this,
things won't be pretty.
What to do?
End of set! Daisetsuzan wins the first set thanks
to Captain Fukuhara's amazing technique.
15 to 0. As expected, Daisetsuzan
showed a crushing strength.
Aw, shucks!—
Oh? Where are you going, Grandma?
I forgot to buy something.
Her two-handed attack turned out
to be even stronger than I had anticipated.
Yes…
But I have an idea
how to overcome it.
For real, sir?
What can we do?
Fukuhara plays from the center.
When Hijiri and Sugihara jump to block,
Fukuhara sends a ball at Sugihara.
So if Hijiri-san and I tried to block,
she'd send the ball under me.
Exactly.
When she attacks from the side,
she hits the place where Hijiri should be.
That's right!
Don't be fooled by her
usage of both hands to spike.
What's important is that she
makes you block prematurely.
How can we prevent this?
Surely you're not going to suggest
that we give up on blocking altogether.
You're reading my mind.
Hold your positions without jumping to the block
and instead do diving receptions.
Remember to stay low
so that you can jump out sooner.
Got that?
Yes, sir!
The second set stats.
Will Tachibana rebound,
or will they let Daisetsuzan crush them?
Which hand will she spike with?
No one from Tachibana
is trying to block!
Daisetsuzan · Tachibana
Tachibana has neutralized
Fukuhara's two-handed attack!
Giving up on blocking is unthinkable,
but that's the tactic Tachibana chose.
By blocking, they were giving Fukuhara time
to decide which hand to play the ball with.
Without that, Fukuhara is in a bind.
Tachibana is on the offensive!
Daisetsuzan · Tachibana
Daisetsuzan is in trouble!
Tachibana scores one point after another,
quickly taking the lead.
Keep it up, Mimi!
That pretty attacker over there
is my granddaughter!
– You don't say?
– Amazing child!
Timeout!
Daisetsuzan managed to get the ball back
and asked for a short break.
Sir?
Good work.
Now we just have
to face their "snowstorm".
Don't worry if it works
once or twice.
Watch the ball closely.
Yes, sir!
The game will be resumed
by Captain Fukuhara Yōko.
Kimiko!
Ladies and gentlemen, there it is,
the famous "snowstorm"!
The technique that the girls practiced
in the midst of the Hokkaidō snow
really deserves its name.
The ball rose as if hit with a strong wind,
then furiously hit on the opponent's half.
Daisetsuzan is at Tachibana's heels!
Daisetsuzan · Tachibana
10 to 10.
Daisetsuzan evens the score!
If it goes on, it's over.
Don't worry
if it works once or twice.
Watch the ball closely.
Watch the ball.
Right!
Tachibana's captain, Hijiri Mimi
neutralizes the "snowstorm" with a spike!
That's impossible!
Hijiri Mimi demonstrates
amazing jump height!
Tachibana wins the second set.
Mimi!
Grandma, are you back
from the store?
Now's not the time to do shopping!
We didn't train
in the snow to lose now.
Fukuhara-san, you're
a good player and I like you,
but I have to beat you.
The third set is progressing
in a very balanced, yet fiery way.
Daisetsuzan · Tachibana
It is a real show of
ferocity and perseverance.
It's not about techniques anymore.
It's about the will to fight.
For every point scored
by the Daisetsuzan Academy,
Tachibana responds with
the "lightning" and the double spike.
14 to 13.
Match ball for Tachibana.
It's the "lightning"!
And we have a victory!
Tachibana goes to the next round!
Daisetsuzan · Tachibana
What a fantastic match.
They beat the favorite for this tournament,
Daisetsuzan Academy from Hokkaidō.
They did it! They did it!
Fukuhara-san.
We won only thanks
to a stroke of luck.
You fought beautifully to the very end,
without losing your fighting spirit at all.
Thank you. I don't feel sad.
I'm glad that we gave our best.
I'll show you even better techniques
at the Interhigh Championships.
Although they have just lost, Daisetsuzan
already makes a promise to play a rematch.
Although they have just won,
Tachibana does not flaunt it.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is what sport should look like.
The "light attack"…
We have to figure it out somehow.
Then there's the "shadow attack".
Yes. I never know
which one to expect.
Our heroines advance
to the quarter-finals, in which
they will face Shijōdōri
High School from Kyōtō.
The techniques known as "light" and "shadow"
will prove to be a real problem for them.
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"Between light and shadow".
See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offensive
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death