kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 14:
Towards the Semi-finals
Asuka has long distrusted people,
which sometimes turned even into hostility.
However, Mimi managed to melt a bit
the ice that covered her heart.
After Asuka made friends with Mimi,
she handed over the title of captain.
Tachibana High School's Volleyball Club
for the first time was truly unified
and took another step on their path
towards the National Tournament.
This is the coach of the Sakuragi High School
team that's standing behind me,
and he's my friend from college.
He was so nice that he let us practice here
until the prefectural round is over.
Consequently, we will train extra hard
so as not to disappoint him.
Your team is finally united
in the way it should be.
What's more, you managed to achieve it
yourself, without anybody's help.
You did well.
I waited a long time for this day.
Finally, we can really devote
ourselves to training.
You know it won't be easy.
Still, I count on your enthusiasm.
Yes, sir!
Yes, sir.
Good. Keep it up.
Today you will have the opportunity
to play with the guys from Sakuragi.
Hello, girls!
Hey there!
Hijiri. Come back where you stood
and go two steps forward,
and from now on dive in
to the ball from that sport.
Ichijō, you try to practice spiking
from a higher position.
Sugihara, you start practicing
spikes from side passes.
Ōta, Nishi, Sekiya. The three of you are
to practice very loose receptions and passes.
It doesn't have to be perfect,
just try to play them high.
If it's high, it'll be fine.
Sakuragi High School
Hijiri, faster!
Ichijō, improve your coordination!
Sugihara!
Jump higher!
Nishi, Ōta, Sekiya!
You pass that ball higher, too!
Sakuragi High School
Shirobara
Tachibana
Tamagaoka
Sei'iku
Fitness Academy
Fukuichi
Kōei
Sakumoto
Hakushin
Ōkura
Sakijima
Urakawa
Tomi'e
Yokohama
Minato
Shirobara
Tachibana
Tamagaoka
Sei'iku
Fitness Academy
Fukuichi
Kōei
Sakumoto
Hakushin
Ōkura
Sakijima
Urakawa
Tomi'e
Yokohama
Minato
Shirobara
Tachibana
Tamagaoka
Sei'iku
The match against Tamagaoka
is tomorrow already.
Tamagaoka…
It doesn't tell me anything.
What's up?
Why are you still up?
Tomorrow's your second match.
You'd better go get some sleep.
How can we go to sleep when we haven't
even discussed the strategy for tomorrow?
To think he himself said today that we were to
train hard and he counted on our enthusiasm.
Not to mention that today's training isn't going
to be very useful for tomorrow's match.
Yeah, I feel the same.
I wondered myself what was up
with training with these boys.
I won't be able to sleep
with such thoughts.
Mimi, could you talk to the coach?
Maybe he has a plan we don't know about.
No problem.
I'll go and let you know.
We don't need any plans
to face Tamagaoka.
But sir…
Hijiri, don't tell me you don't know the reason
for the training we started today.
We can be more than sure that Hadori Kyōko and
Yokohama East Port will advance to the finals.
The aim of the training we started today
is to strengthen us before we face them.
So, sir, you're suggesting
that we'll meet them in the finals?
Yes. Seeing how lively your team has become,
I haven't the slightest doubt about that.
I believe in you with all my heart.
That's why I'm not worried about the second
match at all, no matter who your opponent is.
Our final goal is the finals
and Yokohama East Port.
We don't need a plan
for tomorrow.
If you stay relaxed,
I guarantee that you'll win.
Is that clear?
Yes. Thank you, sir.
Thank you!
Perfect.
Now off to bed, all of you.
Yes, sir.
Good night, sir.
National Volleyball Tournament
Elimination Phase – Kanagawa Prefecture
Tachibana's "lightning"
scores another point.
The score is 13 to 2. Tachibana leads
with a crushing advantage.
The team captain, Hijiri Mimi, and
her high jump deserve special attention.
Her attack easily passes over enemy blocks,
like a jet plane above the clouds.
Great! Show them who's the boss!
Now it's double spike!
Another point!
Keep going, Tachibana!
Tachibana wins with Tamagaoka, finishing
the third set with a score of 15 to 2.
"The black horse of the tournament, Tachibana
High School, advances to the third round."
"Unbeatable spike
of Hadori Kyōko."
"Quick promotion! Tachibana High School
goes to the semi-finals. "
"First place! Yokohama East Port
advances to the semi-finals. "
Tachibana · Fitness Academy
Tachibana defeats Fitness Academy,
finishing the third set with a score of 15 to 13.
Tachibana advances
to tomorrow's finals.
Who would expect them
to go this far?
Tachibana High School
advances to the finals
We won! We did it!
Unbelievable. The coach was right
from the beginning.
Hey, girls.
Don't change just yet.
We're going to Sakuragi
to make the final touches.
But, sir, aren't we going to watch
Yokohama East Port's semi-final game?
You don't need a clairvoyant to know that
Yokohama will prevail. There's nothing to look at.
Preparing for tomorrow's match
is much more important.
Yes, sir!
Hadori Kyōko's unbridled spike
makes her a very dangerous attacker.
Hijiri, you'll try to capture Hadori Kyōko's spike
from a fixed position before she plays.
Before she even plays?
I see, so that's what
the exercises were for, right?
Ōta, Nishi, Sekiya, if her spike slips through,
don't try to receive it normally.
Just try to bounce it lightly so that
it loses as much power as possible.
Send the ball as high as you can.
We're not sure if we can make it.
It's enough if it works out
once every two, or even three times.
Yes, sir!
Ichijō, you'll relay their passes
and play at Hijiri for her to spike.
But every once in a while
play to Sugihara instead.
Sugihara, in such cases you have
to play the "lightning".
Yes, sir!
If we add a double spike
to this mix,
we have nothing to be afraid of
Hadori Kyōko or the rest of her team.
Hadori-san, you said that volleyball for you
is fun and you take it seriously at the same time.
I also take volleyball seriously.
I will show you that
you are not invincible.
Go, go, Tachibana!
Go, go, Yokohama!
Tachibana and Yokohama East Port
today meet in the final match.
Which team will qualify to
the National Volleyball Tournament?
Hijiri-san, I applaud you
for having come so far.
I never in my life would've imagined
that I'd see you in the finals.
Well, we both know
who's going to win today.
Let's try to play a nice game
so that people don't regret buying tickets.
Hadori-san, I'm afraid we're
no longer that weak team
that you played against
the last time we met.
Can you believe it? Hijiri-san
has the audacity to mock her.
Where does her confidence
even come form?
What can I tell you, they don't know how to lose.
Until now somehow they had luck,
but today Kyōko will show
them the harsh reality.
Hadori-san, I want to play a beautiful final too,
so don't hold back and show what you can do.
Good. That's exactly
what I wanted to hear.
The whistle starts the match.
The ball is on Yokohama's side.
The server is Shiraishi.
Tachibana promptly recovers the ball
with their trademark technique, the "lightning".
Good job! Keep it up!
Tachibana tames Hadori Kyōko's spike,
but loses the ball due to a reception error.
Tachibana · Yokohama East Port
15 to 9. Yokohama East Port
wins in the first set.
Tachibana players receive in an unusual way,
very loosely. What could be the reason?
Most likely, they're trying to
reduce the power of the spike.
I don't think they practiced
it too much, though.
If this situation persists,
Tachibana will be in trouble.
Damn it, they already played so well.
Why did they have to change things?
Grandma, do you think
it'll be okay?
Yes, of course.
Look at Mimi's face.
There is not a trace of anxiety.
Yes. You're right, Grandma.
How was it?
Did you get used to it?
Yes, sir!
Good. Now that you have warmed up,
we can reveal our cards.
Hijiri, we'll start with you.
Yes, sir.
When Hadori Kyōko sees that you can
receive her spike, she'll be shocked.
Sugihara, you'll deepen this surprise
by playing a feint with the "lightning".
Yes, sir!
That should be enough
for the second set.
Don't use the double spike just yet.
We need to save something for the end.
Yes, sir.
Alright. Go get them!
Hijiri Mimi… Why are you so calm,
even though you just lost the first set?
And you never tried to defuse my spike
with that somersault technique of yours.
Hadori-san, I'm going to show you
that your spike can be received.
Hadori's going to spike!
Hijiri managed to receive
Hadori's spike!
That's what we're talking about!
How did she receive my attack?
What are we going to do now?
No, I can't think like that.
We haven't lost yet.
Since Hijiri can receive my attacks,
I'll just try to play against others.
Sekiya easily receives
Hadori's attack!
They play the "lightning"!
A brilliant feint on the part of Tachibana!
Hijiri faked an attack that Sugihara executed.
It's the birth of a new technique,
the "double lightning". A point for Tachibana.
The Yokohama East Port team's players
stand astonished on the court.
Tachibana · Yokohama East Port
Tachibana wins the second set
with the score of 15 to 7.
So cool!
That's my sister over there!
The third set.
Now they'll start to go crazy.
Don't let them surprise you.
Stay focused and keep up the teamwork.
Yes, sir!
It's not a coincidence
that we've come this far.
It's your skills. Thanks to them,
we have a chance to win this tournament.
Yes, sir!
Remember about the double spike.
Use it in the very end.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the third set's about to start.
The team that will win this set
will advance to the National Tournament.
Who will become the winner,
Tachibana or Yokohama East Port?
Hijiri-san, we will win the third set
and there's nothing you can do about it.
Hadori-san, who will win, me or you?
I can guarantee you that I will give my best.
Both teams go head to head!
Losses are recovered from point by point!
Tachibana · Yokohama East Port
Match ball for Tachibana!
Although the Yokohama team
seems to be better in terms of technique,
Tachibana can boast excellent
teamwork under Hijiri's lead.
Perhaps that is the difference
that will prove to be decisive.
Match ball!
You know what to do!
Yeah!
Double spike.
Ready, Ichijō-san?
Is this the "lightning"?!
I can't believe it…
I lost to Hijiri-san.
We won! We did it!
We have advanced
to the National Tournament!
Tachibana · Yokohama East Port
Tachibana High School
wins the match!
Their team advances
to the National Tournament.
A really great finale, full of tension
and unexpected twists.
Who's the boss? Who's the boss?
That's right, it's Tachibana!
Good job!
I can't believe it…
Kyōko has lost?
Oh? Look at Hadori Kyōko.
Hijiri-san, congratulations.
I lost fair and square.
But I promise that we'll get you
in the next tournament.
Congratulations, and I wish you good luck
in the next matches on behalf of my team.
Thank you, Hadori-san.
As the representatives of Kanagawa,
I promise we won't bring shame to us.
I've always believed in you!
The next stop:
the National Tournament.
Mimi and the girls now face
a new, even greater challenge.
A "dragon attack"?
What could it be?
What, are you still thinking about
the upcoming match against Ryūsei?
Yes. I don't know
what to think about it.
Don't worry too much.
You'll see how it goes when you play.
Overjoyed after leaving the prefectural phase,
the girls from Tachibana High School
are about to feel the harshness of the
National Tournament right in the first match.
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"The Charging Dragon".
See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offensive
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death