kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 17:
Between Light and Shadow
VIII National High School
Volleyball Tournament
Shijōdōri · Kuroshio
Captain Katsura Haruka of Shijōdōri High School
scores another point with her "light attack"!
The speed at which she executes it can
be compared to the speed of light, indeed.
Match ball!
Shijōdōri dominates the game!
Nothing compares to the speed at which
Katsura Haruka plays her technique.
Shijōdōri defeats Kuroshio. Tomorrow,
they will face Tachibana in the quarter-finals.
I wonder where
the coach disappeared.
He's probably in the hall.
Let's just wait for him.
Girls, what do you think about
that technique, the "light attack"?
It's terribly fast.
They said on television that it could be
compared to a camera flash.
I agree with them.
Yes. However, speed aside, her technique
doesn't look like a particularly strong spike.
So as long as we can keep up with it,
there should be no problem.
I think so, too.
There's nothing to fear.
I don't want to brag,
but I have perfect eyesight.
There's no way her play could
escape my eyes. Right, Tomiko?
I still remember Hanabusa
Mitsuru-san's "killer spike"
and Hadori Kyōko-san's "mortar". I was worried
that this technique would be just as strong.
Exactly. As you can see,
we'll be fine.
I'm not even mentioning that Ichijō-san's spike
is at least as fast as her technique.
Hey, girls.
Locker room of the
Shijōdōri High School team
Oh, it's you, Fuwa-san.
How is my favorite
spoiled bunch? All good?
You are very rude.
We're not spoiled at all.
Now, now.
I'm here for a small interview.
What do you say?
What? We'll be in the newspapers?
Feel free to ask whatever you want!
Yes, our conversation
will make it to the evening release.
Let's start, then. What do you think about
Katsura Haruka's "light attack"?
Katsura Haruka.
The "light attack"…
She jumps up in the air
and spikes immediately.
When you think it's going to come,
the ball's been long flying towards you already.
It's damn fast, that's a fact.
Maybe even faster than my spike.
I see.
Still, I wouldn't worry too much.
Alright. Now to ask your captain.
Hijiri-kun, do you have
any plans against Shijōdōri?
Huh?
We don't.
Our coach always tells us
not to think too much and just do our best.
Right, captain?
What? Ah, yes.
In other words, you're convinced that you'll
win by playing just like both previous matches.
You're twisting my words.
I never said we were convinced of winning.
You can't know who'll win or lose
until after the match.
So you do your best and the rest is destiny.
Okay, sounds good.
It's late.
Let's go to the hotel.
Right. Goodbye.
Goodbye, sir.
Locker room of the
Shijōdōri High School team
Hi.
Hey.
I came across your girls outside.
Why aren't you with them?
I'm waiting for Shijōdōri to return from the court.
One of their players caught my attention.
She wears No. 2 shirt, so I suppose
it's their vice-captain.
She was sitting on the bench the entire match.
She didn't come out even once.
It picked my interest.
Locker room of the
Shijōdōri High School team
Maybe some injury?
A sensible thought, but she hasn't
played in any previous round, either.
That's their captain,
Katsura Haruka.
The girl with glasses behind her
is the mysterious No. 2.
Isuzu Hotel
They wrote about us! Kimiko,
look, here they quote what I said.
Good morning, sir!
Something happened?
Listen to this.
"No matter how fast the ball is,
it doesn't matter to us.
The only thing that matters for us
is that we always try our best."
I put that nicely, huh?
Alright, but what do they write
about our opponents?
They posted here the statement of one
of the Shijōdōri High School players.
"A master swordsman Chiba Shūsaku said that the
sharpness of the sword lies in the cutting speed.
In other words, the faster the cut,
the more lethal it is.
I think it is similar
with volleyball. "
Wow, a historical reference.
They're smooth-talkers, alright.
I'm sorry to say this,
but their statement was cooler.
Katsura Haruka and the technique called
the "light attack"… Then, the player No. 2.
Hijiri-san, what about you?
Are you confident?
So you think that if we fail to receive
their "light attack", we have no chance?
No. We'll receive it,
no doubt about it.
The best way to defend against
a fast cut is to cut first.
So we must develop an attack that'll
be even faster than their "light".
How are you going
to achieve this, Hijiri-san?
What if we played the double spike
only that rather than me, it'd be Ichijō-san
who spiked, whereas I'd just play a feint?
Sounds like a good idea.
Ichijō-san's spike is faster than the "light".
The best defense is a good offense, huh?
Okay. Let's try to do as you say.
It's… the chairman of
the Student Council!
Hi. Congratulations for
advancing to the quarter-finals.
Hara!
I learned something new.
Your mysterious No. 2
has a name: Katsura Shigemi.
She's the twin sister of
Shijōdōri's captain, Katsura Haruka.
A twin sister?
In addition, identical.
They're the same in every respect.
What about the prefectural phase,
did she play in any matches?
I probably won't surprise you when I say
that she didn't go out on the court even once.
Shijōdōri has gone so far thanks to
Katsura Haruka's "light attack" alone.
Which means that the No. 2, Katsura Shigemi,
must be their secret weapon.
I think so, too. They knew from the start that
one special technique might be not enough.
You sure you don't want
to tell it to the girls?
No. It'd only cause
unnecessary anxiety.
There's nothing to talk about
until I know some specifics.
Thank you for coming
to visit us, Fusejima-kun.
You're welcome.
I'm only here only for a moment.
I came to Tōkyō to take part
in the college entrance exams.
We're honored, anyway.
After all, one of the best students
in the entire school visited us.
Are you surprised
that I support you?
See, I…
I don't have anything against
the people devoted to sport.
I'd like to do something myself, believe me.
The thing is, I don't have time.
I'd also like to make music.
Take part in plays.
So many possibilities, so little time.
We have to decide on one thing
and use the time we've been given.
Most of all, I want to go to college.
However, my family is not rich,
so I can consider only public universities.
To get there, I have to sit with
my head in a book every day.
There are so many things I'd like to do,
but months go by, one after another.
This is why sometimes I feel that
life is leaking through my fingers.
Fusejima-kun…
Time's a funny thing. Sometimes it
flies faster, sometimes slower.
But the truth is, it rushes
very, very fast, like a bullet train.
I don't regret my choices.
I'm just walking on the path
I have set out for myself.
When something's eating me up
or I feel lost, I close my eyes like this.
Then I can see the path that
I promised myself to follow again.
Hijiri-kun…
Fight well, for yourself and for me.
See you soon.
I will fight.
For Fusejima-kun who can't play,
even though he'd like to, and for myself.
"Light attack"…
Katsura Haruka.
And finally…
The secret weapon
named Katsura Shigemi.
Today starts the third round of the tournament,
which is also the quarter-final round.
The first match will be played by Tachibana
from Kanagawa against Shijōdōri from Kyōtō.
What will win, Tachibana's double spike,
or Shijōdōri's "light attack"?
As expected,
Katsura Shigemi is not playing.
Rock it, girls!
I didn't see a thing!
It's all right, Sumi'e!
Double spike!
But with a small modification!
Rather than Hijiri Mimi,
this time it's Ichijō Asuka who spikes.
Shijōdōri · Tachibana
A very balanced match.
What is going to prevail:
the "light" or the new double spike?
Shijōdōri · Tachibana
I have to tell you that it isn't easy
to make any predictions.
Good luck!
You can do it,
Tachibana High School!
Shijōdōri · Tachibana
A draw again! 14 to 14!
Once again the result
was evened out.
The new double spike is just
as effective as the "light"!
Now even smallest mistakes count.
A truly beautiful and very intense game!
Shijōdōri · Tachibana
Hijiri-chan, I believe in you!
It's like I said. We have to come up with a way
to break the "light", or it's all over.
So when something's eating me up
or I feel lost, I close my eyes like this.
Then I can see the path that
I promised myself to follow again.
This is it!
I can hear it.
I can hear the ball.
Now!
The "lightning"!
Astonishing! Tachibana's captain Hijiri Mimi
finally manages to receive the "light attack"!
Shijōdōri · Tachibana
18 to 16.
Tachibana wins the first set!
I'm so glad you managed
to figure it out.
The second set should
be a piece of cake.
Sir?
What? Ah, yes.
For now we've won the first set.
Feel free to play whatever you think is right.
Yes, sir!
I can't make anything
of their game.
Shijōdōri · Tachibana
Why is Katsura Shigemi
still not coming out?
Shijōdōri · Tachibana
Shijōdōri announces
a team rotation.
What's up?
What are they planning?
Holy hell!
They're waiting for us to get tired!
We don't have anyone in reserve.
We can't ask for a rotation.
Shijōdōri · Tachibana
Shijōdōri scores
a point by blocking!
The new double spike is neutralized!
How will this continue?
Don't give up,
don't give up, Tachibana!
Another block!
Shijōdōri · Tachibana
15 to 11.
Shijōdōri wins in the second set
with a four-point advantage.
The new double spike no longer works.
We must stop their "light" somehow.
For now, only Hijiri can receive it.
We can't rely on her alone.
Push everything else out of your minds
and focus completely on the ball.
The rest is a matter
of spirit and courage.
Shijōdōri wants to win
this tournament, it's clear.
They won't let Katsura Shigemi
play until the very end.
Both teams show an incredible will to fight
and play one advanced technique after another.
Shijōdōri · Tachibana
Has this moment come?
Will they finally let her play?
Shijōdōri · Tachibana
Shijōdōri requests
a change in their team!
We finally got them to get her out on the court.
The only question is, what will she do?
What is this?…
Which one is attacking?!
Katsura Haruka's attack is "light",
and Katsura Shigemi's attack is "shadow".
You can't tell which one spikes,
so you can't receive.
Shijōdōri · Tachibana
Hijiri-chan…
Hang in there, you poor thing.
Which one hit it this time?
Shijōdōri · Tachibana
Hijiri-san!
You did well.
I let you down.
I didn't predict what they planned.
My poor Hijiri-chan…
It was a good match, Hijiri-san.
If it weren't for you figuring out our "light",
we wouldn't have to let my sister out on you.
I must applaud you.
You'll have the chance to learn more about
my "shadow" at the next Interhigh.
Yes.
Next time we meet, we'll crush
both "light" and "darkness".
And that's how Tachibana High School
dropped out of the tournament.
However, Mimi was far
from despair.
She only felt a kind of fulfillment, knowing
that she had done everything in her power.
Did something happen, sir?
Someone secretly
recorded our training.
Who could it be?
I have no idea.
Let's go back to training.
A disturbing shadow falls on our preparations
for the Interhigh Championships.
Who could it be?
What's his purpose?
There are so many unanswered questions,
and the championship is fast approaching.
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"The Next Goal – the Interhigh".
See you soon.
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offensive
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death