kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 12:
The Fearsome Double Spike
Shirobara · Tachibana
Tachibana is still in trouble.
The second set is in full swing and their team
still hasn't scored a single point.
A pass to Hanabusa!
Will she target Ichijō again?
Ichijō-san!
Timeout!
Asuka.
The score is eleven to zero.
If Tachibana is to recover, this is pretty much
the last moment they still a have a chance to.
Don't be so down, girls.
After this match, we'll start from the beginning.
But as we promised ourselves,
we won't give up without a fight.
We'll play the best way we can
until the last whistle.
Finally we can
dial it down a little bit.
Yes. Now that we know how the match's
gonna end, there's nothing to stress about.
You have to be kidding me!
What?
Sir… Ichijō-san.
Listen carefully. You said that
we would start from the beginning,
but personally, I don't think that
we'll ever recover.
This is especially true for you,
Ichijō-san. Isn't that right?
Anyway, this applies
not only to Ichijō-san.
I feel that if we lose today's match,
I will never recover, either.
That's why I want to
win this game at all costs.
I'm begging you.
So what if we lose to zero
or look pathetic?
Please, just don't give up.
Let us think of the victory.
Well said.
Hijiri's right.
That's what I meant by playing
until the last whistle.
I'll tell you one more thing.
I have this one crazy idea.
What idea, Mimi?
What are they talking about there?
I can't stand it anymore!
Think we can do it?
It's impossible. We've never practiced it.
We cannot base our strategy on this.
We have to do it.
It's the only way.
Ichijō-san, are you with me?
Hijiri, you're asking
for the impossible.
However, we're left with nothing else.
If we lose, we'll do it without regret.
We'll do as you said.
Hijiri-san,
the victory is already ours.
Thank you for teaching me this technique.
I promise you that I'll make it up to you someday.
Hanabusa-san.
I won't let my club fall apart.
I won't let you crush us.
We will win this match.
We have to.
Hanabusa jumps up to the ball!
Will it be another service at Ichijō?!
What a stunning action!
Hijiri Mimi receives
with a somersault!
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is a phenomenal play.
I want to win, no matter what.
– Can you see it? Can you? Can you?!
– Yes, yes, calm down!
Tomiko!
Shirobara · Tachibana
We have a point! Tachibana High School
scores their first point in the match!
Asuka…
You can do it, sweetheart.
Keep it up, keep it up, Hijiri!
What is this, you donkeys?
We're cheering her on, okay!?
Sure thing, boss!
Keep it up! Keep it up!
Just keep going!
Great, great!
Tachibana scores another point!
Could Hijiri Mimi's impressive technique
be the breakthrough we've been waiting for?
Hanabusa Mitsuru's spike, unstoppable thus far,
has now met with tough resistance.
Give them hell, Hijiri!
The whole hall is with you in spirit!
Onward, onward, Tachibana!
Shirobara · Tachibana
Timeout!
That moment has come. Shirobara's coach
asked for a break for the first time in the match.
Most likely, he wants to
comfort his surprised team.
Anyway, perhaps due to
Hijiri Mimi's spectacular play,
a new spirit has come over
the players of the Tachibana team.
How long will they be able
to keep it up?
Whatever happens, I doubt that we'll
have to wait long for Shirobara's answer.
This is a critical moment.
Shirobara certainly prepared
a way to bypass Hijiri's defense.
We can't give them time to recover
and must attack with all our strength.
What do you say
if we played the "lightning"?
But to do that…
To play the "lightning",
we need Ichijō-san's cooperation.
Exactly.
Besides, how do you imagine to defend
and play the "lightning" at the same time?
Actually, it's a great idea.
We will play the "lightning".
Ōta, you will replace Hijiri
on the attack.
Me? I mean, yes, sir!
Ichijō, I'm hoping for your cooperation.
This is the only way.
Ichijō-san, please snap out of it,
whatever it is.
At last the sirens stopped.
Maybe they put out that fire.
But she's probably still shocked.
– What are you doing here?
– It's okay, I'm here only for a moment.
Come on, don't be such stuck-ups.
I'm from Tachibana, I go to class with them.
Let me pass,
it'll only take a moment.
Ichijō-kun, this is for you.
What is this, Arashi-kun?
It's not from me. That guy over there
asked me to pass it on to you.
Rock it, girls!
Dad?!
Asuka, the fire has already
been extinguished.
You don't have to worry
about anything anymore.
Your father watches over you.
So does your mother.
So let go of those bad memories
and show everyone what you're made of.
I'm fine, sir.
Please, let me play.
Okay.
Ichijō-san…
– Go get them!
– Yes, sir!
Darling, look after our daughter.
That's what we're
talking about, Ichijō!
Keep it up, sweetheart!
Thank you, Dad.
Tachibana's attack known as the "lightning"
indeed hits at lightning speed!
Even Shirobara couldn't
defend against it.
Ichijō Asuka, not long ago
completely unable to play,
has undergone an amazing transformation,
just like her team has before.
Go, go, Tachibana!
Shirobara · Tachibana
Timeout!
What do you say now? Serves you right.
I knew it'd be like that from the start.
Ichijō, Ōta, don't slow down.
The same also applies to the rest of you girls.
Yes, sir!
The road across the hill is difficult and arduous.
We're currently approaching the highest point.
We can't lose momentum
and tumble down.
So did it work?
Are you worried about
the Tachibana girls, mister?
Oh, I get you now. Yes, I was able
to give that card to Ichijō-kun.
But what did you write there?
It sure worked like hell.
She's like, born anew.
That was the plan. Can you say
something about their coach?
Sure thing. He's Hara Daisuke,
their biology teacher. Cool guy.
But between you and me, I think
I'm a hundred times more handsome.
Why are you asking, mister?
Is something wrong with him?
No, not at all.
It's just that I met him before.
Sweetheart! Asuka!?
Asuka?!
You are alive… Thank God.
Somehow I managed to
get her out of there, but…
My wife… she's still there?
I see… Thank you for everything.
Thank you.
Please take care of her.
Wait a second! Could you
at least tell me your name?
I'm just a random passerby.
Please, don't concern
yourself with me.
There's no doubt about it.
It's the same man.
He's the same man
who saved Asuka at that time.
Hey, mister? Hello?
What, were you napping or what?
You'd better look at the court.
The second set is about to end!
Shirobara · Tachibana
Tachibana High School bounced back
in the best possible way.
It was 11 to 0, and now thanks to the "lightning"
and an unusual reception technique
they managed to turn the tables
and win the second set.
The question remains, who will win the first match
of the tournament: Tachibana or Shirobara?
At the moment it is difficult
to make any predictions.
It seems that all we need
in the third set is the "lightning".
I think so, too.
The fate stopped smiling upon them.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Don't let them fool you. We won the second set
just because we caught them by surprise.
I feel the same. I'm afraid Hanabusa-san
will somehow neutralize the "lightning".
Okay, but surely you don't want us
to stop playing it completely?
Of course not. I just suggest that we try
something new besides the "lightning".
Come on. Relying solely
on your defense was risky enough.
If you start looking for something new now,
you'll only cause confusion.
There is no way that it'll work out.
Also, because they copied
your defense technique,
my usual attacks
no longer work on them.
All that is left is the "lightning".
I think you'll agree with me?
I'm glad you
came back to us, Ichijō.
I hope you give a taste
of your biting also to them.
For now, let's keep playing the "lightning"
and then see what to do next.
Yes, sir.
Go, go, Hijiri!
Now all together. Go, go, Ichijō!
Go, go, Ichijō!
Shirobara neutralizes
the "lightning"!
Their impenetrable block
defuses Tachibana's "lightning",
even though it was so effective
in the previous set!
That stone wall will certainly be a big
problem for Tachibana High School.
It should've been
a piece of cake now!
Asuka…
Darling, protect our daughter.
The "lightning" is already burned!
Oh, boy. This isn't good.
Mister, could you write
one more note for Ichijō-kun?
Shirobara · Tachibana
Tachibana falls powerlessly
against the Shirobara stone wall.
Will this block prove an insurmountable
problem for Tachibana?
They read our movements
like an open book.
Piercing their block with the "lightning"
will be very difficult.
What should we do, then?
All we need to do is to find a way
around Hanabusa Mitsuru's defense.
The question is how to do it.
Even Ichijō's attacks are not enough.
Hijiri? What's up?
I'm sorry. The truth is, it's me who taught
Hanabusa-san that defense technique.
What?
Why did you do that?
It doesn't matter now.
Hijiri-san, you betrayed our team.
Wait. I'm sure that
she had her reasons.
We'll hear what
she has to say later.
We'd better focus on how
to overcome this crisis.
Maybe we could break their defense
if we hit the ball strong enough?
Yes, but let's not forget that you developed
this technique precisely to deal with that.
Like a willow that can't be broken,
you were to tame the strength of the ball.
One needs a whole lot of strength
in order to break a willow.
I know how we can break a willow.
Ichijō-san, I'll need your help.
Sounds like a good plan.
Let's do as Mimi says.
Hijiri-san, what are you trying to do?
What's your plan?
Hijiri-chan, for God's sake,
be more careful!
Tachibana plays become incomprehensible.
They're clearly trying something new. But what?
Timeout!
Shirobara · Tachibana
Sir, this double spike was a mistake, after all.
Let's try something different.
Don't give up just yet.
Have patience and you'll be fine.
– Mimi…
– Give me one more chance.
Ladies and gentlemen…
I struggle to find the right words.
Tachibana played a double spike!
Hijiri Mimi and Ichijō Asuka's double spike
has broken through Hanabusa's defense!
We did it.
We broke the willow.
I'm sure you'd be glad to see
our Asuka having met Hijiri Mimi.
Shirobara · Tachibana
Hijiri and Ichijō's double spike leads
Tachibana High School to the match ball!
Shirobara · Tachibana
Shirobara Academy's captain Hanabusa Mitsuru
tries to defend without any success!
Shirobara · Tachibana
And they won!
Is everything okay, Hanabusa-san?
Thank you.
I lost. What to add here?
But I have no regrets,
because we played a really good game.
See you at the
National Tournament.
Yes. See you soon.
When I realized that we had won,
my heart literally stopped.
I just couldn't believe that!
Me too. I didn't know that winning
a match could be so exciting.
Yes. I'm glad that I decided
to join our club.
Ichijō-san, we're going now.
Okay.
Mr. Hara, right?
I am Ichijō Asuka's father.
Thank you for looking
after my daughter.
I lost my wife this year.
I am sorry that we didn't meet earlier.
It's all right.
By the way, I meant to ask you
a personal question.
It was you who helped me
during that fire, right?
Yes, it was me.
I would like to thank you
once again for saving Asuka.
I would never have imagined that you
would be her teacher after we had moved.
Fate has a strange sense of humor.
Yes, life works in mysterious ways.
I was surprised to see her at Shōyō.
And this time I accidentally
came across her in high school.
Perhaps it was thanks to my late wife that
you and Asuka kept bumping into each other.
Does Asuka know
that you saved her?
No, I never told her that.
Ichijō-san, it's only my opinion,
but in that fire she lost her mother,
because nobody tried to help her.
Therefore, now she is afraid to trust anyone and
believes that she does not need anyone's help.
This distrust, this aversion to other people greatly
affects her interaction with the environment
and is something that
she will have to face in the future.
Thank you…
What are you doing here?
Ichijō-san? Looks like the coach
is talking to your father.
– Dad!
– Asuka!
You did a great job.
I'm very proud of you.
Thank you.
All thanks to your letter.
Ichijō-san, we're sorry. We didn't understand
what was happening to you at the time.
What?
We had no idea that your mother
died in a fire. I feel so sorry for you.
Who told you about this?
Ichijō-san?
– Leave me alone!
– Asuka!
Ichijō-san!
Did we say something wrong?
She doesn't want anyone
to know about her pain.
She doesn't want
to let anyone around her.
Until now, we didn't know
the real Ichijō-san.
Will Asuka, struck to early by the reality of life,
ever overcome her trust issues?
What about the Tachibana High School's
Volleyball Club, that just won their first match?
How will they do in the upcoming
matches of the tournament?
– I'm thinking about dropping out of school.
– Because your past has come to light?
You don't need to feel ashamed.
That's not the point! I just hate
when other people pity me.
Finally, we won our first match. We are
already starting to prepare for the next one.
But then, Ichijō-san takes a break
from school without notice.
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"The New Captain".
See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offensive
Nothing else matters
hora kurushii omoi demo
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death