kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 10:
Opening of the Spring Prefectural Tournament
Let's give our best shot
in the Spring Prefectural Tournament!
Hijiri-san, why Ichijō-san
never comes to training?
To think she's the captain…
Before we lost to East Port,
she didn't miss a single workout.
What can I say…
Seeing her enthusiasm, I felt like training hard
myself, but when things are like this…
The girls are right, Mimi.
No matter how hard you work,
we can't play without a full team.
I know that all too well.
The tournament is around the corner.
What's our plan?
Stay patient for now.
I'll talk to Ichijō-san and see what happens.
Let's give our best shot
in the Spring Prefectural Tournament!
Please, Ichijō-san.
Come to the training.
You're our captain.
Without you,
the club will fall apart.
Maybe it's for the best? We keep talking about it.
Maybe it's time to let the inevitable happen.
Ichijō-san!
Honestly, I'm devastated.
Hijiri-san, why do you think
we lost to Yokohama East Port?
The girls can barely receive
the ball, let alone pass it.
Not to mention to spike it.
So what if you or I work hard?
We have no chances, anyway.
That's the reason we train,
to improve the skills of the whole team.
No training is going
to help them improve.
You know full well that we won't win anything.
Our participation is just a waste of time.
Don't say that.
Who's that?
Oh? That's one of
Shirobara's players.
Hello there. I am Fukagawa Natsuko from
the Shirobara Academy's Volleyball Club.
Maybe you remember me?
Yes. Thanks again for the match.
Get off your high horse.
We lost only thanks to
Hanabusa's stubbornness.
The rest of the team
doesn't recognize this defeat.
Someone doesn't know
how to lose here. Pathetic.
Who are you, anyway?
Let me introduce you to the captain
of the Shirobara team: Nikaidō Yuka.
But wait… Your captain
was Hanabusa Mitsuru-san.
Not quite. She was the only substitute
for me during my absence. I'm the captain.
I was suspended at the time.
I came to settle my bills with you.
I want a rematch.
We refuse.
What, you're chickening out?
Chickening out?
Who are you talking to?
Are you retarded, or what?
I'm talking to you. There's no one else here.
So how's it gonna be? Are you fighting or
running away with your tails between your legs?
Who do you think you are?
Just calm down, Ichijō-san.
Somehow you had no problem
accepting the challenge from Hanabusa.
I am Ichijō Asuka, captain of the Tachibana
High School's Volleyball Club.
I accept the challenge.
Don't do this, Ichijō-san.
You're making a mistake.
Great. So it's decided.
We'll meet next Saturday.
This time we'll play
at our hall, got that?
I'll just say that I'm the one
who developed our famous "killer spike".
I'll add that Hanabusa's execution
cannot be compared to mine.
If I were you, I'd prepare
real good for this match.
What are we going to tell the coach
and the rest? I don't like this.
If it's any consolation,
I'll start coming to training tomorrow.
Hijiri-san, what are you waiting for?
Serve me the next ball.
Okay!
Now it's your turn.
We'll play a hundred receptions.
Get ready!
Yukari!
Good! Dive in to the ball!
Sir?
I need to tell you something. Ichijō-san…
Our captain arranged a rematch with Shirobara.
Yes, she already told me that.
And you agreed?
I gave her free hand.
She hasn't told the rest yet, huh?
I see. She'll probably do it only once
she's convinced that you're able to win.
That's just how she is.
Earlier she said that our participation
is doomed to fail and it's just a waste of time.
To be frank, sometimes
I don't know what she's thinking.
I sense that you're not exactly
looking forward to this match.
Yes… I get the impression that
Ichijō-san has agreed to this match
mostly because she let herself get
provoked, wanting to protect her pride.
Hijiri. If I remember correctly, the match against
Shirobara was due to their lust for revenge.
That didn't stop you
from agreeing.
You said it'd help you
unite your team.
That's why I didn't say a word and let you
play that game. It's the same now.
The only difference is that
the tables have turned.
Hijiri, I'll give it to you straight.
Currently, Tachibana High School's Volleyball
Club doesn't deserve to be called a team.
Sir!
You can't be considered a team
until everyone is fully involved.
Earlier the balance in your team was disturbed
by the first-graders, now it's Ichijō-san.
Even if she's doing it for the wrong reasons,
she's fully committed to your training.
I admit, I've been waiting
for this moment for a long time.
I don't want to lose
everything now.
If this match is necessary to gain
Ichijō commitment, so be it.
Hijiri. No labor
can go without pain.
Only when you overcome this pain
will your group become a real team.
Oh!
Hi… Hijiri-chan,
step away from the edge!
Arashi-kun?
Why are you so nervous?
I thought you were about to jump.
What? Jump?
Don't be silly.
But when I saw you looking sadly away,
I really thought you could do it.
I'm sorry.
Yes, I guess there are
things I'm worried about.
Girls don't have it easy.
I'd like to help you somehow, Hijiri-chan.
But I don't know what I could do.
Arashi Sankichi isn't
very good at thinking.
Thanks… Unfortunately,
nothing can be done.
Hm?
Today is the anniversary
of Wakamatsu-san's death.
Amazing that you remember that date.
I'm impressed, Hijiri-chan.
It's nothing, really. After all,
she was my friend from the club.
Hanabusa-san?
What are you doing?!
Go away.
Yukiko is my best friend.
I will not let anyone from
Tachibana High School disturb her peace.
Who disturbs peace here?!
Arashi-kun.
Hanabusa-san, I think Wakamatsu-san
wouldn't like to watch us argue all the time.
Everything indicates that we'll stand against
each other again, but I don't like it at all.
I don't have the slightest desire
to play a match motivated by revenge.
If we have to play, we should do it
like decent rivals, with sportsmanship.
Please, talk to Nikaidō-san
and tell her to cancel this match.
No. It's no use.
See, I…
I have no influence on her.
How's that? Why?
This girl is the biggest
hooligan in our school.
Some time ago, the principal expelled her
for cruelly beating another student.
But recently she was
allowed to come back.
She came back to our club.
She joined us right
in the first grade.
From the very beginning it was clear
that she was a great attacker.
Hanabusa-san. Our school tradition has it that
the captain is the strongest member of the team.
You better get ready.
I was completely unable to receive
the spike of Nikaidō Yuka.
She snatched my position
as the team captain.
Alright, but your attack technique
is the same as hers, right?
I wish it was so.
She's incomparably stronger.
Don't feel too bad.
I'm sure I can handle her.
Hanabusa-san, I'll teach you
my somersault reception.
But in return, I'm asking you
to confront Nikaidō-san again.
You want to teach me,
your enemy, your own technique?
Yes.
Don't think that I've forgotten
that your club led to Yukiko's death.
But alright.
– Hijiri-chan, that's not very smart!
– Arashi-kun, stay out of this.
Hanabusa-san. I sincerely hope
you can become a captain again.
I'd like to fight another match with you,
free from resentment and hostility.
Yukiko…
Yukiko, I…
I…
Yukiko.
Wakamatsu-san loved volleyball
more than anything.
She loved it to such an extent
that it ultimately became her doom.
I'm sure that wherever she is right now,
she keeps her fingers crossed for you
and wants you to return
to the captain's position.
Hijiri-san.
Hanabusa-san…
Thank you, Hijiri-san.
I will master your
somersault reception.
And when this happens,
I will stand again in front of Nikaidō Yuka.
Okay, stop!
Let's have a short break.
I'd like to tell you something.
Your enthusiasm really impresses me.
If we keep this up,
there's nothing we can't do.
I'm not sure what you mean?
Well, now the cat's out of the bag.
Before we play in the tournament,
we'll have a rematch with Shirobara.
The match will take place tomorrow after school.
Of course we have permission from Professor.
That's great!
We've been training forever.
Finally we can play with someone!
I can't wait. I'll be finally able to see
how much these exercises were actually worth.
Let's show them!
Yes. Let's show them!
Sir?
This is a letter from Shirobara's captain.
Ichijō, it's addressed to you.
Yes?
What could she have written there?
"Forgive me for skipping the introduction,
but I am writing in an urgent matter.
I am sorry to inform you that we will not play
the rematch we asked for the day before yesterday.
There are important circumstances
that prevent us from carrying it out.
We made a mistake in assessing the situation.
I am sorry for this misunderstanding.
I am asking for your
understanding and forgiveness.
Captain of the Shirobara Academy's
Volleyball Club, Hanabusa Mitsuru,
to Tachibana High School's
Volleyball Club captain, Ichijō Asuka-sama."
Hijiri-san, looks like they've
changed their captain.
Yes… They wrote that they have
some important circumstances.
They're probably going through
some difficulties.
Either way, they sent us
a letter with an official apology.
Apparently your rematch is off.
What a bummer.
Yeah, I was so happy.
Let's not take it personally.
The tournament is around the corner.
What difference does it make
who we're gonna destroy?
Let's get them!
Hijiri, there's also a letter
addressed to you.
Thank you.
Hanabusa Mitsuru
I don't know how you did it, but you managed
to prevent this childish rematch
and Ichijō still appears
to be in high spirits.
Finally, your club is
thriving as it should.
Sir…
"Hijiri-san. Thank you.
I thank you from
the bottom of my heart.
No matter how many times I thank you,
I can't express my gratitude enough.
Yesterday I challenged
Nikaidō Yuka to a duel."
"Hijiri-san. I won with her.
I regained my position as captain of
Shirobara Academy's Volleyball Club.
Without your help
I would never have succeeded.
I am sure Yukiko
would be very happy.
I also kept my word
and just like I promised you,
I have informed your captain
that we are canceling our match.
Hijiri-san… Thank you.
Thank you so much.
I know that one day we will meet
on the court as opponents,
but this time we will play
a beautiful match.
I cannot wait for this day
and I am already training for it.
With gratitude, Hanabusa Mitsuru
to my dear friend,
Hijiri Mimi-sama."
I'm so happy.
Hanabusa-san, I can't wait
for that day either.
The High School Spring Volleyball
Tournament in Kanagawa Prefecture begins
We warmly welcome
the Tachibana High School team
What?
Shirobara?
Yes. Isn't it ironic that we play with them
in the first match of the tournament?
Well, nothing changes.
Give them hellfire.
Today the High School National
Volleyball Tournament begins.
Shirobara · Tachibana
We broadcast straight from the hall,
where you can feel a bit nervous atmosphere.
The first match will be played
by Shirobara Academy from Yokosuka
against the Tachibana
High School from Misaki.
I'm looking for Nikaidō Yuka,
but I can't see her anywhere.
It's safe to assume that we're playing
against a completely different team.
Mine, mine!
Hijiri-san, she copied
your reception technique!
Ichijō-san!
Ichijō-san, what's going on?!
Arashi, I think there's a fire.
Something's burning near the hall.
What's going on with Asuka?
The match has just begun,
and there problems already.
What will become of Mimi's teaching
Mitsuru her reception technique?
How will the the match between Shirobara
Academy and Tachibana High School develop?
Ichijō-san, don't worry,
I'll take care of the defense.
I don't need anyone's help.
Each of us is alone.
Everyone lives and struggles by themselves.
Hanabusa Mitsuru from Shirobara Academy
directs her spike at the weakest players.
Sirens of fire trucks keep
resounding during the match.
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"Asuka's Fiery Past".
See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offensive
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death