kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 18:
The Next Goal – the Interhigh!
Hey! Hey!
Hijiri-chan! Hijiri-chan!
What's up, Arashi-kun?
Thanks for supporting us.
That was very nice of you.
Come on now.
Thank you for reaching the quarter-finals and
making our school famous throughout the country.
Thank you for your kind words, Arashi-kun,
but there's really nothing to talk about.
Yes, there is! That is what they'll be talking
about today at the Student Council meeting.
What exactly do they
want to discuss?
They'd like to organize a big party in your honor
because you ranked in Top 8 in the country.
Ah, that. I thought
it was something else.
Wait, you already knew? How?
What's more, allegedly it's you
who's taking care of the logistics.
Who told you all this?
Fusejima-kun. He warned us that you
were preparing something like that.
That damn nerd!
Always has to spoil everything!
To be honest,
we were just talking about it.
Since I was elected to be the head
of the executive committee,
I promise you that this will be
the best party you've ever… uh?
Hey? Hey! Hijiri-chan!
Is that something
everyone agrees with?
Yes. It's the will of the whole club.
All right. Let's inform
them right away.
Conference room
I suggest inviting also parents and
graduates to the ceremony.
We'll show a picture of a modern school
that shows its gratitude…
Oh, it's you and Hijiri-kun.
Perfect timing.
We just talked about the ceremony
in honor of your—
We're here to talk about it. Actually,
we'd prefer to go without any ceremonies.
Excuse me?
No ceremony?
I don't understand.
What's that supposed to mean?
The request comes from the girls, not me.
They voted unanimously among themselves.
Hijiri-kun, is that true?
Yes, sir.
Could you briefly
outline your reason?
Of course, sir.
Mr. Principal.
Dear student council.
I believe with all my heart that we have
come so far, and with only six people,
solely thanks to your
unwavering support.
It may be a bit selfish on our part,
but we are not satisfied
with the result of the last tournament.
Not because we were
eliminated in the quarter-finals,
but because we could
have played better.
Please, let us refrain from celebrating until
the end of the next Interhigh Championships.
Interhigh?
The championships will take place in August,
but the qualifying round is about to start now.
Right off the bat?
We want to show our game at the
upcoming Interhigh Championships.
That the six of us mean business.
That you can't mess with Tachibana High School!
True, in the last tournament
something was missing at the end.
However, we have reason to be proud.
Your team is very fresh,
yet you still came in eighth.
We will definitely win at Interhigh.
You have matured a lot
in this short time.
However, the most difficult
is yet to come.
You are no longer some unknown
team from the backwoods.
Teams from all around the country recognize
you and see you as a formidable opponent.
I'll ask you again.
Can I count on your enthusiasm,
even knowing that things won't be easy?
Yes, sir!
Very good.
As expected, Shijōdōri easily
won the last tournament.
If we don't do anything about it, Shijōdōri
will undoubtedly win also the Interhigh.
Sir, do you have any idea
how we could beat them?
Yeah, do we have any plans how to
overcome their "light" and "shadow"?
No.
I troubles me a lot, but unfortunately
I haven't come up with anything yet.
That won't last forever, though.
Sooner or later, we'll think of something.
For now, we're going back
to daily training.
Yes, sir!
Sekiya! More accuracy!
Get up! Come on!
College entrance exams will
take place on Saturday afternoon.
If you want to go to college,
you must take them.
Remember that this is just the first session.
In two months there will be two more.
It flew by faster than I'd like…
I don't feel optimistic.
I wonder how it will go.
I have heard that the senior students are
starting to take collage entrance exams.
I heard that, too.
You heard that, too? So, like what,
you're not going to college, Sugihara-san?
Oh, I am, but I'm going somewhere you can
get into without cramming days and nights.
Do such places even exist?
Of course. There are a lot
of less known universities.
And which university
is our captain going to?
I'm not going anywhere.
Wait, why? You're much
smarter than Sugihara-san.
Hey! Kimiko, what's that supposed to mean?
I'm still here and can hear you well.
Gee, don't take it personally.
Right. Mimi is very smart,
that's true.
She always scores the second
or third best in the tests.
Then why aren't you
going to college?
What a loss.
Life doesn't revolve around
getting to a college.
Maybe you're right, Ichijō-san.
And what will you do after finishing school?
I can't part with the volleyball.
When I finish school, I would like
to join some professional team.
My dream is to get
to the national team.
And play in the International
Championships and the Olympic Games…
Exactly. But for this to succeed,
we must win Interhigh first.
Work out time!
Come on, girls.
That's just Ichijō-san.
See you tomorrow!
Hijiri-kun!
Fusejima-kun.
Are you coming home now?
Yes. I was stuck
in the library until now.
Still a bookworm, I see.
My father has agreed to pay my tuition,
but only if I become a doctor.
I need to study a lot if I want to get
to the National Medical Academy.
I see that you don't
have it easy, either.
I heard you don't want
to go to college.
Yes. Grandma says she can get by
without my help and I'm free to go.
So why aren't you going? With your grades,
you'll get wherever you like.
I am still not sure what I want to do.
I don't want to go to college without a goal.
While I realize that
it may not be everything,
but I like going to school
and playing volleyball.
Yes. Devoting yourself to do what you like
can be the easiest road to happiness.
What about you, Fusejima-kun?
Do you like to study?
Not that I don't like, but…
Cramming for tests is hardly studying.
Everything is so messed up, huh?
I love volleyball, but I don't know
if I could play professionally like Ichijō-san.
For now, focus on the Interhigh.
Yes. No use dwelling on it.
Got to focus on one thing at a time.
Good luck.
Thank you.
Interhigh Championships… I won't regret it,
even if I sacrifice everything for it.
The qualifiers
are around the corner.
But we still have no tactic
against the "light" and the "shadow".
Sir…
Hijiri.
Ichijō.
Sugihara.
Nishi.
Sekiya.
Ōta.
Each of you has matured and become
a great player, in body and in mind.
Meanwhile, I still don't know
how we can beat Shijōdōri.
Maybe someone like me, who hurt a friend
on the court, doesn't deserve to be a coach?
Okay, next one!
That's it!
Sir!
Have you really figured out
how we could defeat Shijōdōri?
Yes, but whether we succeed
is mostly up to you, Hijiri.
Excuse me? Up to me?
For this attack to succeed, we need a good jump.
You're the best for this job.
So this is an offensive technique
that the captain will perform individually?
Yes. You got a problem with that?
No. That's not my point.
I was thinking, what about the defense.
Receptions will be handled
by Sekiya and Nishi.
We'll be the only ones
on the defense?
Yes. Nishi will focus on "light",
and Sekiya on "shadow".
I don't know if I can do it.
If you really can't, so be it.
But as long as you work together,
you should be able to receive a few spikes.
Once we're at the ball, we'll be playing the
"lightning", double spike and this new attack.
So, the best defense is offense.
Exactly.
Ōta, you'll take care of the passes.
Ichijō and Sugihara, your duo will play
the "lightning" and double spikes.
Yes, sir!
Perfect. You can go back to training.
Hijiri, you stay here.
Yes, sir!
Come with me, Hijiri.
Yes, sir.
I keep telling you
to get these legs higher.
Mr. Nagaishi,
I'd like to ask for a favor.
Oh, Mr. Hara.
I'm happy to hear you.
If this is not too much
trouble for you,
I'd like you to train Hijiri
from my club in high jump.
I'd love to do it myself, but the thing is,
I have no idea about athletics.
No problem, I can train her.
But can I ask what is it for?
Hijiri and I are developing
a new attack technique.
All right, that's enough for me.
I'll train your player.
Thank you very much.
I also thank you, sir.
One more thing.
If possible, I'd like you to teach her
how to jump from both sides of the pole.
From both sides?
Both sides, huh?
Yes. Is it even possible?
Yes, of course, so long as
her leg muscles are strong enough.
I can vouch for that.
I leave her in your hands.
Ah… Sir!
Hijiri-kun, let's start right away.
Show me what you can do.
Yes, sir.
Remember to straighten
your legs when you jump.
Higher!
Again!
You're turning too fast!
Let yourself fly for a moment!
"Light" or "shadow"?
"Light".
Nishi, you're barely grazing it!
Sekiya, it's not enough
to touch the ball.
You must send it
as high as possible.
That was excellent.
Thank you. Now the same,
but facing the pole with the other arm.
Not a problem.
I have to tell you, I'm impressed.
I've never seen anyone
master a high jump so quickly.
Is there any chance
for Hijiri to join our club?
Just kidding.
I have one more request.
I'd like her to be able to do the same,
but without a run-up.
No run-up?
How do you imagine it?
No way!
I know I'm asking for a lot.
But it's necessary for our
technique to work.
She won't have much time
or space to do a run-up.
Plus the power of our attack will be halved
if we give our opponents time to react.
What do you think, Mr. Nagaishi?
I have to say,
the chances are very poor.
Sir, please agree.
If you agree to train me,
I promise I won't let you down.
Good. I'll hold you to that, Hijiri.
Yes, sir!
Could you at least tell me
what this technique actually looks like?
If I tell you what it looks like,
you'll just get impatient
and stop focusing on training.
At the moment, I can only say
that I named it a "V attack".
A "V attack"?
Yes. "V", as in "Victory".
It's a letter of might.
Hijiri-kun, it's started raining.
Let's wrap it up for today.
No, I want to keep practicing.
Excuse me?
Please, please let me
practice a bit more.
Cut it out, Kyōko.
Don't exercise in the rain.
I have to train if I want to take part
in the Interhigh Championships.
Last time we totally blew it.
But this time I'll do everything to beat Hijiri Mimi
and get out of the prefecture.
How else can I prove my skills?
I understand how you feel, but you'll
only harm yourself this way.
I'll repeat what I once told you.
Volleyball for me is a game,
but also a way of life.
"The qualification round is coming!
Tachibana vs. Yokohama East Port"
Oh, captain!
Were you able
to master the "V attack"?
Not yet… And the eliminations
are right around the corner.
So far we've practiced
individual game.
Today I'd like you to practice team play.
Last touches before the qualifiers.
Yes, sir!
– But, sir…
– What's up, Hijiri?
I still haven't managed
to master the "V attack".
What gives you the idea that
you'll be using it in the eliminations?
Excuse me?
Listen carefully, Hijiri.
You too, girls.
All our training so far was to prepare us
for the match with Shijōdōri.
In other words, in my opinion
with your current level of skill
you'll easily go through the qualifiers
and advance to the main event.
One more thing. Hijiri.
Yes?
All you have to do is master the "V attack"
before our match against Shijōdōri.
Yes, sir.
It won't be easy,
but sooner or later, you will succeed.
Thank you, sir.
Of course, don't let your head get big
and play with full commitment.
Hadori Kyōko will want
to win at all costs.
Okay, assume positions.
We begin with the training.
Yes, sir!
Ōta, show me a better reception!
Yes… Yes, sir!
Our weapons for the qualifiers
are the "lightning" and double spike.
For them to work, your passes
must be fast and precise!
Yes, sir!
Did something happen, sir?
No, it's nothing.
What are you standing there for?
Back to exercise!
Yes, sir!
What is it this time?
Sir?!
Someone secretly
recorded our training.
Who could it be?
A disturbing shadow
looms over Mimi and her team.
Who could it be?
What's his purpose?
There are so many unanswered questions,
and the championship is fast approaching.
What's going on?
Why won't we ask for a break?
Professor is worried about
the man with the camera.
Not good. The coach's anxiety
spreads to the rest of the team.
The prefectural preliminaries
for Interhigh are starting.
We have a crisis
in the very first match.
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"Black Clouds Over the Court".
See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offensive
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death