kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 11:
Asuka's Fiery Past
Ichijō-san, what's going on?!
Timeout!
Tachibana asks for a break already!
Their captain, Ichijō Asuka,
appears to be in pretty bad shape.
Let's hope that nothing has happened to her
and the game will resume soon.
What's going on there?! Hijiri-chan almost got it,
and that girl sits down in the middle of the court.
I can't stand her!
Easy, easy, boss.
Yelling is not gonna help.
Go, go, Hijiri!
Is everything okay, Ichijō-san?
Ichijō-san!
I don't understand.
Sir, maybe she got sick?
No, that's not it. She is just
a little shocked and overwhelmed.
But why? What happened
to her all of the sudden?
Sir, what are we going to do now?
How are we supposed
to continue playing?
This is a good moment for us.
Ichijō Asuka started freaking out.
Hanabusa, send the balls
straight at her.
Yes, sir.
As you know, everything depends on this match.
Prove that you deserve to be called captain
and lead your team to victory.
Understood?
Yes, sir.
Just don't make the same mistake
you did at our last match.
Yeah.
Sir?
Don't worry, Ichijō.
It's okay if you give up on the first set.
Just try to stall for time, as long as possible.
Yes, sir!
Ichijō Asuka is back on the field!
She still needs support.
I would like to remind that Tachibana has
no one in reserve, so they must rely on Ichijō.
As the sirens suggest, something is burning
nearby, but for now the hall remains safe.
The match resumes.
Ichijō-san, don't worry
about anything.
I'll take care of the defense.
It'll be fine.
Ichijō-san!
Shirobara · Tachibana
Forgive me. Friendship aside,
a match is a match.
I am the captain of
Shirobara Academy team.
My role is to lead
the team to victory.
Ichijō-san!
I can't look at this…
Shirobara's captain, Hanabusa Mitsuru
plays intensive attacks on Ichijō Asuka.
Tachibana is in serious trouble.
Let them put that fire out already!
Ichijō Kazuo
Mom?!
Santō Junior High School's
Volleyball Club · Ichijō Asuka
Mom!
Don't go there, child! It's dangerous.
The firefighters will be here soon.
Mom…
But my mom is there!
She's sick and cannot move!
Somebody help me!
Please, somebody take her
away from there!
Mom!
Mom?
Ichijō-san, don't try
to receive her attacks!
I don't need anyone's help.
I don't need anyone…
Mom!
Mom, where are you?!
I'm coming over to you!
Mom?!
Mom!
Mom, wake up!
Dad…
Dad!
Save us!
Ichijō-san!
Hm?
Your daughter's on television.
Something's wrong.
I'll be right back.
Could you keep an eye here?
Once again, Hanabusa Mitsuru's
merciless spike hits Ichijō Asuka!
Will Ichijō get up?
You can do it, Ichijō!
Ichijō gets up!
Asuka…
Ichijō-san, try to avoid the ball.
Don't attempt to receive it.
Nobody asked you for advice.
I'll play until I fall.
Each of us is alone.
Everyone lives and struggles
by themselves.
Hanabusa jumps!
Will she play at Ichijō again?!
Mom!
Asuka…
Ichijō is still lying on the court.
Apparently she got knocked out.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have a second break!
Coach Hara has asked
for a second break in this set.
Ichijō is walking towards the bench,
supported by her teammates.
Today's game is accompanied
by unusual brutality.
The score is thirteen to zero.
Shirobara · Tachibana
Shirobara Academy leads with a crushing
advantage. How will this go on?
Is that a fire brigade?
Yes, the commentator said earlier that they're
putting out a fire near the hall where they play.
It probably reminds you of
the fire in which your poor mother died…
If only I was at home back then.
I'm sorry, Asuka.
Fight, Asuka!
Do not give up!
You can overcome any pain,
even the worst. You can do it, Asuka!
Ichijō-san?
I'm so glad you're okay!
Me too.
We were worried that something
had happened to you.
Ichijō. Can you pull through?
Yes, sir.
I'm the team captain.
I have to set an example for others.
We're going to show them.
Ichijō is back on the court!
The hall is reverberating with
deafening applause for her fighting spirit!
Asuka…
Your mom is looking at you from Heaven
and won't let anything bad happen to you.
Asuka…
Whatever can be said of her,
Ichijō is one tough cookie.
I didn't know that side of her.
She really impressed me.
Arashi Sankichi can admit when he's wrong.
I'll cheer her on like Hijiri-chan…
Wait, that's too much.
She didn't impress me that much…
But still, it was quite a bit…
Alright, never mind.
Guys, we're cheering on Ichijō-kun!
Go! Go! Ichijō!
Ichijō-san, if it goes on
like this, we'll lose it big time.
We have to do something…
But what?
Hanabusa-san, you'd better
not expect us to give up without a fight.
I'll play until the very end.
Hijiri-san, for the sake of my team,
I will not stop short of destroying you.
No! Hanabusa-san is about
to play at Ichijō-san again!
Ichijō-san won't stand her attacks for long,
and then we'll be doomed!
I have to protect her!
Will they ever put out that fire?
The ball flies straight at Ichijō!
Darling, save our daughter!
Ichijō-san!
Mimi!
Hijiri-chan!?
Come on, let me go!
What was that supposed to be?
Don't get involved in my game.
Ichijō-san, if nothing changes,
you'll be of no use to us.
You know best that
we'll lose without you.
Or maybe you want to continue this charade
in the belief that we'll lose anyway in the end?
I won't stand for it!
Hijiri-san… you amaze me.
Amazing play!
Hijiri Mimi's desperate decision
rescues Ichijō Asuka at the last moment.
Tachibana High School
is in a lot of trouble.
Fourteen to zero.
Set ball for Shirobara.
Asuka, I'm coming to you!
Mimi!
Hijiri-san, I'm impressed by your will to fight.
However, this will not stop me.
Oh, boy! Who to pray to,
God or the Venerable Buddha?
Why do I never know anything?
Shirobara · Tachibana
Fifteen to zero. That's the score
we finish the first set with.
As a result of Captain Ichijō Asuka's peculiar
lack of shape, Tachibana loses the first set.
Despite this, it's a good match.
One can feel a great deal of tension.
Will Tachibana get back on their feet
in the upcoming set?
Or maybe Shirobara will crush them,
winning the whole match to zero?
It is a truly great game, undeniably
worthy of opening this tournament.
It's not good, sir. If Ichijō-san
doesn't get it together, it's over.
I agree. No matter what we try,
nothing works against them.
In my opinion,
we have choice but to give up.
Wait a moment! We cannot
put all the blame on Ichijō-san alone.
Mimi, what do you mean by that?
Are you telling us that it's our fault?
No. It's not like that!
It's because I taught my somersault
reception to Hanabusa-san.
That's why even Ichijō-san's spike…
Even her spike won't help us much.
We should just give up. With such score,
it'll be nothing to be ashamed of.
So? Do you keep playing
or do you call it quits?
We'll keep playing! Surrendering
means disrespect for the game.
Ichijō, what do you think?
Me?
Ichijō-san, if nothing changes,
you'll be of no use to us.
You know best that
we'll lose without you.
I don't want to play
a match destined to be lost.
Or maybe you want to continue this charade
in the belief that we'll lose anyway in the end?
I won't stand for it!
I want to keep playing,
but not to lose.
Sugihara, and you?
I feel the same.
And you guys?
Same.
We won't let them push us around!
Very good.
In that case, we're not going to give up
until the final whistle blows.
Yes, sir!
Ichijō, I'm more than sure that
they'll aim at you again in this set.
Don't worry about anything.
Forget about everything.
What do you mean, forget?
I meant that you should focus
on volleyball alone. On here and now.
What is our coach trying to tell me?
Professor is right.
I want back the Ichijō-san I know.
Leave me alone. Next time,
don't interfere with my game.
I don't need anyone's help.
Ichijō-san…
Dear God, Venerable Buddha!
Hear my prayers
and protect Hijiri-chan!
Your servant, Arashi Sankichi, for the next
ten years… well, maybe five… or maybe three…
Well, for the next year,
he'll do whatever you want!
Just look after Hijiri-chan!
The boss is kind of funny
when he's worried.
Yeah, a bit crazy,
those prayers of his.
Yeah. He's totally love-struck.
Ladies and gentlemen, we are starting
the second set. Will Shirobara Academy's
Captain Hanabusa Mitsuru's spike shake
Tachibana again, and above all Ichijō Asuka?
Asuka…
Ichijō-san, let me
take care of the defense.
I'll defeat Hanabusa Mitsuru
and her somersault reception!
Ichijō, don't worry about anything.
Forget about everything.
Just forget!
Ichijō…
Hey, you!
Come back here at once! Hey!
Come back here!
Ichijō-san!
Mom!
Mom…
Ichijō…
Please… Get my daughter out of here.
Get Asuka out of here.
Why won't anyone save her?!
Why aren't you here, Dad?
Hold on tight, okay?
Just hold on!
Ichijō-san!
Mom… Mom.
Are you hurt?
Talk to me!
Save us, Dad.
Save Mom.
No one else can save her!
Mom…
Ichijō-san!
In the end, no one saved
her mother in that fire.
After this incident, distrust and
aversion to people rooted in her heart.
If only I got there a little earlier…
Another merciless attack!
Hanabusa Mitsuru ruthlessly sends
one ball after another at Ichijō Asuka.
The match became
quite depressing.
You can see that Ichijō
can barely stand on her feet.
How much longer
will be able to hold out?
The second set is developing like the first,
with Shirobara's lead to zero.
Shirobara · Tachibana
It appears that the match
is already decided.
Ichijō-san…
Hijiri-san.
I know perfectly well
how dangerous you can be.
Therefore, as long as I can,
I will play at Ichijō-san.
A… Asuka!
Ichijō.
Get rid of bad thoughts.
Don't dredge up these memories now.
Ichijō-san…
Ichijō Asuka has lost her faith in people
in a drastic way, and her heart turned into ice.
Will she ever be able
to trust someone again?
Hijiri Mimi struggles with a sense of guilt
after teaching her technique to an enemy.
Will she be able to overcome the vision of
a humiliating failure without scoring a single point?
The match between Shirobara Academy
and Tachibana High School continues on.
Shirobara · Tachibana
Ichijō-san, please, snap out of it.
I'm fine, sir.
Please resume the game.
Asuka's father appears at the match,
and his presence helps her recover.
Will the girls manage to organize a counterattack
in the chaos that their match has become?
Will Asuka conquer
her inner demons?
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"The Fearsome Double Spike".
See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offensive
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death