kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 13:
The New Captain
How about a little break?
To tell you the truth, I was just getting
warmed up. Let's train a little longer.
I agree with Tomiko.
Okay, assume positions.
We'll take that break later.
I've got it!
I'm so glad that we won our first match.
Girls got much happier already.
If this keeps up,
we'll also win the second one.
Who knows, maybe we'll
even reach the finals?
Yukari, I thought that out of the two of us,
you were the realistic one.
You know best that in sport, motivation boosts
the power by five, or maybe even ten times.
There's some truth to it. The most important
thing now is not to lose that momentum.
Let's get back to the game.
Okay.
Sir!
You're bursting with energy today.
Yes. We've decided that we'll do
everything in our power
to make it through the qualifiers
and advance to the National Tournament.
Therefore, sir, please allow me
to speak from the manager's point of view
and ask you to fill the application for
the participation in the National Tournament.
I see that you're
already planning ahead.
Way to go. But for now,
let's focus on your second match.
Now listen. The Prefectural Tournament
Committee confirmed the schedule
and you'll play with
Tamagaoka High School.
Tamagaoka High School?
Yes. Not much is known
about their team, just like ours.
So we'd better go and learn
something about them.
I understand where you're coming from,
but nothing is more important than training.
What ultimately matters
is the difference in fitness and skill.
I count on your full commitment in training.
Do we understand each other?
Yes, sir!
By the way, where's Ichijō?
She didn't come to school today.
Interesting.
I hope it's only today.
It wouldn't be good if she stopped
showing up at school for a long time.
– I'm back.
– Hello.
Asuka, were you at school today?
No.
Did something happen?
I'm thinking about
dropping out of school.
Hmm? Is it because your friends
found out about the accident?
You don't need to feel ashamed.
It's true. People are weak.
However, you cannot
avoid them indefinitely.
Sooner or later,
you'll have to face the reality.
I just don't want
to see anyone right now.
I see.
However, remember that without you,
your clubmates will stay on high five.
You probably know
what that means, right?
Yes.
You just won your first match.
If I were them, I'd be very disappointed.
Ichijō Asuka's absence
was dragging on.
She didn't show up at school
the next day or the day after.
What's up with Ichijō-san?
She won't be here today either?
Yes. Let's focus on training.
– Sumi'e, tell them.
– It'll be better if it's you, Tomiko.
Don't look at me.
What are you mumbling about there?
If you want to tell us something, just do it.
All right, just don't hit me.
Once again there are only five of us,
so we can't play in the tournament.
And if that's the case…
why are we even training?
There it is,
the beginning of the end.
I'm sorry, Hijiri-san,
could you make some space for us?
Wait a moment. According to the schedule
approved by the Student Council, today is our turn.
Oh, we are perfectly aware of this.
The question is, what's the point
in you having the access to the hall,
when you don't have enough people
to participate in official games?
Meanwhile, it's more than likely that our club
will advance to the National Tournament.
It's better for us
to have access to the hall.
What makes you think that
we can't participate in the games?
Don't give me that nonsense!
Stay calm! Yes, I admit it'll make more sense
for your club to practice here.
Mimi!
Hijiri-san, surely you're not gonna
give them back the hall?
If we go by what's better for school,
that's for the best.
We can always exercise outside.
What's that?
Why the long faces?
I'm worried if we'll be able
to play the second match.
That's understandable.
Unfortunately, I can't do
anything about Ichijō's absence.
Why she doesn't show up
at school is her business.
I think that you, as her friends,
could do more than me in that regard.
It can't go on forever.
What do you say if one of us
went to visit her
and she simply asked
why she doesn't come to school?
I've thought about it
and actually I'd happily do it,
but I'm afraid that it'd only cause
more harm than good.
What do you mean?
Ichijō-san is very independent.
If we came to question her,
she could understand it so that
we only care about keeping our club alive.
It could make her want
to come to school even less.
Honestly, I feel like going
to school less and less myself.
Don't say that, Yukari!
You have to stay with us.
The day after the girls didn't show up
at training, thinking up different excuses.
Mimi was alone.
What's going on there?
What was that sound?
Getting old is no picnic.
Grandma, look!
Isn't she the captain
of the Sister's team?
I think she is.
Let's go to her and say hello.
Good day.
I am Hijiri Mimi's grandmother.
Mimi told me you haven't been
to school for some time, Ichijō-san.
I'm glad to see
that you're in good health.
I must tell you, sweetheart, that you and
my granddaughter are like two peas in a pod.
Like two peas in a pod?
What do you mean by that?
You see, Mimi doesn't even know if you'll be able
to play the second match, but she trains anyway.
Ichijō-san, you also can't part
with volleyball, even outside of school.
You're both obsessed
with this sport.
Sorry to bother you.
Good luck in your training.
Easy, easy!
Now, to the basket!
Beautiful!
Excuse me!
I'd like to ask you something.
What, are you so tired of volleyball
that you came to ask us to join?
If so, we'll welcome you
with open arms.
I didn't come for that.
I wanted to ask you to let me
train with you a little bit.
Train… like, basketball?
Or volleyball?
A little bit of both.
If it's a joke, it's not very funny.
Don't waste our time.
But I'm serious.
I just saw you shoot, Shiraki-san,
and I was impressed with your precision.
Thank you for the compliment.
But how does this relate
to volleyball?
I'd like to be able to send the balls where I want,
with the same kind of accuracy that you have.
That's why I thought, maybe I could practice
receptions and spikes together with you.
Please.
You want to practice playing
volleyball into the basket?
Yes. Exactly.
There's no way you could do that.
Exactly. Don't be ridiculous.
This is why I want to practice
until I can, I think that's logical?
Please.
Trouble, big trouble!
Hijiri-san went all alone to the basketball club
and they're probably gonna fight!
They're gonna fight?!
I'm ready, Shiraki-san!
Play with all your strength!
What a nutcase.
It will never work.
Ready, yes? Well, then.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Face it, it's impossible.
It'd be strange if it
worked on the first try.
Shiraki-san, please, let's repeat.
It's pointless,
you're never going to make it.
Let me ask you something.
Did you know how to shoot at the basket
so precisely since you were born?
Fair point. Very well.
Get ready!
See? It was closer now.
With your help,
I'll master it in no time.
Come on. Why should I,
the basketball club captain, help you?
Because we're—
Hijiri.
Sir?
Excuse me.
No need to apologize.
You didn't do anything wrong.
I wanted to talk to you
about something.
I wanted to talk to you about the Prefectural
Tournament. The second round is in a few days.
However, judging by the current situation,
it's unlikely that you'll be able to play.
So I'm planning to submit a form
to withdraw our participation.
If only Ichijō-san
were here with us…
Hijiri. You don't want to pretend it's all right
when you don't have enough people, right?
No, of course not.
I think that at the moment, we have
nothing to look for in the tournament.
In that case, I won't stall and send the necessary
paperwork to the Committee right away.
Now that we got that out of the way,
there's one last thing.
Are you not interested
in what is happening with Ichijō?
Excuse me?
What is it?
I'll say this upfront, if you're here to make me
play a second match with you, count me out.
No, it's too late for that. The coach
has withdrawn us from the tournament.
Oh, yeah?
Then why are you here?
There was a lot going on in class when you
were gone. I came with notes and overdue tests.
Here.
Did you come all the way
here just for that?
Yes. To tell you the truth,
I wanted to drop by long ago.
But I didn't want you to think that
I'm here only to pester you about the games.
For better or worse,
the solution presented itself.
Anyway, I'm glad that
we can avoid misunderstanding.
Hmm? Something smells good.
Oh, it looks delicious!
I'm sorry.
I haven't eaten since morning.
Asuka!
Why don't you invite
your friend to eat with us?
I don't want to impose on you!
Delicious!
My daughter is a great cook.
She'll turn anything into a great meal.
Ichijō-san, I'd like to make it up to you. Maybe
you could come over to eat with us tomorrow?
At your place?
I make a terrible cook, but Grandma's food
is out of this world. What do you say?
Say yes, Asuka.
This is the first time someone
has invited you to their place.
Come on, it'll be fun.
With pleasure.
Awesome!
What? Again?
Please. Let's practice
like the last time.
What's the matter with you?
Your club has withdrawn
from the tournament.
Why do you still want to practice?
Believe me, I want to play
more than you can imagine.
However, that is not
why I want to practice.
See, I love volleyball.
That's enough for me to want to train.
I don't need any big goal.
I just want to do what I like best!
What's so strange about that?
Hijiri!
I'll play with you.
Sir…
Asuka was happy.
Until now, she couldn't trust anyone. She didn't
have anyone who she could call a friend.
But today Hijiri Mimi
invited her to dinner.
Asuka's heart of ice
thawed a little bit.
Maybe… Maybe she'll finally
be able to make friends with someone?
Well, well.
You look wonderful.
I didn't know there was such a beauty
behind that usual grimace.
I'm so proud of you. I'm so glad that
you're finally behaving for your age.
Here's the cake and
the flowers for a gift.
When are you meeting her?
At six o'clock, in front of the bank.
I don't know where Hijiri-san lives,
so we agreed that she'd show me the way.
It's quite late.
You'd better go now.
See you later.
Darling.
All signs point that our daughter
will start smiling again.
Let's get started, Hijiri!
Mimi!?
Mimi!
– Hang in there, Mimi!
– Hijiri-san…
Hijiri.
Hey! Hijiri!
Hijiri, are you okay?
What time is it?
Mimi…
Ichijō-san!
Ichijō-san, I'm so sorry!
Why did you come here?!
Go home.
I'll do anything
to make it up to you.
But you must know that I did
not forget about our meeting.
Look at this.
The coach trained with me
one on one until late.
You trained?
But wait, you told me
that you had quit the game?
That's right.
But I love volleyball!
What exactly did you practice?
I was playing receptions
and tried to hit the basket.
But that's beyond your level.
Yes. That's why I wanted
to practice it.
Unfortunately, I got hit with the ball in the head
and I lost consciousness. I'm sorry.
Doesn't matter. Everything's cool now.
Hijiri-san, I'd like to see this exercise.
I'm ready. Please start!
One more time, please.
All right. Please continue.
You did it! It went in!
Awesome!
Congratulations, Ichijō-san!
I'm so happy.
I'm so happy for you!
What exactly are you
so happy about?
Because you were able to do something
that others couldn't do. It was amazing!
Like a proper captain.
You are the captain here.
What?
Hijiri-san, you're much more
suited to be the captain than I am.
Please, become our club's captain
and let me come back to you.
Mimi, I'm joining her request.
Long live the new captain!
Hijiri-san, will you let me
come back to you?
It wouldn't be the same
without you.
Hey, hey, we have six people again!
Looks like we'll be able to play
the second match after all.
Yes, but… The coach has already
sent the resignation form.
Not quite. For now, I've only filled out
the application, but I haven't sent it yet.
Now I can say that I wanted
to hold off with it until the last minute.
In other words, I never stopped believing in you.
And that is the essence of sport.
I told you a little white lie
to see how you'd behave.
I'm sorry for having
manipulated you.
Who would've thought,
the coach knows us better than ourselves.
With such a trainer
we're indestructible.
On that day, Tachibana's Volleyball Club
for the first time became truly united.
Sir, please tell us the plan how to play
in the tomorrow's match.
In the tomorrow's match?
There is no plan.
– But sir…
– Hijiri.
Don't tell me you don't know the reason
for the training we started today.
As the second match of the tournament
approaches, Mimi and the girls begin to worry.
They ease up a bit once they find out that Daisuke
is already thinking about tactics for the finals.
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"Towards the Semi-finals".
See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offensive
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death