kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 20:
The Shocking Precision of Machines
"Tachibana becomes the first team
to reach the quarter-finals."
"Shijōdōri demonstrates
a devastating strength."
Today we'll be a witness of a game
between the Jōmon Academy of Tōkai
and Women's Technical School Rinsen
from Akita, who debuts at the Interhigh.
Tomorrow we'll play quarter-finals
with one of these teams.
Although none of the Rinsen players
are particularly outstanding,
their teamwork is incredible.
Rinsen proved their worth by beating Shukutoku
from Fukuoka to zero in the third round.
As far as I remember, Shukutoku had won all their
previous matches with a crushing advantage.
And they beat such
a strong team to zero?
The Rinsen's team has become very strong
ever since Todoroki Jun became their coach.
If I'm not mistaken,
in college, their trainer, Todoroki Jun…
That's right. He was an attacker along with Daisuke
Hara, the current coach of Tachibana High School,
and at one time both of them
qualified for the national team.
I didn't know that
our professor was so amazing!
Please take a look. The camera shows
a close up on trainer Todoroki.
It's him! That's the man
who's been filming us from hiding.
So these recordings were to be used
by Rinsen, to aid them in their training.
Rinsen is said to use computers
to develop their strategies.
You don't say? Computers?
Apparently they simulate opponents' moves and
know how the game will go before it even starts.
Interesting.
Computers…
That explains a lot. They want to analyze
our playing style with a computer.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the match is starting.
Set ball for Rinsen!
Rinsen's beautiful spike
leaves no room for compromise.
Jōmon is playing a feint!
Jōmon played an unexpected feint,
but Rinsen somehow predicted it!
No matter what Jōmon tries to do,
Rinsen is not surprised.
Jōmon plays an aggressive spike!
Rinsen receives it lazily!
Rinsen's defense
is truly like no other.
Jōmon can't break through
Rinsen's defense.
Every their attack
is reflected with ease.
Jōmon players
are tired and frustrated.
Now that they have managed to tire
their opponent, Rinsen is on the offensive.
Jōmon players are unable
to defend themselves.
It's hard to watch.
Let's hope our match
won't look similar tomorrow.
What are you talking about?
We've come too far to lose now.
But yeah…
Oh, it's you, sir.
Sir, Rinsen knows everything
about our game.
It's likely that we'll end up
like Jōmon today.
What to do?
Hijiri. Remind me,
what's our goal in this championship.
Well, it's to win…
So we just have to do our best
and worry only about Shijōdōri.
Don't let anything else distract you.
But, sir…
I have to leave for a moment.
Hijiri, start the training without me.
Yes, sir…
Shijōdōri.
"Light" and "shadow".
Let's listen to the coach for now and focus
on training. It won't hurt, that's for sure.
Yeah!
You're doing pretty good.
Ah, it's you, sir. Good day.
Where can I find Hara?
I'm afraid I can't help you.
He went out without telling us where.
Eh, that sucks. I have only a moment,
then I have to get back to work.
If you'd like to leave him
a message, I can gladly pass it on.
Yes, I think I can trust you.
Come on, let's take a little walk.
I met Todoroki yesterday.
Do you mean the trainer of
Rinsen Technical School?
Yes, precisely.
Hara, Todoroki and I belonged
to the same volleyball club in college.
To the same club?
Yes. But to be honest, I couldn't
compare with them at all.
Anyway, imagine that Todoroki
showed me his computers.
Rinsen has a sister school in Tōkyō.
That's where they carry out their secret training.
And now, the "lightning"!
Good heavens…
So, what do you think of it, Fuwa?
This is a perfect defense
against the "lightning".
Now, double spike!
The best part is the thing
he told me at the end.
That he doesn't care
if I tell Hara about it.
He must be very confident.
Then he said one more thing.
"This time, I will prove to Hara
the superiority of computers."
"This time"?
Todoroki suggested using
computer modeling in college already.
But Hara…
How did he take it?
He claimed that sport is for people,
from beginning to end.
When you start using machines,
it ceases being sport.
Finally, that man will always
triumph over the machine.
That difference of opinion
divided our team.
We decided to resolve
our dispute through a match.
It didn't go very well.
That's how Todoroki lost his hand.
Hara felt responsible and
declined invitations to many teams,
deciding to become
a teacher instead.
I had no idea about any of this…
What did you want to tell me, Hara?
Do you really think it could change anything?
Spit it out already!
Todoroki, we are not in college anymore.
We are now coaches of our teams.
Let us leave the past behind
and play a civilized game.
"Let's leave the past behind"?
What, maybe my hand should
also forget what you did to it?
Because of you not only I was forced
to give up on playing volleyball,
but I became a cripple.
No…
You can't imagine how much
you destroyed my life.
Since that game, I've lived every day cultivating
my hatred for you and planning my revenge.
I have nothing against your computers.
But understand what I just told you.
Those kids count on us.
Caring for them is our duty.
They're not the tools
to settle personal grudges.
Tools?
Yes. Do you even look
at your players at all?
Each day, they more and more resemble tools.
No emotions, no feelings.
And that's how it's supposed to be.
In our computerized training there is
no room for such nonsense as emotions.
Hara, I'll gladly listen to your
lectures, but after the match.
And I'll do it only if your team wins.
I can't wait
for the match tomorrow.
Ladies and gentlemen,
in a few moments the match between
Tachibana High School and
Rinsen Technical School will start.
Rinsen, who plays at Interhigh for the first time,
uses cutting-edge computer simulations.
Meanwhile, Tachibana,
although it's also their debut here,
they advanced all the way to the
quarter-finals in the Spring Tournament.
Both teams show a great potential.
Interesting fact, the coaches of both teams
were also rivals at college.
It's a chance to settle
their score from the past.
What game will Todoroki
and Hara show us today?
Yesterday I told you about what
happened between me and Todoroki.
I didn't do it because Hijiri found out
about it from another source.
I already wanted to tell you before.
There should be no secrets between us.
Our goals are the same.
However, I'm asking you not to think
about it now and focus on the game instead.
As I said yesterday, we don't have any
particular tactics against their computers.
But remember that
I deeply believe in you.
I believe that people are
fundamentally better than computers.
Alright, go get them!
Yes, sir!
Let's show them, girls!
Yeah!
Both teams show unforgiving play right from
the start, demonstrating their high level.
It's the "lightning"!
The "lightning" has been blocked!
Double spike!
Double spike gets easily
received as well!
Rinsen · Tachibana
Although the difference in points is still small,
Rinsen inexorably keeps increasing it.
They were just waiting for us
to use our techniques.
It's as plain as day, but I don't care.
Nothing works against them.
How to break them?
Where is their weak point?
Rinsen · Tachibana
Rinsen quickly increases
their advantage!
I have to applaud you, Todoroki.
However, computers have
a fundamental flaw.
Their weakness is the inability
to create new solutions.
Solutions such as the "V attack".
If possible, I'd like to keep the "V attack"
until the last game against Shijōdōri.
What's more, it can't be said yet
that Hijiri has fully mastered this technique.
Hijiri and Ichijō jump at once!
It's the "lightning"!
What a shame!
The "lightning" gets blocked again.
Rinsen completely sees through Tachibana.
The girls are in a very difficult situation.
Rinsen scores a point with a block
and finishes the first set!
You can see that
Tachibana is already tired.
Is it Rinsen who is going
to win this quarter-final?
Rinsen · Tachibana
Rinsen, who won the first set
with the score of 15 to 6,
retained the advantage in the second set, too.
The score is already 11 to 4.
New double spike!
Not even this Tachibana's
technique has any effect!
Women's Technical School Rinsen
mercilessly increases their advantage.
Rinsen · Tachibana
Who would've thought that Tachibana would have
such problems after such good results in spring.
Took the words right out of my mouth. Rinsen's
simulations' effectiveness is awe-inspiring.
Yeah! This is it.
Todoroki used computer simulations
also in our last match in college.
My most effective attack
was the one where I lost my balance.
Timeout!
Ladies and gentlemen,
Coach Hara asks for a break!
Sir…
Nothing's working on them!
If it goes on, we'll lose.
We haven't lost yet.
But, sir…
Relax, girls. The computer
only understands data from the past.
It's the man who invents new things,
not the machine.
New things?
The "V attack"!
Exactly.
But if we burn it now, we won't have
anything left for the match against Shijōdōri.
Plus I'm afraid that
I still haven't fully mastered it.
And that's why we'll use it.
Play the "V attack"
at a 30-degree angle.
That way, Shijōdōri won't be
able to see it very well.
It should be enough to confuse Rinsen,
even if it's not perfect.
After all, their computers
have no idea about the "V attack".
Very well, sir.
Let's try to do it this way.
We resume the game.
Will Rinsen keep their advantage
and advance to the semi-finals?
Good. The end is near.
Which one?
Ladies and gentlemen,
Hijiri played an unknown technique!
What… What was that!?
Hijiri surprises yet again
with graceful acrobatics in the air
and recovers the ball for her team.
Damn it!
Sport is really unpredictable.
This one move by Hijiri completely
confused Rinsen Technical School.
Tachibana does not hesitate and quickly makes up
for the earlier losses with their new technique.
Rinsen · Tachibana
Tachibana wins the second set!
All right! Keep it up!
Sir!
Well done, girls.
Keep it up in the third set.
Yes, sir!
In a way, people are
less perfect than computers.
However, people have something
that machines will never possess.
Yes, sir!
– Sir…
– How could the computer be wrong?
The computer is never wrong.
Listen to me.
We must remain calm.
Get rid of your emotions.
Be like ice.
Rinsen · Tachibana
We move on to the third set.
Hijiri's spike scores a point!
15 to 4!
Tachibana wins the third set!
Tachibana defeats Rinsen
and advances to the semi-finals.
Sir…
Hara!
Hara. I admit defeat.
It's embarrassing, but I think it's only now that
I fully understood what real volleyball is.
Until now, I thought that the perfect game
requires getting rid of personal feelings.
From the beginning I trained my players
to make them work like gears in a machine.
However, when we lost,
the girls started to cry.
When I saw their tears, they seemed
very precious in a peculiar way.
Computers are unable
to shed tears.
Todoroki…
I will start training my players from scratch,
this time using different methods.
It looks like you and I will never
be able to part ways with volleyball.
Yes.
Good luck in the rest
of the matches.
The girls' tension was replaced by serenity,
pure as the blue sky above them.
Their next goal was the semi-finals,
followed by winning the championships.
We only have the six of you. When even one
of you gets injured, it'll be our end.
Are you sure you're okay?
Are you alright?
Everything's fine.
Next time I will succeed.
We meet the Daisetsuzan Academy again,
who wants to pay us back with a new technique.
However, before our match begins,
Ichijō-san injures her right arm.
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"Now or Never".
See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offensive
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death