kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 23: Looking to the future
Winning the Interhigh Championships
is the dream of every team in Japan,
and Tachibana High School's
Volleyball Team is no exception.
Mimi and her friends managed to overcome
the biggest obstacle in this year's final
and develop a technique for accepting the "light"
and "shadow" of Shijōdōri High School.
However, the friendship Mimi feels for Asuka
has put the team in a difficult situation.
What's more, Mimi herself
feels doubts creeping into her heart,
and is currently unable
to lead her team like a real captain.
Fusejima-kun…
Grandma… Tsuyuki.
What should I do?
Ichijō-san!
Your dream is to play for
the Musashi Steel Group's team.
And today their director
is watching us!
Tachibana · Shijōdōri
The first set is won by Shijōdōri
with a score of 15 to 11.
Yamanaka-san, why Ichijō Asuka is the only one
who's attacking in the Tachibana team?
I have no idea, but I'm more worried
that Hijiri-kun seems to be nervous.
After all, she's
the heart of her team.
Her aggravation
means nothing good.
What the hell is this?
Why do you keep passing to Ichijō-kun?!
Hijiri-chan!
Have you got your wires crossed?!
I'm sorry, but I won't let anyone
sling mud at my granddaughter.
Mimi is poor and all by herself.
On the court, everything's on her.
But ma'am, I didn't mean…
It'll be fine.
Hijiri-kun will alright, I'm sure of it.
Thanks to the efforts of Nishi, Ōta and Sekiya,
we were able to completely break their offensive.
Hijiri, what's the matter with you?
Your attacks are all the same.
It doesn't matter. Ichijō-san's spike
is enough to defeat them.
Don't be silly, Mimi.
Even I would be able to deal with
Ichijō-san's attacks in this match.
Hijiri-san. You know well that
the coach and Sugihara-san are right.
In the next set we should play
the "lightning" and double spike,
and maybe Tomiko's spike.
No, you can't give in like that!
Sir, maybe we could add
the "V attack" to Ichijō-san's spike?
Please tell me what
you think about this.
It's way too early
for the "V attack".
But why?
Mimi, you wanted to know
what the coach thought about it.
I hope you didn't ask
just to argue with it now.
We play the "lightning".
Finally!
For heaven's sake.
Right, ma'am?
Tachibana
Something has finally awakened
in the Tachibana's team.
Shijōdōri
Considering that Shijōdōri's "light" and "shadow"
no longer impresses their three-man defense,
Yamanaka-san, how do you assess
Tachibana's chances of winning?
I admit that Tachibana
at times looks promising,
but we must remember that
it was Shijōdōri who won the first set.
Let's also not forget
about Hijiri-kun's mental state.
Something is troubling her,
though I can't tell what that is.
Spike is the essence of volleyball.
Ichijō-san won't
achieve anything like that.
Yukari!
Listen, we'll play to Ichijō-san.
Let's play a new double spike
in the next service.
Mimi, why did you insist
on playing to Ichijō-san?
I'm asking you, Yukari.
No way. Her hand hasn't
even fully healed yet.
Okay, forget it.
I'll never ask you for anything again.
We're no longer friends.
What? Are you
out of your mind, Mimi?
Mimi, you better get ready!
Thank you, Yukari.
See, I told you
it wasn't a good idea.
Let's try again, please.
Ichijō-san…
Don't give up your dreams.
I believe in you.
Tachibana · Shijōdōri
Tachibana has been
completely worked out!
Shijōdōri easily deflects
every attack of Ichijō Asuka.
Here we go again…
Hijiri-chan, what are you doing?
Yes, yes. Gee, you can't
say anything these days.
Anyway, good luck!
Hijiri-kun is trying
to help Ichijō-san…
But she neglects herself
and the rest of the team.
Good luck, Hijiri-chan!
Let me have that flag for a bit.
I'll try to cheer on them, too.
Go! Go! Tachibana!
I will not let Ichijō-san
ruin her dream.
Ichijō-san!
Tachibana · Shijōdōri
Hijiri, I expect some explanation.
Sir, Mimi…
No! It's my fault.
Please don't blame Hijiri-san.
I have eyes. Hijiri is entirely
responsible for this farce.
Hijiri. Stop this self-pity.
You know what I mean.
If not, I'll tell you.
You want to make Ichijō's dream come true,
so you try to get the audience's attention to it.
But in reality, it's you who wants
to join the Musashi's team.
But you can't, because of
the situation in your family.
That's why you quietly
projected your dream onto Ichijō.
But instead of helping her, you're ruining her.
Your selfish actions put the entire team in a bind.
Mimi!
Hijiri-san…
I'm sorry.
I… I…
Mimi, you don't have
to say anything.
It's all right.
Everything's fine, okay?
Look, it's no use
to cry over spilled milk.
Let's play this last high school game as friends
and show them that we are the best.
Captain!
We will also give our best.
– You can count on us.
– Exactly.
Girls…
Thank you.
– Come on, Mimi.
– Don't cry.
Let's show them who's the boss.
Shijōdōri must now think
I'm our main attacker.
I'll attract their attention
by marking offensive.
In the meantime,
you'll be scoring points for us.
Ichijō-san…
Tachibana · Shijōdōri
Ichijō-san, you are amazing.
Tachibana introduced
some variety to its tactics.
Yamanaka-san, Hijiri Mimi's doubts
seem to have vanished somewhere.
Yes. I really like this
new Ichijō Asuka tactic.
Abandoning the spotlights for the team's sake
is a rare and commendable feat.
What a surprise!
Ichijō's tactics go so far that she gives up
her the new double spike to Sugihara!
Yamanaka-san, you often say that
in volleyball, the team is one.
Ichijō's actions today
strongly match these words.
Yes. Ichijō Asuka…
Mom…
Mom.
Save us, Dad.
No one else can save her!
Ichijō lost her mother in that fire.
It instilled in her distrust
and deep aversion to people.
Today you have
overcome it, Ichijō.
Know that your coach
is very proud of you.
Tachibana · Shijōdōri
Tachibana wins the third set!
Keep it up, keep it up, Tachibana!
Oh? There is some
commotion on the court!
Ladies and gentlemen,
something unbelievable has happened.
Just before the start
of the fourth set
Shijōdōri replaced the entire team,
not sparing even the Katsura sisters!
Matsumoto's coach made a bold,
but well thought-out move.
Unlike Shijōdōri's new lineup,
Tachibana struggles with fatigue.
It's the same as in
the Spring Tournament.
Shijōdōri will now definitely
show some new technique.
Looks like Shijōdōri intends
to give up on the fourth set
and bet everything
on the final fifth set.
Tachibana · Shijōdōri
Of course I can't speak
for Matsumoto,
but I bet his goal is to take
advantage of Tachibana's fatigue.
He's perfectly aware that "light" and "shadow"
alone are not enough to beat Tachibana.
Coach Hara knows it just as well.
Sir, everything goes like in spring.
Please, let us play the "V attack"!
Calm down.
I know you're tired.
Patience. Hold on a little longer!
If you get impatient, we've already lost.
But everything has its limits…
Wait, Yukari.
The coach must first see what
Shijōdōri has prepared for us.
I'll be blunt. I'm worried about
their No. 11, Akiyoshi Megumi.
I suspect she's their secret weapon,
just like Katsura Shigemi was in spring.
For now, the plan is not to let
any "light" or "shadow" to pass through.
If they see that their main techniques
are of no use, they'll have to use No. 11.
We can't play the "V attack"
even a second before.
Coach is right.
Let's have patience.
By showing the "V attack" we'll give them time
to find gaps in it and everything will be in vain.
Hold on a bit longer.
The counters of both teams were reset
and the main dial now displays number 5.
Time for the final set of this year's
Interhigh Championships.
Oh no! They attack Kimiko!
Our weakest player!
Tachibana · Shijōdōri
Timeout!
Maybe we should play
the "V attack" after all.
Bad idea. Remember what the coach said.
Patience. We must endure!
Ichijō-san feints no longer have any effect!
What do you suggest?
What do you say
about feinting a feint?
What?
Tachibana · Shijōdōri
They still don't want
to let her come out.
Patience, girls.
Almost there!
Tachibana · Shijōdōri
Timeout. Player change.
Now it makes sense!
Akiyoshi Megumi…
A great offensive!
I didn't even see very well
what actually happened…
No. 11 camouflaged
the "light" and "shadow".
I'm interested
in the reaction of Coach Hara.
He has a really big fish to fry.
What do we do now, sir?
Tachibana · Shijōdōri
Timeout!
It's time for the "V attack".
We'll do it like this…
Keep it up, keep it up, Tachibana!
Show them, Mimi!
Everything for the day
called tomorrow.
Tomorrow.
Another amazing technique!
An attack I've never seen before, that makes
it also possible to defend half the court!
This is my attack.
This is my attack…
Attack on tomorrow!
Tachibana · Shijōdōri
Long live the Tachibana
High School's Volleyball Club!
Long live!
Congratulations, girls.
Thank you!
Ichijō-kun, special
congratulations to you.
Excuse me?
I just finished interviewing
Director Yamanaka of Musashi Steel Group.
He told me that he'd love
to see you on their team.
I think he confused me
with Hijiri-san.
No. He spoke specifically about you
and the Katsura sisters of Shijōdōri.
Ichijō-san, I'm so glad that
your dream came true.
But… it's you who should…
No.
I love volleyball.
Nothing changes.
I'll always play it, wherever I go.
Hara-kun.
My congratulations.
Thank you so much, Yamanaka-san.
I really liked your game, Ichijō-san.
From today you and I
play on the same team.
Yes! You don't even know
how happy I am!
By the way, I was just talking to
the Japanese Volleyball Federation.
Hijiri-kun.
They suggest that you
join the national team.
What do you think?
What?!
Mimi!
Hijiri-san!
Sister!
I knew from the start
that it'd end this way.
Mimi, don't you dare turn them down!
You'll be able to keep playing.
Grandma…
Tsuyuki!
This will be
my attack on tomorrow!
Today is calmly coming to an end.
However, before Mimi
and her friends
now extends something much more
magnificent: the day called tomorrow.
Mimi will not rest, looking
to the future wherever she goes.
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offensive
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death