kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 22:
The Last Game
In the second game of
this year's Interhigh semi-finals
Ryūsei High School from Nagasaki
will face Shijōdōri High School from Kyōtō.
Ebihara Saori of Ryūsei is known for her
unique technique called the "dragon attack".
Today we will see how it works against
the "light" and "shadow" of the Katsura sisters.
Which of these two great teams will meet
Tachibana in the finals tomorrow?
Shijōdōri · Ryūsei
It was a new, improved
"dragon attack".
They significantly improved it
compared to the spring variant.
Most likely, Shijōdōri's techniques
didn't remain unchanged, either.
It goes without saying.
I'm surprised why your girls
aren't watching this match.
Well…
Sorry, sir, but we'd prefer
to work out a bit more.
If possible, we'd like to ask you
to arrange a hall for us.
Watching this match is pointless.
No matter who wins, Shijōdōri or Ryūsei,
the finals will be very difficult, anyway.
It's as you always tell us.
We just have to do our job.
That's why we want to train and
do the final touches with the "V attack".
We want you to be
proud of us tomorrow.
We believe that the best is to
keep training until the last moment.
This is, in fact, our last chance
to achieve something in high school.
We want to remember this period well.
Please, let us train some more.
Hijiri preferred to keep working
on her jumping technique
while Ichijō and Sugihara simulate
the "light" and "shadow",
so that the rest could learn
how to receive it.
Wait, that's…
It's the "light" and "shadow". You've already
seen them. Nothing has changed since spring.
No, I was talking
about something else.
Look at their bench.
No. 11, next to Coach Matsumoto.
Whenever Ryūsei's
"dragon attack" scores a point,
No. 11 gets up and nervously talks
with Matsumoto about something.
I suspect she's asking him
why he doesn't let her play.
In turn, he remains
completely adamant.
It was the same in the
Spring Tournament.
Shijōdōri eventually won back then. They used
Katsura Haruka's "light" the whole tournament
and let Katsura Shigemi play her "darkness"
only when they had no other choice.
So they have some secret weapon ready on
the bench again, and this time it is player No. 11.
I think so.
That's enough for today.
It's better to finish now, or tomorrow
we'll be too tired to play.
At last.
I'd eat something already.
I'm exhausted.
At the end you got it right, Mimi.
It was perfectly 45°.
I think so, too. The question is
if I can do the same tomorrow.
And how did it go for you, girls?
Pretty good. Right, Ichijō-san?
I guess, but I'm not sure if we'll be able
to receive their real attacks.
By the way, Ichijō-san,
how's your hand?
All good.
See, it's like new.
Ichijō-san, it's not nice
to lie like that.
Let me guess.
You are on an anesthetic injection.
Excuse me,
but who are you, ma'am?
You must be Captain Hijiri-san, right?
I am Ōhara Ritsuko.
I was watching your game
with Daisetsuzan yesterday.
Ichijō-san's unusual play
made me worry.
I asked at your hotel and
they told me I'd find you here.
I don't want to interfere too much,
but I thought I'd advise you.
Ichijō-san, are you sure
your hand is all right?
Excuse me?
To tell you the truth,
I went through something similar.
This took place right after
I was selected for the Olympics.
I really wanted to improve my jump,
so I trained harder than usual.
But as luck would have it, during
these exercises I sprained my ankle.
I started thinking about the worst. I couldn't go
to the Olympics with a sprained ankle.
It started to bother me a lot, to the point
that I started to tell myself things.
The ankle should've healed long ago,
and it was still hurting.
Today I know that everything
was only in my head.
Ichijō-san, don't you think
it's the same for you?
You're afraid that you won't join my team
because of a dislocated wrist
and you'll bury your chances of a career
as a professional attacker. Did I get that right?
At the end of the match against Daisetsuzan,
all I was thinking about was the victory.
But you're right, ma'am.
I felt terrible pressure, that's true.
I was afraid that I wouldn't
be able to join your team.
Ichijō-san…
Sorry for everything.
You don't have to worry anymore.
Ōhara-san's words helped me
identify and tame my fears.
It doesn't hurt anymore.
– Ichijō-san!
– Thank goodness!
Thank you.
That's all I wanted to say.
Good luck at tomorrow's finals.
I'll be watching you.
Thank you.
We'll give our best!
Thank you so much.
See you soon.
Oh boy, it's tomorrow already!
To think that we're graduating
from school right after Interhigh.
Yeah.
Mimi, have you decided what to do?
No. I still have no idea.
What about you, Yukari?
I'm going to study in Yokohama.
Mom's sending me there. She says
it's too early for me to be a bride.
And you, Ichijō-san? What are you going to do
after you let go of the Musashi Steel Group?
I may have let go of Musashi,
but I didn't let go of volleyball.
We've come too far.
I can't imagine my future
without volleyball.
At the end of high school, my adventure
with volleyball will come to an end.
I have to take care
of Grandma and Tsuyuki.
I can't just go and do what I like.
Oh, it's you, sir!
Good morning!
Hello.
So, how did it end?
Shijōdōri won.
So it was as we thought.
Did they show any new techniques?
Ryūsei played
a new "dragon attack",
but Shijōdōri shattered them
with their "light" and "shadow".
So Shijōdōri used the same
techniques as in spring.
Yes.
That's a relief.
I'm not even convinced that we can
handle the "light" and "shadow".
I dread to think what would happen
if they added something else.
Yeah.
Exactly.
I wanted to talk to you about your training
in receiving these techniques.
When I saw them live today,
something occurred to me.
We must always be ready to accept them,
no matter what combination they play.
Combination?
Exactly.
When they mix both of these techniques,
it'll be devilishly hard to see through them.
That's why we have to make them play
one particular technique when we want it.
I don't know about this.
Is that even possible?
Force an opponent
to play the way we like?
No way.
It has a chance to work,
all we need is a perfect timing.
In the case of "light",
the ball flies further than usual
and you have to run up
to the outside of the court.
In turn, in the case of "darkness" the ball usually
falls just behind the net, so you have to dive.
We'll provoke them by feinting
corresponding receptions.
Right. Of course! By approaching the grid,
we encourage them to target the second line.
And by approaching the border of the court,
we encourage them to play inside.
That's brilliant in its simplicity.
There's no way it could fail.
Kimiko, you speak as if it was you
who had come up with this plan.
Let's suppose that we can accept
the "light" and "shadow".
Is this really enough?
Somehow I don't believe
that they've wasted all this time between
the Spring Tournament and Interhigh.
That wouldn't be like
the Katsura sisters.
What if the coach
is keeping something from us?
We meet again.
Yes. We haven't forgotten our defeat
at the Spring Tournament
and we've been training hard
to face you again.
Hijiri-san, we knew from the beginning
that we'd face you in the finals.
Really?
Oh, it's Mr. Yamanaka,
the director of the Musashi Steel Group.
Director Yamanaka is said
to appear on air today.
Me and my sister dream
about getting into their team.
We've even talked
to them about it.
I understand.
As usual, you talk too much,
Shigemi. Let's go now.
Yeah, yeah. I'll only add that
we're going to give our best today.
See you on the court, Hijiri-san.
See you soon.
Press room
So, did you find out
something, Fuwa?
As usual, your hunch
has proven accurate.
No. 11: Akiyoshi Megumi
No. 11, Akiyoshi Megumi,
a second grade student.
From the beginning of the championship,
she didn't move an inch from the bench.
So she's their secret weapon,
just as Katsura Shigemi was in spring.
Yes, without a doubt.
But something puzzles me here.
What?
According to our branch in Kyōtō,
Akiyoshi Megumi was originally a gymnast.
Apparently she joined the volleyball club
right after winning the Spring Tournament.
A gymnast?
The Katsura sisters, Ichijō-san and
even Yukari have it all figured out.
Only I'm so dull.
I want to go to university like Fusejima-kun.
I also want to play volleyball like Ichijō-san.
But I can't. I can't get
my family out of my mind.
Sister!
Hey.
Tsuyuki! Grandma?
Grandma, what are you doing here?
I met Fusejima-kun on the train
and we've decided to pay you a visit.
Thank you, Fusejima-kun.
Can you imagine that he came out of the books
specifically to support you today?
I'm sorry, but isn't it better for you
to study for exams?
No, everything's fine.
I wanted to take one day off from studying
and finally have some life.
I'm going to scream like a little boy today
and not think about anything.
I understand.
Thank you for coming.
What's going on, Hijiri-kun?
You look down.
Ah, no, it's all right.
To tell you the truth, I talked a bit
with your grandmother on the train.
You are still wondering whether to pursue
your education or go looking for a job.
She's always worrying about me and Tsuyuki,
but it won't occur to her to worry about herself.
I don't want to talk
about this again.
I want to live with you,
end of the story.
You can see how stubborn she is.
We'd better take seats.
Yes, good idea. We'll give you
a moment for yourselves.
Good luck, Sis.
Thanks.
Fusejima-kun,
I'd better go get ready, too.
You're such an egoist, Hijiri-kun!
Egoist?
Yes, you heard that right.
You think you're the only one so unhappy.
You can't see beyond
the tip of your nose.
Do you think I'm doing so good? I want to do
so much in my life and I have to keep cramming.
Nothing but exams and exams.
Everything leaks between my fingers.
But unlike you, I never
considered myself unlucky.
Of course, I also am human.
There are times when I want to just
throw it all to hell. To live here and now.
In fact, I came here today
because I had one such moment.
Live here and now?
Yes. However, this kind
of thinking is limited.
After today comes tomorrow.
Hijiri-kun, stop fooling yourself and using
your grandmother and brother as excuses.
Better think what your
tomorrow will look like.
– Fusejima-kun…
– Mimi!
It's time!
The match is about to start.
I'll be there soon.
Fusejima-kun, will you support us?
Yes! Good luck!
See you later.
I'll try to be more ready
for tomorrow.
Go, go, Tachibana!
There can only be one. Shijōdōri!
Today is the last match of this year's
Interhigh Championships.
Shijōdōri, the undisputed winner of the Spring
Tournament known for the "light" and "shadow"
will play with Tachibana, known for the "lightning"
and many other innovative techniques,
and only has six people
on their team.
Do you have any favorite
in today's meeting, Yamanaka-san?
It is difficult to say anything, as both teams
have developed a lot in a short time.
It is true that Shijōdōri beat Tachibana
in the Spring Tournament quarter-finals,
but three months
have passed since then.
The question is how much both teams
have developed during this time.
This is a very important factor.
There can only be one. Shijōdōri!
Shijōdōri!
Go, go, Tachibana!
Tachibana!
Just you watch, Fusejima-kun.
I will show you that I am able
to welcome tomorrow with a smile.
Today we will win, and then we will join
the team of the Musashi Steel Group.
Ichijō-san.
Ready and waiting.
I won't let Ichijō-san
lose my dreams.
I know!
Director Yamanaka
is watching today's meeting.
Ichijō-san has a one-in-a-million
chance to get his attention.
If all goes well, maybe they would
even take her to the Musashi team.
– Let's rock it today!
– Well said!
Go, go, Tachibana!
"Light"!
Tachibana · Shijōdōri
The first surprise! Before, only Hijiri Mimi was able
to receive the attack of the Katsura sisters,
and today it's the whole team.
We have the first point of the match.
"Light"…
It's "light"!
I've got it!
Good! Keep it up!
Keep it up!
Tomiko!
Timeout!
Tachibana · Shijōdōri
I have to say, I'm shocked!
I would've never thought
it could go so well.
It's a hundred times better
than I expected.
The match has just begun.
Heads getting swelled already?
You've barely scored a few points.
Yes, sir!
Hijiri, your attacks are a little too monotonous.
If only Ichijō spikes, they'll eventually use it.
Everything will be fine. Shijōdōri
now focuses on "light" and "shadow".
I'm worried about something else.
Sir, I feel like Shijōdōri is holding
some ace up their sleeve, just like in spring.
Hijiri, worrying about stuff is my duty.
You'd better focus on the game.
I didn't expect that. What do you say,
Yamanaka-san? Is the result already determined?
Not at all.
Tachibana is in a bad situation.
What do you mean?
They have an undeniable advantage in points.
Their offensive is too monotonous.
Go, go, Tachibana!
There can only be one. Shijōdōri!
The coach is hiding
something from us.
Shijōdōri is not worried about
that loss at all. I have bad feelings.
Hijiri is worried about something.
Grandma… Tsuyuki…
What to do?
Fusejima-kun…
Tell me what to do.
Mimi's ambition to make Asuka's dream
come true causes problems for the team.
At the same time, Mimi is confronted with
doubts about how she can face the future.
Will Mimi manage
to overcome her crisis?
The climax of the Interhigh
Championships is just around the corner.
It's time to start
playing the "V attack"!
No. It's too early.
But if it goes on, we will lose!
The coach's right.
We're too nervous.
We're losing control!
We throw everything we have against Shijōdōri
so that we don't regret anything.
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"Looking to the Future".
See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offensive
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death