kaze wa nannimo iwanai keredo
I've been wandering in the dark
for the longest time
shiroi bōru to aoi kōto ga
But the white ball and the blue court,
kitto watashi ni oshietekureru
such simple things,
yet they give my life meaning
ashita to iu hi wa donna iro
They show me
where I'll be tomorrow
yume to iu mono donna iro
They show me
where my dreams are
dakara dakara
And that's why,
and that's why
hitai ni ase o nijimasete
Though my clothes
are soaked with sweat
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
ashita e ashita e
I'm going on, I'm going on
ashita e atakku
I keep going on,
attacking tomorrow
Attack on Tomorrow!
Episode 21:
Now or Never
The quarter-finals of the Interhigh.
Defeating Rinsen Technical School,
the girls from Tachibana High School
have proven that a computer
can not match a human being.
Some teams are left behind,
the others are moving forward.
The court is a witness
to many dramas.
What dramas will our girls
have to face tomorrow?
Locker room of the
Tachibana High School's team
In spring, we've dropped out in the quarter-finals.
This time we reached the semi-finals.
Play without holding back,
so that you won't regret anything later.
I'm just asking you,
be careful not to hurt yourself.
We only have the six of you.
When even one of you gets injured,
it'll be our end.
Each of you must be very careful.
Yes, sir!
Yes, sir.
Locker room of the
Tachibana High School's team
It was Ōhara Ritsuko.
Captain of the Musashi Steel Group's team.
They represented us
at the last Olympics!
She probably came here
looking for fresh talent.
Fresh talent?
Yes. I heard they're looking for new players.
They probably hope to find someone here.
Do you think I could
get their attention?
Not in this life.
Ōhara Ritsuko…
Captain of the Musashi Steel Group.
Ichijō Asuka?
That Tachibana High School's attacker?
Yes, ma'am.
After graduating, I would like
to start playing professionally.
Could you consider
making me part of your team?
I saw your game and I think
that you are pretty good at attack.
But to be honest, I doubt you'll be ready
to play professionally at this stage.
I am absolutely convinced
that it would work out.
I guarantee that I would not let you down.
Please, let me prove what I can do.
Fine. Let's see what you can do,
if you insist so much.
Yes, ma'am!
A pass to Fukuhara Yōko!
A point for Daisetsuzan!
What ruthlessness! The attack of Captain
Fukuhara Yōko is second to none.
Her two-handed attack has significantly
improved since the Spring Tournament.
That last ball was a bit light.
This time it will be stronger.
What happened?
It's nothing.
Everything is all right.
That's okay then.
Ichijō-san.
Yes?
Looks like you have the talent
and the courage we need.
I can't promise anything, but I'd like
to talk again after the championships.
For real? Of course!
Don't stop training.
Yes, ma'am!
Hotel
Daisetsuzan went through them like butter.
They're really dangerous.
I guess, but in my opinion,
there's nothing to worry about, really.
Right, captain?
Yes. Apart from improving both-handed attack,
they didn't demonstrate any new techniques.
But still…
What?
It'll be fine, I'm telling you.
Right, Sugihara-san?
What? Ah yes, sure.
I'm worried that Ichijō-san is late.
Where could she go?
We only have the six of you.
When even one of you gets injured,
it'll be our end.
What's going on, Ichijō-san?
You didn't come to the training.
We were waiting for you, but you didn't
come back, so I went looking for you.
Where were you?
I'm sorry.
It was nothing important.
Let's go to the hotel.
Okay…
Hotel
What if it was something serious?
What will the girls say?
They trained so hard,
and I'm about to drag them down.
Shijōdōri High School from Kyōtō.
Ryūsei High School from Nagasaki.
Daisetsuzan Academy from Hokkaidō.
Finally, Tachibana High School from Kanagawa.
These four great teams will face
each other in the semi-finals.
Only three games left
until the end of the Interhigh.
Show them what
you've got, Tachibana!
You can do it!
The first semi-final match will be played
between Daisetsuzan and Tachibana.
Daisetsuzan can boast
overwhelming power.
Will the improved two-handed attack
of Captain Fukuhara Yōko
be enough to erase
the shame from spring?
Tachibana, who has great teamwork,
the "lightning",
double spike and other techniques
pose a great danger.
Which of these two giants will qualify
for the finals: Daisetsuzan or Tachibana?
The match begins!
It hurts even more than yesterday.
I don't think I broke anything.
If I broke my wrist, I can kiss
goodbye the professional career.
Hijiri-san!
Nice to see you again, Hijiri-san.
I'm happy to see you, too.
As promised,
we've developed a new technique.
Today I'm going to show it.
Good. I wouldn't have it
any other way.
We've prepared this technique
especially for a match with you.
We won't go soft on you,
either. Good luck.
Whatever they came up with,
we have nothing to fear.
At our current level,
we can handle them easily.
They seem to give their best.
But something is wrong with Ichijō.
She took a defensive position.
It's the "lightning"!
There goes the first "lightning"!
The "lightning" failed!
How did this happen?
Hijiri and Ichijō have played it so many times.
How could they do such a basic mistake?
Ichijō-san!
Ichijō-san! What's up?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
I slipped during the jump.
Something's wrong here.
It wasn't just a slip.
Ichijō protected her right hand.
Is everything okay, Ichijō-san?
Are you sure you're alright?
Everything's fine.
Next time I will succeed.
Let's get back to the game.
Yeah!
This time Ichijō is playing
the "lightning" to Hijiri!
Wha… With her left hand?!
Hijiri loses the opportunity to spike,
but somehow launches an attack from below!
Fukuhara jumps!
Will we see a new technique?
My goal…
…is right there.
What… What was that?
Fukuhara Yōko's incredible attack
hits the court on the Tachibana side.
Sekiya and Kimiko didn't even flinch.
The attack practically grazed the line.
I'd call this technique
the "sniper attack".
Fukuhara Yōko squeezed a highly
curved ball right in front of the line.
Also noteworthy is the play of Ichijō Asuka,
which was done with her left hand.
My attacks hit the target
down to the millimeter.
And now, I have found
a very interesting target.
I have to admit,
it's an astounding spike.
But what is going on
with Ichijō-san today?
Daisetsuzan · Tachibana
Fukuhara Yōko's "sniper attacks"
score one point after another.
Tachibana failed
to get even one so far.
Curiously, Ichijō Asuka completely
stopped playing with her right hand.
Both double spikes and the "lightning"
lack their usual power.
Daisetsuzan easily
receives both techniques.
Another left-handed play!
Daisetsuzan · Tachibana
Daisetsuzan wins the first set
with a score of 15 to 0.
Sir…
– Sir—
– First, wipe away sweat.
Yes, sir.
Ichijō!
Sir!
You probably realize that this
disastrous result of the first set
is partially thanks to you.
I have nothing to defend myself.
It's evident that you have an injured
right hand. How did this happen?
Ichijō!
Yes, sir.
It happened yesterday.
Ichijō Asuka?
That Tachibana High School's attacker?
Be honest, I doubt you'll be ready
to play professionally at this stage.
I am absolutely convinced
that it would work out.
I guarantee that I would not let you down.
Please, let me prove what I can do.
I wanted Ōhara-san to see
the potential in me so much.
I overdid it.
I've damaged my arm.
All right. I see.
You warned us so much
to be careful.
Yet I did something like that and now
I'm dragging the whole team down. I'm sorry.
No use crying over spilled milk.
Sugihara. Swap with Ichijō.
Yes, sir.
Now I will tell you how we can deal
with the "sniper attack".
Listen carefully.
The purpose of her technique is to point your
attention to the sidelines and to confuse you.
Therefore, just stand near the lines
so that you don't have to run to them.
But we'll only do them
a favor that way.
Exactly, they'll start
playing at the center.
And that's what I'm counting on.
If they decide to play
at the center of our court,
it'll be much easier for you to dive towards the
center of the court from the lines than vice versa.
Oh, right.
Sir, when it comes to reception,
I can use my right hand.
Ichijō-san, all you have
to do is wait.
We'll take care of the rest
and cover you.
But…
I don't want to win a match by force,
if it means sacrificing your dreams.
I totally agree with Mimi.
Don't do anything stupid.
– Exactly.
– Don't risk it.
Girls…
Perfect.
Show them who's in charge.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we're starting the second set.
Tachibana receives
the "sniper attack"!
Sugihara plays a double spike!
And we have a point!
Tachibana finally scores their first point!
That's the way it should be!
Now just win the entire thing!
This time it's Hijiri who spikes!
The new formation of Tachibana, Hijiri and
Sugihara is quickly gaining a lot of ground.
I give up on the second set. But in the next…
Ichijō-san, get ready, because I will target you.
Daisetsuzan · Tachibana
Tachibana wins the second set.
Fukuhara spikes!
Tachibana receives!
The game is now very balanced.
Hijiri and Sugihara never cease
to amaze with their teamwork,
but Daisetsuzan doesn't let up and
plays difficult balls as well.
This is no longer
a battle of techniques.
The match will be won by sheer
stubbornness and fighting spirit.
Hang in there, Hijiri-chan!
A pass to Fukuhara!
Ichijō accepts the ball
with her left hand!
Fukuhara plays at Ichijō again!
She fails to receive!
Another mistake.
Today is not Ichijō's day.
Don't worry, Ichijō-san.
All right! Time to pay them back!
Yeah!
Daisetsuzan · Tachibana
Daisetsuzan continues to torment
Tachibana by playing at Ichijō!
Daisetsuzan · Tachibana
Ladies and gentlemen,
what a meeting!
As soon as Fukuhara Yōko from Daisetsuzan
and her "sniper attack" scores a point,
Tachibana fights back, attacking fiercely
and covering for the obviously injured Ichijō.
The match became a crazy guerrilla fight
for literally every point.
Daisetsuzan · Tachibana
Ichijō-san.
Looks like you have the talent
and the courage we need.
I can't promise anything, but I'd like
to talk again after the championships.
I don't want to win a match by force,
if it means sacrificing your dreams.
I totally agree with Mimi.
Me too.
Exactly.
I will not let us lose,
even if it costs me my career.
I will do anything for
Tachibana and the girls.
I will bet everything
on this one last service!
Ladies and gentlemen,
match ball for Tachibana.
Another pass to Fukuhara!
Ichijō Asuka plays a direct spike!
It scores beautifully!
End of the match!
Daisetsuzan · Tachibana
Tachibana advances to the finals!
What an amazing game.
Full of tension
and unexpected twists.
Daisetsuzan has to
accept defeat again.
That is the nature of sport:
some win, the others lose.
We did it!
Our girls reach the finals
they have dreamed of for so long.
What plan does Mimi have against
the Katsura sisters of Shijōdōri High School?
Also, what about
Asuka's right hand?
Good luck, Tachibana!
You will need it.
Sir, do you know if Shijōdōri
has developed any new techniques?
No, so far they've only used
the "light" and "shadow".
So there's a chance
that we'll win, right?
After the spring defeat, the day to face Shijōdōri
High School from Kyōtō again finally came.
In the next episode of
"Attack on Tomorrow":
"The Last Game".
See you soon!
shiroi bōru ni seishun o
When everything around
is so chaotic
supaiku saseyou RURARUNRUNRARA
I can rely on my spike,
lu-la-lun lun-la-la
goran miteru yo taiyou ga
See, how beautiful the sun is
goran miteru yo aoi sora
See, what a clear sky
mune hazumasete atakku sureba
When I do my best
on offensive
hora kurushii omoi demo
Nothing else matters
minna minna
All the problems
dokoka e dokoka e kieteyuku
They disappear, disappear,
somewhere far away
barē ga suki barē ga suki
I love volleyball,
I love volleyball
barē ga barē ga suki suki suki suki suki
I love volleyball to death