Burst! Burst! Burst! Burst! Burst! Finish!
Burst! Burst! Burst! Beyblade!
Even out on street corners lit by the sunrise,
Asayake ni terasareta machikado de mo
The sounds you hear are Beys clashing somewhere!
Doko kara ka kikoeta oto wa bei no butsukariau shōgeki da ze
Are you all warmed up and ready to go?
Wōmingu appu wa sumasetekita ka?
Blazing hearts are tirelessly burning for battles!
Atsui kokoro wa nemurazu ni shōbu ni kogareteru no sa
Even when you stumble, you can get back up everytime!
Nando tsumazuitemo tachiagareru sa
If you have a rival spurring you both to improve,
Takameaeru raibaru ga iru no naraba
Set your sights on reaching the top upon the greatest arena
Saikō no futai de teppen mezasu tame
and unleash your Shoot right away!
Shūto wo hanatsuze ima sugu ni!
3, 2, 1, Go Shoot!
Beyblade! (Burst!) Beyblade! (Shoot!)
A whole new world awaits!
Aratanaru sekai ga matsu
Battles like you've never seen before!
Mada mita koto nai batoru misetsukete yare
Beyblade! (Burst!) Beyblade! (Shoot!)
With an evolving bond with my partner and quickening heartbeat,
Shinka shi tsuzukeru aibō to no kizuna to takanaru kodō de
Spin faster and clinch the battle with a
Kaiten no sokudo o agete kimeru ze
Burst Finish! (Burst Finish!)
BURST BURST BURST BURST BURST FINISH!
BURST BURST BURST BEYBLADE
BURST BURST BURST 3, 2, 1 GO SHOOT!
BC Sol's Fierce Battle!!
Okay, boys and girls, we're gonna train our muscles!!
Come on! We can't not wait! It's time for Beyxercise 2!
It's more intense than the version 1!
First of all, showtime from last review!
Go shoot!
Go shoot! Heave-ho!
Go shoot! Alright, speed up!
Go shoot! Go shoot!
Feels great, right? Now you've perfected basic shoot!
But it gets harder from here!
Raise your hands and tension!
Go shoot!
Reforge your muscles!
My shoot is godly!
Shoot from the right! Shoot from the left! Shoot, shoot from the right!
Shoot from the left! Shoot from the right! Shoot, shoot from the left!
Last week, this week, I'm doing "go shoot"!
This week, next week, he's also doing "go shoot"!
Every day, practice! Everyone's doing "go shoot"!
Spring, summer, fall, winter, "go shoot" all year round!
Okay! Training every day is necessary to get good muscles!
Time for the last go!
1 · 2 · 3 · 4 · go shoot!
Come on!
Let's go!
1 · 2 · 3 · 4 · go shoot! Let's go!
3, 2, 1 go shoot!
Burst finish!
Nice go shoot!
Nice Beyxercise!
Climax! Great Rival Clash!!