Finally.
Right on mark.
Seira.
Toshiaki-kun!
Ah, good morning.
You're the worst!
Why did you go without me?
Ah…
You didn't come at the usual time,
so I went ahead.
I was just a little bit late.
I'm sorry.
I'll let it slide just for today.
Let's go!
The cultural festival is right around the corner…
Yeah.
It's strange…
What is?
When I was little…
…walking here felt really incredible.
The older girls and boys walking here had this adult vibe around them.
But now that we're older ourselves,
I don't feel like that at all anymore.
Was I there too?
You were! Kazuo was driving us together.
So it's from kindergarten days…
Right.
You don't have any memories from before six years old, Toshiaki-kun…
If it only wasn't for that accident…
Good morning, Megumi!
Ah, morning!
Come on, hurry up!
We'll be late. Let's run!
Today I'm about to introduce a new transfer student…
Tōno Tsukasa
…or rather was about to.
"Was about to"?
What do you mean, Professor?
The transfer student has escaped!
– Huh?!
– For real!?
He's pretty good.
Just what kind of guy he is?
I'll introduce you.
Ah, okay.
Fantasy novel
"I'd like to return to that day"
"I'd like to return to that day"…?
For me, "that day" means only this…
Toshiaki!
Toshiaki…!
Ambulance is on the way.
One child has been hurt.
The reason for the explosion is still unclear.
Amnesia?
Yes.
But his consciousness remains steady.
It's better to teach little by little rather than forcing him to remember.
Toshiaki…
That day…
…I lost my entire self.
I'm borrowing this.
What?
Your stare is awfully intense.
Is my face so unusual?
Uhm…
That book is exempt from issuance.
I can't let you borrow it.
I see.
How disappointing.
But it doesn't resemble him at all.
Huh?
Never mind.
Where can I find the sci-fi section?
Let's see…
It's the third book stand to the right.
Thanks.
Say…
Hm?
Did we meet before?
I don't think so.
You see, I just transferred to school today.
Then you must be Tōno Tsukasa?
You're from the same class?
Nice to meet you.
Toshiaki-kun, let's go home together.
Ah, I'm sorry.
I'm not finished arranging the books yet.
Go without me.
All right then. I still have flute practice.
What kind of relationship do you have
with the librarian guy?
And who are you?
I'm interested in you.
You could call it love at first sight.
See you tomorrow!
But it doesn't resemble him at all.
"Resemble"…
As if he could know how the real man looked like.
Tōno Tsukasa
But he had such nostalgic feeling around him.
Tōno Tsukasa…
Seira, watch out!
Seira!
A dream…?
"Seira"?
And who was that woman?
Why don't we hang around after school?
I can't.
Our acting club has music practice.
Why don't you skip it?
Is something wrong, Megumi?
Ah, good morning, Toshiaki-kun.
No, everything's fine.
Yo.
Huh? He asked you to a date?
Yep. He didn't mince words.
So will you go?
Hey, Toshiaki-kun…
Why don't we go to the Forest Park again?
Forest Park?
We used to play there a lot with other kids
back at the kindergarten.
You might remember something while we're there.
Hey, you two!
No slacking!
Please return it by Wednesday.
Okay.
All right, then.
I guess I can call it a day.
You're…!
She's not here?
Hold up.
Do you always run away after looking at one's face?
That's not it, I was…
We need to talk.
Is Morio Megumi your girlfriend?
Why do you ask that?
Just answer the question, man.
Megumi is my childhood friend.
So she's not your girlfriend.
I see.
Which means that it won't matter to you if I invite her.
Tōno!
Remember how you said that Hideyoshi didn't look similar at all?
Yeah.
Because he didn't.
How can you know?
I met Hideyoshi.
Huh?!
You… met Hideyoshi?
Well, to be honest, my phrasing was off.
Strictly speaking, I met him in my previous life.
Previous… life?
I have memories of my previous life.
Don't be absurd.
I'm dead serious.
Before being born in modern age…
…I plotted against the shogunate in the Satsuma Domain at the end of the Edo period.
Earlier than that, I was a strategist during Warring States period under Toyotomi Hideyoshi.
The famous siege of Odawara was my strategy.
But nothing of it matters.
What matters is that I'm interested in Morio Megumi.
Oh, wait.
Memories of previous lives…?
Mr. Y's Neighbors
2-2 ~When I see you in my dreams~
Looks like you got the hang of it for the most part.
I'd say it's still so-so.
But it's important to stay sharp…
…so I'll have to practice after school too.
Megumi.
What do you think of Tōno Tsukasa?
Let's see…
He invited me to a date,
which means he has good taste in women.
Just kidding.
Why do you ask?
Nah, forget it.
Let's go. The afternoon classes start soon.
Huh?
What about the practice in the auditorium?
I skipped it.
Are you okay with that?
Yep!
Hey, let's go in a roundabout way today.
Where are you?
Seira.
The diligent candidate for the head of the class, Kara.
It's you, isn't it?
Yes.
Just like I thought.
I know about you too.
You're Seira, the prodigy that set the new record on the semestral tests.
Happy birthday, Kara.
Thank you for the earrings.
They look great on you.
Seira… we'll be together forever, right?
We will.
Seira.
Seira!
What's wrong?
I heard someone just now…
Someone said "Seira"…
Awesome!
Tōno-kun is so cool at everything he does!
Tsuzuki was at a tennis club at middle school so it's only natural they have such a pushy match.
He did it!
Game set!
Have you played tennis before?
Does your music practice go well?
Yep.
I may not look like it, but I can play piano.
The stage music should be flashy.
Why don't you play in an orchestra with me?
It'll be great, I'm telling you.
But I've already planned my music career.
It's all right.
You can discuss it with me should you want to change it.
Cut it out already.
Hm?
You're troubling Megumi.
Knock it off.
What is it to you?
Or maybe you do love Morio after all?
Tsuzuki.
Tōno!
Wanna fight?
Don't! Toshiaki-kun!
Tōno-kun, you too!
Morio…
Tōno-kun!
Toshiaki-kun!
W-What was that?
Tōno-kun!
Wait!
"Seira"?
I felt Tōno's voice even though he didn't speak…
Wait, Tōno-kun!
Why do you pick on Tsuzuki-kun?
Is it okay for you to skip classes?
Answer the question!
I don't like him.
I don't like seeing you with him!
Wh-Why do you care about us?
You too? You love him, huh?
I do.
We've always been together ever since we were little.
I want to know everything about him.
I want to stay with him forever.
He was in an accident when he was 6 years old.
It seems that he lost his memory before then.
What if his memory returns…
…and this time he forgets about you instead?
Being forgotten is very painful.
I felt it.
There's no mistake.
Psychokinesis waves.
Also something else but frail.
It was probably telepathy waves.
Telepathy…?
Seira.
Seira!
Seira…
Who am I…?
Tōno.
Did you come to finish the business
from the chemistry class?
Nope.
When you met me at the library for the first time…
…you asked me if we had met before.
What about it?
Frankly, I also felt like I have met you before.
The me who was in Kyūshū
around the end of the Tokugawa period.
The me who was a strategist under Hideyoshi
during the Warring States period.
But actually there's one more timeline of my past lives' memories.
Remember how the measuring flask
broke by itself?
Yeah.
I caused it.
What…?
I did it with a power from my past life.
Sometimes I can't suppress it and it manifests.
That former life is, how to say it… it's from far in the future.
In that era, there are lots of psychokinesis users like me as well as telepaths.
Those people undergo elite education in special schools.
Looks like I was in such school too.
But I believed that you should work for your success by yourself, like in the American dream.
I dropped out of school with a bunch of friends and tried living such life.
And what does it have to do with me?
One of those friends.
You look like a guy who was my best buddy.
To make it worse, both of us
fell for the same woman.
Tōno.
Do you seriously believe
in your previous lives' memories?
I do…
Seira!
Seira…?
Yeah!
It's that future friend's—
Or rather, love rival's name.
This is absurd.
Seira.
Hello?
Tsuzuki here.
Of course. Please wait a moment.
Toshiaki?
You got a call from Morio-san.
Hello?
Toshiaki-kun?
Did I wake you up?
Not at all.
I'm sorry for calling you so late.
I don't mind.
What's up?
I just wanted to hear your voice.
I wanted to hear you too.
Thank you.
Toshiaki-kun.
You see…
What is it?
Nah.
Never mind.
Megumi.
Are you free tomorrow?
I'm so glad.
You remembered what I said before.
I guess.
But it wasn't just that.
I wanted to come here too.
I wanted to come here…
…with you, Megumi.
Toshiaki-kun, look.
It's a picture of you and me.
It's a picture taken when everyone has been playing here.
You have become somewhat shy after the accident.
This is the only picture of us together.
You used to bully me a lot at that time.
You were very mischievous then.
I guess I can say it after all this time…
To be perfectly honest,
I'm a little thankful for that accident.
You've stopped bullying me ever since.
You became a little shy.
I think that's cute.
I don't think it's cute, though…
But…
I'm not sure why, but…
I'm afraid that one day you'll disappear from me without warning.
I felt like this since forever.
Megumi.
I can't leave things like this.
I want to regain my memories from before the age of six.
Okay.
34th Cultural Festival
Watch it.
I'm fine.
Okay…
Heave-ho.
So heavy…
It's finally tomorrow, huh…
Yeah.
She's pretty good.
– She is.
– Hm?
Telepathy waves!
He's here after all.
He's in this era!
Seira!
Huh?
What's wrong, Tsuzuki?
– Seira!
– Huh?
That voice…!
Seira!
Kara!
Kara's right here!
Kara?
Yeah.
Your lover, Kara!
You still don't remember?!
You're Seira!
Seira!
Megumi, watch out!
Megumi!
You're…
Taisa.
Seira.
Kara!
Are you okay?
Hang in there.
What in the world happened?
Kara…
Seira.
Why didn't you take that selection exam?
I'd like to go with Taisa.
No way.
You promised we'll be together forever.
I'm sorry, Kara.
I've already decided.
There's no going back.
Taisa, please…
Why don't you talk him out of this?
Kara, Seira decided for himself.
I can't say anything.
Seira!
Seira.
They're us at that time!
Taisa Haim!
Seira Mon!
We're arresting you on the grounds of spacetime manipulation!
Don't be stupid!
We didn't lay a finger on the time machine!
You left evidence behind.
It's your card numbers.
Kara!
You did this?
It's you, isn't it?
We finally meet again…
I've been looking for your voice for a long time ever since.
Seira.
I wanted to apologize to you.
I didn't understand your thoughts at that time.
I'm sorry.
Kara.
Seira!
The culprits are on the run!
They're approaching the time machine room!
Are you okay, Seira?
Yeah.
As if we'd let them break our dreams like this.
Give up, you two!
Shit!
The machine…!
It's going to explode!
Seira!
Toshiaki!
Toshiaki…!
Ambulance is on the way.
One child has been hurt.
The reason for the explosion is still unclear.
I understand now!
Due to the explosion of the time machine,
I was blown away into that day 10 years ago.
An explosion accident of unknown cause.
It was caused by the blast of the time machine.
Back then…
…the explosion has already torn my body.
I wanted to live and so I left my body.
Caught in the shock of the explosion…
…the real Toshiaki's consciousness that has gone out of the body was no more.
With what remained of my power…
…I, who have just left Seira's body…
…entered the body of Tsuzuki Toshiaki.
All of his memories have been erased back then.
I remember now.
Toshiaki died at the age of six.
Toshiaki's memories will never come back again.
Seira.
Still, Toshiaki Tsuzuki had lived for 16 years.
The lost memories will never come back…
…but in exchange, there are a lot of new memories.
You should take good care of both and keep on living.
Kara.
Are you going to take us back to the 23rd century, to the spacetime police?
Of course not.
I see.
Thank you, Kara.
Stay safe.
Taisa.
Seira.
It's just like Taisa said.
You can't regain lost memories…
…but you can always make new ones.
I want to cherish the lost memories.
Everything's connected through the current me.
Seira.
I'm glad I got to meet you.
Kara.
I can clearly understand you now.
But…
It's fine.
I was able to see you again.
I'm so happy.
I will never forget that I loved you.
Thank you, Seira.
I'll love you forever.
Kara.
I wonder if Kara's doing well.
Yeah.
She'll be fine.
But Megumi is incredible.
She acts the next day like nothing happened.
She lets us listen to that brilliant flute play…
Sorry. Looks like I won again.
Don't be stupid.
Like I care.
Heh.
You can drop the tough act.
Since when do they get along so well?
You can get by wherever you are.
There's place for everything in this wide world.